THE NIKKATSU CORPORATION
PRESENTS
Where's our limo?
It's a truck!
Oh, we deserve better!
Is there a festival on tonight?
- A festival?
- Yes, the big one at Suwa Shrine.
That's in Sakagi.
That bus will get you there
in 40 minutes.
By bus?
How much is the fare?
It's about 80 yen.
80 yen...
How far is it on foot?
Two miles over the ridge...
The bus is leaving!
Hey, wait for me!
Climb aboard!
Is it 80 yen to Sakagi?
I have a proposal.
Can I pay later?
I ran out of cash getting here.
If it's OK, I can pay tomorrow.
I don't think so, sir...
I'm Shintaro Funaki, a sophomore at
Jonan University majoring in Economics.
I promise to bring the money
to your depot. Take my student ID.
No way! Forget it!
Buses and public baths
never take credit.
- Sorry.
- It's OK, I'll walk.
Sorry to trouble you!
THE WIND-OF-YOUTH GROUP
CROSSES THE MOUNTAIN PASS
Will I leave? Or will I go back?
The dimples on her pretty face
I can't leave behind...
CAST:
KOJI WADA,
MAYUMI SHIMIZU
NOBUO KANEKO,
HIROSHI NIHONYANAGI
SHIN MORIKAWA,
ARIHIRO FUJIMURA
In the town of Soma,
Winds blow over the bushes
On the wind-blown bushes
Is a pretty flower
My hometown of Soma
Where the Enlightened One rests
DIRECTED BY SEIJUN SUZUKI
Tie horses in a line
So we won't separate...
That's Mom and Dad up at the front.
And Mr. Murakawa, the trumpeter.
Next to him is my sister Misako
and Motchan.
And next to them is...
Oh? What's wrong?
I can't tell one from the other.
I bet!
- I'm Megumi. Nice meeting you.
- Same here.
I wish I traveled all year round
like you.
- You like traveling?
- Oh, yes.
I went to Hokkaido.
Next up is Kyushu.
I'll cover Japan while I'm a student,
then I'll go to America.
I'll sell Japanese products.
That's great!
You aim high!
I wish I were like you.
That was a dusty ride!
Stop right there!
Stop!
I'm Akita, the promoter.
Who's Kinyo Imai?
I am, sir.
Thanks for meeting us out here.
- Who does the striptease?
- Let me show you.
That girl there.
Just the one?
What about her?
That's my daughter.
She does magic.
Girlie, come here.
No trouble.
Let's see what you've got.
Akemi...
You have great legs.
And tits too!
Do you strip right down?
If I feel like it.
Good!
Goodbye, sir.
Make sure she feels like it.
Who's that jerk?
Let's swerve this town, Boss.
We'll stay. It's only for a night.
Kurita, we're on.
Put the banner up.
Akemi, sit here.
KINYO IMAI TRAVELING
MAGIC SHOW
This is a magic troupe
but she's the star.
Feast your eyes on this!
This lock will keep your home safe.
With guaranteed durability.
A hit from a hammer won't scratch it.
It's yours for just 200 yen.
Excuse me.
Is this spot taken?
- What's it look like?
- Thank you.
What are you up to, young fella?
I'm working.
Working?
You know what a vendor's space is?
No. What's that?
You don't know?
You need permission
to sell things here.
I just asked you.
That won't do.
You really are clueless.
Monopolizing trade is illegal!
Listen, kid.
You're pissing me off.
Wait. All I ate today was
a boxed lunch on the train.
Hunger irritates people.
- That's enough.
- Stop, you idiot!
We outsiders can't afford
to get into brawls.
He commandeered this space.
I didn't. I don't know
what he's talking about.
You're a student?
Move it.
What's your story?
I worked to fund my trip,
but my boss went bankrupt
and paid me in merchandise.
Young men today are pragmatic!
Is that right?
I just like traveling.
I see.
We're the Senba Yakuza family
and we go round all the festivals.
Why don't you tag along?
That sounds great!
My name is Shintaro Funaki.
I'm Jeep Aoki.
He's Full Moon Sanpei.
For my fully rounded personality.
What are you selling?
These.
These won't sell.
Oh, no!
There you are!
Akemi!
Will you marry me
if I left my wife?
Come on, Akemi!
Take them off!
Hush! I was just about to.
- I'll have a go.
- Out of my way!
Where's the light?
Oh, what a surprise!
That was something.
The wiggling and the wobbling
and the shaking.
That vamp made me dizzy.
If she got you dizzy,
the next act will kill you!
Yeah? What's the next act?
For the first time in Sakagi,
we have the great magicians,
Kinyo and Kinka.
Let the magic begin!
Let's hear it for them, folks!
- Off the stage, Pop!
- Old lady, take off your clothes!
This is dumb!
Give us the striptease!
- OK, I'll do something exciting.
- Don't bother!
I'm not here for a magic show!
Akemi!
Strip, please!
Here, have an eye full!
Akemi!
Hey, sis.
- What's wrong?
- Get ready.
I saw that student
hawking at the festival.
- What was he selling?
- Well...
It's something too shocking
for a lady to say.
Like some, ladies?
No!
- He has some nerve.
- Just looking at 'em makes me blush.
Take a look.
Hi, there!
Young man, do me a favor.
Certainly. You're my first customer.
I'll give you a special deal.
That's not it.
I'm traveling but I'm short for cash.
You look new at this.
You're wasting a good space.
I'll be your hawker.
- And do what?
- I'll show how it's done.
Step aside and watch.
You've got nothing to lose.
Step up, one and all!
Slip 'em on!
Bras and undies!
They're not old undies.
Nylon undies
from a Tokyo fashion house.
Of the best quality!
Gentlemen.
Ken-san. Let's drink
to celebrate our new friendship.
Thank you, but I have business.
Please, excuse me tonight.
That's a shame.
Young man, I have to go.
What's the mark-up?
- Mark-up?
- What's the cost price?
I don't know.
My boss just paid me off in panties.
I see.
How about quatro-seis?
What's that?
It means 4 to 6.
You get 6 out of 10.
OK, that's good.
Here.
Young man, sorry I bothered you.
Farewell, brothers of the Senba family.
He's all business.
- I haven't seen him around.
- I bet he's experienced.
Is he in the same trade?
He's an empty-handed Yakuza.
He's on the road and broke.
They hawk for other Yakuza
for a percentage.
He goes around empty-handed.
That's funny.
- He's tracking someone down.
- I bet.
Mister!
Do you know him?
He gave me a ride on their truck.
Now I can pay him.
I like that, Student!
You're more dignified
than most young men today.
I have a candle here.
With a presto,
I'll turn it into a bouquet. Behold!
- Whoops...
- You're too hasty.
Hold this hole down like this.
I know that.
Let me try again.
Magic is 50% skill. Right, Dad?
Otherwise I'd be out of business.
- It's ready.
- Thanks.
Hercules, it's payday.
- Here.
- Thanks, Boss.
Has Akemi gone out?
- Mr. Akita took her for a drive.
- A drive?
She's so laid-back.
Why is she staying up
when she has a show tomorrow?
Her act is always lousy
after a night out.
Talk to her, everybody.
Mura, didn't you know about Akemi?
I knew we shouldn't have come here.
I don't like the look
of that man, Akita.
But you know Akemi.
She flirts with any rich looking guy.
Take that back!
Akemi doesn't flirt!
When did you see her flirt?
Break it up!
Stop, Hercules!
Mura, run!
Stop it!
Please don't!
Let me down!
- What a dumb muscleman!
- Who called me dumb?
Who said that?
He said you were all muscle.
I heard what he said.
I challenge you!
Hercules, the student
didn't mean anything.
- I won't let him off.
- I accept you challenge.
Come outside!
Let's do it here.
But I'll decide how we settle this.
In a duel,
the challenged chooses the weapon.
Good! Judo, sumo, karate...
Just name it!
No good, I can't do any of them.
How about this?
- What's that?
- Thumb wrestling.
- You joker!
- Hold it!
I thought I could choose.
Unless you're no good at it...
Nonsense! Come on!
We do this sitting.
- He got away!
- Come on!
OK, Mary Akemi.
- Are you in on the plan?
- Sure thing.
- Long as you pay up.
- I'll do as I said.
Mr. Akita,
you've been gone a while.
Business!
Hey, Sabu.
- Get me ten thugs right away.
- Yes, sir.
He won!
Having a good time?
- Evening, sir.
- Akemi's back!
Thanks for putting us up
in this nice inn.
We usually sleep backstage.
I'm pleased you're happy.
Can I have a word?
- With me, sir?
- Yes.
Listen, Kinyo.
It's about Akemi.
She was confiding in me tonight.
It sounds like she's had it
with your act.
What do you mean?
- That's horseshit!
- Stay out of this!
Akemi's tired of going
from one venue to the next.
She'll have to leave your company.
- Is that true?
- Something like that.
You could've told me sooner, Akemi.
You can't walk out
on such short notice.
Can't you just finish the shows
we've booked?
Yes, that sounds fair.
Why are you quitting?
Is some guy behind this?
Ms. Mary Akemi signed
an exclusive contract
with Akita Promotions.
She'll perform at my shows
and at bigger venues. She'll be a star!
You should be happy
that she got a break.
Mr. Akita, don't mess around.
- You're being so irrational.
- He's right!
I wouldn't act tough if I were you.
Come up here!
Get your ass out of here!
Let him go!
Didn't I warn you not to do that?
Put her down!
Go.
- Don't you have a contract?
- No, we don't.
Call me old-fashioned,
but verbal agreements mean more
than a piece of paper.
Then there's nothing you can do.
- There isn't?
- No.
If she's not legally bound,
she's free to go.
But he deserves a slap
for the trouble he's caused.
What's that?
You bitch...
You can hit me.
What's going on?
- He shot me!
- Don't be so rough, Student!
You joker!
- Then what?
- I slept in the stable.
Do horses sleep quietly?
I'd say they're probably
quieter than you.
Oh, you don't know me!
- I can tell.
- You can't.
I can barely pay my tuition
but I travel,
so I should put up with the stables.
- Want one?
- Thank you.
Living rough makes life interesting.
You meet people
and have encounters.
I envy students.
You're optimistic and easy-going.
- You think so?
- Yes.
There's more to it.
I am naturally easy-going.
But I know that pessimism
gets me nowhere.
There's enough trouble in the world.
I'd rather be carefree than worried.
- We don't have that luxury.
- Why not?
We always walk in the shade.
That's an old wives' tale.
If you don't like the shade,
walk in the sun.
- It's just how you see it.
- You're right.
But living with Dad can be bleak.
We don't even have a home.
I want to go to Tokyo
and work in an office.
I want to live like a regular girl.
After all
I'm just like maiden grass
Wilting sadly by the stream
And just like me
You're maiden grass
Wilting sadly by the stream
We know very well
What our future holds
We know our love won't bloom
Not in our lifetime
For we're lonely
Wilting maiden grass
Where would
that magician family be now?
They got to me,
especially the girls.
Come on, sis!
And then he goes...
...like that!
We need a striptease act, dear.
I can go to Tokyo
and find a stripper.
- I could be back in five days.
- Don't you worry.
We're a magic show act.
We have no use for a wild girl
bouncing around.
My magic tricks will attract people.
I hope so, dear.
You must be joking.
Use your common sense.
Audiences these days
want a striptease.
- That's how things go.
- Have a drink.
- But, sir...
- I'm sorry the girl left you.
But it says striptease
on the marquee.
I can't pay you in full.
Kayo, honey.
We wouldn't be in business
if it wasn't for your songs.
- I'll do my best.
- Go get 'em.
I'll pay you half.
I said three days
but you have two days.
That makes no sense!
We're a magic show act.
The striptease was just for variety.
Take it or leave it.
People only came to your show
to see Mary Akemi.
Magic shows aren't enough.
That's why I got a singer.
The wind comes whistling along
The tide comes rolling along
It's lonely on the beach
With the setting sun
If you're all by yourself
It's even lonelier
On my hands, harvesting kelp
As the tears fall
I stretch my back
Look up and see
Beyond the faraway sky
Thank you.
Watch your step.
Let's go.
- Lady, let me do it.
- How nice of you.
- Here.
- Thank you.
KINYO IMAI
TRAVELING MAGIC SHOW
Boss, let me tell you a bad joke
that Mura told me.
It was so bad I...
Maybe later.
I can only depend
on Mr. Yamaguchi now.
He and I go way back
and he knows us well.
He can help us
with his connections.
He always said he'd help us
if we had a problem.
Kurita, take a letter to him
after the show.
I will.
I don't like asking for favors but...
I think I'm getting old.
Ken-san, is that you?
Hey, Shintaro!
Oh, hello.
- Dad, Shintaro is here.
- Hi!
- How's business?
- Not bad.
Good for you.
- Here.
- Thank you.
It's a gift.
Dad, open it.
- Anything wrong?
- Keep out of it.
Business is bad.
I'll open your gift.
People don't go to magic acts.
Kurita, pour some tea.
It's time to pull out
and start a new business.
Don't be silly!
Dad, you know
Mr. Katsumata was right.
Fool! You're a fool!
He's the only fool.
Let him keep his dignity.
Please leave.
It's nothing to do with you.
We need an outside opinion.
Otherwise, we'll go on living
from hand to mouth.
Excuse me.
Shintaro, I want to hear
what you think.
I admire the courageous way you live.
I wish you could find a way
to continue.
Dear...
Do you know a man
with a scar on his face?
I do!
He asked us
about Kurita and his tattoo.
The falcon tattoo on his shoulder.
How about a lock for 200 yen?
Only 200 yen!
This lock won a special national prize!
Far better than first or second place.
- Hey, Ken-san!
- Why don't you take a break?
OK, it's your turn.
So you're looking for someone.
Is it a gal?
Or somebody you want to kill?
Do I look like that type of guy?
I just enjoy traveling, same as you.
Can I have your attention ladies,
young, old, tall or short?
Student!
Meet me behind the shrine
tonight at ten.
- What for?
- I'll teach you to stay away.
You can bring company if you want.
Be sure to come!
I don't know what you mean...
Hey!
This must be a mistake.
I have no money on me.
Don't worry, I'm no thief.
Just keep walking
and don't make a scene.
I'm delivering an important letter
from my boss.
Can't you wait until I've delivered it?
Our company's future depends on it.
Keep walking.
Stop.
Show me the tattoo, Gen.
Who are you?
I'm Ken.
I'm affiliated with the Ezaki family.
I knew it!
I knew someone would
come for me someday.
Listen, Ken-san.
It's true,
I did run away from the Yakuza.
But I didn't go blabbing
to the police.
I'd just had enough of drug dealing.
Do you still have to kill me?
Looks that way.
- That's what the deal is.
- All right.
- Then so be it.
- Now walk straight.
Turn around when I say.
That'll be the end for you.
Ken-san. Do me a favor.
Deliver this letter for me.
You're awfully loyal
to that no-good company.
We traveled, ate and slept together.
They're more important
than family to me.
- You wouldn't understand.
- No.
I don't want to.
Please...
Come on!
Stop tormenting me!
Is that your gun?
Sorry about that.
But you lied to me.
I'd say we're even now.
Mr. Kurita!
Move it!
Go and do what you have to do.
Thank you.
I owe you one, Student!
What am I supposed to do now?
We've had enough trouble.
You wouldn't shoot me for no reason.
You're not a mad dog.
Maybe I am a mad dog.
You get on my nerves.
Out of my sight now!
- Not yet.
- Why not?
I need to ask you a favor.
That's enough fooling around.
I'm in trouble. A tough guy from
the magic company wants to fight me.
I'd rather not get involved
in some dumb fight.
I figure it's best
to get it over and done with.
I want you to be the mediator.
I don't want anybody hurt.
You're alright, kid.
You're late!
I see you've got a sidekick.
Don't get me wrong.
He's just an observer.
Why don't we talk before we fight?
This is ridiculous.
I'm not here to talk!
He doesn't want to talk.
Mr. Mochizuki!
Are you OK?
Look at you,
there's mud on your face.
You're one lucky son of a gun.
- You're not so bad yourself.
- Don't flatter me.
What about the old clown?
He won't be back.
I'll just find him again.
He's trying too hard to go straight.
Leave him be.
No way.
Stick to your own business.
Lady, step up and take a peek.
Why not strip off and try these?
Stick to your own business
when it's all you have.
Come enjoy our magic show!
Thank you for coming, sir.
Mr. Yamaguchi.
It's usually more crowded.
It's so hot,
folks don't leave home.
In the evening,
we'll get a packed house.
Did you say quit?
Yes, I think you'd better disband.
I came all this way,
but I won't promote this act.
Mr. Yamaguchi, I beg you.
I know it's a risk,
but I want to perform in your theater.
We'll do our special show.
I'm not young anymore.
I won't do anything reckless.
Mr. Yamaguchi, give us
one last chance, please!
Mr. Kinyo, what would you bet?
Bet, sir?
If I promoted your act,
I'd be spending a lot on your show.
I'd be getting that.
What about you?
I see.
I bet my pride as a showman.
If I fail, I'll call it quits.
Your pride isn't worth a penny.
Let me ask you, sir.
What should we bet?
How about Ms. Misako?
Don't get me wrong,
I don't want her for my concubine.
I want her for my son's wife.
But your son's a dim...
Yes, he's a dimwit.
He's a little simple
after he contracted meningitis.
Folks, presenting
the strongest man in Japan.
George, psst!
George!
He's Hercules Sano!
With a yell,
he will break this thick chain!
Witness his power.
Of course, I'll make sure
Misako is taken care of.
And I'll take care
of your magic show from now on.
I have to say no.
I'm Kinyo Imai, the magician.
I can't sell my daughter for a job.
You're not selling her. It's a bet.
If the show's successful,
the bet is off.
Do you lack confidence
in the show?
This is no joke!
We can't barter Misako for our show.
Right, everyone?
Boss, I'd rather perform on the street.
Don't be rude.
Don't assume we'll fail.
People will come!
I still have it left in me...
- But, my dear...
- What?
You don't have faith in me?
What about you, Misako?
You think I'm too old for this?
Misako?
Dad...
If your show's a success...
...let me go to Tokyo.
Mr. Yamaguchi...
So we're on, are we?
You bet. I'll put on a performance
of a lifetime! You just watch.
You can't gamble
with your future and happiness.
This is my only chance
to flee to Tokyo.
I can't let you marry that idiot.
What do you suggest?
Shintaro.
Sorry.
I'm just a helpless student.
We just have to trust your father.
Dad's practicing
his special magic trick.
Come and see his rope escape.
Isn't it exciting?
Come and cheer for him.
Cheering won't do any good.
I'm ready.
Misako, do the countdown.
I'll do it.
Ten seconds.
Four minutes and 40 seconds.
Four minutes and 50 seconds.
Boss, you can do it!
Dear...
Honey, I can't do it.
Oh, my dearest!
Dearest!
- I can't...
- Dad, don't be so pathetic!
Get a grip.
I have faith in you!
Thanks for the other day.
I delivered the letter.
- Why did you return?
- To talk to Ken-san.
Are you crazy?
Go before he sees you.
- I have to talk to him.
- Okay.
Ken-san.
He has something to talk to you about.
To me?
You've got a nerve,
you son of a bitch!
Ken-san.
I've had enough
of running and hiding.
You can do what you want with me.
I won't hide anymore.
On one condition, though.
I have a favor.
What is it?
Let me live
until the end of the next show.
The next show will determine
the fate of this company.
I want to help them
make the show a success.
Ken-san...
If you don't trust me,
come and keep an eye on me.
Ken-san, please.
I beg of you.
Have mercy on me.
Ready, Boss?
Here I go, Misako.
Five seconds.
Ten seconds.
Fifteen seconds.
Be quiet! He's concentrating.
Twenty seconds.
One minute and 15 seconds.
One minute and 20 seconds.
One minute and 25 seconds.
One minute and 30 seconds.
One minute and 35 seconds.
He did it.
One minute and 40 seconds.
- One minute and 45 seconds!
- Hurray!
Boss!
- Now I'm even!
- That hurt.
I did it!
You were great, Dad.
It took too long.
I would've drowned.
Drowned? What do you mean?
I'll be bound, cuffed
and locked in a box underwater.
That's dangerous!
Don't worry, I'll use a trick box.
Once I'm free, I'll come right out.
Cuff me.
Just when we've become pals,
we have to say goodbye.
I'd ask you to go with us
if you could, but you're a student!
Don't go to university
in your next life.
What's next, Student?
Thanks to you,
I got rid of the undies.
Now I'll explore Japan.
If you come across a festival,
look for us.
I will!
You made this trip a lot of fun!
Well, thanks to you,
we learned that panties sell well.
I'll toss my locks
and take up panties.
We'll be staying at Tatsumi Inn
in Wakamatsu.
Let's get moving.
- Off we go. So long!
- Thank you!
Bye-bye isn't a bad thing
But it's kind of sad
We hold back our tears
Until we meet again, that's right!
Good morning!
Mr. Kinyo and the gang
went to the dam.
With my vital capacity,
I'll last two minutes.
I'm sure I can get out
in one minute or so.
But wait until one minute
and 40 seconds.
I'll leave it to you.
Yes, dear.
This is thrilling and suspenseful.
Will Dad be OK?
It's a piece of cake for him.
I got you!
Come one, come all!
Kinyo Imai performs
the greatest show of his life!
Get ready to give him a big hand!
One minute and 25 seconds.
There are no bubbles
coming to the surface.
Can you feel any movement
on the rope?
One minute and 30 seconds.
Pull it up.
Leave it there.
One minute and 38, 39 seconds...
Forty.
Forty-one.
Forty-two.
Ma'am.
I know what he can take.
Wait till two minutes.
Do it! Pull it up!
Quickly!
- We'll have to quit.
- I guess that's the only choice.
Don't give up!
You know I'm not smart.
I'll never make it on my own.
It won't be easy for me either.
There's no other option.
What can we do?
The show was built
around the boss' magic act.
What a happy way to go.
You died mid-performance.
That's the best way for a performer.
I want to put on a show.
We can't just call it quits.
It's my chance to go to Tokyo.
But I want the show to go on
for the troupe.
If Mr. Yamaguchi agrees,
I can pull it off.
But the audience won't be satisfied
with old tricks.
It takes time to master new tricks.
Do you have any good ideas?
You can make it into a revue.
A revue?
Your father's rope escape
would've been a great attraction.
That's the way to do it.
Mr. Kurita.
Mr. Yamaguchi is pulling out on us.
He can't!
He thinks it's gone too far.
He wants out.
If you want this,
you should go and talk to him.
YAMAGUCHI
I don't think people
are bored with magic.
It's just how it's presented.
Audiences get bored
with how the show unfolds.
She's right.
The tricks shouldn't be in a sequence
but integrated into a revue.
A revue?
The magic acts will be part
of an exciting show.
But you have no star attraction.
You can't attract people with your name.
I think I'll have to cancel.
All companies start
without stars and name value.
Give us two days, or just one day.
Give us a chance.
And our bet is still on.
I can't lose this bet.
It seems unfair.
Let's not do this.
Let me talk to some magicians
about your mother and the troupe.
Mr. Yamaguchi, this is not
my father's bet. It's mine.
Have you seen my son?
This is Ryosuke.
Say hello.
Misako.
Are you still on?
Yes.
- Mura?
- Can't you find Mura?
He's nowhere!
Well, go without him.
- So long!
- Take care.
I haven't seen Mura since last night.
Did he split?
Imagine leaving us at a time like this!
Let him go!
Let the coward be gone!
Off we go, start the truck!
I'll be at Star Theater!
I hold the deck like this
and the lady taps it.
The card you selected will remain!
If it works,
let's hear some applause!
- Is this the card?
- Come on, Motchan!
Fail with style!
Don't ruin your gag!
Oh, can't I get it right sometimes?
Six, 2, 3, 4!
Seven, 2, 3, 4!
Misako, this is a striptease number,
you know?
Yes, and I'm doing it.
Anything for the show.
I find the way
they apply themselves wonderful.
Performers are looked down on,
but they have such dignity.
Not everyone can do this.
Exactly.
Who'd dedicate themselves
to something so silly?
You say that,
but you come to see it every day.
I'm just keeping my eye
on the clown.
You never know what he's up to.
He calls himself a clown
but he can't get it right.
He doesn't know how to move.
Can you put this up?
It's a revue...
Our clientele wouldn't appreciate this.
OK, I'll have a coffee.
Now I'm the clientele.
Give him a coffee.
Now can we talk?
2 X COFFEE
7 X COFFEE
CAF
We're the Shurei Imai Traveling Revue.
We have a new show for your fans.
New entertainment
for you lovely folks!
He sucks.
He's chasing people away!
- Maybe you can help.
- What baloney!
- I will, then.
- What, you?
I should be OK.
I learned from the best.
Correct me.
Attention, fair local ladies,
young and old!
Intelligent gents,
kids, pops and grandpas!
Come see the one and only
Shurei Imai Revue
and its brand new show!
It made a Bolshoi Circus
illusionist faint!
You'll read that in the papers soon.
That's right!
Kick back and try 'em on!
Have a ball with the Shurei Imai Revue!
That's good!
Welcome to our show,
ladies and gents.
Let me present myself.
I'm a handsome bachelor...
- Daddy!
- Don't give me away!
Let me present
my beautiful daughter.
Good morning, darling.
I feel cold under my nose...
Oh, no!
I have here a deck of cards.
Just like what you have at home,
no tricks.
Pick a card, please.
Sir.
We have group discounts.
Shut up!
I'm not here for your silly show.
Give me Akemi and Mura!
They quit, sir.
Don't lie to me.
Mura took Akemi from me.
Give her back!
Or else I'll make a scene on stage.
Where's your ticket?
Don't play dumb! I'm Akita!
If you insist, I'll call the police.
I'm not scared of cops.
Come on!
How much?
To the box office, please.
To the end of the line, please.
Don't make a fuss
when you can't find Akemi.
Shut up!
- What do we do?
- Beats me.
I thought Akemi could be useful.
Even dead trees on a mountain
look cheerful.
Are you saying I'm a dead tree?
How did you do that?
It wasn't easy with that Akita.
I forced my way in to get Akemi.
Akita's men caught up with us.
- I was a little rough...
- That's not good.
Then the police probably won't help us.
Should we get Mr. Yamaguchi's help?
We don't want him involved.
And Ken-san?
He won't help.
Megumi, go to the Tatsumi Inn.
Ask the Senba family for their help.
Men!
Get her!
I'll keep Akita busy.
Who's in charge?
Student!
Stop, Student!
Where did you hide, Akemi?
I'll sue you for breach of contract!
Sabu! Takao!
How long do I have to wait?
I have a short fuse!
When the show ends, you can talk
to Mura, Akemi and the boss.
He's just buying time.
Let's crash the show.
You're right.
Let's go.
Hold on one more second.
Don't touch Mr. Akita!
You started this!
What's the racket?
Ken-san!
Your attention.
A girl will shoot
out of the cannon instead of a ball.
Will she come out alive?
Fire!
Dad, can you hear the applause?
Aren't you coming?
Then I'm gone.
Bastard!
Out of my way!
Move!
Sorry, fella, we have business
to take care of.
We're the invincible Senba family!
If I let you walk away
All that'll be left is
A memory of you
Who wants to live
Just with memories?
You're the one I set my mind on
I'll never let anyone
Never let anyone
Have my baby
Even the stars
Fall in love tonight
This wouldn't have been possible
without you.
Thank you, sirs. I'm so happy.
Ma'am, we should be thanking you.
We kicked butt so good,
we feel like kings!
Come inside.
Wonderful! This is magnificent!
What a success!
Are you saying we won?
Oh, yes, I completely lost.
I have an offer.
How about a half-year contract?
I want your show
to tour all my theaters.
Ten days here,
then half a month in Sendai.
And I'll raise your salaries.
I'll buy you a missus.
We can finally have a baby.
I can get that new designer suit.
What do you say?
Thank you, sir.
Father would have been so happy.
I'll accept the offer.
Don't you want to go to Tokyo?
Forget it, Mother.
Let's drink to us, Misako.
Hold your drinks up!
Cheers!
Old man, are you ready now?
Yes, I have no regrets now.
I was able to perform
to a packed house.
I appreciate it.
Ken-san?
Oh, give it up, mad dog.
I told you to mind
your own business.
So you want to do it?
Come on, it's not that I want to.
But if I don't shoot him,
I'll lose face.
Just empty it then.
The problem is,
I've never missed my target.
I see.
Right, then.
Shoot.
Come on.
Go ahead and shoot.
Don't rush me, you're annoying me.
Sorry. I'll turn around
and have a smoke.
Does shooting off a round satisfy you?
You put in blanks!
When did you do that?
Last night.
I had a foreboding hunch.
Some joker you are!
If I heard you right,
you have no reason to shoot him now.
I'm out!
Have a nice life, old man.
Shintaro!
See you later.
Okay.
Where have you been?
I had a talk with Mr. Kurita.
Oh, I was afraid
you'd just go off and leave us.
I'll stick around until the run ends.
Sorry.
I broke my word.
Seeing the troupe, I thought...
I'm a performer's daughter.
You and I live in different worlds.
But the time we shared
was the best in my life.
I guess it's the last time
I'll feel like this.
We're still young.
We'll meet again one day.
You're right.
- I hope so.
- I've never met a gal like you.
The girls at school talk a lot,
but don't do much.
You make much more of your life.
- I admire you.
- Thank you.
I love how you're so kind.
Walk with me.
Listen, don't forget me
when you're back in Tokyo.
This is it for me.
I hope you have a successful tour.
Why here?
I want to walk and
enjoy the scenery.
It'd be harder to say goodbye
at the end of the ridge.
Well, then.
Goodbye.
Shintaro! We might see you
when we're touring America!
Go, driver. Step on it!
Goodbye!
In the town of Soma
Her hometown of Soma
It's breezy
So I whisper sweet words to my love
THE END