Right, though.
Let's kick this off, then, eh?
Once upon a time...
Once upon a time.
Anyway, once upon a time, yeah?
Okay.
Well, let me tell you about
getting fucked over by your demons.
How, eventually,
they're gonna catch up with you...
...tear you to pieces.
Let me tell you about him and her,
and her and him.
These poor good people,
and what happened to them.
It's quite sad, really,
to see how it all ended up.
How they all ended up.
Pulped on the floor
in that god-awful fucking place...
... With their guts spewed, hanging out,
dissected, dismembered.
Deceased.
Fucking dead.
Fucked.
It didn't end up good. It didn't...
Oh, it didn't end up good, you know.
Come on,
that's a fucking understatement.
I mean,
they meant the best for me...
... But, well, real life
doesn't have a happy ending.
At least
they don't have to live with it.
Because if there's one true victim
to be had from all this...
... I'll be perfectly honest with you...
...it's me.
It is me.
My name's Nick West, by the way.
We should rewind here.
I wanna tell you how it began
so innocently.
No one understood.
No one knew how deep all this ran.
I really wanna tell you
how it all went down.
If you stick with me,
it'll be worth your while.
Yeah, I didn't...
This is Sammy.
Hot fucking Sammy.
Sweet, sweet girl.
Fucking beautiful.
Sexy, filthy.
We're gonna get off our fucking nut.
I won't bore you with the details.
She's not gonna be around
long enough for them to matter.
I guess you've seen Hellraiser.
I'm guessing you've seen those kinds
of films. Pumpkinhead or whatever.
That's probably
why you're watching this now.
But after what happened
and what we found that day...
... Well, I wish I'd shown
a little more interest, you know...
... Paid more attention.
I might've learned something.
Nice.
Welcome to the asylum, baby.
I do what I can, you know.
First impressions: -
Fucking shithole.
So, what do you think of this place?
I guess the cleaner
must've pulled a sicky, eh?
Cunt's dead.
Yeah, cunt must be dead.
- Stupid bitch.
- Why so vexed about this...
I wouldn't say Sammy was easy,
you know.
But she wasn't exactly hard
to crackeither.
So are we gonna fuck
or are we gonna sightsee?
You know, couple of drinks,
few tabs...
... You stand a good chance
of a happy ending.
Romantic cunt, aren't you?
Oh, you got something.
Got something for you.
Wish you had a zipper.
Why don't you take a look at these?
What's that?
That's a little piece of magic, baby.
Acid? Come on, Nick, not here.
Come on.
Open your fucking mouth.
I'll stick a knife in your ass...
...you won't be able to sit down
for six weeks.
Okay.
Tongue.
One for you and one for me.
You're so fucking beautiful.
And you're fucking filthy too.
What you doing
with a lunatic like me?
I like weirdos.
I like the fact you like weirdos.
Come on, let's go see
how fucking crazy this place is now.
What the fuck is that?
Fucking hell. Fuck, look at that.
What the fuck?
What is that?
Now, that's the fucking reason
why we came here.
- Is that real?
- It's fucking real, you tit.
Wait, I know, I know, I know.
It's a fucking chair.
Big deal, right?
Well, all I can say is,
things aren't always what they seem.
Get in it. Go on.
- This is weird.
- Just sit in it.
- Go on, just get in it.
- It's just all the metal just lying around.
- Short and sweet.
- Let me tie you down.
So beautiful.
So, so beautiful.
Get my cock out. Get my cock out.
Suck me.
Come on. Deep, deep, deep.
Look at the dirty little rotter.
Sucking me till the 12th of never.
I want a go.
Come on, let me have a go.
I wanna see you fuck yourself. I'll be
the marquis, you can be my little slut.
I'm gonna fuck your mouth.
You look amazing.
You look beautiful.
The moment
before it all changed forever.
The moment before life fucked me
once and for all...
... And ripped out
whatever was left of my heart.
However you wanna say it,
it was fucked, it was stamped on.
It was done. And then, bang.
It all got really fucking weird.
Baby.
Fuck yourself.
Everything from here now
is sort of hazy...
... Like a nightmare or a fever dream.
Bits and pieces, that's all I've got.
- This is...
- Fuck yourself.
Fuck yourself.
Nick, please help me.
Sammy!
Nick. Nick, no!
Nick.
Blood.
Blood all over my hands,
all over my clothes.
Sammy missing...
... And me in the middle of it all,
ranting and raving about a chair.
It's not a big equation.
It all adds up
to an indefinite stay in hospital.
Have a guess what.
Me, Nick West.
I'm criminally insane, apparently.
Pills.
Pills they've got in here
make acid look like aspirin.
Just say no, don't do drugs.
Knock them back and swallow.
Don't ask questions.
Hi, my name's Nick West.
I'm medicated, how are you?
I've been inside for four years.
Four years of pills and bullshit.
Rotting in a room
because they don't believe me.
Nick.
Haven't seen it for themselves,
so it can't be true, yeah?
I wish they were right.
I wish I was crazy...
... Then there'd be one less psycho
on the streets, right?
And you'd feel safe in your beds.
Only we know that's not the truth.
The truth is...
... You're all in danger.
When you're trapped in a cell
that long...
... You think you're alone, forgotten,
but I wasn't.
Turns out he was watching me,
observing me, pulling my strings.
And then one day, he turned a key,
pushed a button.
Opened the doors
and let the world in...
... Or me out, I'm not sure.
And how do you feel these days,
Nick?
I feel healthy. I feel okay.
And the headaches?
They come and go.
What about the stories
you told the police?
How do you feel about those?
I've learned
they were my mind's responses...
...to the stress of what happened.
It's not uncommon for people
to create...
...fantasies in times of trauma.
What do you think the trauma was?
I know I'm guilty.
There's no other explanation.
I just have no memory
of what happened.
None at all?
That bothers you?
Of course it does.
He was acquitted of murder.
He's been a model patient
for four years...
...never putting a foot out of line.
Surely you don't think
he's dangerous?
To others, no,
but to himself, quite possibly.
He's suffering severe delusions.
Once.
Four years ago.
Never since.
I'm not very happy about this. He...
I'm not asking you
to just set him loose on the world.
I'm asking you
to put him into my care...
...so we can find out
what happened to Sammy.
Think about her family,
they deserve to know.
And you will take full responsibility
for the consequences?
Just show me where to sign.
Sign here, walk free.
Doesn't matter
that we think you killed someone.
Nick West?
They didn't think very much of me,
sending one guy.
I'm here to give you a lift, sir.
No, I'm gonna get the bus.
You're not gonna get a bus
around here, sir.
Look,
why don't you come with me, sir?
Come on, just get in the car.
And just like that...
... I was gone.
Where are we going?
Oh, I'm taking you
to meet someone, sir.
Fucking punts.
Welcome to Cambridge.
Here we are, then, sir.
Just knock and go in.
The doctor is expecting you, sir.
Doctor who?
Dr. Willard, sir.
Just go in.
Oh, here we go, Gandalf, slut.
He's half pedo, don't you know?
Melissa, leave us alone, will you?
Mr. West and I
have some business to discuss.
She's a little worried
leaving me alone with you.
Silly thing.
Why am I here?
Very well. You have been released,
but under certain conditions.
What conditions?
I'm writing a book.
What, do you need a typist?
No, no, no. Oh, no.
I need a subject.
You, Mr. West.
You want to write a book about me?
Absolutely.
Your situation provides me...
...with a fairly unique opportunity.
I want to study you
and your psychotic episode...
...where the episode itself
took place.
What do you mean?
The Blackwater Asylum.
You are to travel there with me.
Arrangements have been made.
The possibilities of this
on the study...
...have got my publisher
really very excited.
You don't know what you're doing.
I can't go back there.
Oh, I'm afraid you can.
Unless you want to return
to the asylum.
That's blackmail.
Yes.
No, no.
I'm simply asking
for a few days of your time...
...in exchange for answers
to questions that plague you daily.
Is that too much to ask?
Perfect timing.
Nick West, Rachel Fowles.
First impressions: Fuck me.
New mission:
Get her out of that outfit.
First hard-on in four years.
Pleased to meet you, Nick.
Rachel is one of my brightest
psychology students.
She's going to be helping me
with the study.
So, Nick, it's really great
that you're helping us with this.
Great for who?
So I guess Brett's running late.
Shit. Sorry I'm late.
First impressions: -
Well, look at the cunt, tosser.
Flat-line tosser.
Brett Wilson. How's it going?
- Brett, this is Nick.
- Nick?
- Nick West.
- Oh, yes.
I went to school with a Nick West,
but I imagine it wasn't you.
Brett, come on.
- What? That was funny.
- Cock.
Come on, just be nice.
Where's your sense of humour?
- He's had a really tough time, okay?
- Oh, has he?
- Dr. Willard.
- All right, all right, that's enough.
Melissa will be waiting outside
in the car.
Come on.
O my brothers...
... It really was this ridiculous,
like a bad Scooby-Doo.
Five hours of countryside
and educated nothingness.
Fine art and the theatre,
croquet and carrot cake.
Houses in France...
... And stuff that could never mean
anything to me.
Can they not hear themselves?
Their banal conversations
floating through the air...
... Like faeces
smeared across a crusty sky.
Sad bunch of vacuous little cunts.
With their private- school
educations...
... Strong, perfect parents.
Silver- spoon-fed failed models.
Preening, perfect, empty.
Clueless clown.
Poor little me.
And Gandalf.
Thank you.
Nick, you okay?
Of course I'm not okay, big tits.
Yeah.
This is gonna be easier
than you think.
Just whenever you're ready,
all right?
God.
This is atmospheric.
Careful where you tread.
No shit.
Looks like the maid died.
What?
Memories washing over me
like a fever...
... Making my head spin.
I started to sweat,
thought I was gonna throw up.
Was a real fucking trip,
and I wasn't having any fun.
Classic. He's having flashbacks.
Maybe we should follow him.
There's film in the camera.
We could follow him
and get his reactions.
Just leave him.
Tell me something, Willard,
am I the only one slightly concerned...
...that we've returned to the scene
of the murder with the murderer?
Nick.
Lot of memories in this place?
Something like that.
You can talk to me, you know.
Tell me what happened.
I don't know anymore.
It's all right.
Come on,
let's get back to the others.
Now, I suggest we eat...
...and discuss our reasons
for being here.
Melissa,
if you could organise the food...
I'll fetch the hamper from the car.
I'm just going to take you and Rachel
and show you the room upstairs.
Excuse me, Nick,
if you don't mind waiting here...
What the hell is this?
This is where the incident
supposedly took place.
At his worst point, he claimed that
that was what took his girlfriend.
So you know all about
why you're here?
I know bits and pieces
that he tells me.
And what did he tell you about me?
He didn't have to.
I know what you are.
So you think I'm a murderer,
do you?
I didn't say that.
If I were you,
I'd stay well away from me.
Dr. Willard wouldn't put me
in any danger.
He already has.
Hold on to this.
- What are you doing?
- Sitting down. What's it look like?
- Brett.
- What?
Mr. Wilson, get up from there.
That is not a plaything.
It's perfectly safe, I'm sure.
I mean, how...
- Brett?
Brett? Dr. Willard.
Brett! Brett!
"Brett! Brett!"
Oh, Jesus, Brett, you idiot.
Mr. Wilson,
I'm quickly tiring of your nonsense.
Get up out of that damn chair.
It's not funny.
Perhaps you could use up some of
that energy setting up the work lights.
"Brett! Brett!"
Grow up, Brett.
"Brett! Brett!
- You're on fire, Brett."
- Shut up!
He won't be laughing for long.
I never dreamt
I'd spend another night in that place.
But day turned to night pretty fast,
and where was I gonna go?
I was a dog on a leash,
with a cruel master.
One more left.
Fingers crossed, you piece of shit.
Never been afraid of the dark.
I was always more afraid
of the light.
I didn't wanna see
what was gonna happen.
If you can't see what's coming for you,
maybe it can't see you either.
Oh, we have light.
Here you go.
- Don't all thank me at once.
- Thank you.
Good work, Brett.
- Where's Dr. Willard?
- No idea. You want some of this?
Don't you think
we should wait for the doctor?
Why, is he the barman?
Do you want some of this?
I knew what was coming.
Needed to keep my wits about me,
stay sharp.
If he was smart, he'd do the same.
Last thing you wanna be is liquored- up
when the shit comes down.
And it would come down.
No?
Come on, man,
it's bloody freezing outside.
It doesn't mix with my medication.
Thank you for the light, Mr. Wilson.
It's wonderful.
Now we can see one another.
Say hello to fucking Gandalf.
Well, dinner's served.
Sorry it's not more exciting.
So, Willard, what have you
got planned for this evening?
Bit of disco dancing?
Game of cards?
Actually, I was hoping that Dr. Willard
would tell us more about this place.
Well, we are currently...
...in the kitchen area
of the Blackwater Institute.
Brett, you were supposed
to be filming this.
During the 1950s...
...this place was an institute
for mental health care...
...of a sort.
- An asylum?
- Yes, a private facility.
It was run by a revolutionary scientist
called Blackwater.
He was a great thinker,
an innovator.
He was taking the study
of the human mind...
...into whole new spheres
of research.
Sounds like a swell guy.
No, no, no, he was...
...for a time.
The details are a little sketchy, but it
would appear that at some time...
I would put it around 1958, 1959.
The scientific world, of which
he had become such a key part...
...turned on him.
I suppose he refused
to modernise his thinking...
...and so paid the price.
No longer taken seriously...
...Blackwater boarded himself
and his patients...
All of whom had significant
psychological problems.
Into the asylum.
None of his discoveries
were ever published...
...in respected journals.
By the time the authorities
shut him down in 1963...
...he was a shadow of a man.
As tormented as the last
of his surviving patients.
And what's that got to do with me?
Well, technically, not a thing.
The history of this place
is merely incidental.
What is significant...
...is that the beginnings
of your story started here.
Bringing you back to investigate
the reactions of your mind...
...that is the defining aspect
of the research.
We will begin tomorrow.
We will ask you questions,
ask you to relive your experience.
I wasn't listening.
Just staring into the shadows,
wondering what they were hiding.
I had to get out of there.
I was suffocating.
Excuse me.
I'll go check if he's okay.
I did think about ending it.
I'll admit that, better for everybody.
Long-run, maybe it would've been.
Me dead, they might've just left.
But I'm not a quitter.
It's something I just couldn't do.
There you are.
Are you all right?
I shouldn't have come back
to this place.
I spent years trying to get past this.
This is dangerous, me being here.
If you really want to leave,
I'm sure everyone will understand.
Maybe some more therapy
wouldn't be such a bad thing.
Back at the institute?
No.
Here, with Dr. Willard.
The things you think you saw...
...they seemed real.
Delusions always do.
Ghost stories are exactly that,
Nick...
...stories.
Your mind made them up
for some reason.
That just makes the truth worse,
doesn't it?
When we start the study tomorrow,
the truth will come out.
Then you can put all of this
behind you.
I killed a woman
and I can't remember doing it.
You don't get a lot of sympathy
when that kind of thing happens.
Your family and friends ostracize you.
They don't wanna know you anymore.
I spent every day at the institute trying
to piece together what happened.
And every day,
I came up with the same answer: -
That they think...
I'm there for the reason
they think I am. That I'm crazy.
I just can't find the answers.
It's just darkness.
- I've gotta go.
- No, don't.
Just stay one night.
I wanna show you something.
And if by tomorrow morning
you still have doubts...
...then leave
before anyone wakes up...
...and I won't say a word.
What do you mean?
I have an idea.
Sorry, Willard.
Really, Mr. Wilson.
This is cosy.
I tried my best.
- So where's your friend Nick?
- Gone for a walk, I'd imagine.
And where's Rachel?
Keeping him company,
I would think.
- Is that safe?
- Of course.
I don't trust him.
- Me neither.
Gives me the creeps.
It's been a long day.
I think it's time I went to bed.
- I'll take you.
- Thank you, Melissa.
- Good night, Brett.
- Good night, Willard.
You see now,
you've been overdoing it.
Nonsense, my dear.
I'm as fit as a fiddle.
As long as you let me know, okay?
Have you the list
of all my items I required?
- Yes.
- And they're all in my room?
Nick.
I'd like to talk to you in private
for a moment, if you don't mind.
Where's Rachel?
She's asleep.
If you don't believe me,
go and check, she's still breathing.
I didn't say anything.
Dr. Willard, I'll just make
your room up the best I can.
Thank you.
There's something
I haven't told the others...
...but I think that you should know.
Will you come with me?
I have not been entirely honest
with the others.
My book, it is not about you.
It is more about what happened.
I recently came into possession
of Blackwater's private journal.
The journal details much
of Blackwater's research practises.
And makes very disturbing reading.
Blackwater was experimenting
on his patients...
...inmates of his asylum,
in the most unorthodox of ways.
Medical practises
on the clinically insane...
...were not of a high standard
in the 1950s.
But Blackwater took his research
to a whole new level of depravity...
...of cruelty.
Most of the work
was concentrated in the basement.
That is where the real horror
took place.
He was ostracized
from the scientific world at the time...
...because of his attempt to suggest
the existence of the human soul.
Why are you telling me this?
Because...
That's not all the journal details.
The purpose of those experiments...
...was connected to the contraption
that you say took Sammy.
No...
That thing didn't take Sammy.
I know that now. It was in my head.
- Rachel told me.
- Rachel?
Rachel's a student, Mr. West,
a good one...
...but no expert.
I am not as convinced of your guilt
as you appear to be.
Blackwater claimed...
...that the machine he was working on,
that thing upstairs...
...was a portal to another realm.
A realm
which could separate the soul...
...from the body.
And you believe that?
I believe it's possible.
This place is filled with evil.
I feel it at every turn.
There is a chance
that whatever took Sammy...
...still lurks in the darkest corners
of this asylum.
So you don't think I'm crazy?
No, Mr. West.
But right now, you and I...
...are the only two people in this world
who really believe that.
Doctor...
I don't know
how you think I can help you.
You know why?
Because they were just delusions!
I don't think so.
When dealing with matters
of the mind, there is nothing certain.
What happened to you
four years ago...
...was just one in a series
of misadventures...
...that have taken place here
over the years.
They were all in my head!
I know that now!
In my head!
They had to be.
Did they, Mr. West?
I am interested
in the answers to a question...
...that no one in my profession
dares to ask.
What if the crazy person
isn't crazy?
What if what they're saying is true?
And now that we are here...
...I am in a position
to do something about it.
For years,
I've been told that I was crazy...
...that I made this whole thing up,
and now you're saying that it was true.
Yes, Mr. West.
You're crazier than me.
Everything is in place.
Brett and Rachel are my controls,
only they don't know it.
They are grounded in science.
They absolutely will not believe
in anything I have just told you.
They are an intrinsic part of this study,
even more than you.
So will you help me, Mr. West?
This is...
I don't know.
Then think carefully
about what you want.
If the journal is accurate...
...men with a greater reason and will
than you...
...have lost their lives to this place.
And just like that, everything you think
you know is turned upside down.
And nobody is what they seem.
They slept too easily.
They had no idea.
So naive, so innocent.
So fucking stupid.
Come on.
And so it began.
A young girl with a plan
way out of her depth and sinking fast.
Come on.
This is foolish.
- You don't know what you're doing.
- Nick, it's gonna be fine.
Please, Rachel, don't do this.
- It's not safe here.
- It's perfectly safe.
And I'm gonna prove it to you.
Please don't, Rachel.
Nick, I'm gonna go
and sit down on that chair...
...and you'll see
that everything is gonna be fine.
- Don't!
- Nick, it's gonna be all right.
But Willard...
What about Dr. Willard?
He told me...
I wanna believe you, but...
Nick, look at this thing.
It's nothing.
Brett sat in it earlier,
and he's all right.
Well, he's a bit of an asshole,
but he's always been like that.
Don't sit in that thing, Rachel.
She should've listened to me.
They should all
have listened to me.
But they're too carried away,
you see, with their own ideas...
... Wrapped up in educated egos
that don't know what I know.
See?
There's nothing to be worried about.
Famous last words.
It's a chair, nothing more.
What are you so afraid of?
You haven't seen the things
I've seen.
You don't know
what you're dealing with.
What is it
that you don't understand?
Can't you see, Nick?
It's all in your mind.
No!
Rachel!
- Oh, Rachel.
- Fuck.
- Hang on.
- Help me!
- Willard!
- Get it off me!
Willard!
I fucking warned you!
- Nick!
God! God!
I told you.
I warned you. Didn't I say to you?
Willard!
Gone, just like that.
Just like Sammy.
- Dr. Willard.
- What is it? What's happening?
It's happened again.
Rachel, she's gone through.
It's taken her.
Nick.
Nick?
Rachel. Rachel, help me.
Rachel.
Rachel, help me.
Help me.
Nick!
Rachel!
Rachel.
Nick.
Nick!
It'll hardly come as a surprise
that I got the blame like last time.
You can kind of see why.
So you think she got sucked
into the machine, just like Sammy.
Wait a minute, timeout.
I don't know, maybe.
She was trying to help me.
I could hear the voices.
Willard, have you been
handing out crack pipes?
You have a better explanation
for what happened, I suppose?
Well, I'd say
it's the insane-asylum inmate.
Yeah, in the torture chamber...
...with whatever murder weapon
he used to kill the last girl.
You think I did it?
Well, it's not like you're a nutter
or anything.
Show some respect for the patient.
Can't you see you're upsetting him
with these baseless accusations?
- Baseless bollocks.
- That's enough.
Nick.
- Rachel.
- Nick.
Rachel, help me.
- Nick?
- Rachel, help me.
Help me, Rachel.
Rachel, help me.
- Nick?
- Help me.
- Rachel.
- Nick?
Rachel, help. Rachel.
- Nick.
- Rachel.
Rachel. Rachel.
Rachel.
- Help me.
- Nick.
Rachel.
- Rachel.
Nick?
Rachel. Rachel.
I'm going through.
I have to bring her back.
Yeah,
that's what we've been saying.
Yeah, bring her back,
everything will be fine.
This is the last time
I'm going to tell you two to be silent.
There are things happening here
you can't possibly comprehend.
Nick.
Supposing you do go through...
...there's no guarantee
you'll come back.
We don't know
what's waiting for you over there.
You shouldn't speak ill of people,
but what a fucking coward.
Room full of try-hards
and big shots...
... And nobody wants
to take responsibility.
Time for good old
Nick West to step up, eh?
Whatever it is,
Rachel's mixed up in it right now.
- I'm going through.
- No!
Stop.
Wait.
You'll be no good to Rachel
if you can't come back.
What are we gonna do, then?
Blackwater's journal.
There must be something in there.
He built this thing.
He knows better
than anyone how to work it.
Where is the journal?
It's in my room.
Come on.
All right,
we'll do it your way, old man.
But we don't have much time.
Twenty quid says
the old man goes missing next.
You think it's Nick?
Of course it is.
It's fucking obvious. He's a psycho.
Dr. Willard doesn't think so.
Yeah, well,
Dr. Willard's as full of shit as Nick is.
Brett, I'm scared.
Don't be scared.
What was that?
Fuck all, who cares?
Wait a minute.
I think it came from the chair.
God, not you as well.
It's a chair for chrissake.
I sat on that thing earlier
and nothing happened.
It's bullshit.
The whole thing is bullshit.
- You sat in it?
- Yeah.
Show me.
What?
Please.
Right, but we carry on
from where we left off.
I've got a right horn on.
See? Nothing.
- Brett.
- Yeah.
- What do you think that's for?
- I don't know.
What...
Is there anything yet?
We don't have time for this.
I'm going as fast as I can.
Portions of the text are damaged.
You can't build
a machine like that...
...and not have some kind
of get-out clause.
For Rachel's sake, let's hope not.
Fuck.
Rachel?
Hello.
Hello?
Hello, sailor.
Horse.
Come on.
- What the hell is going on?
- Shut up, Brett.
There is something in here with us.
What, in the closet?
No, you idiot, in this place.
It's some kind of a...
I don't know.
But I think it's after me.
Well, then, we should split up.
I have a feeling
it's probably after you too.
Nick was right.
Yeah.
Where's Dr. Willard
when you need him?
Come on, old man.
Do you want me to help you or not?
Dr. Willard. It's taken Brett.
- That thing, it's taken him.
- What?
He sat in the chair.
He wanted to show me it was safe.
I know.
He disappeared.
I didn't believe you, but you were right.
This is crazy.
That fool.
I told him to show more respect
for things he does not understand!
Enough of this fucking melodrama.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know,
but we're wasting time here.
I'm going through.
Nick.
Nick!
This is madness! It's suicide!
I don't have a choice.
I let Sammy down.
I should've gone after her.
I'm not gonna make
the same mistake twice.
Dear boy...
...if you go through...
...there's every chance
you'll never come back.
Come back to what?
This? The institute?
Everything I ever cared about
is through there.
Then there's nothing more
I can say.
You take care of yourself, professor.
It's been educational.
No.
Well, my dear.
That was easier
than we anticipated, eh?
The fools.
Never saw that coming, eh?
- Rachel?
- Rachel. Rachel.
Rachel?
Rachel!
There's a door, come on.
See if you can open it. Hurry up.
- Jeez, I can't, it's locked.
- What?
I can't, I'm trying.
Rachel, there could be anything
behind this door.
Brett, don't be ridiculous.
We need to get out of this place.
- Just open the fucking door.
- All right.
- Shit, I've cut my hand.
- Oh, God.
Brett, put some pressure on it.
I can't. Look.
Look how deep it is.
Put some pressure on it.
Run, Rachel, run.
Rachel? Rachel!
Brett.
- Who's there?
- It's Nick.
What, the psycho killer?
Fucking idiot.
He'd seen the demon,
he still wanted to blame me.
Some people just get
what's fucking coming to them.
Why did you do that?
- Where's Rachel?
- Who?
Where's Rachel?
She went that way.
Or it may have been that way,
you cunt.
So that book's supposed
to keep you safe?
That's the idea.
Let's have a look.
How much blood
does this demon need?
A lot.
- Dr. Willard.
- Sorry.
The demon must be satisfied.
- It's me. Are you okay?
- Nick, Nick.
Are you okay?
- It killed Brett. It killed Brett.
- What killed Brett?
What killed Brett?
Please save me, please.
Please.
I'm gonna get you out of this place.
I promise you.
Okay, you ready?
Come on.
Wait, it's coming.
And finally, we come face to face.
Me and my demon, head-to-head.
Toe- to-toe.
- Can you see it?
- I don't think so.
- It's the blood it wants.
- We have to go.
It's the blood. It's the blood it wants.
Told you I'd get her
out of that outfit.
If only I could get her tits out now.
Shit.
Come on.
Close your eyes.
Please.
You've done us both so proud.
So proud.
Where is it? Where is it?
It's gone.
Oh, God!
Stop toying with her.
Who...
Willard.
Dr. Willard.
There you are.
Bitch!
Strewth,
turn the v olume down, Granddad.
What a rotter.
As you can see,
it all got a bit silly at this point.
Girl with her puppies out.
- Demon, old banana in pyjamas.
- What are you doing?
Is this what I promised you?
Are we prick-teasing you enough?
Are you full up?
Is this what you came here to see,
O my brothers?
My gift to you.
Look at this poorly written,
badly acted bullshit.
Is there any truth
in these B- movie banality?
- No, no.
- Help me.
There is no truth, my friends.
Believe no one, believe nothing.
I tell you what, party people...
... You geeks and freaks,
you bloodthirsty morons, fuck you.
Bring on the red parade.
Get off me, old man.
I am not so old in this place.
- Help me!
Or weak.
So are there any pulses
in the house?
You deadbeat, midnight freak,
geek- witted torture- porn gore whores.
I know what you're looking for.
So have it, take it.
Fair thee well,
and fuck you very much!
Do you ever get the feeling
you've been cheated?
But it's killing her!
Small price to pay.
She'll find her peace very soon.
You set us up.
You played directly into my hands
from the very start.
Just as I knew you would.
Call it off her. Call it off her!
She does not answer to me.
Nick.
No.
But it answers to me.
Oh, Nick, please.
None of this is real.
I am demon.
Rachel, get away from him.
Nick, please, listen to me.
This is not real.
Finish him, Nick.
All in good time, baby.
I love you.
Get off her now!
Please.
Oh, my God, no!
Nick, no, Nick!
No.
Nick, no!
I love you.
- No!
No!
Run, Rachel, run!
Oh, God, run!
Run!
- Oh, no.
- No!
Oh, God, no!
Nick!
No, no, no.
My God!
No. Nick, Nick!
No!
Nick, Nick!
Oh, God.
No!
You're a cunt.
You're just a low-rent cunt!
You're a cunt!
Hey, hey, hey.
There's no use
begging or screaming.
Because you're a whore.
- Open your legs.
- No.
Open your fucking legs!
You're a worthless,
cheap-perfume-smelling cunt.
And you're weak.
And as my mother used to say...
...the weak are always trying
to subvert the strong.
And I am the strong.
So buckle up, bitch.
Here comes the pain.
Rachel!
Rachel.
Where are you?
Rachel!
No, no.
See, Nick? There is no chair.
No chair?
It's okay.
- What? What's funny?
- You're a genius, shrinky.
You're a fucking goddamn genius.
- What?
- Of course there's no chair.
There never was a fucking chair.
No chair.
No chair, shrinky.
No.
Rachel!
Rachel.
Rachel, where are you?
Sammy?
Sammy!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I did this.
They're all dead now.
It's just me and you, Sammy.
It's me.
Never seen you look so beautiful.
Look at me.
It's Rachel.
You look so beautiful.
Nick, it's Ra... This is Rachel.
It's just me and you now, Sam.
I'm not...
It's okay, Rachel.
It's okay.
Please, don't.
No, please.
Oh, Nick.
Please, please don't! No!
No, no, no!
Well, that was a bit of fun, wasn't it?
Hey, you're not gonna tell anyone
about this, are you?
Trust me.
No one's gonna believe us.
Are you sure you wanna go on the run
with a crazy person?
I love you.
Well, let's go get crazy.