Quarto dei Mille  District.
Here they embarked for
lands south ...
... led by the Hero of Two Worlds
who tried to create a country.
So tenacious legend tells ...
... made of ashes, blood
and dreams corrupt.
We do not know how many thousands  returned, ...
... undergoing a sea
that welcomes and trains ...
... men and the shadows of
our time.
The new inhabitants of
Caverns ....
... non-fishermen
or sedentary.
are men who migrate.
not know their stories.
know they have chosen,
found this place ...
... and no other ...
... to feel secure, ...
... to fend off a road
becomes a city ...
... in the shadow of those who rest
and guarding, ...
... as characters old ...
... among the thousands who inhabit the
places in our memories ...
... and our memory
fades.
Perhaps  from the sea, ...
... stranded like castaways.
Here are their bodies  ...
... on the threshold of our adventures.
La Boca del Lobo
My love, do something.
Thou hast waited for many years
and now we're near the end.
You know what my dream, remember?
A house in the countryside,
with dogs, ...
... ducks, a pond, and I
I do a garden.
With our limited means
live this way.
That's what I always wanted.
I think it is also your
dream, right?
I love you, my love, as you always
I have loved you, silly.
You are all my life.
When I met him I had not imagined
he was born the love between us.
He intimidated me, his gaze I
got uncomfortable.
But I learned to know him,
day after day ...
... and I finally understand that under this
mask strong man, arrogant, ...
... hiding a soul
tender and sensitive.
has the sweetness of a child
in the body of a giant.
That's what I like.
I realized this one day ...
... when I saw him mourn with "Bambi''
Walt Disney.
was very friendly, and
I fell in love.
We met in adversity.
We  alone ...
were very young.
We had nothing.
decided together,
forget the past ...
... and face life together
encourage each other.
I got home, my love.
I'm tired.
I missed you, my love.
not know what came over me, I turned
joy, the joy of living.
will have been your cassettes, ...
... or maybe your letter.
not even know, my love ...
... but they have turned their love of life,
to be happy, my love.
I give a kiss, my love.
Another ... other ...
- Stop! Throw your gun!
- Yes, yes. Expected to throw it away.
I took the other ...
that day and should not
even work.
One was called  Cochis
and the other Indian.
They chose the wrong local ,
I was in Zanzibar.
was my life then ...
... and then became
in my hell.
police, good guys, ...
... I took the gun and
threw me. Five shots ...
... four legs
and one in the belly.
I put three shots a
and four other.
had with me that night
my shotgun.
had only a revolver, ...
... as a 44 Magnum
Inspector Callaghan, ...
... and one chrome, German.
I had killed them.
Luckily , but now have three
sentences on my back.
Listen, my love, yesterday afternoon
I received your express ...
... and I've already answered.
Then I got your tape  ...
... and this morning, as you wrote,
also got the money order.
I thank you with all my heart,
my love, for all this.
My love, forgive me if I speak
a little low.
I have fear that I feel duty
and discover that I have the recorder.
continue later, for now
go to tell.
Chau, love, goodbye.
I love you! I love you, bitch!
My love sweet and sensual
How are you
hope you're a little
calmer.
I received your letter  ...
... where I say you are
very angry, nervous, ...
... and you've ruined everything
in your cell.
You know it hurts me read it ...
... I fear it will bring you problems.
know it's a drama for you
when you are forbidden to go out, ...
... it is for them.
But it is useless  haywire.
the contrary, if you are sanctioned,
would be much more serious.
I want to achieve our dreams.
Do you remember our dreams?
Try to calm down.
I leave, I have things
to do.
Remember I love you,
I love you and you wait.
I love you, adore you,
Dearest son of a bitch
If you put me  horns,
when you go ...
... Do you remember when I cut home
chicken chunks
That's what you will.
Do you understand, fucking whore
I love you more than life, love,
but try not to make me mad.
If your husband suffers  in here
as a motherfucker, ...
... Thou shalt not ever have whims, you
suffer as your husband, home and work.
whims and fun when you leave,
we will do together.
Never forget that. If you love me,
That's what you do.
want something else. I want to write
day in and day out ...
... and I'll do the same.
Do not forget.
Enzo grew up in these streets.
He went to school in Sicily, ...
... but was expelled after
Several incidents.
born in the countryside,
near Catania.
was when he came to town,
problems began, ...
... crime, jail.
Enzo started working as a child,
in Genoa, with his father Pippo, ...
... selling lighters, ...
... cigarettes and other things
at night.
Enzo  took them without knowing
what they were.
As a child,
there was less risk.
Come! You're cute, please
between Sarah and me.
Between the two of us.
Come on.
Hi, honey.
Give me a kiss.
What a beautiful finger.
You are beautiful as any!
¿Coffee, honey?
What do you want? Come on, give it!
What is it?
- The Coffee Serena.
- I take it.
It's good coffee!
Do you crook leg touched me?
Your wife will get jealous.
- What do you do?
- Porno!
I go to work. See you soon!
Thanks for the coffee, Siberia!
After all these years,
he felt lost.
The atmosphere had changed
completely ...
... did not go to anyone,
had no friends.
Many of them had died
or disappeared.
At first I was a little scary
out to the street.
Accustomed to being in a cell
three meters ...
... was completely lost,
distressed, disoriented.
addition, he always
a knife from him.
I see old  already ...
... hair white as snow ...
... sitting with hands folded,
shaking for me.
I realize you're still
still beautiful, ...
... my eye is sincere.
Who betray a similar love
in life
Both have to do it.
We consoled ourselves  old and happy.
I will give thanks for this life ...
... close to you without speaking.
cross  places ...
... Archaeology is a memory, ...
... unknown desires, ...
... forbidden memories
a vanished world.
cave dwellers
resting.
No sailing  someone else's dream.
wave only sets the pace
time.
Soon, the sun's rays
fall on their faces ...
... wake-up call, ...
... to repel the charm
dark of night.
They invade the streets of the city.
They will cross the lost places  ...
... descending and ascending ramps
remote slopes ...
... where lies the dark.
be installed in the
forgotten ruins, ...
... as a castaway on earth ...
... transparent ...
... untouchable.
Another time, other lives to live.
I, father, Enzo.
How are you, Father Serafino?
It helped me when I came out of jail
Pianosa, some years ago.
Pippo's son: "Lighters, apparatus,
aerosols, hand grenades ...".
Do you remember the little Enzo?
The son of that Pippo that
sold cigarettes ...
I went to greet you, Father.
I'm in trouble.
I'm too young to retire,
too old to work. Where am I?
What should I do?
Is going to steal? Kidnapping ¿?
To shoot back to the police? Are you shooting
again to end my days in jail?
A countdown.
He counted the days, hours.
For him, every day was a
less suffering.
For me, it was difficult.
He had the responsibility ...
... to find shelter
for when out ...
... and think a little
our future.
He called me every time
gave permission and I ran.
spent the day and
night together.
were wonderful days.
Every week, we sent
a package of clean laundry, ...
... something to eat and cassettes ...
... where my voice was recorded.
I tried to calm him.
We had a dream .
Having a house in the country
a Huertita ...
... and perhaps a porch
a beautiful bank ...
... where we squeezed
to look to the horizon ...
... surrounded with our dogs, and ...
... which wait for the old age ...
... where we were a little peace,
with confidence.
That's all we wanted.
home to Christopher Columbus
- What health for whom? Do you pay?
- Yes, do not worry.
- To your health, nothing. You have not paid.
- Here's to your health.
- Pants pay!
- He says he pays.
- To me! A bottle of champagne.
- I should!
- Want to bet?
- No. You're gonna lose.
It was a round,
Do you want to offer!
He touched my ass!
No, I pondered the situation
economy.
Do not bother! I am very hot.
Break my balls!
I pierced my eyes!
Do not start again.
I want to ask a question.
Where fulfilled your worth?
No, seriously.
Where was what? Does the jail?
What the fuck do you care where
I turned my grief?
- Were you in jail?
- Ever ...
And now, chupámela!
What the fuck are you looking at me?
I asked, is all.
Go ask the police!
They will tell you where I turned off!
They have a good record.
Claudio, do you serve a beer?
A Turbo.
- A Bourbon?
- A Turbo!
Understood bourbon,
as whiskey.
A Tuborg!
- I hate that.
- I am deaf.
Man, I wash your head?
- Do not touch!
- Stop it. What are you doing?
A wash!
I will make one.
A kick in the ass!
Then, play the juke-box.
You put a disc and I sing.
The juke-box!
Tell me what you want to hear ...
... and I get to the stage.
And I sing.
- Do you sing?
- I sing!
- It is not the same as you.
For those who did not listen,
I want to sing
Oh, Richard!
- Pausini? No, Cocciante.
- Exactly.
It Cocciante, I'm sure.
- For, Enzo!
- Bravo!
I put the horns
in my nose!
- First me, then she.
- Do we stop?
Do not forgive this. I
you loved me.
- You're a friend!
- You betrayed me!
Coward!
You is friendship,
with her is love.
- You betrayed me! Before you kissed me!
- Who do you tell?
- Yes, for the film, to the scene.
- Be careful, huh?
She's a friend.
To you, I love you.
Right now, he kissed me.
You is love. With it is friendship,
40 years.
She is the wife of Mimmo,
of Piccadilly.
- I was the wife of Mimmo.
- Yes, he died.
Enzo has spent much
of his life in prison.
long gallery, as he says,
began in 1986.
lasted fourteen years and ended
nine years ago.
day of his release
was wonderful.
But then when I thought
it was all over, ...
... came one night
and arrested him.
had accumulated.
was a shock to him.
He even started drinking  ...
... and derailed.
Someone should make me dance!
I  Machaco has ruined his life
by nonsense.
He has spent a lot of years
in jail for anything ...
... instead of, I do not know ...
... taking acting lessons.
He could have become an actor
with their physical ...
... and break into the movies.
The police are always right,
law always prevails.
its way, not mine.
This changes everything.
she was a murderer for hire.
But I'm not at all.
am free and independent.
Police extorts  nightclubs.
A true mafia
That is the law? A law
I'm going to do.
I turned off until the end.
Twenty-seven years.
Nine years  first time, four of
second, and fourteen the third.
each cross.
mine, have been
so far.
It is your word.
It is not true what he said.
I was in prison in
that moment ...
... because before I got high.
I too, like him, was in
the limit of the ...
... of despair.
He sent me almost five grams
of heroin a day.
It was really a scrap.
Until a supervisor told me:
''Mary, there is a Sicilian boy
upstairs ...
... that can give you cigarettes ...
... if you shorten the pants. "
As I had nothing
at all, ...
... I have a package suited
of cigarettes.
And I agreed.
Then I brought the pants
and I fixed it.
And when I finished ...
... I went to the floor where he was.
The cell and the door was closed,
then scrimmage.
The peephole opens soon ...
... and I see it in all its glory.
Wearing shorts ...
... and it was all ...
Long sport.
He had a magnificent physique
at that time.
I was struck by her composure, ...
... for its impressive beauty.
But at the same time,
was intimidated ...
... by air so rude.
I expected nothing at all.
I was almost intimidated,
could hardly speak.
And he ... ''Thanks.''
And he gave me cigarettes.
He said:''If you
sending poems, ...
... I can do you translate?''
In short, it was an excuse
to approach me.
Seeing that I was alone, ...
... I was happy
to make friends.
So I get these letters, ...
... to translate these poems,
and I took them in my cell.
Thus began.
But I was a little reserved, ...
... I kept my distance.
Until one morning when I went
library section ...
... I had to go through a broker
to get to the library.
I walk into the library, ...
... and when I leave the door
bookstore, I find it before me.
He grabs my hand ...
... give me a kiss on the lips, ...
... so ... I was shocked.
And that was the beginning
of our history.
As soon as we could, we were
during the hour ride.
It was the only one speaking.
He, too, had not a penny ...
... but he was gifted with his hands.
Did you know ...
With the matches, was
lighters, ...
... small frames. Very beautiful things.
Those items manufactured
exchanged ...
Over the supervisors,
was supplied ...
... cans of tomatoes,
peas, pasta.
With it, we've never gone hungry
in my cell.
I was with two other
transsexuals.
We were separated from the others.
I saw it during the daily walk.
I spent my time to ride
in your company.
As we were in two
different cells, ...
... took place in my apartment,
front of my cell.
In this way, we could talk.
To achieve this, as
I could not scream ...
... taught me a dumb alphabet.
I learned little by little, ...
... We communicated through
this alphabet.
I do not know.
It is he who ... communicated
that way.
Honestly, ...
... I spent four months ...
It may sound absurd ...
... but those four months
were wonderful.
I'm not saying they have been
the best of my life ...
... but those four months
were exceptional.
This is absurd since
was in jail.
But honestly, for
those four months, ...
... I got everything you could want ...
... tenderness and understanding.
All the love I sought,
I met him.
He showed me and I spent
four wonderful months.
This is how our story
began.
And it takes twenty years.
Twenty years have passed since
we're together.
These are the four best
months of your life.
I owe you the best fourteen
years of my life!
He was sentenced to
almost ten years.
But I waited.
Meanwhile, I went from
one prison to another ...
... to see him almost every month.
But it's ...
First, it's like
I stopped using drugs ...
... because when I met him ...
... No one had visited ...
... neither my family nor my friends
ones.
He had tried to give me advice:
''For, you should stop
take drugs. "
"Step into the wonderful person
you were. "
I said "Yes, yes," but not
had the strength.
- Meanwhile he ...
- Thanks to my strength.
... with her tenderness, her character, ...
... its hardness, but also
with its sweetness, ...
... gave me the strength to have
a purpose.
Even to wait ten years.
I said, I see ...
... I have to go far,
how far we can go.
It has almost become a target
in my life.
- And twenty years later, we're here.
- We did it!
Not without difficulty, because ...
... life is not only difficult in prison
even in prison is easy because ...
... the only problem that exists,
is eating and sleeping.
And make the time pass.
What is ugly in life ...
... are all problems
to be faced to live.
- There is something else, my love.
- What?
¿I can say something?
The guards who brought the food ...
... did not like homosexuals.
The mistreated.
One day, I called one. Peace to his soul,
because they died.
I said,''you bring to eat
to this cell.
"If you touch Mary, I play to me, and
're dead. "
- Who do you bother then? No one.
- It's true.
You belong to Enzo and nobody bothered
for a long time.
Thirty people lay alone for
When walking, does not it?
Yes, indeed.
And I broke a leather ball
in the face. He blew his head.
Is not it true?
This boy was the goalkeeper.
I said, "Forward."
I threw a pitch and
I broke the ball.
- It's true.
- She confirms it.
And woe to those that touch!
Neither the guards was allowed.
One night, a guard put chile
under the nose.
I said, "Guard, come here a
moment ... Do you see?
If you allow it once again, I cut
the head. I stab with or without uniform. "
I had shit to lose.
Or not?
It's true.
We were so close to both ...
... which was isolated from all ...
- Of all the rest of the band!
- In the entire section.
They were afraid of me. We were
time of thirty to ride ...
... and nobody said a word wrong.
Otherwise, they are
was seen.
All detainees!
She and I both are
dominant.
She dominates me and I domain.
But she's the one going.
Only when I raise my voice,
all is well. Is repeated.
Not because I want to dominate.
Because we understand!
We are old now.
What is the song of the old?
"Both of us must do one."
No, the beginning.
No, better not
sing it now.
Dila, I sing.
In any case, not dominate.
We know, that's all.
Both , we must make one.
We consoled ourselves  old and happy.
I thank God for this life ...
... close to you without speaking.
Our journey ends here  ...
... between the lights of the night
and Quarto dei Mille.
Let the castaways  protected
in these caves.
On  want to be forgotten.
There are only traces of the
memory and the ways ...
... that become blurred.
Small  great stories,
That's what it was.
as night,
the day ...
... time, love,
of the shadow, of light.
That's what it was ...
... once, in a city.
Translation: ChadItes