[eerie music]
[shoes clicking]
[dramatic music]
- Hello, I'm famished.
I haven't had supper
for two weeks.
- Well, I'll be glad to give
you some money for food.
- Can't keep food down,
never could.
- I'll do anything I
can to help you.
[tense music]
- Anything?
Oh, thank you.
[dramatic music]
[tense music]
May I be permitted to
introduce myself?
My name is Eramus.
I am a vampire.
Oh, but of course,
you know that.
- I say, what
happened your fangs.
- Oh they're retractable
when not in use.
- Oh, it's all right, I
didn't bite deep.
You won't become one of us.
It was the best blood I
have ever tasted.
Mm, and from such a
noble source.
You are the great R.
Chetwynd-Hayes,
the writer of those
magnificent horror stories.
You are my favorite author.
- I wouldn't have thought you
needed to read horror stories.
- Oh, my dear sir, you
do yourself an injustice.
Everybody likes to read
about themselves
and their own kind.
- Yes, well I'm glad to
have been of help to you.
I'm glad you like my blood, uh,
my books,
but I must be on my way.
- Oh no, I can't hear
of such a thing.
- You want more of my blood?
- No, no, no, you
misunderstand me.
I owe you something.
I want to help you,
to repay you.
- No, it's quite all
right thank you very much.
I'm glad to have
been of service.
- Well, I can get you
material for your next book.
- Material, what sort
of material?
- I will take you to a place
where my friends forgather.
There are vampires, werewolves,
ghouls,
every kind of monster
you could ever imagine
and some far beyond the
imagining of mere mortals.
There you will find stories
of such blood-curdling terror
that it will make your toes curl
and your hair reach up
towards the sky.
- Where is this place?
- It's just a short distance.
It's called the Monster Club.
["Monsters Rule O.K."
by the Viewers]
♪ Every night on the streets ♪
♪ When all the people
are fast asleep ♪
♪ From every corner creeps ♪
♪ The shape of something
you wouldn't like to meet ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Another sinister night ♪
♪ Another vampire girl to
give me hot love bites ♪
♪ Down at the Monster Club ♪
♪ A zombie and a ghoul
can do the monster dub ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
- Wolfgang, my table, please.
Wolfgang.
I'll have the usual.
- I'm afraid, type B is off,
sir.
- Then I'll have to make
do with common type O.
- Mm.
If I may suggest, sir,
tomato juice.
It will look less conspicuous.
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ I'm Dr.
Frankenstein's creation ♪
♪ I good-lookin' in the
monster nation ♪
♪ Mr. Werewolf wants
to meet you ♪
♪ He's waiting for the
moon to greet you ♪
♪ Sister Snake with a
poison touch ♪
♪ Wants to catch you in a
midnight crush ♪
♪ Got a friend you know
you can trust ♪
♪ He's a fiend and
he's one of us ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
[monsters cheering]
[mellow music]
- Thank you, Wolfgang.
Now, this is pleasant enough,
but it doesn't sustain us.
To get real nourishment,
we have to take our food
directly from the source,
and it becomes more
difficult constantly.
People are so
well-educated these days.
It's all those horror
films and television.
Everybody knows about garlic
and stakes through the heart.
- Yes, we all have our
cross to bear.
- I'd rather you didn't
use that word.
- What's this?
- Oh, that's a monster's
genealogical chart.
You see, first we have
the primate monsters,
vampires, werewolves,
and ghouls.
Now, a vampire and a werewolf
would produce a werevamp,
but a werewolf and a ghoul
would produce a weregoo,
but a vampire and a ghoul
would produce a vamgoo.
A weregoo and a werevamp
would produce a shaddy.
Now, a weregoo and a vamgoo
would produce a maddy,
but a werevamp and a vamgoo
would produce a raddy.
Now, if shaddy were to mate
with a raddy or a maddy,
the result would be a mock.
- A mock?
- Frankly, that's just the
polite name for a mongrel.
You know, it's, it's
quite simple really.
All you have to do
is remember the basic
rules of monsterdom.
Vampires suck, werewolves
hunt, ghouls tear,
shaddies lick, maddies yawn,
mocks blow,
but shadmocks only whistle.
- Shadmocks?
- If a mock were to mate with
any of the other hybrids,
their offsprings would
be called shadmocks.
- And they only whistle.
- Well, they don't do
it very often.
- [R] Doesn't sound
too terrifying.
- Oh, but you should see
the results of a
shadmock's whistling.
Shadmocks are the lowest
in the monster hierarchy,
yet they have this power.
- What happens when a
shadmock whistles?
- I heard of a man once
who saw the results of
a shadmock's whistle.
That's all he saw, and yet,
and yet.
[eerie music]
- He's been like that
for the past six months.
If we only knew what was going
on behind those staring eyes,
we might be able to help him.
He was found extraordinary and
inexplicable circumstances.
[upbeat music]
♪ Ah ♪
- [Angela] Anything?
- Nothing of use to us.
[Angela sighs]
- Maybe we ought to look
for proper jobs.
- And be slaves all our lives?
No, what we need's the
big one, one big break,
someone we can take for
all he's worth.
With enough money, we
might even get married.
Oh now, here's something.
♪ I felt a vampire's ♪
- Antiquary requires secretary
to help catalog collection
and prepare new book.
Some of those old fools
have got stuff that's
worth thousands,
gold, melt it down, untraceable.
- Not very likely.
- He's offering enough money.
Hmm?
Umbrick House.
[gentle music]
[birds chirping]
[bells jingling]
[tense music]
[shoes clicking]
[bells jingling]
Mr. Raven?
I'm Angela, Angela Jones.
I wrote to you about your
advertisement.
- Yes, of course, please do,
do come in.
My study is this way.
[clock chiming]
- So many things.
- They all have to be cataloged.
Before we begin, there's
something I must tell you.
Some people find me difficult,
um, impossible to work for.
- Why, do you beat up
your secretaries?
- No, nothing like that.
I, I pride myself on being
a very easy taskmaster.
It's just.
[suspenseful music]
- I'm sorry.
[tense music]
I can't do it.
- [George] Why, did he
turn you down?
- He wanted me, all right,
and the house is full of good
stuff, but the way he looked,
there was something
terrifying about him.
- Full of good stuff?
- I'm not going back.
[tense music]
[bells jingling]
- You came back.
- Ooh, why don't you get
someone to clean this place.
- I can't.
I, I can't ask people
to come here.
You have no idea how
hard it was for me to,
to advertise for you.
- Why?
- Well, I must never
go near people.
I can never go outside
these grounds.
- Aren't you ever lonely?
[Raven chuckles]
- If only you knew the
agony of my loneliness.
Uh, some of my relation will
visit me from time to time,
but they're different.
- But why can't you go out?
- Well, there's all
the noise, the traffic,
I might--
- Might what?
[tense music]
[sullen music]
- I didn't mean to
frighten them.
- They're my only friends.
Soon, they'll, they'll
learn to get to know you.
Soon, they'll accept
you as a friend.
- Well, I must get to work.
- I've always been fascinated
by the things of the dead.
[sullen music]
It's probably something
to do with my ancestry.
And the living have always.
[peaceful music]
I used to wear a mask once,
but it was no use.
It just made people curious.
They had to see what was
underneath, and then,
much better to get over the
shock right at the beginning.
Then they might even
grow accustomed.
You should always have
flowers, masses of flowers.
You should always be
surrounded with flowers.
- The birds will expect
their breakfast.
- Oh yes, yes, you're right.
I mustn't neglect my
other friends.
You have no idea what
meeting you has meant to me.
- What are you playing at?
What's going on?
- Let's forget it, chuck
the whole thing in.
- Are you afraid of him?
You said yourself he was a
weakling, what can he do?
- I don't know.
- Look, at least get
hold of something,
so I can see what sort of
stuff he's go, get it valued.
- I don't like it!
- You in love with him
or something?
- No.
He terrifies me.
And yet.
[peaceful music]
[tense music]
- No!
[Raven whistling]
[Angela screams]
[tense music]
[Raven panting]
[Raven whimpering]
- This sort of stuff's
almost impossible to fence.
It's too specialized,
and we'd need a ton of
it for the meltdown value
to be worth anything at all.
- So, we give up?
- No.
We've invested too much
to chuck it in now.
- But it is no use.
- He almost certainly pays
for that stuff in cash.
He must have a safe
somewhere to keep it handy.
Probably keeps some of the small
really valuable
articles in there too.
Has he come out of his room yet?
- I haven't seen him for days.
- Good, then you'll have
plenty of opportunity
to look for the safe.
[gentle music]
[birds chirping]
- Angela, look.
It used to belong to
Princess Sahuya.
She was said to be the most
beautiful woman of her day.
That was some 3,000 years ago.
Sahuya must have had
your coloring.
It matches your eyes,
your skin, beautiful.
[lock clicking]
- You should keep all
those things in the bank.
- Oh.
I don't like banks.
You have to see people.
No, my things are much better
here with me.
Angela, will you marry me?
Well, I realize my
appearance and everything,
but you could still love me.
- But we've got it all planned.
[Angela sobbing]
- I can't do it to him.
- Oh, don't worry,
everything will be all right.
Just remember the plan.
Play along with him.
Get him to give you the ring
as an engagement present,
and then remember the
combination
when he opens the safe.
- Oh, you've made me so very,
very happy.
Of course, you may
have the ring.
It's only fitting it
should adorn
a living hand after so
many centuries.
And such a beautiful hand.
[Raven panting]
I, I have something of a
confession I must make to you.
I am a, a shadmock.
I don't suppose you
know what that is.
If I ever whistle,
well, I must never whistle,
no matter what happens.
Oh, you must meet some
of my relations.
They can explain the
situation to you
much better than I ever can.
We could have a party,
an engagement party.
It can be in fancy dress.
Everyone can wear masks.
My relations are a bit
much to take all at once.
That way, you can have a chance
to get used to them gradually.
- I like dressing up.
- Well, in spite of my
relations,
in spite of everything,
you could still love me.
[peaceful music]
It is a crime to hide
such beauty,
but here we must all be masked.
My love, may I present
my Great Uncle Uriah.
Great Uncle, may I present
my bride to be, Miss
Angela Jones.
[dramatic music]
[peaceful music]
[light orchestral music]
[Angela screams]
The money and the other things,
they don't matter to me.
Take them.
Do what you want with them.
Give them to
whomsoever you please.
But you could still love me.
- No, no, no.
Don't touch me.
That's all I've wanted from you.
- Don't say that.
You mustn't say that.
- I could never love you.
[Angela panting]
You're horrible.
- No.
- Horrible.
[Angela screams]
I could never love you,
never, you're horrible!
[Raven whistles]
[tense music]
[heels clicking]
[lock clicking]
- Well, did you get it?
[music intensifies]
- You could still love me.
You could still love me.
[dramatic music]
Love
me.
[sullen music]
[Raven sobbing]
["Sucker For Your Love"
by B. A. Robertson]
- There is nothing
sadder the agonized grief
of a tenderhearted monster.
[singer slurping]
They're playing my song.
- Hey, fix me a drink and
make it a Bloody Mary.
Don't forget to spike it.
Play my favorite record,
You're So Vain.
You come from Pennsylvania,
I'm from Transylvania,
and I'm a pain in the neck.
♪ She's the kind of girl ♪
♪ To drive a man insane ♪
♪ I think I love her so ♪
♪ And I give her pain ♪
♪ Good golly, I'm fate ♪
♪ But she's the one I rate ♪
♪ She's just the kind of girl ♪
♪ I love to punctuate ♪
♪ When I kiss and I fondle her ♪
♪ I'm makin' love to
a colander ♪
♪ I said, I'm just a
sucker for your love ♪
♪ I'm just a sucker
for your love ♪
♪ Ah ah ah for your love ♪
♪ When I take her out ♪
♪ Just to have a drink ♪
♪ Baby, there's no doubt ♪
♪ That you tend to sprinkle ♪
♪ Almost on the bar ♪
♪ People near or far ♪
♪ They can borrow you ♪
♪ When they wash their cars ♪
♪ Just hang me in the garden,
man ♪
♪ I said, well, you could
use her as a watering can ♪
♪ Ah ah, I'm just a sucker
for your love ♪
♪ I'm just a sucker
♪ Ah ah ah ah for your love ♪
for [slurping] ♪
♪ I'm just a sucker
for your love ♪
♪ Love ♪
♪ For your love ♪
♪ I'm just a sucker
for your love ♪
♪ Ah ah ah ah for your love ♪
[monsters cheering
and applauding]
[monsters yelling]
- [Monster] Boo!
Boo!
- The club secretary.
[monsters yelling]
- Hello monsters!
Please, silence, for
tonight's guest of honor,
the great vampire film producer,
Lintom Busotsky.
[monsters cheering]
- A vampire film producer?
- Well, aren't they all?
- It's a great honor for me
to be invited here tonight
to show you an excerpt
from my latest film.
It is, I assure you, a picture
very close to my heart,
for it's based on my own
childhood, but in a modern
setting.
- Lower budget.
- I was born and brought
up here in London.
I can't say I, um, ever
felt the urge
to follow in my
father's profession.
You see, he was a night worker.
He spent the daylight
hours asleep.
He needed peace and quiet.
But as a naturally shy child,
I too was glad we lived
in a secluded house
and avoided our neighbors.
But even the shyest
children must go to school.
My mother, may the earth
lay lightly on her bones,
was always determined that
I should look my best.
[sullen music]
- Now, remember what
I've told you.
Never speak to strangers.
- I'll remember.
[sullen music]
[children chattering]
[haunting music]
- Ah yes, ah, ah, watch this.
[Manford chuckles]
- Now Manford, you must hurry,
or you'll miss the 5:30
from Oxford Circus.
- Oh, all right, yes,
you're quite right, my dear.
- Your business is so messy.
I shouldn't like to think of you
being mistaken for a butcher.
[light violin music]
- Daddy, I wish you could
play with me during the day.
- You know, I work
during the night.
I must get my sleep.
- Are you a waiter?
- Oh, [chuckles] no, my
son, I am not a waiter,
but I suppose I do have
something
to do with the food trade.
- What do you do?
- I lighten the burden of
those who have too much
and receive certain
nutritional benefits in return,
a nip and a suck [chuckles]
and they never feel a thing.
Feed without greed, that
has always been my slogan.
The rush hour trains and
the after theater crowds
provide a rich harvest for
someone who knows his business.
But I must always be on the
lookout for the bleaney.
[mother gasps]
The beast squad.
Beware of men carrying
violin cases.
- I do not think, dear,
there's any need to reveal the
problems of your profession.
- You're right dear.
- A gentleman does not mix
his business and home life.
Sufficient for Lintom to know
that he has an unusual father.
- Who loves his family
very much. [laughs]
Home at seven, hmm.
[sullen music]
[children cheering]
- What have we got here?
- [Tall Student] This shrimp.
- [Student With Long
Hair] The thing.
- The weird.
- Bet you can't do that.
- Of course, he can't.
- Coward.
- Weird.
- Isn't he pale?
- Sickening.
You daren't do that.
- Cry baby.
- Weird.
[children laughing]
[tense music]
[whistle blows]
- Now, you mustn't worry
about those horrid
children teasing you.
See, you must remember that
you are better than they are.
Back in the old country,
where we came from,
your father was a nobleman.
He's a count, which means, of
course, that I am a countess.
Well then, you must
be a viscount.
[children chattering]
- I don't care, I'm
better than all of you!
I'm a viscount!
- What did you say?
- I said, I'm a viscount.
- My lord.
- [Tall Student] Your grace.
- You thing.
- Weird.
- Children, what's
going on here?
Oh oh, come on, I'll uh,
I'll walk home with you
and see that they
don't harm you.
Merciful heavens, why not?
- My mother told me never
to speak to strangers.
- But I'm not a stranger,
I'm a clergyman.
Would you like a caramel?
- No, thank you.
I can't let anyone
come to my home.
- Why not?
- I don't know.
- There must be a reason.
- I think my father
escaped from somewhere
in the middle of Europe.
Perhaps, he's hiding.
- Why were those limbs of
Satan so angry with you?
- I said I was a viscount.
- Mm, is your father a nobleman?
- I hardly see my father.
He sleeps all day and
goes out at night.
- Where does he sleep?
- Downstairs, I've
never been there.
- Why don't you go down
there one day?
He might wake up early
and play with you.
Wait till your mother goes
out, then she needn't know.
[Pickering chuckles]
[tense music]
- I'm just going to the shops,
Lintom.
Now, you remember not to let
anyone in while I'm away.
- I'll remember.
[door clicks]
[suspenseful music]
[light string music]
[tense music]
[Lintom gasps]
- Take us to your father.
- Leave me alone.
- Where is your father?
Come on!
- Who are you, what do you want?
- We are the beast squad,
sonny, the bleaney,
special branch concerned
with blood crimes.
We have sworn to eradicate
the curse of vampirism
from this land.
- Sir.
[tense music]
It is getting dark.
- The boy said his
father slept downstairs.
Look for a cellar.
Your father has been the most
difficult case of my career.
I've hunted him for months.
He's been clever, very
clever, but now, I've got him.
- Sir!
- No, you can't go down there,
you can't!
- Take him down.
He should witness the end.
[tense music]
[music intensifies]
[mother screams]
[Manford screams]
[Manford groaning]
[Pickering screams]
[tense music]
[Pickering groaning]
[peaceful string music]
What?
Don't just stand there,
get an ambulance.
[mother laughing]
- You need more than
an ambulance.
My husband didn't just take
trickle or refreshment.
He bit deep.
Do you know what that means?
You are one of his kind now.
You will have to be
staked by your own men.
- She's right, sir.
The virus is in you.
Come moonlight, you'll be
on the rampage.
[head clops]
We'll have to do our duty, sir.
- You can't mean that, Sergeant.
You are talking to Pickering,
a departmental agent, head
of the bleaney.
Why, I've staked over
2,000 vamps.
You can't mean to.
Oh, oh.
- Sir?
You wouldn't want us chasing you
through the underground, sir.
Wouldn't be respectful, sir.
Now then, if you could
just see your way
to layin' out nice
and flat like,
we'll have the old doings
to your ticker in a jiffy.
Where would you be most
comfortable, sir?
- No!
[suspenseful music]
[Pickering groans]
[Pickering screams]
[Pickering groaning]
- Watson.
The stretcher.
["Funeral March" by
Frederic Chopin]
[wood cracks]
[sullen music]
[dramatic music]
[Manford groaning]
[Manford laughing]
- It's a good thing I always
were this stake-proof vest.
[Manford laughing]
It's filled with tomato
ketchup. [laughing]
[cheerful music]
Come!
The one thing you must
learn in life, my darlings,
is you cannot be too careful,
hmm?
Ah, such happy family.
[monsters applauding]
["The Stripper" by Night]
- Well, thank you for a
very pleasant evening,
but I really must go.
- The entertainment is
about to commence.
♪ Take a look around you ♪
♪ Someone might recognize you ♪
♪ It's not the type of place ♪
♪ You wanna bump into friends ♪
♪ I know what you came for ♪
♪ To watch me on the
dance floor ♪
♪ May get what you paid for ♪
♪ A part of your dreams ♪
♪ But it's all right ♪
♪ Come on and see me
every Saturday night ♪
♪ But it's all, all right ♪
♪ Don't know you ♪
♪ My hands along my thighs ♪
♪ You can't believe your eyes ♪
♪ My body hypnotizes ♪
♪ I'm a stripper ♪
♪ So, let the show begin ♪
♪ I'll show you everything ♪
♪ Oh, undo my safety pin ♪
♪ There's nothing you say ♪
♪ To take my pride away ♪
♪ I can be a lady and
a stripper ♪
♪ I got abilities ♪
♪ Don't you look down on me ♪
♪ I can live without
your dirty minds ♪
♪ Can you ♪
♪ Ha ♪
♪ Now, let me tell you why ♪
♪ You kissed your wife goodbye ♪
♪ You take a swig of brandy ♪
♪ And come here to me ♪
♪ Gettin' satisfaction ♪
♪ No negative reaction ♪
♪ I'm playing with body ♪
♪ That's what you wanna see ♪
♪ But it's all right ♪
♪ Come on and see me
every Saturday night ♪
♪ But it's all, all right ♪
♪ Oh, don't you know ♪
♪ You men are all the same ♪
♪ Don't wanna know your name ♪
♪ Just come back again ♪
♪ And pay the stripper ♪
♪ So, let the show begin ♪
♪ I'll show you everything ♪
♪ Pullin' off the safety pin ♪
♪ I got abilities ♪
♪ Don't you look down on me ♪
♪ I only want your money ♪
♪ I'm a stripper ♪
♪ Don't try to understand ♪
♪ It's just that you're a man ♪
♪ And I'm a stripper ♪
- Beautiful bones,
don't you think?
- Magnificent.
♪ But it's all right ♪
♪ Come on and see me
every Saturday night ♪
♪ But it's all, all right ♪
♪ Oh, don't you know ♪
♪ My hands along my thighs ♪
♪ You can't believe your eyes ♪
♪ My body hypnotizes ♪
♪ I'm a stripper ♪
♪ So, let the show begin ♪
♪ I'll show you everything ♪
♪ Oh, undo my safety pin ♪
♪ There's nothing you can say ♪
♪ To take my pride away ♪
♪ I can be a lady and
a stripper ♪
♪ I got abilities ♪
♪ Don't you look down on me ♪
♪ I can live without
your dirty mind ♪
♪ But it's all right ♪
♪ Come on and see me
every Saturday night ♪
♪ But it's all, all right ♪
♪ Whoa, I'm a stripper ♪
[monsters applauding]
- Eramus?
- Yes?
- That girl there at
the bottom of the chart,
surely, she's not a monster.
- Well, no, that's a humgoo,
a cross between a ghoul
and a human being.
As well as mating
with each other,
monsters can also mate
with humans beings.
The results are nearly
always disastrous,
but they will do it.
- What do they do?
- Do?
- Well, do they whistle
or anything like that?
- Humgoos?
Evil, hell no.
A part from an unfortunate
appetite for carrion,
which they get from the
ghoul side of the family,
they don't do
anything interesting.
- Huh, I'm relieved to hear it.
- Oh, but their relations do
have some fascinating habits.
One of them told me an
intriguing story once.
It started with, you shall see,
you shall see.
[jazzy music]
[tense music]
[fire crackling]
[woman screams]
- Cut.
- Do you wanna go again?
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no,
it's a wrap.
- Right, it's a wrap
everyone, house lights!
- I want you to print three, 11,
and 13.
I suppose I'll have to sort
the whole mess out in the
cutting room, as usual.
- Ah, Sam, can you have
a look at these
pictures of the new
locations that we've found?
- Ah.
Where have you looked?
- Here, here, and here.
- Well, what's wrong
with this area?
It looks far more remote,
far more promising.
I wanna strange, eerie,
lonely half-deserted village
in which to make an
atmospheric horror film.
Now, do you really expect
to find such a place
surrounded by a motorway,
a power station, and a
group of five-star hotels?
I'll go out this weekend and
I'll find the place myself.
[crew chattering]
[eerie music]
[tense music]
[wind howling]
[Sam knocking]
Yo!
Anyone here?
Innkeeper!
Ah.
I'd like to use your telephone.
- No telephone here.
- Well, perhaps you can help me.
You see, I'd like to use
this village for a film.
A film for the cinema.
Well, whose
permission do I need?
Who runs things around here?
- Run things?
The elders.
- Well, how do I contact them?
- They'll be here soon.
- Don't worry about it.
You see, I'll have my production
office sort it all out.
I'll talk to my art director
when I get back to
London tonight.
- You'll not get there tonight.
Too far, not safe go at night.
You stay here.
[tense music]
- Oh, this evil day.
[engine stuttering]
Who did this?
- Be them vermin, all
right, be them vermin.
Real monsters, they are,
nothing be safe.
- Can someone direct me
to the nearest garage?
- Garage?
No garage.
- Well surely, you can
suggest something.
- It soon be dark.
'Tain't safe in dark.
Stay here in Plath.
[music intensifies]
[Sam groaning]
[Sam sighs]
[tense music]
[eerie music]
- Dada say you eat this.
- What is it?
- Rabbit stew.
I cook.
- What's your name?
- Name?
You mean, how am I called?
- Yeah.
- Luna.
Dada is keeper of inn.
[Sam sighs]
Do all people on the outside
wear clothes like yours?
- Outside?
We're only a couple of
miles from the main highway.
An hour in my car would
take you to a big city.
- These only clothes we have.
Only clothes in boxes.
No clothes like yours.
- Boxes?
- All come from boxes.
Dicken, who work with
hands, make that from boxes.
- Well, where do you
people get these boxes?
- In ground.
On gathering night, all
come from boxes.
Clothes, wood, food,
all from boxes.
No more boxes left now.
All gone.
I not like others.
I humgoo.
My mother, from outside.
When I born, she be
put into box,
then dug up for great eating.
Dada say she caught in
mist, like you and motorcar.
- Luna.
What are they gonna do with me?
You're gonna tell me, Luna.
You tell me what
they're gonna do me.
- Luna no tell.
Dada beat me if I tell.
- Tell me, I'm not gonna
let you go until you do.
- We must have our food.
[tense music]
- Luna, I need your help.
I've gotta get outta here.
- Hide there.
They not go in there.
Fall down if go in there.
- Can you go in there?
- I not like them, I humgoo.
Can go in.
I come when I can, help you.
- Thank you.
[dramatic music]
[eerie music]
[haunting vocalizing]
[tense music]
[eerie music]
[haunting vocalizing]
- [Man] Almighty God,
hear the prayer
of your miserable servant
and grant me the power
to set down the unthinkable
evil I have witnessed.
We should have destroyed
the first one,
crushed it underfoot,
burnt its foul carcass,
and tossed the ashes
to the winds
as it squatted behind a
tombstone and did jibber upon
us.
But I, may I be forgiven,
did implore mercy for
the creature.
I took it into my house
and washed away the filth,
filth, the like of which
I had never before in
my life beheld.
I clad it in clean raiment
and laid it on soft bed.
Where did I sin, merciful God?
For should we not succor the
afflicted, give good for evil?
Then one night when the
moon was full, I saw it.
Cursed be the eyes that
see, the ears that hear,
feeding in the churchyard,
mud on the hands,
sitting on a pile of earth
and gnawing, gnawing.
We chased it away, but
for the one we drove away,
12 did return, and they danced
around the village bounds
to mark the place for their own.
[haunting music]
Even as I write, I can
hear the howls.
[tense music]
- [Innkeeper] Luna.
Luna.
- No.
No.
No, no!
[ghouls hissing]
[eerie music]
Dada beat me because I help you.
I not go back.
If you go, Luna be left here.
- That's nonsense.
When I escape, I want
you to go with me
and live the life a
pretty girl should.
- You take me outside?
I wear clothes like yours?
You really take me outside
and ride on underground?
- Underground?
What do you know about
the underground?
- Elders say there is much
good eating underground.
[glass breaking]
[dramatic music]
Stone kill if hit head.
They caught many
animals that way.
[ghouls hissing]
[eerie music]
- What will their next trick be?
- Nothing more.
They wait for elders to
come for great eating.
Elders not like us.
Have much wisdom.
No escape when elders are here.
- When will they come?
- This night.
[suspenseful music]
- Run when I run and
stay beside me.
[ghouls hissing]
[tense music]
- Follow, follow.
And stop them.
[suspenseful music]
[ghouls yelling]
- Mist, elders make, look.
[Luna screams]
[ghouls screaming]
[gentle music]
I hurt bad.
[Luna panting]
Back broke.
Like when Dada hit rabbit.
Rabbit die soon when back broke.
I die soon.
Never see outside.
Never wear pretty clothes.
- I'll go and get some help.
You'll be all right.
[traffic rumbling]
[Sam whistles]
There's a village, there's a
village up there, a village of.
Well look, if you'll take
me to the police station.
[tires screeching]
[tense music]
Where are you going?
This is the way to the.
Stop!
- Don't worry, sir, we saw.
The supply wagon will
take care of it.
- Supply wagon?
- It's just behind that car.
[dramatic music]
You see, we always
give the elders
a police escort when they
return to Loughville.
[eerie music]
[dramatic music]
[ghouls grumbling]
[Sam screams]
[mellow music]
- A village of monsters?
- Well, it would make a
good story, wouldn't it?
I mean, it's so moral.
No nudity, no sex,
a little violence perhaps,
but [chuckles].
- Now really, I must go.
- Oh no, no, I've taken a
liking to you.
- But you promised.
- Oh, no, no, no, I'm going
to put you up for membership.
- But I'm not a monster.
- Nonsense, you're the
greatest monster of them all.
[secretary grumbling]
Oh, Mr. Club Secretary, I
want to propose my friend here
as a member of this
august assembly.
- But he's a, he's, he's a hume!
- Yes, but can we truly
call this a Monster Club
if we do not boast
amongst our membership
a single member of
the human race?
- [Monster] Nonsense!
[monsters yelling]
- [Monster In Green Dress]
What can he do?
- What can he do?
In the past 60 years,
humes have exterminated over
150 million of their own kind.
No effort has been spared to
reach this astronomical figure,
and the methods that
they have used
must demand our
unstinted admiration.
You know, humes began
with certain very serious
disadvantages,
but these they overcame
with wonderful ingenuity.
Not having a fang or a claw,
oh, or even a whistle
worth talking about,
they invented guns and tanks
and bombs and airplanes
and extermination camps
and poison gas and daggers
and swords and bayonets
and booby traps
and atomic bombs and
flying missiles,
submarines, warships, aircraft
carriers, and motorcars.
They have even
perfected a process
whereby they can spread a
lethal disease
on any part of this planet,
not to say anything about
nuclear power. [laughs]
Oh, during their short history,
you know,
humes have subjected
other humes to death
by burning, hanging,
decapitation, strangulation,
electrocution, shooting,
drowning, crushing,
racking, disemboweling, hmm,
and other methods far,
far too revolting
for the delicate stomachs
of this august assembly.
- I never realized he
was so talented.
- We don't like to boast.
- I second the proposal.
A member of such a talented race
can only be a credit to
any Monster Club.
- [Monster] Ah, bravo, bravo!
[monsters cheering]
- Maestro, to celebrate the
installation of a new member,
may we hear our song?
["The Monster Club" by
the Pretty Things]
[monsters chattering]
♪ You read in books ♪
♪ About the things that
chill the human heart ♪
♪ I was necking with my
ghoulfriend ♪
♪ When she just snapped
out the light ♪
♪ Saying, fangs for the memory ♪
♪ As she took a bigger bite ♪
[singer crunches]
♪ Then there's the blood ♪
♪ Blood ♪
♪ Welcome to the Monster Club ♪
♪ The Monster Club ♪
♪ You hear those
hefty footsteps ♪
♪ Follow you down the hall ♪
♪ As you open door to
your late night visitor ♪
♪ You really lose your cool ♪
♪ Whoa oh ♪
♪ When he borrows a spanner ♪
♪ To tighten his bolts ♪
♪ You feel such a fool ♪
♪ Then there's the blood ♪
♪ Blood ♪
♪ Welcome to the Monster Club ♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪ Welcome to Monster Club ♪
♪ The Monster Club ♪
♪ Ow ♪
♪ There's a face at my window ♪
♪ As the darkness closes in ♪
♪ The door starts to creak ♪
♪ And scream for the night ♪
♪ There's a figure of
the phantom ♪
♪ With a strange,
twisted smile ♪
♪ Given these circumstances ♪
♪ You'd run a mile ♪
♪ Or two ♪
♪ Or three, ow ♪
♪ You feel so proud of being ♪
♪ Part of the human race ♪
♪ There's just a
little sadness ♪
♪ Not much grief
upon your face ♪
♪ Oh oh oh ♪
♪ You look into the mirror ♪
♪ There's a stake driven
right through your heart ♪
♪ Then there's the blood ♪
♪ Blood ♪
♪ Welcome to the Monster Club ♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪ Monster Club ♪
♪ Ow ♪
♪ Welcome to the Monster Club ♪
♪ The Monster Club, babe ♪
♪ Take a seat ♪
♪ Welcome to the Monster Club ♪
♪ The club ♪
["Monsters Rule O.K."
by the Viewers]
♪ Every night on the streets ♪
♪ When all the people
are fast asleep ♪
♪ From every corner creeps ♪
♪ The shape of something
you wouldn't like to meet ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Another sinister night ♪
♪ Another vampire girl to
give me hot love bites ♪
♪ Down at the Monster Club ♪
♪ A zombie and a ghoul
can do the monster dub ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah ♪
♪ Monsters rule okay ♪
[peaceful music]