Honey nice work I cannot be a sucker for
a slug opposed let's get busy are you
doing hmm
what's that for just habit Finny that's
all just habit we've paid enough for the
combination let's get busy don't fancy
it up I'll be by the window
you
yes hey Vinnie I got it better just one
man going Dan Lane give me back
dan come on
all right
well here it is ma'am does that have to
right only way to Fort Smith in that.
Emmitt and dial maybe pick up as many as
ten more men between here in Fort Smith
that prison wagon ain't very pretty
ma'am I admit but it's the best we got
to get the prison's to a trial court oh
no will I have they're going right on
just a few more minutes thank you
will you watch it yes ma'am
then
then I didn't want you to see me this
way Lin keys me
you all right Jenny she's inside asleep
don't worry she'll never know
oh then why did you do it why maybe
because I love you so much listen Elena
there was an agreement we made an
agreement that if nevis didn't make it
the other's real economy to whatever
family left behind
so don't worry about food or anything
else because a quarter of what we took
be coming to you when you need the
doctor you get you want that money you
can get that too
I don't care about any money I just care
about you what's going to happen now
just throw a scare into me that's all I
tell you what I'll bet on back in the
ranch within two weeks that's what I
think
and that's what I want you to say
promise me.
I promise
is anything you want.
Oh Harry get the baby
she's kidding even wake up Thank You
Marshall you are very kind
more copy I reckon you told your wife
not to worry because the fellas all will
you take care of her huh don't you
reckon so much party and my day I've
been on both sides of the barge I've
heard what men like that saying I've
seen what men like that do too many
times and the devil of it is by the time
you find out them fellas ain't got a
helper at all it's too late.
Bonnie Elena never asked me to tell her
who was with me
well she probably had too many other
things on our mind like a daughter do
- another way what do you think it'll be a
- boy or a girl.
Now me I haven't got anything on my mind
except to try to convince you of all the
grief you're gonna have just for the
sake of not telling three men's names I
don't know what grief you're talking
about prisons are grief for your wife
even more than for you look Emmitt you
don't scare me I know they won't send a
family man to prison for the first one
thing he ever done they older do you
ever hear of Judge Parker no
you will loser at the bar have you a
statement to make before you're
sentenced Dawson well I have even though
it's too late for you to profit by it
Daniel Slade Hardy you stand convicted
of the crime of armed robbery although
this is your first offense had you been
successful in escaping with your friends
it might have been but the first of many
offenses and so Daniel Slade Hardy I
hereby order you to be placed in the
federal prison here for a term of not
less than 10 years next prisoner average
question nice the batch
that's far
yeah I know it looks at might small but
cheer up five years from now it'll look
just like home and mother.
I ain't asleep no man can sleep in a
cage I don't like nobody to grab hold of
me so I I won't shake hands my name is
Griffin
Felix Griffin after my paw
your name's Hardy charged armed robbery
sentence 10 years where he gets around
fast in there a lot of people talk a lot
of people listen I reckon you even
though was on the job with me that's
your worry not mine that enough next 10
years
I don't think about listen that's it
just make-believe they don't exist lots
of things people things just why why
they don't exist at all hey hey don't do
that that's glass that's my little
animal I found it in some Indian camp
must have belonged to some little kid
they stole but the scar on your chest
supposed to be some kind of an animal -
yeah meant to be a rabbit
I had five sisters once he done it
your sisters yeah you mean little girls
hmm and some of them weren't so little
it was all older than me that there was
a sister baby rabbit I found seeing-eye
I didn't want him to die so I put him in
my littlest this is bed what's the name
what level anyway when she got in she
squashed them and they all ganged up on
me and put this on Paul wasn't around at
the time what about your mother mother
footmen I never had no mother just some
lousy girls was I glad when they all got
in trouble they all got in trouble
oh yeah an ascendant Watson where are we
even here in about six weeks
maybe I'll let you have this when I
leave you got sad eyes you could use a
little friend yeah I'll let you have it
sad man what are you in for me
well I sweet talk this pretty little.
Indian girl and she run off with me yes
a paw would turn me into a pincushion if
he ever saw me again I didn't know it
was against the law to take up with an
Indian girl
well one of was a they said I was given
a whiskey that's what they got me on but
that wasn't law like a des after a while
there
you hung yourself goodnight
no open party you want your food Hut you
got to get there early
it's kind of cold but last man gets
himself a little extra
wait a minute Griffin I blast man you've
been here before you trying to starve me
I got I Seidel Oh fixer soldier heaven
oh good
all right it's all over
eat your life night letter from the wife
yeah hey where's my animal by the bucket
isn't yeah here it is got all dirty she
miss you I told her she'd be taken care
of she doesn't say anything about it
maybe she's afraid of the gods Oh read
the letter she find a way to tell me she
must have heard from funny by now Finny
you know him don't think I'd wanna any
guy who'd take that long to do something
away see she's suffering
she wouldn't that I can read between the
lines she isn't taking Carol I don't
know how she's gonna last you got a baby
coming women never was as good as men.
Elaine is better than most men why I
don't be just a rile sad man is only
trying to ease your pain unless I know
she's taking care of I'm gonna work my
way out of here
you might try to break your way out but
you might end up dead what do you think
I am now
you'll got eyes to see with Griffin come
on Griffin a little dirt will make that
slop taste better.
Oh patience now huh Griffin come on
hurry though he's a pretty sick one sure
enough oh you'd think he didn't like our
grub wouldn't you yeah you could get him
in a wagon I'll be glad to help sir
alright grab his feet thank you
goodnight
never says goodnight
I'll be thrown another Oh stay where you
are writing again getting a letter from
the wife no say you know what I heard in
the kitchen Seidel died about an hour
ago they'd find out what it was
something he had anybody that gobbles
food down the way he done they never
know what they're shuttling down their
gullets til it's too late steady
hey Griffin
yeah there's your stud you're lucky man
getting out on Sunday gives you a chance
to go to church outside seems to me I
should have been let out yesterday I
ain't responsible for other folks bad
arithmetic we ready in five minutes man
mr. Ames mr. Ames
next time you want to know something be
respectful please I never believed it
they didn't steal a thing I was gonna
get out of here the first thing I do is
wait at Ames and beat him down he knows
that man you don't sound like the same
fellow came in here six weeks ago why
not maybe I take care of this names
fella for you buddy I gotta live it you
know they're paying a lot of money.
Indian scalps you have a collect on any
lot something since I came out with
sometimes more than even just a scalp
like a whole girl like he had before
yeah all in one piece I wish I could do
you a favor sad man I wish I could bring
one in here keep you a company so any
one woman able want to see
see on the flush real not just in my
head because I see on my head all day
and all night
10 years 10 years weren't gonna mean a
thing to me
medicines are better here they like to
go local worried about it nothing normal
that she's had the baby whether they're
- taking care of her nothing underneath
- don't upset yourself sad man you might.
As well get used to the idea that this
his wife of yours is moved in with some
- other guy but that's what she's gonna do
- if she hasn't done it already.
Let him go let him go back off head
ain't no way to say goodbye I'm sorry
yeah I know you don't know he got under
me feel the same way myself sometime
come on Griffin you might get that
throttling urge again this is sad man
does anything I can do to make it rest
easier I'll go out of my way to do it.
Thanks
I'll manage Oh hottie about the mail
they tell me all the stamps in
Washington burned up
ain't gonna be no mail never again too
bad shylu
come on dragon I'll be with you in a
minute sir I'd like to leave you
something to remember me by
you know that little animal of mine gave
me lots of pleasure it'll make you feel
any better leave it
I would've liked her but I can't Seidel
yet it.
Finney
Paul Bennett
mr. fini how do you want I come to see
Paul Finney ma'am my name is Griffin
Felix Griffin after my paw my son ate
here what do you want to see him about
well he he done me kind of a Phaethon
and I wanted to pay him back Oh money
yeah there's money in it come on in the
door's unlocked
thank you ma'am thank you
mighty neighborly of you to let me come
in man very nice place here what's this
favorite Paul did you well he introduced
me to a man who put me in the way about
a good thing I'd have been out here a
lot sooner he told me yes ajaan lovely
mother probably told you had a cripple
one though fell off a horse about two
years ago in done something to my spine
yes it's too bad
why why you don't look like a woman who
would ever fall off a horse your turn
right I didn't fall I faded had Satan
spelled ever since it was a child that's
a shame what Wi-Fi was Paul I I I'd stay
by his side
I never leave you alone no he doesn't
care it's gone oh and he won't be back
okay oh oh not all ya knows I have to
get along around here oh I manage that's
all I just barely manage well well if
you don't know what he'll be back if it
makes it kind of a problem about the
about the money don't it you could leave
it with me
yeah I can't can I
but first I can
sit a while talk with her a real pretty
lady a beautiful ring ain't any kid like
I said you got a a real nice place here
real nice
that balls ball no idea and ran away
left it here one day till you sneaking
thieves they come around here once in a
while but I Drive them off with my
shotgun good good to you you will leave
the money with me won't you
well well look if you want me to I will
mrs. honey then you don't need a ball
are coming back again to see Paul are
you planning to cheat a little on your
son man I could put something away then
I could get out of here without any help
from him
is that your wandering boy coming back
or maybe he never did go away huh
you won't tell him what I said about the
money with her ma'am
obvious quietest is here weapon
ma.
Put your gun down put it down she lied
to me
now supposing you tell me the truth
where's the money who who are you me my
name is Griffin.
Felix Griffin after my par and I'm a man
that hates to be lied to
I wouldn't worry about her if I was you
she told me a lie about you be in a way
she was gonna cheat on her own son
mister what do you want I want you to
tell me the truth will he keep all the
money you stole I never stole any money
you sure want to join your MA
real quick don't ya no no wait I'll tell
you it's over there under the rug in the
second step kid that's Florida sometimes
folks keep guns in funny places you go
over and set by your law
well I'm glad is one honest person in
the Finney family
bad baby a very bad baby mom is gonna
give you a good spanking
man outside
what dolly man I don't know he just
cooked it you all Jani and say hello
mommy would be along on red I said no
hello hello my mother's been feeling
awful sick she's lying down but this is
a real good time of day to lie down and
energy that's my real name
how do you know it I know it because I I
passed a buzzard on a fence post a while
back and he told me your name is Jani
and your mother's Elena that's right
and when my new baby brother gets here
he'll be called in after my daddy my
buzzer didn't tell me that now you sit
right here and watch my horse all right
time
mrs. Hani I'm sorry I haven't been
feeling well maybe I I came just at the
right time man my name is Griffin
Felix Griffin after my paw and I was in
the same cell as your husband dan yeah
how is he he's he were right yeah he's
he's healthy enough or or was the last
time I saw him but well he got in a
fight with a man named Seidel and the
next day the cycle died
oh no yeah he died oh but but but don't
you worry about it I don't think they're
gonna do anything to him it wasn't dad's
fault was it
I wouldn't say so no but he did hit the.
Seidel first he's been mighty edgy these
last days knowing that you didn't get
the money he stole from the bank I don't
want to talk about that money some
mighty cruel thing someone holding back
in a pretty woman's mana I don't care
about that money it's rotten if it's
it's poison
my money's clean maybe we can do
something with my money huh I don't want
any charity charity I didn't say
anything about charity I feel right at
home here yeah you mean it you might buy
it I didn't say nothing about buying
either but Dan's as good as dead and you
and me we could we could use each other
couldn't we we get have a good time once
he got in your feet again even if you
didn't get out you hear I got some how
he said that you've got the money and
they're gonna lock you up and give your
child away somebody's head
you shouldn't have done that.
Oh.
Nucky's eyes
mega driven friggin trip he's gonna
break his ribs Brady's red hard.
Christmas break his ribs
he won come on mister pay up I totally
win no matter what you little miss may I
don't want to watch things like that
scares me maybe from now on I'll just
leave you out of the house sorry
come on first time I ever seen a woman
at one of these Phoenix she goes where I
tell her how come you know my name I
don't know yours you will you're gonna
see a lot of us I'm gonna be looking
right through you not me you want grey
alright Jim boy you seen mrs. Hardy
house house who is mrs. Hardy well now
all of a sudden you show up around these
parts with considerable cash money buy
yourself a house outside town bring in a
beat-up last companionship take your
ease in general I just thought maybe Dan.
Hardy's cash might have had something to
do with your living so high off the hog
and then maybe his wife's come into some
of that bank loot - oh you mean Dan's
wife I have no reason to see her but Dan
said this was such pretty country I I
figured I might as well settle down here
if you were so worried about what his
wife Scott why don't you go and see for
yourself huh
reckon I might fold it where'd you get
all this money anyway Griffin it was
left to me from a man who died he died
of natural causes you might say he died
hard like I think you will someday
alright Jimbo I know cause I think the
one
man who is 10 cents in his pocket want
to make out a will just in case you
don't have a dime
Jim yeah he saw a rattlesnake ready to
strike did you take off your boot to
make it easier for him weird you know I
wouldn't so don't you start walking
around barefoot either Jim boy you're
gonna have to start out in Fort Smith
without me tomorrow no I'll get Pete.
Prager to do the driving
I never made the run without you before.
Frank no and you won't again but I got a
ride out there and re tonight I just
came back from the Hardy ranch
something's come up you find it Chuck
about stole Oh money I found mrs. Hardy
lost the child she was carrying you're
gonna have to swing out of your way and
drop her off some supplies how'd she
lose the child she follow something.
Griffin went out there give her a real
bad time Griffin what that slime belly
want here as I can make out her
we shit what about you wanted that baby
so much
well it made any difference if I didn't
all the difference you're just talking
I'll give you three names so I can go to
it yeah nothin in this world with so
much that I tell a lie like that to get
no I guess you
is anybody with him not when it happened
before what do you mean before Felix
Griffin when I was here it happened
right after he left Griffin to see it
didn't you tell him
I didn't even know
he was in my part of the country I don't
wanna run my ranch he's crazy
I don't ever gonna thousand miles in my
wife ain't much you can do about that
now then what do you do - what no cept
off a bad hand I guess - look
something's scatter pretty bad seemed
like he wanted to scare tell me did you
ever hit him anything like that yeah
buddy but there are no buts about what
he does to anybody who lays I had yeah
but I'm the one who laid a hand on him
why is he taking off my wife he ain't
particular matter of fact I think he
kind of likes it I'll give you the three
names in it I wish you're done if I fall
again what do I get out of here there's
as soon as we can make it go ahead
deadly cock Lu Lane what's the matter
maidenly cock was shot to death last
month in New Mexico and I try to hold up
a state station hmm who else I leave her.
Miss penny
Paul Finney would spin edom supposed to
get that money out to my wife take care
of it did you ever tell Felix about
about finning in the money I don't know
maybe y-yes Fenian s ma were killed in
this house robbed and burned right out
- the Felix got out of jail we thought
- Indians done then I saw Felix around.
With his pockets full of money I began
wondering where it came from and I think
I know
Felix Kilduff in easy stole the money
yeah and all the men you a named of debt
kind of there's things in a different
light as far as your freedom is
how old was the boy 21 just 21
what are you doing it I'm turning it in
I ain't going to get the man who killed
Jim and Pete with any batch you know who
did it
the same Indian the killer finis felix
crew grip are you sure he's Rena
laughing at badges for years
ever since they hung his paw but he
ain't gonna slaughter people like hugs
in my territory
have you turned this badge in it won't
be your territory anymore I reckon I
ain't yet lost the knack of gun and a
man down however Oh Emmet you let the
law take care of Griffin rock log gun
law what's the difference he'd only be
so dead sooner the better
please Emmet I know dyers death has
upset you but you remember when you
first put on this badge you said was
good to get out of a trade and into a
profession and you remember what that
trade was I was a gun sling
and a good one yeah and you also said if
you couldn't make the country bad you
might as well try and make it good
especially since you'd get paid every
month I was younger then a lot younger
but now you're older analyzer so you're
going back outside the law
I ordered Jim Dyer Frank you also owe a
lot to the people who live in the
territory you owe them the right to feel
safe in their beds when you first put
this badge on you took on that debt and
taken it off as like trying to dodge
payment another doesn't understand my
life neither has the law Jim Dyer I'll
be paid when the Griffons crazy but he
he's smart too
he'd keep this up for years we'll find a
way to trap him I promise you that
there's a lab make it snappy
where are we going mr. Ames I understand
they're gonna run you for president
- that's nice I say which party Judge
- Parker Italia judge Parker was he gonna.
See me for
I hear he's gonna tell you you don't get
no more mail for five years I'd like
that
I hate spelling out world you're pretty
cocky tonight just begging for a broke
head anything else you'd like yeah
what's in your face when you find out
what's in my right hand
you know mr. Ames you're one fella I'd
like to spend a couple of hours with
just man to man but beggars can't be
choosers and I'm in a hurry
come in Hardy come in any trouble not
much hope you weren't too hard on Ames
I'd hate to see you back here on another
charge I won't be back soon here's
nothing for you you'll find some money
in the pocket probably more than you
need and you'd be real careful when you
meet up with Griffin remember one slap
in the face cost two good men their
lives I'll be real careful look I know
what you'd like to do the woman but
killing him isn't the answer
kill him in cold blood mule hang you get
evidence on Griffin so we can legally
try them along to the Resta you'll get
your pardon what makes you think he's
gonna give me any information does a
chance we'll have to take you're our
only link with him and yours are the
only friendship he's even come close to
heaven I understand Hardy once you go
out that window you're on your own
you'll be considered an escaped convict
not even your wife must know the truth
you understand I understand
yeah but what about a horse in some
trees about 300 yards behind the wall
and Dan in order to make this look like
a real breakout the wall guards haven't
been told anything
- so B ain't quick there's a good chance
- you'll be dead.
Thanks then you know you you don't have
to go no what would you do
go in somewhere Little Miss Maine I'm
just going out to sit on the porch at
sir I'm here looks like yeah dad hurt
hurt yourself messed up it wouldn't be
safe you going out all all hurt like
that there's someone out there who what
do you think it is nobody you better
learn to believe me Little Miss may open
the door well if it isn't my old friend
hello Griffin I broke out cool good I
never thought you had it in you
come on and sit down sit outside man
little miss me
I got myself a guest how about a bottle
in two glasses huh sir don't out of old.
Fort Smith did you kill anyone doing it
no but I gave him something to remember
those yeah I'll bet you did y'all good
at that sign man you got a humble noon
would you miss me hell of a horse
yes to be said
tastes funny after summer you'll get
used to it again yeah once I can settle
down someplace after I found funny yeah
penny I was gonna take a look in on that
finian find out about your money but
some Indians got there first went up to
see him mm-hmm
was all burn up if a trust in Indian
don't kid with me Griffin
have you killed funny that's your
business if you got that money I want a
piece of it not all but enough to get me
and my family out of here but he found
no money just just to burn bodies
gunshot and heroin
so don't go blamin Mika what some evens
did look like you're doing pretty well
you didn't have a dime when you get out
of prison man be a fool to take cash in
a place like that you mean you have the
money outside I always have money sad
man by the way I uh I seen your wife oh.
I wish you that's a good he she lost a
baby
yeah
what'd she say well I I guess I must
have rubbed her the wrong way err
something but I not mean into it well
she was kind of set the way things have
been going be worse now when she finds
that I broke prison not knowing where I
am what do you think on seeing it I
don't know I'll be watching my place all
the time waiting for me to come and get
her I wouldn't worry about them watching
your place sad man
why not well they using all the men they
can get looking for killed Emmett and
aya
somebody killed Emmett and Dyer yeah
they was bushwhacked and the horses ran
off with a wagon full of prisoners they
must have been a mighty saw tailed crowd
of the horses run all the way to Fort
Smith that's a long haul
oh no yeah I know I just made it yeah
you look kind of tired sad man I think
you need some sleep
come on I'll show you a way to line up
yeah I just throw yourself down
don't don't even bother to take your
boots off yeah why not what Thanks
ah I'll see you in the morning sad man I
got some things to do
good night hey Mei Mei
what are you doing in the shed you
wanted to talk to him alone didn't you
yeah my old friends use in the bedroom
if you want to sleep do it out here
suppose he wakes up and wants something
if you can hear me you won't get it.
Willy
okay hlne later whole lane then the
babies I know.
Oh dad it was wrong for you to break out
but I am glad I don't care I am glad
don't forget your daughter sad man hello
woman hello daddy
how's my big girl sad man you know I had
a hard time convincing you is here bet
you're glad you listen mr. Toddy huh
thanks for bringing up Griffins oh
that's all right anything for an over
let me take a look at you you're really
growing up to be a big woman aren't you
you got big whispers dad oh honey I love
you I love you then you look different
what did I do did they beat you beat me
I'm a anak my own head against the wall
a couple of times but nobody else did
tell her about Seidel sad man Janey you
come over here let them do their own
- talking I'm gonna show you some pictures
- cool and I mean good pictures then you.
Didn't kill anybody when you escaped did
you
no honey sit down here don't worry all
right
nothing like that thank heaven we can go
away and start again
well maybe but not right away
why because you need money in a
dog-eat-dog world like this that's it
sad man you're getting smarter and
smarter he's then speaking for himself
before you I'm the only one who speaks
for me Elena you have to be realistic I
don't want us to have a bad time anymore
I wanna get my hands on some money first
how but by robbing somebody again if I
have to sure you can see a thing like
that if you think about it mrs. Hardy
the way this whole world keeps turning
is because it's a treadmill but for the
people who got robbed chasing the people
that robbed them then then I want to
talk to you can't we go somewhere else
by ourselves
there's nothing we have to say that we
can't say
listen that's my old friend Janie would
you like to fly like a buzzard in yeah
and I mean really high like a buzz hotel
zone he's not gonna hurt her Lelaina
hurt her put head down but head down I
said you're the only one that wants to
have some fun Janie Janie you go out in
the wagon oh no no just put a little
white darling go ahead did you know this
madman came up to the wrench Elena
please
he told me all about it he told you all
about it what he said to me and what was
he his mind when he said it he's only
trying to help us help us he'll help all
right he'll help you right back to Fort
Smith if you give him a chance
and then he's tried to help himself to
me just hearty there's no call for you
to talk to me that way then then please
listen please don't make the same
mistake again don't depend on Beth
friends come away with me please then
where you can far from here before he's
too late maybe she's right sad man why
try to get some money when you and your
little family can starve to death for
free
I'm staying here Elena we're doing what
I think is right for us I'm sorry if you
don't see it my way
I I I was right after all
you look different then you are
different
this this thing you're with when he came
out to the ranch whining that you had
broken out of prison I I didn't believe
him I wasn't going to come now I know
I'm glad I came because if I hadn't I
might have thought for the rest of my
life that you were to steal them
so I'm sorry they didn't shoot you get
in that robbery and I hope they do when
they catch up with you next time
what's so funny get the right thing you
let her go
my Paul wouldn't have thought so my Paul
would have twisted a neck like a chicken
right then and there
but well I I guess you got your own
problems uh I think you did the right
thing for me anyway
how do you mean well now we can sit
together and drink unless you don't feel
up to it
yeah I feel up to him I knew you would
drink up Simon
yeah she goes and here she comes
come over here little miss may pull up a
chair sit right with us huh right next
to me come on now we can all have some
fun what do we do sign man I don't care
just relax and chew the fat what about
anything good I like to talk hold up.
Little Miss maid do we lie uh what tell
the truth why go ahead why should I
makes no sense to lie to a friend I said
drink up Little Miss mag I'm like a
drink Felix if she doesn't want to
it's a toast get post to me wouldn't be
nice if someone would entice me to you
Felix come on drink up whiskey is quick
to sore muscles and you got a sore arm
little miss me come on drink up oh she
ain't deserving of anything better than
that I a little miss may we need another
bottle sit down I'll get in support you
know
this time we'll drink the truth yeah
yeah I feel very truthful this morning
how truthful I know what you're thinking
sad night you're thinking that I'm gonna
tell you that I really did get the money
from Finney am I right maybe I'm right
I'm right because I can think right
inside your head I didn't feel what
you're gonna do even before you do it
just like with Little Miss may I even
know when she's gonna hurt herself
so we trying to show you sad man well I
I did get the money from Finney I
figured as much
ain't mad I thought you'd be mad why
should I be you got what was coming to
him now get a piece of the money yes
sure you will everything that's coming
to you
what would you say I told you that miss.
Mae put some clothes on you look like a
slob
what would you say if I told you I not
only kill a Finny's but I done in
evident diattou I'd sir you were lyin if
I tell you sad man that I killed someone
you know damn well that's just what I
did I tell me because you want to know
don't you sad man
yeah Felix if you say so I know so now I
want to get a little truth out of you
there's a couple of things that are
bothering me one is when you said he
came straight here from the prison I was
just wondering how you knew where to
find me
and the other is why should a man who
doesn't stop moaning about his wife all
the time treat her the way you did why'd
you bring her here to test me I could be
sad man
that could be that tell me how'd you
find out where I was Hemet told me where
to look.
Emma's dead I got a first shot right
here you killed a man by the name of.
Prager I told you you were lying
hard to get around to mr. hemmond later
so he was someone who sent you probably
rigged up the whole jailbreak - I really
appreciate all the trouble they went to
I suppose I told you I kid if I caught
on to what you were doing I didn't have
to tell me that I guess they didn't know
that I kill you anyway though
choking me the way you did they
mentioned that - they know me better
than my own Papa has very funny sad man
miss Leigh miss may go out of the shed
and get in mile area Creek
she's a slow mover ain't she now sad man
tonight we're all going out to your
ranch because all of a sudden come to me
but that's the one place they won't be
looking for you meanwhile there's
anything else you'd like to hear about
my wicked deeds maybe because I wouldn't
want you to die without knowing you're
white either you leave her out of this
huh I couldn't do that it wouldn't be
right side man but an IKE were all gonna
have some fun me and mrs. Hardy are
anyway you're gonna be all tied up in
other things
Griffin you want to be do anything like
that don't you like big parties this one
they lasted days not worth mir-21
yes it well maybe I better give you a
little hot lead first so you won't be so
active that's better
all right Little Miss May time up and
good here now I'd turn around her I want
to see what she's doing.
Oh.
Now this edit I want you to study the
face of my clients very carefully can
you honestly say that the man sitting
there is capable of murder
Phoenix cribs not only capable of murder
mr. Gage he's broken you mean you
believe he might have other murders to
his credit beside the one for which he
is now being tried I do I have here the
full criminal record of this homicidal
monster Felix Griffin it shows that he
spent a shocking total of ninety days in
prison for giving whiskey to an Indian
now I try it let's say you now order
order
there will be no more lad mr. Gage there
is a time for rhetoric and a time for
cross-examination at present you will
confine yourself to the latter yes sir
mr. Alex will you tell me please why
this according to you most dangerous man
has never been tried for these other
murders you say Maher committed we've
never been able to pin anything on it
until now that's right until now I think
the jury will be interested to find out
how this pinning was done let's all
understand mr. Hardy you testified that
the authorities engineered a prison
escape for you in order that you might
seek out Felix Griffin you've also
stated that posing as his friend you
succeeded not painting from him an
admission of guilt the murder of one
more City am I right yes and what was
your reward to be 30 pieces of silver
like the other duty objection sustained
I'm sorry for jumping two obvious
conclusions your honor I should try to
phrase the question another way what
were you promised for this betrayal I
almost said betrayal for this service to
the law a pardon and if your mission
failed
they didn't say anything about failure
why didn't you as a bartender fail
self-confidence is a fine thing I wish I
had more of it mr. Hardy however you
have said you were committed to prison
for the crime of armed robbery yes sir
with a sentence of 10 years 10 years a
very long term especially to a young man
who had heard prison doors clang shut on
what might have been wonderful days with
a beautiful wife and a dear little
daughter now that I've been in your
shoes mr. Hardy I should have prayed
every night for self confidence and of
self confidence so that I could without
care or consideration of any human
feeling with merciless lies found an
innocent man to the gallows and a lot of
reason than to be able to return to the
creature comforts I had lost through my
own evil deed now mr. Griffin did you
ever see this before
that's amazing my housekeeper now you're
quite sure yes she wore a lot do you
know where she got it well I I never
asked her but I remember her telling me
once she had it a long time
thank you mr. Griffin that's all
do you recognize this ring I said do you
recognize this ring you realize that
you're under oath and that any false
statement makes you guilty of perjury
will you please state your name again me.
Matthew su-mei Mathewson em him take a
look at the inner band of this ring tell
me what you see
speak up so they jury can hear you it's
two letters mmm you're sure mm thank you
well young lady if this is your ring
it's the first time in human history
that an F stood for Mathewson have you
an explanation for this discrepancy miss
Madison yes sir five years ago I was
married my husband gave me this ring my
name was made fallkniven
the trial is over who told you about it
I wish you head
then you know everything
and did you know that I didn't mean the
things I said him that it was like
killing myself to to hurt you the way I
did Oh Dan oh now you are home and we
are free of Felix of all this season 11
the jury didn't convict Felix is free
too
you
what was it just an animal then you
can't leave this way I don't attend him
some more coffee just about the cup left
when are you going to decide what you
are going to do sir
why can't we leave here what are we
waiting for
I want to see which way Griffin's gonna
jump but if we go away he won't bother
us do you want huh how could he if
nobody knows where to find us anyway I
don't think it would be as foolish as to
come back to town
he's come back to town all right well
boys it's a bit of thought but we can't
break his neck just because he broke
hers you see he's got a perfect excuse
there's no point in killing it why not
she had as much to do with catching him
as I did more yeah but what she lied
about having been married to this
fortifier if she was lying
she saved Griffin's neck now don't ask
me why she did it
I will live long enough to figure some
women it and the way a jury looked at it
is that Mays horse probably shied away
from something jerked her back into the
wagon broke her neck meanwhile Felix can
just come and go as he pleases and I'm
afraid so Dan we haven't got anything on
him yeah well you think he might be kept
from coming and going tomorrow so I can
get my wife and daughter away without
him known I reckon Sir Harry maybe you
could pick him up a question say
sometime around daylight no doesn't go
to light the dark a pleasure and the way
things stand now Dan you make a mighty
smart move I tell you what I'm leaving
tomorrow with prison wagon report Smith
be kind of nice to have some law-abiding
people along fine it's no trouble no no
trouble at all will seem kind of funny
to you riding alongside the way and
instead of inter then I don't think so.
Anna I won't be going
we ought to be thoughtful dan do you
want to make good campsite by nightfall
yeah there you go sweetie
now you mind your mommy huh all right
Elena see how come you're taking the
wagon instead am it he didn't tell me
and I didn't ask him then can you help
me with something please yeah why'd you
want me to help you
I'm sorry darling but you can around
here I couldn't help it will we come
back here won't we
I thought you wanted to go away
this is the only home we have ever had
oh damn honey you'll come back here I
was not afraid before I am now it's not
a way to get the thing done but why
can't you come with us no matter where
we went riffin it find us he isn't gonna
give up until he gets me there's another
reason what I guess I feel guilty some.
Hobbit Griffin is still free to come and
go you'll kill other people it'll be my
fault because I wasn't quite smart
enough to stop unless I stop it you
understand yeah we'd better be moving
out
be careful I can't promise you that
because that's what he expects me to be
you
move over JD
come inside man I was thinking of coming
out to see you but you surprised me I
couldn't wait for it to happen.
Sadam have a drink I couldn't wait for
what to happen gonna shoot me in the
back shoot you in the back I know you
you got me all wrong
you think I hold it against you if it
turning me in nah you got out of serving
ten years and I got acquitted the only
ones I cut hurt maybe were a couple of.
Deputies so why should I hold a grudge
you was real smart sad man pulling a
trip like that
it won't work Griffin he worked on me
but not on me Little Miss me I've been
all broke up since she died I even saw
this this warning ban on my arm yeah you
know when I'm surprised you didn't get
her to sew it on for yourself before
yeah yeah you're real smart sad man I
never thought about that but she
she thought - will you hurry no huh yeah
but it's all over
woman's ring in a man's with look
couldn't your wife deployed if she'd
wear it I bet you I can make her wear it
when I get out to your house we're all
gonna have a good time together you your
wife your little girl in me a lot of fun
clean and journey you've come on yeah
where'd they go
you mean you're living out there all
alone
I'd be scared
I moved into town Griffin staying at the
hotel good good now we can spend a lot
of time together huh yeah we can't oh
but I don't think you're gonna like it
why not cuz every time I see you I'm
gonna do this just take the me cut stuff
oh that's too bad cuz I think cuffing
you just about the most fun I've ever
had and it's so much fun I don't want to
sit up maybe a side now and die ahead
and stuff they'd still be alive today
one day I'm gonna be alive and longer
because the only way you're gonna stop
me from cuffing you is to be wearing a
gun that next time you see me is that's
the only chance you're gonna have to get
me out in the open man to man until you
shut up
what are you every minute of every day
whatever you do wherever you go
philsie better come up me open stage
rustle in the next 20 years
come on you silly
I'll be waiting for your sadness
you almost got yourself shot in her
hundreds in town ban expected you'd be
dropping in on me didn't think I only
called him
I hear that scene Griffin yeah I
might've run into him once or twice they
have been baton him around a little he
complained no but you better stop it Dan
you're gonna wake up dead some sunny
morning I stopped at I'm damn well
shootin I thought you got over being a
fool it's my job to get Griffin for you
to do what you're doing is going against
the law
I'll tell you this much Emmitt I sure
don't intend to get buried because I
went with it I want you to keep away
from Griffin I don't think I will
I try to chill away once and I'll do it
my way then I got no choice but to put
you under arrest for your own safety
hmm my charge the old one you're
forgetting I was pardoned for that
robbery you aren't pardoned for breaking
prison huh let's have you got in the end
boy I'm sorry
yeah I'm sorry - that's a beautiful ring
where'd you get it
woman gave him what for the favours
received you might say what favors and
do you know what she told me she said
Felix I'm just passing this ring on to
you when you find someone that does the
same favors for you I want you to pass
it on to her and then she died
what she died Oh happiness but it is
pretty I wish I had you never see things
like that in this town how'd you like to
go in some ways where they grow on trees
with you mm-hmm
when tonight maybe right now I'll tell
you one I got something to do first can
I try the ring on ain't done me no
favors yet what would you like I know
still in town now Felix still alive to
the other one that's dead sad man don't
worry about that when I see you weren't
a gun I don't see you wearing one now
outside you go outside I'll see you
later a gun old friend good.
No.
Oh.
Are you feeling danboy oh pretty good
he's as healthy as you or me Frank he's
just after all this thing but she can
get how about that reward money dad made
any plans for it well it was planning on
buying a new herd of cattle
- but now I think I'll give it back to the
- government all these side trips you're.
Making out here and their time has run
into a lot of money don't pay any
attention he's buying another herd how
about you or later did you buy anything
a lot of good weather
you