ABuried Forest Production
Committee Presents
A Kohei OGURI Film
THE BURlED FOREST
(Umoregi)
"Won't you dance with me?"
That's what I asked you,
First we danced apart,
Then we started crying,
Our bodies and faces drew closer,
And we tasted each other's tears,
Beats me.
What's so interesting?
It's only a story, just fiction.
But the pictures are good.
Mmm...
Machi, you were talking about
the pet shop...
That funny pet shop.
I'd hardly call it a shop.
Hey...
Shall we make a story?
Huh!
What?
With lots of fiction.
Story?
About the pet shop owner.
He got a camel.
A camel?
You can't be serious...
In this town?
And why not?
It's just a story.
Mind you, it was hard.
There was nowhere to walk it.
So...
he dug up the road...
filled it with earth...
and made a path for the camel.
After that,
everyone preferred the dirt road...
and they dug up all the roads
in the town.
Huhhh!
You continue, Tokie!
Eh...?
I can't!
Jin!
Machi, then.
I'm no good.
Don't be so negative.
Do camels have eyelids?
I've never checked,
but I'm sure they do.
It was three years before they
closed the bus station,
when I took over the business.
I asked my dad:
"Why didn't they make a railroad?"
Some people thought they would.
That's not what I mean.
My granddad was from old Tokyo.
He was dead against a railway.
So he said.
People had a different take
on things in the past.
If the railway had come here...
our little market wouldn't
be here now.
That's true, now you mention it.
Akio, has the delivery gone?
Hey, Akio!
Akio!
That grandma from Sanda just called.
She wants a big bucket.
A bucket?
Do we have one?
Oh, I'll look for one.
Ouch...
Hey, Tahbo!
Stop that!
Ah, here's San-chan.
Yo!
What's up, Machi?
What is it with your hair?
Thanks for the CD.
It was okay.
You like vocals, right, San-chan?
I suppose.
Summer vacation already?
Yep.
Would you like a lift?
No thanks.
- You don't.
Ride Tomo's motorbike?
I'll walk.
I like walking.
Good for you.
Be careful.
What are you doing?
Sailing a boat.
What kind of boat?
A bamboo leaf boat.
It's tiny, isn't it?
But it's carrying very
important things.
Yeah?
Yuko, how come Machi is
so moody these days?
It's probably her age.
Were you like that, when you
were 15 or 16?
Maybe I was.
Scary!
I bet you were awful!
I happened to be very cute.
Oh, yeah?
I feel sorry for you.
You never knew me when I was cute.
Really?
Say...
Is it true that Marui the joiner quit?
He has so much skill.
And now he's driving a taxi.
A taxi?
Yeah.
Marui is a cab driver?
Why a cab driver?
He couldn't bear working alone,
they say.
Maybe he brooded too much
over his daughter's death.
What a waste.
How will he live?
That's a bit callous.
Yes...
What?
A vehicle?
Yes, a story is a vehicle,
We get on and ride, and that's
our life,
I wonder.
Do you think we can choose
our vehicle?
Well,,,
A story is only words,,,
I'll call you.
See you,
That was the news, and now
it's back to the music,
This song is "Morning HaZe",
Hang on!
Take this miso to go with it.
You shouldn't...
- Here.
Thank you.
Take care.
Where's the fishmonger?
At the hospital, his wife's rheumatism
is playing up,
What's this?
It's the egg... of the "Elephant
Bird"... so I'm told.
They can pick up an elephant
and fly off.
They're massive, or so it says
in the letter.
So he sent this, did he?
I love Jugem's jokes like this.
He's never changed.
All the way from Brazil.
Do you think it's a fake?
You never know.
They say they shoot butterflies
with pistols in Brazil.
I've never met granddad
so I don't know.
In the fields...
there was a man who was
watching the sunset...
he suddenly got the urge
to follow the sun.
So he dropped the plow...
and walked off, never to return.
Maybe Jugem is like that.
Ah! It still works.
Don't want people to think
we're breaking in.
It's bigger than I thought.
- Certainly is.
It's been 5 years since he closed.
Amazing.
What photo is it?
Don't know.
I wonder where it is.
They're relatives, but I was
scared of my uncle.
So I don't really know.
Uncle!
Take our picture!
Who are you talking to?
- The dead!
Move that pram and bring a chair.
Be a good girl.
Sit down.
Wimp!
You're really pretty.
It's bright.
I like portrait photos.
Everyone looking in the same direction.
It's not often that happens.
I hate photos.
I always shut my eyes.
I wonder why.
It's a talent.
- What do you mean?
The instant the shutter opens
you wave goodbye...
with your eyelids, I mean.
That's a talent.
That's a compliment?
Yes, it is.
Tomo!
What?
- Leave the ball there.
Huh!
What are you doing?
Bet you can't guess.
There, it's the last one.
Come here, Tomo!
Quick!
Very interesting.
It means "dream" in Tonpa characters.
Tonpa?
Used by a small tribe in China.
Uh...
When I was little...
I was very shy.
I used to like hiding
in small spaces.
Once...
I hid in the hydrangea bush.
It started to rain...
and my parents looked for me.
But I didn't come out.
So, the camel became very
popular in town.
Lots of people came to walk
with him.
The camel was kind and took to
the people well.
They went for many walks everyday.
San-chan often rode the camel.
Called himself "Lawrence of Arabia".
And paraded around the town
2 or 3 times a day.
Why is San-chan in the story?
Never mind.
But...
But?
You've made me forget with
your interruptions.
Sorry.
But...
the camel started getting
depressed.
He missed so much of the simple
life of sand and sky.
Good one!
Tomie, please go back inside!
I want everyone to know
what's going on.
Fetch them some tea instead of
dithering about there.
What's up here?
- Oh, hello. What a fuss, eh?
Maybe you're making matters worse,
acting like this.
I know I'm sometimes in the wrong, too.
But the way they did it isn't fair.
That's the issue.
Marui.
There was a family meeting.
It was decided, and I can't
go against it.
You could discuss it again.
How?
My daughter and the family already
trooped back to Tokyo.
My son said:
"Show of hands or secret ballot?"
Now I'm being put in an "old home".
What was the vote?
Eight to one for packing me off,
the "one" being me.
I see...
Ah... I'm sorry for the fuss my
mother is causing.
That's okay.
Okay! Now everyone!
Move away from the area.
Cars are passing.
Watch out!
There's a car coming through!
Step back!
This way!
Sorry for dragging you out
- I don't mind.
It's the old woman next door.
I was born way in the mountains.
My mother lived there till
the day she died.
How old was she?
Ninety.
She was alone for 20 years
after Daddy died.
I felt sorry for her.
But she loved the mountains.
She never complained.
"What if you get ill up here?"
I used to say.
"l couldn't be happier if my
time comes here."
That's what she said.
I was... still young.
I couldn't... understand.
How did I ever become such
a weak person?
I feel I can't live if I don't cling
to my son and everyone.
But Tomie-san...
you need help sometimes,
what with your legs...
Never mind that.
It's something to do
with myself.
Tomie-san.
We're making up a kind of story.
Each of us takes turns.
It's my turn next.
Will you listen?
The camel came from a place
where dunes lead to the sea.
Once, a whale washed up and couldn't
get back in the water.
The villagers tried dragging it
with boats.
They dug trenches to make
a path to the ocean.
They tried hard, but couldn't
rescue the whale.
The whale became weaker
and weaker.
By evening, the villagers had
given up.
But one little girl didn't leave.
She stayed and bathed the whale's
eyes with sea water.
Then it was morning.
Some fine specimens here.
They're called gurnards.
With those snouts they
look like dogs!
They're a spring fish.
They live quite deep, but sometimes
get dragged up.
It's the day of the altar gods.
So it is.
Used to be a toss up between the
altar gods and the market...
as to which would disappear.
After all...
they are both still here.
There were more kids when
I was younger.
We divided what we made, but it
never came to much.
My dad would pass us a few times
to boost our income!
When did we start calling it
"traffic tax"?
I wonder, too.
It's like a border crossing.
The kids have their own country.
They could form a republic!
Not a bad idea. I would be for it.
Oh!
Good job!
Here, It's not much,
but this is for you.
Thanks, mister.
You can make an offering with this.
Hey! Give some to the gods first!
I'm sorry.
- Okay, keep it up.
Here comes a car!
Hey!
What's all this?
It's altar gods day.
The day when the children clean
the statues to ward off...
It's an old tradition, and grown ups
who pass here...
have to pay a traffic tax to
us as a reward.
It's a thank you for the
kids' hard work.
You're kidding.
It's the rule.
Sounds like fun,
how much?
There's no rule about that.
Here.
Thanks very much!
- Thanks very much!
Good. See you.
I've lost all faith in the
older generation.
Instead of knocking those
balls around...
they should be slipping some cash
to their grandchildren.
True.
Here they are.
Okay, that's it!
Thanks for your help.
Think nothing of it.
It has to be turned at least
once a year.
Machi, you can't be up in
a mountain this late.
Are you sure you saw someone?
Hey Akio! Can you fit everybody in?
Were there flames near the big rock?
I think so, but it's hard
to tell at night.
The forest is a lot thicker
at night than it seems.
Is this the right way?
Hey!
This way!
Did that come from beneath the cliff?
Who was it?
Might have been Gen.
Nope, here I am!
That's creepy!
Jeez!
You gave me such a fright!
That's my line, I think!
What the hell...
Here they are!
They're okay.
So much for forming a republic...
When the sun goes down,
things can happen.
I get tempted too, you know.
That's because you've got no customers.
Do you know this song?
As the sun goes down I start to cry.
I wonder why...
I wonder why I start to cry.
Do you know it?
Yes, I remember.
I do remember.
When I saw you it was love
at first sight.
But now I am in a most
terrible plight!
As the sun goes down l
start to cry.
I wonder why I start to cry.
Please, please! Won't you love me?
It must be an old song,
I don't know it.
Would you care for some sauce?
Thank you, it's wonderful.
Thank you.
It's been ages since we had dinner.
In fact, it's the first time.
No, it isn't.
After Kuro died...
Oh, that's right.
You brought tears to my eyes then.
Why?
We dug a hole near the dry river-bed
that the dog liked.
And you paid your last respects.
You know what you said?
"Thank you, Kuro."
Just like that.
I thought:
"Yes, thank you."
We should part with thanks.
And that's when I started crying.
I'm going to do it again.
Dogs can't talk.
He might not have known how
he helped us, me included.
Shall we get a new dog?
I don't want to.
I see.
But you shouldn't shut yourself off.
I think the same myself.
We should be free.
Which hot spring is Dad at tonight?
I didn't ask, it's just an excuse
to drink beer!
They don't care where they go.
Scoundrel!
Tahbo,
do you want to move house?
To Granddad's?
No.
To Mom's?
Nope.
Anywhere is okay.
Sorry, kiddo.
You know my folks are separated.
I never mentioned it...
but Mom runs a business.
What kind?
A bar.
I don't like coming back here.
Is it nearby, her bar?
I don't want to talk about it.
Even when things stare me in the face,
I still don't understand,
I should have guessed, but only
realiZe in retrospect,
I was thoughtless, and now
you're gone,
Changing shapes and colors,
clouds are floating by,,,
bathed in rays of sunlight,
The one who kept me safe,,,
was you,
It's got fuck all to do with me!
Don't you raise your voice to me!
Tomoyuki!
I'm sorry.
Should have chosen a different town.
You don't need to worry.
I know a really cool place near here.
Do you want to go?
Yeah.
Excellent!
What about cars?
They've stopped construction
so it's okay.
No people either.
Very good!
Let me try!
Isn't it a bit big?
It said 3 meters, so it's right.
They still existed up until
400 years ago.
Do the feet look okay?
Huh?
Thank you.
Good, eh?
I've knocked a bit off the price.
This the stuff?
Yes, please.
Calling it "Home Delivery Service"
is glorifying it a bit.
Akio started calling it that
in the first place!
How is it going?
I mean Akio's water distillation idea.
It's ready.
Thank you very much.
I'm not sure.
I don't really understand it.
Let's say you drink a cup of water.
How long does it take to flow
around the body?
Hmm... Iet's think.
An hour?
No!
Thirty minutes.
One minute.
Never!
Just one minute.
Amazing stuff, water.
Hello.
Right away.
It moved!
Separate the ones that move.
I'll collect them over here later.
- Okay.
Here we go!
It's turning.
Mind that roller, it's cracking.
Do you think you'll be finished today?
Yes, leave it to me.
Oh...
Watch your step.
How far are they moving it, Takako?
Ten meters, I heard.
It was slightly in the way
of the new road.
Yours is the room in the
corner, right?
It's odd.
Seeing our house move like that.
I once heard the story of Mayoiga.
MA-YOl-GA?
What's it mean?
Well, I'm no scholar...
Maybe "lost" and "house".
It's a story from olden times.
There was a big house
in the mountains.
They called it MA-YOl-GA.
If people stumbled across it...
they could take away one red bowl.
After that...
that person would have
the luck with food.
Well, that was the story.
We used to call it bogwood.
People used to find lumps
of wood while plowing.
It's amazing.
If this is...
What did you call it?
A buried forest.
If that's what it is...
There could be lots of trees.
A whole forest could be hiding
down there.
An expert is coming down from Tokyo.
That probably means so.
Don't do that!
Wow! It smells of cedar!
This is a town hall announcement,
The 5 by 8 meter object,,,
found in the croquet pitch,,,
is believed to be part
of a buried forest,
Although more details should be available
upon further investigation,,,
Shall we continue the story?
Don't know.
That forest is probably about
3,800 years old,
It is one of the greatest
discoveries in history,
Do you remember who this is?
Mr. Marui, the joiner.
He's here to tell you about
trees and wood.
Well...
Please go ahead.
Hello everyone.
Hello.
How was your summer?
My daughter and your friend Akemi
died from illness.
Since last summer I stopped working.
But now you are studying
about the buried forest.
And after I saw it, too...
I wanted to work with wood again.
So I've started afresh.
If Akemi was still alive,
I might not be here now.
Here's what I think.
Wood is a living thing.
For us joiners, wood is our work.
That's why we say "woodwork".
But the wood we use
is still breathing.
Even 3,800-year-old wood
is still breathing...
This way...
Stop, stop!
Here it is.
- Good.
Hey... perfect!
San-chan,
Why do you always want a horse?
It's too difficult.
So what? I like horses!
Here, fix this to the exhaust pipe!
Hurry up!
- Yes sir!
But, carbon dioxide is heavier
than air, it won't float.
Huh?
He means the exhaust gas.
Hey! Stop with the exhaust!
Have some more.
You can sure hold your own.
I can even drink more than my late
husband could!
He was a kind and good man.
It was a stroke of genius by the mayo.
Bringing the festival down into the
forest excavation.
Yes, he looks like he's daydreaming.
But he knows how to draw a crowd.
So, no "spirit lanterns" this year?
I wonder...?
The girls were making something.
I'll take a peek.
Watch it, Granddad!
Actually, I will be transferred next spring.
Fit as a fiddle as usual, Tomie.
If I was fit
I wouldn't be in this thing.
Maybe she would be better
in an old people's home.
Please!
Please, try some!
Here.
This is good. Thank you.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
I can't tell the difference.
The first glass sort of sticks
in the throat, doesn't it?
But my water goes down
as smooth as silk.
Let me try.
I see!
What's this, then?
A whale!
More like a catfish.
Ah!
What a cheek!
Mr. Marui made the bamboo frame.
We covered it and painted it.
Takako, hold the tail lightly.
- Okay.
Okay! It's going to be fine.
Slowly.
Wait!
What's that?
The cheats!
Balloons are against the rules!
Tahbo! You ready?
- Just a bit more.
I'm counting on you.
Remember last year's flop?
This year we have to!
How can I say...
This year will be different.
I know what you mean.
It's moving!
We did it!
Amazing!
See you, then.
Starring: Karen as Machi
Akira SAKATA as fishmonger
Taka OKUBO as tofumonger
Tadanobu ASANO as San-chan
Hiromitsu TOSAKA as Tomo
Ittoku KlSHlBE as Mr. Marui
Sumiko AKAMOTO as Tomie
Keiko MATSUZAKA as Tomo's mother
Yuko TANAKA and Mitsuru HlRATA
as Machi's parents
Written by:
Kohei OGURl and Tsukasa SASAKl
Music from "Silouans song"
composed by Arvo PART
Cinematographer: Norio TERANUMA
Lighting by: Meicho TOMlYAMA
Sound Recording by:
Masato YANO
Production Design by:
Yoshinaga YOKOO and Koichi TAKEUCHl
Editing by: Nobuo OGAWA
Visual Engineer: Yoshihiko YAMAGUCHl
VFX Supervisor: Art Durinski
VFX Director: Norio lSHll
Directed by: Kohei OGURl
All rights reserved by The Buried
Forest Production Committee,
English translation by: Dean Gascoign