[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[EXPLOSION]
Must you go, Toby?
I wouldn't go if I
didn't have to, Zee.
But what about me,
not knowing if you're
ever going to come back alive?
I do come back, don't I?
'Til now you have.
Someday you won't.
They'll get you.
Now you ain't going to
worry your mom, promise me.
I'll do my best to.
When will you be back?
Oh, in a week or two.
A week or two... why so long?
I can't work around
this neck of the woods.
Folks around here
expect us, and we've
got to respect their
boundaries, so we've
got to work out in the county.
What you got there, Toby?
Oh, just the old newspaper.
Let me have it.
I need the newspaper
to make a bustle.
You double it over and
run a ribbon through.
Now, listen, Zee,
when I come back I'll
buy you a satin bustle
with feathers on it.
Look at that.
Don't read that.
That's an old newspaper anyway.
Oh it's an... it's an
awful thing for a woman
to walk through the streets
of the county in a bustle
advertising a price
on her husband's head.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[EXPLOSION]
Zee, where've you been?
Where are the children?
I've been worrying about
you ever since I got back.
You've been worrying?
How do you think
I felt not knowing
whether you were alive or dead?
I'm alive all right, Zee.
They don't get me that easy.
Thank goodness.
Where are the kids?
They're home.
Home with my family, Toby.
What are they doing there?
They're going to stay there, Toby.
What's the matter, ma?
Matter?
You don't know what
I've been through.
Why, my relations have been
at me all day telling me
what I got to do.
Now, mother...
But I've been listening to it.
It's a wonder I'm not deaf.
What are you doing, Zee?
Taking my belongings.
That last bank was too
much for everybody.
Oh, that?
That was a nine-day wonder.
There've been too
many nine-day wonders.
Years of them.
I can't stand it anymore.
I won't.
I promise.
Please, Zee.
Think of the children.
I am thinking of them.
They don't even know
their own right name.
There was an [INAUDIBLE]
on that train
yesterday Why I had
to write backwards
so they wouldn't see it.
I never was so carsick in my life.
Now, heaven, put the tea
on, and you'll feel better.
I've stood for this in
every county in Texas.
This is only part left
that we can live in,
and for you to come back
here and start up again...
why I... I'm going to
finish my packing.
Said I had to quarrel with my
folks to get back here at all.
I'm going back
tomorrow... early train.
You mean you're going
to walk out of here?
You're going to break up
your home, your family?
Huh, I won't believe it.
Home?
This isn't a home?
Why, I never drew a free
breath in this house.
Howdy, ma'am.
Good morning.
Would you mind fetching the
trunk in the bedroom, please?
Yes, ma'am.
I couldn't believe you'd do it.
I left all my diamonds upstairs.
I don't want them.
Well I'm not going to wear $500's
worth of valuable diamonds
and start people talking.
You can wear those diamonds.
I bought them with
my own money, right
after the Texas Pacific hold up.
I don't want them.
Got any money?
All I need.
I'll send money regular.
And I'll send it back.
I can't take money from a man
I don't live with and respect,
can I?
There are a lot of folks
who're living together
that don't respect each
other, and they get on fine.
Eight years.
Eight years and it
has to end like this.
I owe the milkman 17 cents.
I never thought that day when
you asked me to marry you
on the [INAUDIBLE]
merry-go-round...
the poor children.
I slept alone down there
last night like a dog.
Seems I don't deserve
those children.
Seems I'm not a human man.
Seems my children's
got to forget men.
Seems they'd be better off
without any father at all.
They will!
I'll teach them too.
Go ahead.
I ought to have left
this house long ago.
Well, why didn't you?
I didn't stop you, and
I ain't [INAUDIBLE].
I didn't because I was a fool.
I left your letters up there too.
All of them signed, yours
til and through death,
Tobias Simms.
I didn't want to take anything out
of this house to remember you.
You took the children, didn't you?
I had to.
You were badly advised.
I had to!
You sure are.
Oh, Ma, don't cry.
I'm leaving, Toby.
I'm... I'm never going
to live with you again.
Oh, Ma, you won't head up.
How could you go to church
and pray for guidance
when you live the
way you're doing?
You're right, Zee.
Nothing matters but you...
you and the children.
And I'm wrong.
Dead wrong.
I'm going to make a vow,
Zee... a sacred vow in church.
I'll never ride out
again, so help me.
Oh, Toby.
And, Zee, we'll have a real church
wedding, like I
always promised you.
You had better take that
trunk back upstairs,
Mrs. Zee won't be
leaving after all.
I don't know how I
thought I could do it.
I'll never leave you
again, Toby, never.
Thank you, Zee.
We're all here, now reverend.
Can we start.
Never saw a man so
anxious to get hitched.
If you'll just step
here and hold hands.
Thank you.
Pardon me, reverend.
Toby there's some strangers
riding down the road apiece,
and one of them's on a white mare.
Are you sure, Billy?
Getting surer every second.
Oh no.
No, you're not.
I got to, Zee.
Excuse me, reverend,
but we'll have
to finish this some other time.
Goodbye, son.
Goodbye, daughter.
Mind your mother.
If you don't hear
from me in a few days,
I'll tell you where we'll meet up.
I'm sorry, honey,
but I promise you
we'll have that
church wedding here.
Good luck, Toby.
I warned you to leave him.
I can't, ma.
He's my husband.
I love him.
Love him?
What kind of love can
you have for an outlaw?
Outlaw?
Well, who is he?
Why, he's the El
Paso Kid, reverend.
The El Paso Kid?
Don't take it so hard, Zee.
Toby's a good man.
And your marriage is
a good legal marriage.
Of course, the
justice of the peace
may not be as holy
as a church wedding.
But it's just as binding,
Zee... just as binding.
And you got two fine
children to prove it.
[GUNSHOTS]
(SINGING) Their honeymoon's
on a mountain trail.
'Cause it wasn't a
real church wedding,
they sky overhead
was their ceiling,
and the moss on the
ground was their bedding.
But The Kid, he vowed
by the stars above that
they'd have a real church wedding.
And sweet indoors where the
walls and floors and goose
feather quilts for their bedding.
She was left all
alone today in church,
when the sheriff broke
up their wedding.
On his bridal night no bride
in sight, just his self
and his horse for his bedding.
What do you plan on doing, now?
Don't you worry.
Billy, I'm going to
get me a new state.
Off 'n a train?
No.
Off'n a bank.
A bank?
That's more dangerous, Kid.
No, I've got a new way
to get money from a bank.
You have?
Yeah.
I'm going to borrow it.
Borrow it?
That's the newfangled-est
idea I ever heard of.
I guess I'll turn in.
Lending money from a bank.
I sure hope he ain't gone loco.
BANKER: Come in.
Well, what do you want?
I'd like to open an
account with your bank.
Do you want to make a deposit.
Well, not exactly.
It's the other way around.
I'd like to make a withdrawal.
Withdrawal?
Oh, I suppose you mean you
want a loan of some money.
Is that it?
Yes, sir.
That's just what I want to do.
Open and above board.
I'll give you my note.
Your note?
I could light cigars all day on
notes people want to give me.
How much money do
you expect to borrow?
$500.
500... that's all you want, eh?
You got any collateral?
Nope, I ain't got any.
Just my word, and it's good.
I never broke it.
Is that so?
Well, I'll have to
confront my cashier
on this business matter.
Arthur?
Yes, Mr. [INAUDIBLE]
The gentleman here wants to
borrow $500 just on his word...
no collateral... you think
we ought to give it to him?
Well, do I get it?
Mister, where do you come
from, and what's your name?
I come from the Pecos country,
and my name's the El Paso Kid.
Oh!
The El Paso Kid!
There's no need for ducking
in that [INAUDIBLE], Mister.
This is a business call.
Yes, Mr. Kid, yes.
$500 is all you want, Mr. Kid?
That'll do.
Arthur, give the gentleman $500.
Fine, fine, I'll give you my note.
Yes, yes that'll be all we need.
This bank feels very
friendly to you, sir,
and I hope that you'll feel
friendly to the bank, Mr.
Heath.
I sure do.
Hurry up.
Well, there you are... my note.
Deal is forward, all
legitimate, and above board.
Anything else?
Just one thing more.
I don't work around
here, and I want
you to keep this
transaction secret.
Is that agreed?
It's agreed.
I won't tell anybody, Mr. Kid.
Well, I've got a lot of
riding to do before sundown,
so I'll get along.
I'll see you in 90
days, if not sooner.
Ah, Arthur.
Get the sheriff.
That was the El Paso Kid.
Get somebody after him, you idiot!
Get somebody after him!
SONG: He's plan on
Sunday... he must
pray the whole day through.
But there's always
trains on Monday,
and the banks are open too.
With his good wife and
his kids around to play,
he thinks fondly of
the Monday, and the job
that he's planned that day.
And the next day,
and the next day...
he's dreaming fondly
on Sunday of the job
that he's planned next day.
I spoke to Miss
[INAUDIBLE]... real neighborly.
And they like us too, Toby.
That's a good name we've
got this time, Zee... Heath.
And we're going to keep it good.
Promise me, Toby.
Promise me you'll
never let it get bad.
Well, I'd hate to have
to change our name again.
It's so hard on the children.
They keep losing
track of who we are.
Now don't you fret, Zee.
That's going to be my
son's business someday.
And we're going to stay
right here in this town.
Pardon me.
Mr. Heath?
Why, yes sir?
I couldn't make it
into town yesterday,
and I'm running
pretty short on feed.
I wonder if you'd mind opening
the store to help me out.
Mighty sorry, but
I can't do business
of any kind of business
on the Sabbath.
But here's the key just help
yourself to what you need.
Put the key under the mat there.
Well, that's very generous of you,
but leaving the key under the mat?
Neighbor, I've been in
this town for months.
These people are my friends.
Besides, who'd want to rob me.
You know, Zee, it was
sort of nice to walk
into a bank just
like any other man.
Quiet, not a hand up.
I kind of enjoyed it.
The more honest
your living becomes,
the more enjoyment you're
going to get out of it.
You're right, Zee, and
I'm going to keep it
that way as long
as I possibly can.
Toby, don't you mean forever?
Well, naturally I mean
forever... God willing
and business improves.
Well, good day Brother
Williams, Sister Williams.
Good day.
[INAUDIBLE]
Billy.
Hello, Billy.
Howdy, John.
Howdy.
Jad.
Kid!
Seeing you again was
worth the long ride
and the chance I took coming here.
You sure look good, Kid.
Thanks, Jad.
You too, ma'am.
Thanks.
This is Jim Walsh,
got in just after me.
Howdy, Jim.
Howdy.
Sure glad to see you.
I thought you'd ride into night.
Ma, this is Jim Walsh.
Jim can bunk with Jad.
Howdy, ma'am.
How are you?
Boys, glad to see you.
Jim... Jim's one of
my old friends, Ma.
Yes, the minute I saw
him I was sure of that.
Can I speak to you
for a moment, please?
I have company, Ma.
Hold it for a little while.
I can't hold it for
another minute, Mr. Heath.
It's got to be right now.
Pardon me, boys.
When she calls me by
one of my adopted names
she's upset about something.
Now, Zee...
What are they doing here,
Toby... those awful men?
Why the decent one
of the whole bunch
is poor Billy Taylor, and if he
stays around them much longer
he'll be just as bad as they are.
You're right, Zee.
I tell you what.
I'll send him away the
first chance I get.
I don't want him on my conscience.
You're going to ride
out again, aren't you?
Aren't you?
Please, Zee.
I was going to tell
you about that later.
But you promised me Toby.
We was going to keep the name
of Heath so sweet-smelling.
That's what I'm doing it for.
They hay and feed
business is all right,
but the money I got left
isn't enough to keep me going.
I only got enough
to pay off the bank.
And I got to have more and have it
quick, or the place will
be sold out from under me.
Then let it be sold out.
What about the people who
sold me my merchandise?
I gave them my word
I'd pay 'em back.
And I'm going to if it's
the last thing I do.
But you gave me your word too.
Yeah, I know.
It's a sin to steal from one party
to pay back another party.
And after all the nice
friends we've made here.
And our children's friends.
Well, we'd just have to move on.
I'd rather move on than
to see you start in again.
This is the last time.
I promise.
When do we start?
Tomorrow morning at 5 o'clock.
Here's the route.
Here's where we're
aiming for, and here's
where we'll be... the lake,
west shore trail, right there.
Is it clear?
Mm-hmm.
It's a big job, boys.
We'll be shipping a lot
of money, back east.
That's all right, but I was
hoping it was an express office
in a fair-sized town...
a stagecoach, you see.
Why Jim it's getting so a fellow
can't walk down the streets of
a town with a few pistols on him
without attracting attention.
Is that right?
Sure is terrible what eastern
civilization is doing to man.
Yeah.
[GUNSHOTS]
Drop that gun.
Pull over there.
Hands up.
Hurry up.
Ain't nothing here.
I looked it over
from top to bottom.
Nobody would dare
give me a bad steal.
They must have
switched the shipping.
Come on, let's pull out of here.
We'll split up and
meet at my place.
Billy, you had better turn back.
Turn back?
Yeah, I don't want you
on my conscience no more.
You mean you don't want me
around you no more at all?
That's it.
You'd better get.
Goodbye, Billy.
But I ain't done nothing.
There's no reason for
you to treat me that way.
You got a girl?
No.
You had a girl once, didn't you?
I did once, a long time ago.
She was decent, wasn't she?
I don't know.
I didn't ask her.
Sure she was.
Now you go find her and marry her.
Have her cook your meals and
wash your clothes and bang
some sense into your
bones and keep you home.
I couldn't sleep in bed at
nights wonder where you was
and what load you took.
I'd get up and leave every...
Listen, you.
You get married and settle
down into family life,
or I'll knock you cold.
Now get going.
Hello?
Anybody home?
Howdy. [INAUDIBLE] Who are you?
What you doing?
Howdy, ma'am.
Good afternoon.
I knocked at the door...
What you want?
Just a little hospitality,
ma'am... a bite of supper.
A hunk of corn pone
and a cup of tea,
and a bit of hog
meat, if you got it,
sure would be a kind favor.
I've been riding a long way.
Get out!
The hunk of pone and the
bite of hog meat I got
is going to last me forever.
I'll [INAUDIBLE] slow and alone.
I'll pay, ma'am.
I'm liberal.
What you doing around here?
Just on my way to
meet some friends.
We're going to catch a
stage in the morning.
I've got nothing for you.
And I'm sick of men a-passing by,
and a-dropping in
and a-sitting 'round.
Now don't be scared of me, ma'am.
I don't aim to harm you.
I ain't never forgot
that mother's a woman.
A bite of hog meat a piece
of corn pone washed down
with a cup of tea would be
an act of charity, ma'am.
Well, welcome.
Sit.
Now, that's kind ma'am.
Say, I'll bet you're a baptist.
I am.
[INAUDIBLE]
Shake, sister.
Don't be nervous, ma'am.
I'm a family man, myself.
What might your name be?
Might be Jackson.
What's that for?
You ain't a-gonna give
me a great bit greenback
just for one meal of vittles?
Hold on!
Sure am.
Oh, take it.
It's too much.
Eat and welcome.
You take it, sister.
There's plenty more
where that come from.
No, I can't.
[INAUDIBLE] Forget it.
Thank you.
I hate to take it, but I ain't
got one cent to my name...
not one.
I'll get some water.
Let me.
[HORSE HOOVES]
Oh, howdy, Kid.
Well, I'll be.
Didn't I send you back, Billy?
Yeah.
I just wanted to say the trail's
bad going down... washouts.
Gotta be careful in the dark.
Another fellow just come up.
What, another one?
Widow Weeks, this
is Billy Taylor... a
Baptist in good standing.
And he's just going home.
Sure.
I'll be dagburned.
A gold watch.
Must have cost a heap of money.
I don't know just
what it did cost.
I got this watch off
a leading citizen.
Must have thought a lot of
you to give you all that.
If he didn't then, he's
thought a lot about me since.
You'll have to excuse me for
being so rough with you when
you come in, but I'm a
lone widow woman, and...
You must've had a good
man, you're mourning him so.
No.
He was the meanest,
despiting-est man
in the panhandle.
My pappy traded me
in marriage to him
for a mule when I was 14,
and from the wedding day
he just oozed cursedness.
Drunk up the corn and
wailed the young 'uns,
and you couldn't get
a clean set of drawers
onto his lazy bones...
not even of a Sunday.
How long you married to him?
Nine years?
How man young 'uns you got?
Nine.
He sure was a tough man.
Yeah Before he died, he
took this whole [INAUDIBLE]
and cabin down on
a piece of paper.
Some devil around here
showed him how to do it.
He got money for that piece
of paper and drunk it all up.
Now I can't pay back what he got.
Billy, I'm glad
you're here after all.
I should help her, but I can't.
Don't let her get
another cent out of me.
Sit, brother.
I'm sorry for your misery, ma'am.
Help yourselves.
We're waiting for you ma'am.
I ain't hungry.
You all eat.
Sugar's in the gourd.
What's the matter, ma'am?
Fella's coming
tomorrow to put me out.
I'm moving down the trail
without no place to move to.
I hate whining, but I'm lost.
That's terrible.
Don't you be so kind, Billy.
And don't you let me.
All I got left I owe to the bank.
Now come on, ma'am.
Set in.
Have some tea.
It's good for sorrow and grief.
Tea's my only comfort since
my young 'uns got took away.
Who took 'em?
His folks... said I couldn't
raise them all alone.
That's hard.
No schools around there.
No schools?
Ain't a Baptist
church within 50 miles.
No church You've
got to get them back.
Hold on, Kid.
Mind your own business.
You've got to get them back.
How much do you owe anyway?
All my money there
is, I reckon... $200.
$200?
You see this?
It's a receipt.
Now don't you let nobody
get it out of your hands,
because it'll be all you got.
You make that fellow that's
coming sign his name on it
before you pay him.
Say what?
You got any neighbors?
Old Man Gouty around the bend?
Men in his family?
Eight of them.
Well, get them all
in for witnesses.
You can't be too
careful in business.
What's the day of
the month, Billy?
Danged if I know.
I lost track.
I know the year.
Well that buckaroo that's
coming for the money
can write it down.
What money?
-Yeah, what money?
I'm warning you.
Hold on, Kid.
I'm paying you're debt ma'am.
You're paying my...
how can I give it back?
You can't.
Now, don't you part with
this here until that buckaroo
signs that there.
Saints and Lord above us.
All the heavens above us.
Everything above us.
(SOBBING)
Me too.
I got a roof over my head.
I got a farm.
I got my young 'uns back.
The nine of them.
(SINGING) My darling, my darling,
I dreamed a dream
that's coming true...
just how to spend my life
with you, only with you.
Old moon is a [INAUDIBLE]
and old gal Nature's in tune.
And no one to spy us in
case we two want to spoon.
My darling, my darling, I'll
always love you like I do.
Just two be loved right
back by you, just you.
(SINGING)
Billy, I wouldn't be surprised
if that stranger coming down
the trail ain't
the buckaroo that's
calling on the Widow
Weeks for his money.
Yeah, I reckon it is.
I'm going to rest right
here in the bushes.
What for?
The Good Book says, relieve the
weary traveler of his burden.
Huh?
I'm going to relieve him.
(SINGING)
Well, then did you
take possession?
I did not take
possession, Mr. Hickey.
Why not?
For the pure and
simple reason that
the Widow Weeks paid up in full.
What?
$200?
Impossible.
Maybe so, but she had it.
She did, eh?
Well, let's see it.
Hand it over.
Mr. Hickey, you'd
better sit down
and get a fresh
light on that cigar.
What are you driving at, Sam?
Well, I'll tell you.
I was held up.
That's what.
Now don't joke with me, Sam.
I don't like jokes about money.
This ain't no joke, Mr. Hickey.
I was sure held up.
And I don't like it either.
You don't like it?
How do you think I like it.
I had that Widow Week's place
as good as sold... paper's drawn.
The bank would have
made all of $20.
Instead...
Instead I nearly
got shot in the back.
Well, that's part of your job.
What, getting shot?
You swore in, didn't you?
Yes, and I'm going to swear out.
Well I'll tell you
one thing, this bank
ain't going to take no loss.
No sir.
Well, my family ain't going
to take the loss neither.
Where did she get that money?
All I know is what she said.
She got it off a passing Baptist?
What?
I've been president of
this bank for 30 years,
and I ain't never seen a
man pay that much money
for just passing a widow.
That fellow that held me up... he
must have known what I had on me.
What did he look like?
I don't know.
He was behind me.
Couldn't you have
sneaked a quick look?
He asked me not to.
What'd his voice sound like?
It was right soft and friendly.
Friendly?
And another thing.
He must have put the widow up
to making me sign that receipt.
That's all she kept saying... sign
that receipt, sign that receipt.
Any witnesses to the signing?
Yep.
Eight.
Eight?
Sam, I'm not so sure
that you was held up.
I'm not so sure but what you
was drinking when [INAUDIBLE]
How much further?
Oh, I calculate about 10 miles.
10 miles from where?
I told you Jad, that bank
where I borrowed the money.
Ain't going back to any town
for a while, are you Kid?
I got to, Jad.
I got to pay off my note.
You're out of your head.
Ol' [INAUDIBLE] will
be looking for you.
Pay him back some other time.
Banks has got more money
than they deserve anyway.
It ain't the money, Jad.
It's my word.
Giving back money to a bank.
And with interest.
Where's the collector?
Sam, there's a lady
here to see you.
A lady?
It's the widow.
Oh, it is, then?
Arthur, ask the lady
to step into my office.
Yes, Mr. Hickey.
Now, you sit down and shut up.
I'll get the truth out of her.
I know how to handle
these women... scare 'em.
Scare 'em stiff.
Good day, ma'am.
It's a great pleasure.
How are you feeling today?
I'm president Hickey,
here to help the ladies,
but they call me Pop.
Oh, yes, won't you sit down?
Allow me.
Now, let me help you
straighten things out.
I'm just here to get my recipe.
Then I'm going.
Yes, yes, certainly.
But before I can give you back
to the deed, or recipe as you
call it, I'd like to
ask you a few questions.
Sam here says he received
a sum of money from you.
Payment in full, I says.
He sure did.
Yes, but unfortunately on
the way back, he was held up
and lost it.
He was?
Well, I thought the
roads was safe, now.
It's been suggested to me
that the uh... the gentleman
who gave you this money
may have taken it back.
No, sir.
He weren't that kind.
He was a good-living Baptist.
I see.
Of course, if he did,
the transaction it void.
Is what?
Void.
What's that mean?
That you haven't paid a cent.
You mean to tell me that I
didn't give that welp no money?
I mean to say that
we'll have to investigate
whether you did or not.
Now if you'll let
me see Sam signed...
The stranger what
give me the money
say to hold onto that
recipe 'til the day I died.
He say he don't trust no banks.
And I reckon now he was right.
Oh, now surely.
You give me what I
come down here for.
I don't want no
more truck with you.
Now please let me see
that receipt... err recipe.
No.
He put his name to it,
and I'm a-keeping it.
Get it off her Sam,
you've got the right.
Well, I ain't so sure.
It depends on why she's got it.
I ain't lived alone and
helpless for nothing,
and any man aiming to take
my clothes of for a recipe
better not try it in a bank.
Hello.
Mr. Kid.
Put your hands down, brother.
I'm here on business.
That [INAUDIBLE] was real
fond of you in this bank.
They are?
Is Mr. Hickey the president in?
Yes, sir, inside.
You two wait here.
Just keep a friendly
eye on the door.
Anyone comes in, see that they
stay in until I transaction
my business.
Well, hello, hello.
How are you since I saw you last?
This is a friendly call.
Put your hands down.
Well, my note's due
today, ain't it?
Well, howdy.
I dropped in to see about it.
I don't want you to get the
wrong impression of the El
Paso Kid in this
bank, Mr. Hickey.
It's treated me fair.
El Paso Kid?
Well, excuse me, ma'am for
addressing a perfect stranger,
but you here on business too?
Reckon I am.
Then I feel very [INAUDIBLE].
Let me make it brief.
Kid?
Hello.
Man wants to come in.
Let him in.
Who the...
I reckon.
Is he in?
Yeah.
Don't let him out.
If you've got business, ma'am...
I paid this buckaroo.
He's a deputy.
Just a minute.
Pass me your arms
in a sociable way.
I'm not asking you for
your gun, Mr. Hickey.
We're friends.
Besides I can always tell a weapon
under a Prince Albert coat.
You were saying, ma'am?
I give him all my
money, and now he
says I didn't pay a cent.
I did not.
She paid me $200,
and I'll swear to it.
Anyway, they want to take my
clothes off to find the recipe.
No, no, no, no no,
she misunderstood.
I never...
Women don't understand
business, Mr. Hickey.
My wife don't always
understand mine.
We're here to protect
widows, ain't we, Mr. Hickey?
Certainly sir, certainly.
-After all, Mr.
Hickey, widows are
the backbone of this nation.
I think so, yes.
Then give her her
satisfaction piece,
and make it legal this time.
Unless you want me
to drop by later.
I can.
No.no, no, no...
that's not necessary.
Not at all necessary.
Kid?
Hello.
Two men coming in.
See if they're rich.
Yup, they are.
Then tell Jad to give them
some of those cigars we have,
so they can look back up
on [INAUDIBLE] street.
Sure, Kid.
Can I have some of
those cigars, Jad?
They're in my breast pocket.
This looks legal, all right.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Sure was a streak
of luck I met you.
I don't care who you be.
That's all right, ma'am.
Excuse me.
Well, Hickey it's
business between us,
ain't it... you and me.
Here you are... $500 on my
note and $4.17 interest.
Oh, thank you Mr. Kid.
Count it.
No, I take your word for it.
That's pleasant to
here, but my word's good.
I keep it when I give it.
Count it.
One, two, three,
four, five, and $4.17.
Correct.
My note?
Oh, yes, the note, yes.
I put that note, I think, in
this drawer somewhere or other.
Yes, and there it is.
There's your note.
Thank you.
Is that all?
I hope... I mean, I
think that's all, yes.
We're closed.
Closed.
We're square?
We're square.
That's good.
You know, Mr. Hickey,
folks don't understand me.
I always wanted to
trade with one bank
where I was welcome... come
and go like any other man.
I appreciate the favor.
I reckon we know each
other now, and we'll
go as peaceful as we come.
Say, I've had real pleasure
in our transaction,
and I want to count
you as a friend.
Thank you, Mr. Kid.
Just call me Kid.
You know, I never was so
surprised in my life, uh... Kid.
I said I would, didn't I?
Yes, but the bank didn't
understand it that way.
- You mean you didn't believe me?
- No.
I...
You didn't trust me?
I mean...
You don't mean you
thought it was a holdup?
Well, I suppose you must have seen
what the papers said about it.
No, I haven't read
the papers, I've
been away tending business.
I'm hard-up, Mr. Hickey.
But when I came
here today with a...
Hey, Kid, you out soon?
Yeah.
With a friendly feeling
to pay what I owed.
I regret the misunderstanding,
and I thank you.
I thought I signed my name and got
your promise it was
a secret transaction.
When I rode in before, all alone,
a private citizen, if you'd have
refused me, I'd a walked out.
I would, because I
didn't want any trouble.
I only asked you for a loan.
You lent me the money.
I understand now.
I understand.
No, you don't.
What you don't
understand is that I'm
at the head of my business, just
as you're at the top of yours.
And I take it as a personal insult
that the boys all over the country
have read about our deal.
But you acted like an honest man.
That's just it, and what
do they think of me now?
That I'm losing my grip?
When it comes to letting
people believe I'd stoop to rob
a bank, and for $500, and
never touched the safe,
never cracked the plum?
Me?
Well, a man's got his pride.
Now, Mr. Hickey, you
know your business,
but you don't know mine.
And I'm going to show
you the difference
between borrowing and a holdup.
Oh.
Raise your hands.
Move.
Outside.
Sit down.
Jad, I'm going to crack the
safe myself, personally.
This is the darndest,
friendliest visit I ever paid.
I'm going to vindicate
my honor aplenty.
Hello, ma'am, I forgot about you.
Billy, [INAUDIBLE] one lady out.
Thank you.
God bless you.
Billy, get me a couple sticks of
dynamite out of my saddlebags.
Sheriff, I think they're
holding up the bank!
Get your horse!
Get out of here.
I'll try and get them off.
Split up, fellas.
Well, he didn't make it, Billy.
He ain't never going to make it.
Don't say that, Jad.
They'll never take the Kid.
You know they can't.
That was the Kid's way,
Billy... looking after us.
Somebody better Zee.
Come on.
Well, Jim when did you get back?
[INAUDIBLE] How'd you
two get here alive?
What?
Ain't you seen the papers?
Infamous desperado
pursued by heroic citizens
after bold bank
robbery three days ago.
In desperate flight.
Trapped in the woods.
Escape impossible.
Surrounded.
Now, if you hadn't sent me
home, I'd be with him now.
Reward for the Kid mounting.
Where's his missus?
-Don't know.
No one here...
What did you let him go
back to that bank for?
Let him?
You couldn't have stopped him.
I never heard of such a thing...
borrowing money from a bank.
Pure crazy.
[KNOCKING]
Boys, I reckon they got the Kid.
An extra just come out.
They never took the
Kid alive, never.
He was born in El Paso
county and he'll die there.
He said so.
No, they never took him alive.
Going out to the
stable for awhile.
Don't want anyone with me.
Poor Jad.
They were closer than brothers.
They got the kid.
Sure they get him low.
Ain't one paper had
a good word for him.
Yeah, with all that
money on his head,
somebody would sure
turn him in anyway.
Say, you...
By jingo, there's a happy
show... all that money,
dead or alive.
Lucky cousin.
Stop it.
What's the matter with you?
Will you...
You rouse the neighbors?
Are you crazy?
No, I ain't.
He is.
I'm just telling the truth.
That's all.
What's that?
Did you hear something overhead.
A [INAUDIBLE] or something.
The state's full of 'em.
Kid?
[INAUDIBLE] Can't a man
sleep in his own house?
Kid?
Where'd you come from?
We thought you was
trapped in the woods.
The newspapers said...
You're alive.
How the devil did you get here?
On a Pullman train, Jim.
Pullman?
Didn't no one see you
on the Pullman, Kid?
None of it was dangerous.
I just rode along natural
like everybody else.
Nobody knows what a look like.
Ain't no photographs
of my laying around.
I tell you...
- You hungry, Kid?
- Oh, no.
I ate on the train.
I tell you it's a lesson to a man.
A lesson what I've
been through... never
get your picture took.
That's right.
Where's Jad?
In the barn, I'll get him.
Well, boys, what's the news?
You're the news, Kid.
Well, here you are, anyway.
Yep, I'm home.
There's no place like it.
Boys, it's on me.
The stagecoach job is on me.
I sure come back loaded.
That bank... what a haul.
What a bump.
I'm splitting with all you boys.
Oh, no Kid, no.
You're going to take it.
Oh yeah, say what
was the row about.
Sure woke me up out
of a sound sleep.
Nothing, Kid.
Weren't nothing.
Just over the reward for
you Kid, dead or alive.
Charlie here thinks
that one of the boys
would sure turn you
in for all that money.
No, no, he didn't mean it.
No, no I didn't mean nothing.
Sure.
He didn't mean nothing.
He's young.
He just talks.
Sure He's young.
What is it?
What do you want?
I'm US Marshal Gregg.
May I come in?
Well, I...
I want to see your husband, ma'am.
Oh?
You're Mrs. Heath, aren't you?
Yes.
My husband went out, I think.
I'll see.
You wait here.
Just a minute, ma'am.
In case he's out, I could
tell you what I want.
I... perhaps I'd better not.
You can tell me.
Well, I'm organizing
a posse, and I...
I oughtn't to have told you.
I'm sorry ma'am... mighty sorry.
Ma, I changed my
mind about going out.
Well, I didn't know
there was anyone here.
This Mr. Heath?
Yeah.
I'm US Marshal Gregg from Dallas.
You're the fellow I'm after.
How's that?
I've been making a few
inquiries around here.
Yeah?
And finally I asked
minister nearby
for the best citizens
in his congregation.
Your name headed the list.
Thank you, Marshall.
Sorry I can't ask you
to come into the parlor.
But it's Wednesday night.
Mrs. Heath's sewing
circle is in there.
Oh, that's all right.
I can't stay anyway.
Mr. Heath, we're
getting up a posse
to patrol the roads from
here to the state line.
And I deputize you.
What for?
To help round up the El
Paso Kid and his gang.
I see.
You've got good horses, I hear.
Well, yes, I use
them in my business.
I deal in grain.
I travel a lot.
But I read in the paper
you took the El Paso Kid.
Killed him, in fact.
No, the varmint got away again.
But we'll get him this time.
We're going to close every
blasted road in the state.
The watchword is bring
in the El Paso Kid.
Keep it to yourself.
You can depend on me.
Good.
There's just one thing
about working with you.
I can't let my
business go entirely.
I'm a family man.
That's understood.
You see, I right around
looking up future prospects.
So while you close
the road to the Kid,
can't you give me an
identification card
so I can get through and
get my business over quick.
A pass you mean?
Yes.
Well, certainly.
What are your
initials, Mr. Heath?
T. E.
All right, this'll do it.
I'll let you know
where the posse's
meeting as soon as we organize it.
Thanks, Marshal.
You do that.
There ain't no place I'd
feel safer than right
in the middle of your posse.
Goodnight, Mr. Heath.
Goodnight, Marshal.
Goodnight, Mrs. Heath I'm sorry
I interrupted your sewing bee.
Goodnight.
Toby, sometimes I think you're
in league with the devil.
Oh, Ma, I'm in
league with the law.
Aw, Kid there was
the likes of you.
What a song this'll make.
Keep me out of your songs.
All the roads is closed,
and we ain't got a pass.
That's so.
Better all start riding
before they get organized.
Good luck, Kid.
So long, Jim.
So long, Toby.
Take good care of yourself.
Jad.
Bye, Kid.
So long, boys.
Good luck to you.
Go on, Billy.
Get back to the Pecos.
No, Kid, you need someone.
Didn't I tell you?
And no fooling this time.
Please, Ma.
Give me another chance.
I'll sell the business
first thing in the morning.
And we'll go to California.
We've never been there.
We'll have a real church wedding.
And I'll start all over again.
That's what I'm afraid of...
you'll start all over again.
I'll be up late packing, so
you better sleep in the parlor.
Goodbye, Toby,
(SINGING)El Paso Kid rode
in through town to get
him a loan from the banker man.
In his name he wrote
on a promise note,
left with a roll in
his hand, in his hand.
Yes, he left with
a roll in his hand.
He didn't steal it.
He loaned it.
But when he heard they broke
their word, when he learned
them bankers didn't do
right, the Kid was awful mad.
He cracked that safe
dynamite, and he
shut that bank up tight, up tight.
Yes he closed that bank up tight.
He walked out with some
real money that time.
A Marshal came,
knew Heath by name,
not knowing exactly
the work he did.
The kid was calling
himself Heath at that time.
He swore Heath into
a posse gang to chase
himself, the Kid himself,
to chase himself the Kid.
It's a Good joke on the Marshal.
Oh he chased the
Kid, all that night,
while the Marshal's
posse was in flight.
And he squared up his horse
and he changed his course,
and he left that
posse out of sight.
Yes, he left them out of sight.
And he squared up his horse,
and he changed his course,
and he left that
posse out of sight.
So he chased himself all night.
What, again?
What do I have to do to get
rid of you... plow you under?
I started to leave,
Kid, but the barn
was as far as I could get.
Well, at least
you're loyal, Billy.
Here, I'm giving you a stake.
Take care of it.
No, I ain't no tick bird.
You take it and bury
in a clean tin can
in an unplowed field
like we done before.
Don't put it in no bank.
I might come along.
Save it for a rainy day
when I ain't around no more.
No, I can't take it.
Honest, Toby.
I got a feeling that
as soon as I'm gone
you're going to make for
home and the Widow Weeks.
Well, do it.
Kid... that fellow that
come to see you last night...
that US Marshal... I
saw him in the town
square a little while ago.
Well?
He was sitting up on a
high [INAUDIBLE] horse...
a calico horse, she was... in front
of the courthouse
a-shouting, fellow citizens!
I never saw so many horses
in all my life... sorrels
and blacks were filling
the road in the square
and spilling over
into front yards.
Fellas sitting on them
with ropes yelling,
we'll get him this time.
We'll string him up and
leave him a-dangling.
Billy, you can go
down there and bat them
all that money I gave you.
They won't.
Howdy, gentlemen.
Howdy.
Who are your?
T.E. Heath, Marshal's deputy.
Put up your hands.
Just reaching for my pass.
I'll reach for it.
T. E. Heath, deputy.
Signed by the Marshal.
That's right.
Let him by.
Good evening, Mr. Heath.
Good evening, Marshal.
Going to join us?
No, just out on a little business.
Maybe you better
join us, Mr. Heath.
Put up your hands, kid.
You sure made a fool
out of me last night.
I sure did.
Cinch him tight, Enis.
Mind telling me
who gets the reward.
A good friend of yours.
At least he says he is.
He's young.
It don't mean nothing.
MARSHAL: Let's get moving.
We heading for a courthouse,
Marshal, or a tree?
We're not all outlaws
in the state of Texas.
You'll get a fair trial.
Now let's get moving.
I found out all about it, Zee.
You can visit me once a month.
Why, in 120 visits the
sentence will be up.
10 years.
Yeah, and that skunk Charlie
Jackson gets off scot-free,
and $10,000 for turning you in.
Jad came to see me, Kid.
Says not to worry.
He's got a plan.
You tell Jad to stay where he is.
He's not getting mixed
up with me no more.
I'm glad it happened
this way, Billy.
It's a load off of my mind.
When I get through paying my leg...
Toby.
Thanks, Zee, for being
my wife all through this.
I'm proud of you, Toby.
And I'm going to teach your
children to be proud of you.
Goodbye, Zee.
When you come up to visit
me, cook me some corn pone
and hog meat the way you make it.
What's that?
Oh, just a hold up, I reckon.
Hold up?
Take the key out
of my breast pocket
and unlock these handcuffs.
Make one move that I don't like,
and I'll blow your [INAUDIBLE].
[INAUDIBLE]
Look out for yourself, mister.
They're a bad run of boys.
I know them all.
What are you doing?
Don't worry, mister.
I'm coming right back.
Mighty messy job, so far.
It's the Kid.
Sure is.
Well, boys.
Charlie, you sure
picked the wrong train.
Drop your guns.
Drop them!
Men, go fetch Charlie.
And put those boxes right
back where you got them from.
You crazy, Kid?
There's over $100,000 worth
of gold in those boxes.
KID: All right, folks,
get back to your seats.
Excitement's over for today.
There, that should hold me 'til
we get to the state capital.
How's your shoulder, Marshal?
All right, Kid.
Good.
Texas is sure mighty
pretty country, ain't it?
Sure is, Kid.
I was raised in these parts.
[SHOUTING]
What's going on?
They must have learned
that you was ahead.
Looks like you're a hero, Kid.
I'm from The Chronicle.
Tell us how you did it, Kid.
Well, to tell you
the truth, it wasn't
much different than
holding up a train.
[CHEERS]
Thanks, folks.
Thanks for coming to meet me.
And I want you all
to know I'm mighty
glad I was born in Texas.
[CHEERS]
And to be faithful unto her,
so long as you both shall live?
I do.
Do you promise
love, honor, cherish,
and obey him in joy and
sorry, in health and sickness,
in prosperity and adversity,
and to be faithful
unto him as becometh a good wife
so long as you both shall live?
I do.
In the name of God, the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Ghost,
I pronounce you husband and wife.
Amen.
Wow, they made it!
I sure didn't think
they ever would.
You're in church, you darned fool.
[MUSIC PLAYING]