Oh Tanya, thank you.
Have a nice summer, honey.
Bye, darling.
_ Hey-
This is for you traveler.
Oh, thank you.
What is it?
Oh, you shouldn't have.
- Well I thought this
would be just the thing
to take to the boonies.
You're probably right.
- Why are you going
to a hick town
where you don't know
a soul for anyhow?
Oh, I don't know.
To be alone for a little while.
- Do you really think this
is the right time to go?
I mean are you
feeling strong enough?
I feel fine, Lois, really.
Fine.
Yeah, but your mom just died
and it's only been a few
months since your divorce.
You know what?
You sound a lot like my shrink.
He doesn't give me
any support either.
- Well, George and I
would love to have you
come to the beach.
A lot of great guys out there.
Let's give me a break.
That's not what
I need right now.
Well, no harm in trying.
Oh, I appreciate the offer
but I think I'd really
like to spend the summer
in the old family house.
- Alright, I don't
want to be a pain.
But if you get lonely
or shakey or anything,
you give me a call, okay?
I promise.
I'm going to leave
tomorrow afternoon
and as soon as I get the
phone in, I'll call you.
_ okay-
Oh, I'm going to miss you.
Me too.
- Why are
you so against this?
I'm taking a vacation
in the country.
The air is fresh.
The people are friendly
and no one knows anything
about this last year.
- What will you do
if they find out?
- I'll just tell them
the truth, flat out.
Jane Hardy was on the edge.
And she came back.
Now what's so
terrible about that?
All I know is that I
don't like the pain.
And I want to get away from it.
And away from here.
- Well symbols of
the pain will be here
when you get back, won't they?
I don't know that.
I haven't yet given
myself a chance
to get away from
them to find out.
What if it doesn't work out?
I'll try something else.
Hello, Mr. Pritchard?
Thank goodness.
This is Jane Hardy.
I wrote you about
my aunt's house?
I know it's late.
But you could please come
down here and give me the keys
so I can get into the house?
Well, I'm a little tired
too, Mr. Pritchard.
I've had an awfully long drive.
I'm at the Ramona Court...
Uh, will it take you very long
to get here, Mr. Pritchard?
No, no, no, no one's
trying to rush you.
Okay, okay.
I'll just be waiting for you.
I'm in a red Chevrolet.
Good...bye.
Jane Hardy?
Yes.
I'm Walter Pritchard.
Follow me.
- I really appreciate
you getting up
and letting me in.
Well, you should.
11 o'clock at night, decent
people ought to be in bed.
Come on.
Well, what the hell's
the matter now?
I don't know.
Just a chill.
There.
Oh what the hell,
I told those...
Ha, just as I promised you.
Exactly the way it was
when your aunt died
30 some odd years ago.
Your mother hardly
ever set foot in here.
It really ought to be mine.
What do you mean?
- Well your mother
promised it to me.
Probate, legal fees, and a swift
for generally looking
after the old place
for thirty some odd years.
Well I never heard that.
- Well, you probably
wouldn't admit it if you had.
Here are the keys.
You'll have to drop into
my office in a couple days
and sign some papers.
That is if you
decide to stay here.
Personally, I think
you're crazy for wanting
to live in this old place.
I'll be by.
Yeah, for sure.
Goodnight, Mr. Pritchard.
And thanks a lot.
Huh...
Hey, lady-
You want a lift?
Not too bad.
Not too bad at all for the
first time in 10 months.
Oh!
Telephone company, lady.
Good, I'm glad to see you.
- Yeah, Mr. Pritchard,
he called yesterday.
Oh, come on in.
I'd have thought if
he called yesterday,
it would have taken
you months to get here.
Oh you don't happen to have
one of those pretty powder
blue princess models, no?
Okay, here you go.
Thank you.
Anything else?
- Yes, could you recommend
someone around here
who can help me
with some handiwork?
Fixing some windows,
patching a roof,
some things like that.
Well I don't know.
- Well how about
Bo Rehnquist, dad?
We don't know anybody.
- This Rehnquist
fellow, is he nearby?
- Yeah, about a
mile up the road.
He's got a big red house.
That's $27.54.
Cash.
You're kidding?
- I don't have
that much with me.
Could you send it out?
I'm right out on County Road.
Where?
The old Martin place.
I'm Jane Hardy.
My aunt Rebecca
used to live there.
We don't deliver that far.
It's just down the road.
Dad, I can do it tomorrow.
I got to down to the
Baker's house anyway.
My son will bring it out.
Just this once.
- Is everyone is Blackford
as friendly as you are?
We're busy, Miss Hardy.
Sure.
Hey, dad.
What was that all about?
It doesn't concern you.
Don't you have work to do?
Yeah, sure.
Need any he), m' am'?
No, thank you.
I can handle it myself.
- Yeah, I can see
that from here.
I'm Jack Demon.
I'm sheriff around here.
The old Martin place, right?
Yes, I'm Jane Hardy.
- Well Jane, welcome
to Blackford.
You plan on staying very long?
Well I'm not exactly sure yet.
Maybe for the summer.
- Oh, the rest of
the summer, huh?
That's nice.
Hey, I saw you jogging down
County Road this morning.
I'm not one to
forget a pretty face,
if you know what I mean.
- I think I know
exactly what you mean.
Good bye, sheriff.
Are you Mr. Rehnquist?
I'm Rehnquist, Bo Rehnquist.
- My house needs to have some
general repairs done to it.
And they told me down at
Gordon's hardware store
that you might be
interested in doing it.
Sounds okay so far.
You live by yourself in a house?
Yes.
Look, I live out on County Road.
The big old house off the road?
Would you start tomorrow?
- I don't know any big
old houses on County Road.
Yeah, it's the Martin place.
I'll be busy tomorrow.
What's wrong?
I... I'll be busy.
- But you did say that
you could do the job.
- Tomorrow, next
week... I'm too busy.
- As you are
washed in the blood
of the land, then you will
dwell in the house of the Lord.
Just waiting for the chance.
Yes the Lord...
Will carry you all the way
up to those pearly gates.
Nowhere is safe.
Nowhere you can
hide from the Devil.
Hey, you made it, didn't you?
- Yeah, I got the
stuff you ordered.
My dad told me to come
out here and collect.
In cash.
_ okay-
I'm Paul.
I'm Jane.
You're a lot friendlier
than your folks.
- Yeah, well they're
kind of weird.
- I think everyone
around here is weird.
- Did you get that
handyman you wanted?
Is the job still open?
Yeah, it's wide open.
That Rehnquist guy
didn't want it all.
He didn't want to
come out to the house.
I think he wanted me to
bring the house to him.
- Well, I'd kind of
like to come out here
and work.
Would you really?
Yeah, I can fix anything.
My dad says I'm a
natural born Mr. Fix-It.
Do you have experience?
- I didn't get these
from playing the piano.
You have callouses.
You're hired, Paul.
Alright, I'm so broke.
I can't tell you.
I'm really broke.
- Well you're not going
to get rich working here.
When you can start?
- I've got some stuff
to do this afternoon.
How about tomorrow?
Tomorrow's fine.
Start with putting some screens
on the upstairs windows.
Check out the roof.
And we'll make out
a list of things
that we need for
your dad to fill.
What's the matter?
- I don't think my dad is
going to be too thrilled
about me hanging out here.
Really?
Why?
Come on, Paul.
Don't you think I
have a right to know
why everyone around Blackford
treats me like I
have the plague?
Well...
You don't have to tell me now.
Not until the roof is finished.
You're still hired.
Alright.
0K3)'-
See you tomorrow.
- Paul, aren't you
forgetting something?
What?
The money.
He'd kill me.
I swear to god.
Bash my face in.
Rip out my hair.
- Mr. Pritchard, would you
just lay it on the line.
Is the house mine or not?
My dear Miss Hardy,
of course you own it.
I'm talking here of probate,
finalizing the will,
your taking possession.
All of these things take time.
- Why the hell are
you stalling me?
- Now don't you be
insolent with me.
- The finalized
papers, Mr. Pritchard.
When will they be ready?
- They will be ready
when I get them.
This is not a big city you know.
In a few days, I suppose.
Fine.
- Oh, Miss Hardy, have you
met our sheriff, Jack Denton?
Yes, we've already met.
Well not really.
Just in passing.
You know, Miss Hardy,
on the way in I noticed
a fresh dent in
your fender there.
Have you been in an
accident recently?
You know you're
supposed to report
that sort of thing
to the police.
I backed into a tree.
Really, Miss Hardy?
Trees jumping from
behind every bush.
You never know what's
going to happen
around here these days.
I should have warned you.
You must be careful on all
these old back country roads.
- I'll see you in two
days, Mr. Pritchard.
You know, Jack.
I have a feeling that girl is
not very long for this town.
Yeah, Walter.
I know exactly what you mean.
Miss Hardy, please.
- Oh, you scared
the hell out of me.
- I should probably take
that as a compliment.
Flaughs)
I'm Reverend Winston.
I'm the minister at
the Blackford Church.
Forgive me, please.
Come in to the living room.
I heard you on the radio
the other day, didn't I?
Yes.
You know we tape those shows
right here at the church.
Would you like to
come by one Sunday?
- Reverend, I haven't been to
church since I was a child.
- Well, church is the
tallest building in town.
So if you ever need
anything, stop on by.
Welcome to Blackford, Jane.
Thank you.
- How do you like
our town so far?
Well,
the people are not
exactly friendly.
But then I'm told it's
because of this house.
Why all the standoffishness?
Perhaps it's your imagination.
And you're new.
An outsider.
- Well, they're just going
to have to get used to me,
aren't they?
- Maybe the country's not
the right place for you.
Got to be going, thanks.
A lovely woman.
You look a lot like her.
Thank you.
Goodnight, Jane.
Goodnight, reverend.
- Hope to see you
in church soon.
Perhaps.
Sunday, this is a wonderful day.
Louis and I have finally,
after two years, set
our wedding date.
October 3rd.
The following day Louis
will preach his first sermon
at the new church in Oak Blocks.
I'll miss Blackford
and this lovely house.
But Louis is a man any woman
would be proud to have.
And a minister's wife is called
upon to follow her husband.
Well, hello there.
What's your name?
Alice.
But my mommy told me
not to say hello to you.
- Now why would
she tell you that?
- Because you live
in the funny house.
I live in a funny house, do I?
What's so funny about my house?
- It's haunted and
you're a ghost.
Miss?
Are you alright?
Sullivan, Tom Sullivan.
- Are you
sure you didn't see
that big black car?
- No, but then I had
just turned onto County Road.
Oh, that light.
I'm positive I turned
it off before I left.
Would you mind walking
me to the door?
Certainly.
You really don't have to wait.
I want to.
- Make yourself comfortable
in the living room.
I'll go upstairs and
I'll be down in a minute.
It was nothing.
I guess the wiring's
just shot in this house.
That's a photograph of my aunt.
She was a beautiful woman.
You have her eyes.
Oh, do you think so?
Would you like
something to drink?
I have wine, tea, coffee.
No, thank you.
I've really got to go.
Well thank you for everything.
It's my pleasure.
I'll see to it that
your car gets back home.
Oh no, please don't bother.
I'll call a tow truck.
I insist.
Besides it'll give me an opportunity
to see you again, Jane.
- Alright, well I'm
certainly glad you showed up
when you did.
Good night.
September 19th.
A stranger came to
the house today.
His name is Robert.
He was very polite and
we sat on the porch
and talked for hours.
He was very handsome
and anyone could see
he was well bred.
I'm a little ashamed that
I let him hold my hand.
But there seemed no harm in it.
I'm powerless to stop it.
There's something strange
and wonderful about him.
He brought me a gift.
A beautiful locket with
an unusual symbol on it.
September 21st, can it be true?
After two days, I
write these words
with a mixture of fear and joy.
I'm in love with Robert.
I cannot help myself.
Today I gave myself
to him completely.
I'm alive at the
sound of his voice,
the touch of his hand.
He is the master of my body.
How can I tell Louis?
That I can never marry him because I
have met another man.
Get away from here.
Get out of here, I have a gun.
Tom, I didn't hear you come up.
Oh you brought my car.
Thank you.
You have company today?
Oh just a local boy.
I hired him to help
me around the house.
Would you like to come
in for a few minutes?
Thanks just the same.
But not now.
Jane, what's the matter?
- Somebody broke into
the house last night.
I don't know what it is
but there's something
strange going on
andljustcanT
put my finger on it.
- Nothing happened
to you, did it?
No, I'm fine.
It's just I'm a little scared.
Let's go out tonight, Jane.
Maybe you need to relax.
I'd love to get out.
Eight o'clock.
Good.
Should I dress?
- Whatever you
wear will be fine.
- Tom, do you want me
to give you a lift?
No.
It'll be no trouble at all.
I'll see you tonight.
Just a minute.
I'm coming.
Hello?
Hi.
Come in.
Oh, look at those.
I picked these at my place.
Tom, they're beautiful.
I'll just put them in this.
There we are.
That'll be the first thing
I see when I come in.
Well how nice.
Shall we?
Where are we going?
- I have a little
surprise for you.
0h?
- Why did you come
to Blackford, Jane?
- I wanted to try and find
some place where I could relax.
And when my mother died and
left me my aunt's old house,
I decided to come here.
I was married up until
a few months ago.
When my marriage ended,
I nearly cracked up.
It was something I never
believed could happen to me.
I was very sick for a while
but things are better now.
What about yourself?
Are you married?
No.
Do you live in Blackford?
Yes.
Tom look, over there.
What?
There's somebody following us.
Over there.
Did you see that light?
You'd better sit down.
It's probably kids.
That's County Road and a
notorious lover's lane.
I'm not so sure.
Seems every time we meet,
I'm afraid of something or I
think someone's following me.
Is someone after you?
I don't know.
Maybe I'm imagining things.
It's so quiet and peaceful here.
I wish I could just
stay here forever.
- The only thing that
lasts forever is true love.
Even after death.
That's beautiful, Tom.
Shouldn't we be getting
back to the real world soon?
I don't want my aunt to
see me coming in late.
I'm only kidding.
Thank you, Tom, for
a lovely evening.
Would you like to come
by tomorrow for lunch?
I'd love to.
Wonderful.
About one o'clock?
Yes.
I hope you'll stay here
with us for a while.
I just might do that.
See you tomorrow.
Goodnight, Tom.
I went into Blackford
today and told Louis
I could not marry him
because I love someone else.
He cursed me and accused me
of having been secretly in
love with Robert all along.
I didn't deny it.
I am obsessed.
Making love to Robert was at
once joyful and terrifying.
I have no control.
If Robert ever left
me, I would die.
How simple things were before
Robert came into my life.
I love him and fear
him at the same time.
I fear his power over me
and I know I will
do anything he asks.
I know now what
Robert wants from me.
He has admitted that he's
involved in something
I never suspected.
It's almost impossible
for me to believe.
But it is true.
He wants me to join him
in a pact with Satan.
What the hell do you want?
What do you want?
Get away from me.
Get away from here.
Now Lois, I'm sorry I
told you about this.
I don't want you to be upset.
It was definitely a dream.
Just a dream.
Took me hours to
calm myself down
but I'm okay now.
Listen, I met somebody.
Yeah, he's from around here.
His name is Tom.
Well, he's kind
of old-fashioned.
Very pleasant.
It's kind of strange.
I'm very drawn to him.
It's as though I've
known him all my life.
Well, now don't go overboard.
You'll be the first one
to know if that happens.
Alright.
Well I'm glad I reached you.
Alright I Will.
I'll talk to you in
the next couple days.
Take care.
Alright, bye bye.
- You're not getting
any action off her.
- Well I think I
got a lot farther
than you guys think.
Uh yeah?
You ain't got nowhere.
She kissed me.
Hi.
Hi Paul,
how are you today?
Oh yeah,
I got the stuff you wanted.
You know I'll get
the rest of the pipe
as soon as my dad
gets it fitted.
And then you know,
I'll bring it out
this afternoon.
Oh listen, about today Paul,
you don't have to
bother coming out.
I have a friend coming over
and well, quite frankly, I
had a rough time last night
and I'd just as soon catch up
on a little sleep
this afternoon.
What happened?
Someone break into your house?
Oh no, no.
I just haven't been
sleeping too well lately.
Tomorrow will be fine, okay?
Okay yeah, I'll see you then.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah, I'll see you tomorrow.
Take care.
Okay, 'We-
Bye_
Ooh, she is something else.
- Why Miss Hardy, what
a pleasant surprise.
You're a bit early
for Sunday but...
That woman.
Miss Percy?
Why she's our choir mistress.
Do you know her?
- I'm positive she was in
a dream I had last night.
She was right here
in the church.
- Indeed she was,
until around seven.
But I'm so sure.
- The mind can play
many tricks on us, Jane.
I feel something's
troubling you.
I'd like to help,
if you'll let me.
Thank you, Reverend.
That's very kind of you.
But not right now.
- By the way, that locket,
where did you get it?
Oh it belonged to my aunt.
- I wouldn't show it to too
many people, if I were you.
It's the devil's sign.
You're not in league
with Satan are you?
No, no.
Thank you for
telling me, reverend.
Thank you.
Anytime.
- Well it all started
happening when I began reading
the diary.
First the nightmares, if
indeed they were nightmares.
Then the church.
You don't suppose
that this locket could have
anything to do with it, do you?
Or do you just think I'm crazy?
- No, I don't
think you're crazy.
This locket is a
beautiful, old heirloom.
And that's all.
Most of the people in
Blackford would love
to see you give up and go away.
You're not going to let them
chase you out of here, are you?
I'm hoping you'll stay
around for a while.
Maybe I will.
Good evening, Jane.
What are you doing here?
I brought the probate papers.
How did you get in?
I rang the bell.
Nobody answered
so I used my key.
How dare you?
- You remind me
of your late aunt.
How are things going?
Made any friends in town lately?
- You know damn well how
the people around here
feel about me.
So I do.
- Well then perhaps
you'd tell me why
if you know half as
much as you pretend to.
- Oh I know a lot
more than that.
I know what your
aunt did here too.
You don't seem to be surprised
at what I'm going to say.
Go on.
She worshiped the devil.
I know that.
- She and that
boyfriend of hers Robert
were very badly thought
of around Blackford,
very badly thought of
to the day she died.
Do you know how she died?
- Oh no no, nobody
knows how she died.
Everybody knows
about the accident.
I remember hearing about that
when I was little.
- Then you know
about the hearse.
You maybe even...
- What the hell are
you talking about?
I'm talking about the hearse
that carried your aunts body.
It crashed
on the Blackford bridge.
It exploded into flames
and all that was left
was a charred mass of metal.
Stranger than that,
there was no sign of the driver.
Or the your aunt's coffin.
That Robert fellow,
he just disappeared.
Come on, Pritchard.
Well in the paper
they called it some
sort of freak accident.
But I'm not so sure about that.
What aren't you so sure about?
- Well some people say that
the devil himself reached up
and grabbed that hearse
and dragged it down to
the fiery depths of hell
and it's still roaming
the old county road
in search of victims.
You bastard.
It's been you all along.
Now I don't know anything
about that accident.
But I do know that you're
the one that's been driving
that hearse.
What are you talking about?
- Oh you know damn well
what I'm talking about.
And I'm not going to let
you push me around anymore.
Please get out of my house.
You ought to see a doctor.
You're beginning
to imagine things.
Goodnight, Mr. Pritchard.
Goodnight, Jane.
Pleasant dreams.
Well I'm up for the night.
Help me quickly.
Now hold on a second.
Somebody's trying to kill me.
What's that?
Please, he's after me.
Help me.
- Hey, we've got
something over here.
Well isn't this Jane.
Sheriff, quickly,
somebody's trying to kill me.
Uh yeah?
Oh no, come.
- This is getting to be quite
a popular sport around here.
Open season on good
looking city girls.
Jack, you dumb son of a bitch,
I'm telling you the truth.
- Hey that's mighty
strong language lady.
You're asking for trouble
talking like that.
- Five minutes ago, sheriff,
somebody tried to kill me
in my house.
Now are you going to come and
do something about it or not?
- These city woman are
goddamn crazy, you know that?
Oh god.
Oh god, it's happening
all over again.
Please, dear god, I won't be
able to live through it again.
Hello?
Hello in there.
See there's the drawer.
I left it open last
night when I ran out.
Come on, you'll see.
I swear, he drove his hand
right through that door.
- All I see here Jane is nothing
so much out of the ordinary
and exactly what
I expected to see.
You had a nightmare.
Produced by all that talk
of the occult in the diary.
I'm not crazy.
I'm not.
I said nightmare, Jane.
Now you're not going to
let some dreams get to you,
are you?
You're stronger than that.
I guess so.
Good.
Jane you have got
to rely on yourself.
No dreams, no devils.
Look to yourself, Jane,
and then look to God.
You may be right.
But what it was
so goddamned real.
- Damn real, but still
all in your mind.
Oh why hello, Paul.
Haven't seen you in
church lately, have I?
Well I've been sick.
Yes, I'm sure.
Goodbye, Jane.
Take care of yourself.
Remember, be strong.
I'll try.
Thank you.
- I didn't know he
made house calls.
This was a special occasion.
Speaking of appointments,
don't you have one on the roof?
Yeah, I brought you this.
It's beautiful.
There.
It's just perfect.
I hope you like it.
You don't know how much.
Thank you, Paul.
Now, come on.
I bet you can't get the
roof done by sundown.
I bet you I can.
- Hey looks like
lover boy's back.
Let's see how he did.
Hi guys.
Hey whoa whoa whoa.
So how did it go, hot shot?
Did you get any?
- I don't think that any
of your business, guys.
- That's not a very
nice way to talk, is it?
I did alright, you know.
Well come on.
Sort of.
Well what do you mean sort of?
I mean you either did
or you didn't, right?
You're all talk.
Well we made out.
Bullshit.
Did she have her clothes off?
Well kinda.
You really go to her, huh?
I bet you were hard as a pistol.
Yeah, better believe it, yeah.
Okay, nice chatting with you.
See you.
Oh my god.
Oh what are you doing down here?
- I saw the lights
go out as I drove up.
I thought you might
be in trouble.
Who me?
And then when Reverend
Winston convinced me
that it was a nightmare, I
really felt like killing myself.
- You're a very
strong woman, Jane.
It's good to see you like this.
Most women I know would
have been gone by now.
- Well, out here I'm
learning, for the first time,
how to take care of myself.
It feels good.
It feels great.
If I don't get myself
killed in the process.
- You're beautiful
when you laugh.
Would you like some coffee?
Yes, sure.
Oh don't bother with that.
I'll take care of it.
No, it's not problem.
- Robert talks of
nothing else now.
I can't bear the thought of
our ever being separated.
He believes we can live forever.
Even beyond death,
if I agree as he has
to do Satan's bidding.
I'm being torn apart
by my love for him.
And this terrible choice
he has asked me to make.
But what can I do?
And that's it.
That's the last entry
she made before she died.
Incredible.
To live forever.
Do you believe a thing
like that could happen?
- No, but in some
deranged diabolical way,
Robert convinced my
aunt that it could.
Suppose it could happen, Jane.
Suppose you could live forever.
Span the ages.
Wouldn't that be
worth everything?
I don't know.
You're not serious, are you?
- Of course, I believe
in all that stuff.
- I was getting carried
away again, wasn't I?
I guess it's all the things
that have been happening.
What it amounts to is
one woman alone
in a lonely house
with a very vivid imagination,
sometimes too active
an imagination.
Tom!
There she is.
That's the witch.
There are your spooks.
Witch witch.
Oh, no.
- Apparently I have
quite a reputation.
Even among the
younger set in town.
- You do live in the
local haunted house.
And I plan to stay here.
Kids, do you believe it?
And here I thought that scarred
face man was coming back
to get me.
- I don't think you'll
be seeing him anymore.
Neither do I.
Tom, would you like to
come back for dinner again?
When?
- Would tomorrow
night be too soon?
I'd love to.
Up late last night, huh?
Oh a little yes.
Would you like some coffee?
Uh no thanks, I just ate.
Have a good time last night?
Yeah, pretty good.
Out with that Tom guy.
You must like him, huh.
Yeah, I like him, huh.
Did he stay here last night?
- I don't think that's any
of your business, Paul.
So, how are things at the store?
Oh same old thing.
Kind of boring.
I was wondering if you
wanted to, felt like,
maybe we could go
see a movie tonight.
We'd have to drive
a few hundred miles
but it'd be great.
I'm sorry, Paul.
I'm busy tonight.
You're busy tonight?
Mmhmm.
You going outwith Tom?
As a matter of fact, yes.
Geez.
Oh, dammit.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Now listen, Paul,
the last thing in the
world that I want to do
is to hurt you.
You know that, don't you?
Come on now.
Yeah, I understand.
I'm a little young.
- But you're not too young
for us to still be friends.
Yeah.
Sorry about the vase.
Don't worry about it.
- Well look if that Tom
guy doesn't work out,
I'm going to be back
here in a couple years
to give him a run for his money.
I like you Jane, a lot.
- Where were you when
I was 16 years old?
Nevermind, don't answer that.
I don't want to know.
I better get back to work.
I'll see you soon.
Bye,PauL
I'll call you right back.
- I know you see
me, Mr. Pritchard,
so you might just
as well look up.
Good afternoon, Miss Hardy,
and good bye.
I am very busy.
I simply haven't got time...
I've signed the papers.
I'm staying in Blackford.
- I trust you'll still need
to put the house on the market
when you leave in the fall.
I might not be
leaving in the fall.
- What the hell are
you talking about?
- Well I simply haven't
made up my mind yet.
Well I'm damned if you do.
Afew days ago, I heard
you were so damn scared,
I thought I'd never
see you again.
Now you're talking
about living here.
There are the papers.
When are you going
to get them filed?
This is late Friday afternoon.
I'm not about to be going
over to the county seat.
I'll get around
to them on Monday,
well, maybe Tuesday.
Monday.
- Seems to me you're
acting damn cocky.
What the hell's going on here?
Nothing.
- I ran into that young
Gordon boy that you hired,
Paul.
Took the liberty of asking
him a few questions.
- My personal life is
none of your business.
- Paul seemed, well,
completely bent out of shape.
Something about
another man named Tom?
- Pritchard, why don't you
just climb into the back
of that silly old hearse
of yours and drop dead.
Sullivan, S U L L
IVA N, Thomas.
That's right.
Are you sure?
Well maybe it's an
unlisted number.
No.
Okay, thank you, operator.
Tom, I was wondering what...
flaughs)
Lois.
Yes, I was expecting
someone else.
Well that fellow I
was telling you about.
Busy, going out of my mind.
I don't know.
It's just something
about this place.
Something.
The man with the scar again.
I know, everyone says that.
Maybe it was a dream.
As a matter of fact, he was
supposed to be here for dinner
right now.
Oh Lois, that
would be wonderful.
Any weekend would be fine.
As a matter of fact.
Lois?
Hello?
Run on, run on you.
House robbing, grave
robbing, city bitch.
You want ghosts?
I'll give you ghosts.
Tom, Tom, where are you?
Hey, give an old man a lift.
Hey!
Lift for an old ghost.
Son of a bitch,
I'll get you too.
Anybody there?
Jane?
Tom?
Are you in there?
No.
No, no, no.
Paul?
Jane.
Hello, Jane.
Get away from me.
Get away.
I've been waiting, Jane.
I've waited a long time.
There is no Tom.
Come with me.
There is only Robert.
Paul?
Paul...
Oh god, no.
Not the child.
No.
Jane.
I love you.
Don't fight me, Jane.
No.
What about the boy?
The old man.
It doesn't matter.
I can give you eternal life.
Our love just as we are.
Forever.
Jane, I love you.
I need you.
This is madness.
It's not happening.
It's not possible.
Jane.
It is possible.
Your aunt Rebecca was weak.
She was afraid.
We can do it.
We can have our love forever.
Satan, get thee behind me.
And cast thy servants
back into hell.
Jane!
You can't fight him alone.
You're not going to get me.
You're not, you're not.
Damn you.