Moshe Ivgi - Aki Avni
Osnat Fishman - Asi Levy
David Danino
Eyal Rozales - Renan Haim
Sharon Zalikovsky - ltsik Juliy
Let go of the bag,
you stingy bastard!
Over my dead body!
He's got a gun!
Let go of the bag, bastard!
THE lNVESTlGATlON
MUST GO ON
A Film by
Marek Rozenbaum & Haim Merin
Zohar! Zohar!
Hey! Wait up!
You know, sometimes people
make serious mistakes.
You're a social worker.
You ought to know.
What are you talking about?
Your husband's
been making lots of them.
Why don't you talk to him?
-I would if I could find him.
Can I come in?
Explain the situation?
Hello, Mrs. Shalom...
How are you?
-What do you care?
How's Shalom?
Rumor has it he took something
that doesn't belong to him.
Better warn him!
Shalom.
Shalom, police.
Let me see your badge.
Micha! Ronny!
Hi guys! You mean
you were chasing me?
Got a phone? I'll tell my wife
guests are coming.
We'll surprise her.
Got it?
Nothing surprises her anymore.
-I bet we will.
Zohar! Open up. We've got guests.
You're a wife-beater too, huh?
-I slipped on the sidewalk.
Slipped?
I'm gonna make
one hell of a comeback.
I'll give you a hell of a comeback
in federal prison.
Want something to drink?
Be my guests. Look around...
You won't find anything. I'm clean.
At school, we had a nurse
named Hajija.
I'd show her my hands
and say I'm clean.
She'd say If I look hard enough,
I'll find something.
And she always did. Get it?
-Yes, Hajija.
"ln the Country of Last Things"
You read these books?
Between police searches.
-For your job?
It's a secret.
-Top top secret!
What's this?
A piano.
And this?
It's fish food.
-It's mine. I put it there.
Zohar!
It's mine.
-Ronny, write this down
A narcotic substance was found.
The suspect claims it's fish food.
His wife claims it belongs to her.
We always find something.
Got it? Hajija.
Am I under arrest?
-What do you think?
I'm under arrest. -Then why ask?
-My natural curiousity.
I'm giving you a long rope.
I bet it doesn't even reach
the courtroom.
A really, long rope. Ok?
-Hang yourself with it. Ok?
I'll bury you. -On what grounds?
-We'll see.
We'll see. -We will see.
-We will see.
And see and see...
-And see and see and see...
You always have the last word?
-That's right. We'll see...
Eyes closed.
and,,...
"Oh, beloved fields,
"Oh white stones,
"It's good to roam the roads,
"Oh my love..." (Arabic)
He used to be a famous singer.
-Couldn't this wait half an hour?
I'm on to something. I'll solve
the armed robbery case in hours.
You interrupted us for that?
-Ohana's sure it's Robby and Momi.
Ohana's retiring next month.
So close the case and move on.
The investigation must go on.
Gentlemen, meet
Lieutenant Micha Stein.
The best dressed
detective on the force.
Where do you buy your clothes?
Macy's.
-At Macy's...
Do what you have to.
Just get results.
Come on! We still have
lots of work to do!
Let's go...,,,....
There he is!
That son-of-a-bitch!
There's the bastard
who shot my brother! I'll kill him!
Where is he?
Give the jewelry back!
I'll kill you!
I can't believe it!
You can't stay out of trouble.
Did you see that ape?
He tore my shirt.
He must have thought
I was hiding peanuts.
I can't take this anymore.
Zohar, I don't know what
they want from me! I swear!
What was that all about?
Gun shots?! Robbery?!
What's going on here?
It's all bullshit. I've never seen
that guy before in my life.
I'm as pure as a virgin.
I just can't take this anymore.
Don't say that, please.
Come on...
What should I tell the detective?
The whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
That someone just broke
my arm for no reason?
I don't know why
they did that to you.
Who was that guy who shot at you?
I have no idea! Maybe they're
trying to frame me.
I saw the policeman get shot
with my own eyes!
I didn't do anything!
Look at me!
You can go home now.
The detective was injured.
Come back tomorrow.
Is it possible
she doesn't know anything?
I wire-tapped the house.
Who gave you orders to bug
the house? Ohana?
I bugged my own phone
to spy on my wife.
You've got to help me.
You're the only one I trust.
What are you talking about?
-She's seeing someone.
She goes out nights a week
to a dance class.
Follow her,
just for a couple of hours.
I'm going crazy. I have to know.
How was l?
How could you let them disappear?
Was I supposed
to baby-sit them all day?
At night I can't sleep with
the smell of the horses,
and during the day I have to babysit.
I can't take it anymore!
Smell me!
What am I a dog?
-I went to the store...
the cashier started
sniffing the air.
Good! Finally a chick
shows some interest in you.
Let's go.
Ohana, don't you know anyone
besides Robby and Momi?
Where did the asshole
and his wife disappear to?
What are you going to do to me?
I'm innocent. Torture me?
I'm not afraid of anything.
-Shut up, already!
Sit down.
Name? -Shalom.
Last name? -Shalom.
Shalom Shalom?
-My name is Shalom Shalom.
I'll take your statement now.
-About what?
Let's take your statement now,
Mr. Shalom Shalom.
I have nothing to say.
-Where were you last Thursday...
between a.m. and p.m.?
I don't know what I did last night.
You want me to remember last week?
Don't remember?
-Don't remember.
Don't remember, huh?
-Don't remember. -Try harder.
I'm trying so hard
my brain's about to explode.
You've been resurrected!
-Ronny, how about a cup of coffee.
Make mine with sugars,
stir it well.
Where were you last Thursday?
Doesn't remember,
heard nothing, saw nothing.
Thursday. That's all I want to know.
-He doesn't remember.
Thursday.
-Where was I and what did I do?
Yes, where were you
and what did you do?
I was at the beach all day.
-You're lying.
Know what? I wasn't.
-Then where were you?
First tell me
what I'm being accused of?
Thursday.
-What's the charge against me?
Don't play games with me.
I won't stop until you tell me.
Got it? -No.
Last Thursday. -Thursday or Friday,
I was at the beach.
It could've been Wednesday.
Write down Wednesday, Thursday
or Friday. I'm not sure.
Thanks. -Did you stir it well?
-Where's my coffee?
Last Thursday!
I don't know what you want!
I'm clean!
What soap do you use?
-Ajax.
Thursday! You little shit!
Whatever I have to say,
I'll say in court. I need to pee.
Thursday!
I was with a chick.
-Who? -I'm not telling.
With whom?
-Top top secret.
Hello?
-Coffee? Captain Ohana?
Someone said "screw" and hung up.
Well screw you too!
And your mother!
Oh, I'm sorry. Just a second.
Micha. It's your wife.
I don't know when I'll be home.
Shit! Four to three.
I have to pee.
-Who is this?
No one informed me.
-I cleared it with the chief.
I'm in charge here
and I have another lead.
I have to pee.
-Make in your pants. Got it?
I also need to lay some bricks.
Get him out of here!
Who's that? -The guy from the
Abramov robbery. -That guy?
Who's your informant?
I bet he's bullshitting you.
I got an anonymous call.
A woman's voice...
Don't worry.
Who said you could sit?
Go stand in the corner!
Face the wall!
I'm sick of you!
No problem, Ohana.
Keep chasing your tail.
What's the score?
Even. Four-Four.
I'm hungry.
I haven't eaten all day.
Sit over there.
Come closer. -How close?
-Close enough for me to slap you.
Ok, what's your name?
Mine -No. Your sister's.
-Barbara Walters.
You already asked me that.
-I'm asking again. -Shalom Shalom.
So what do you have to tell me?
Ok, you cracked me. I confess.
I smoke pot and once
I ran a red light.
You're not a kid.
Either play it straight or not.
What'll it be?
-I prefer the crooked way.
You're being a wise ass.
-No I'm not.
Do you know Robby and Momi?
-Just from the 'hood.
You haven't seen them
around lately? -No.
We've got a witness that saw you
robbing Abramov the jeweler.
I don't do that sort of thing.
-What sort of thing?
Armed robberies.
-There's no point in lying.
You're a lion. I'm a nightingale.
How can the bird beat the beast?
You're no nightingale.
You're a frozen chicken.
I'd like two eggs
sunny side up with toast.
We've nailed you.
We've got an air-tight case.
You just sit here
and think about everything
you've done. Got it?
You must be able to identify
at least one of them!
I told you. They wore helmets.
You said someone had been
following you
for a week before the robbery.
Is this the guy?
Maybe...
Maybe not. I don't know.
We'll wait till you're better
for a line-up.
Don't tell anybody I showed you
the picture. Ok?
Why did you bring us here?
I have to go to work.
-I have to pee.
Everyone who comes here
has to pee.
So, she can talk.
-I thought she was deaf and dumb.
What do they want with Shalom?
-Nothing. He's done nothing.
In the end they'll let him go
and beg for forgiveness. Creeps...
Careful, she might shoot you.
Here's my angel!
-Lady, leave him alone.
He's innocent!
-Mom, go home!
You're embarrassing me.
Come in, please.
Not you, Madam.
Why? Why not me?
I said no. -But why?
Come, sit down.
Allow me.
I wanted to have a chat with you.
-A chat or an interrogation?
Whichever turns you on.
Is this the guy that hurt you?
Solomon Cohen, a.k.a. Little Momi?
Is this the guy?
Don't know him. What do you want
with my husband?
Last Thursday. When did he go out?
-I don't know. I leave home early.
When you got back from work,
was he at home? -I don't remember.
I see you've got a hell
of a relationship.
It's a bit more complex
than a hell of a relationship.
Is he as free as a bird? -What does
that have to do with anything?
Do you think we just pester people
for no good reason?
From my experience, quite frequently.
Do I seem like that kind of guy?
-Yes.
You're a beautiful woman.
So now you think you'll soften
me up with compliments?
So a guy just walks up to you and
breaks your arm for no reason?
My husband owes money
to all kinds of people.
We're talking attempted murder.
A million dollars worth of jewelry.
What's so funny? A guy is dying
in the hospital. Is that funny?
That's just not his style.
-Then what is?
Surely not armed robbery.
Haven't you asked yourself why
you were assaulted?
You should start looking out
for yourself.
Anything's possible.
-What do you mean?
Do you want to get out of this mess?
-What do you think?
Getting out of this mess...
is a lot easier than you think.
Too bad you're a cop.
You're kind of cute.
I want to help you.
What are you trying to say?
What are you going to do?
Think about this chat.
Very good.
We've lost them again.
Let's go.
Why'd they beat up your wife?
-Don't know.
Maybe they hate my music.
-Why are they after you.
Nobody's after me.
-They wanted money. Ok?
Why? What money?
Who were you with on Thursday?
-Who asked for your opinion?
You find this amusing, huh?
Where were you on Thursday?
How many times are you going
to ask the same question?
I got up, brushed my teeth,
parted my hair,
put on a shirt and went to pray.
One more time.
I got up early. About p.m...
Went to the mall,
had some coffee...
Helped Abe with his deliveries.
He has a big truck.
Abe the Midget...
How tall is he?
-About your height.
Stand up. Let's see.
What did you do next?
-We went to the movies.
Why do they call him The Midget
if he's my height?
Maybe your friends call you
"The Midget" behind your back.
Who'd you go to the movies with?
-A girlfriend.
Hey! We're trying to work
over here!
What movie? -We didn't go.
We went to her place instead.
Give me her name and address.
-Silvia Cohen. She lives on Sinai St.
Number or.
or?
- or?
or.
Is she better than your wife?
-Don't know if she's better or worse,
but she's very clingy.
She's crazy about me.
Doesn't care that I'm married...
or that I see other women...
What did you do at her place?
-You really want to know?
We went rounds.
Is a blow job
cosidered a round?
Yes it is.
Then rounds.
I didn't want to exaggerate.
As it's written in the Kabbala
"He who over indulges
in intercourse, ages quickly and
loses his power of body + mind."
My family's into photography
I caught the same bug.
I help my dad shoot weddings.
That's how I met Shalom.
Your voice sounds familiar.
Like I've heard it before...
Maybe in your dreams.
When did you last see him?
-Thursday.
Thursday? -Yes.
What makes you so sure?
-You don't forget a day like that.
What did you do all day?
What'd we do? We did it all day.
It was incredible.
Fire works...
What's he been charged with?
Do you see him often?
-As often as I can.
He spends the night here
and his wife doesn't mind?
She's used to it.
What did he do? Steal the
church's charity box?
Armed robbery and attempted murder.
Got it?
Shalom?
I didn't know I was hanging out
with such a big time gangster.
Do you know his wife?
I've seen her a couple of times.
Are they having problems?
If not, do you think he'd be
seeing me for years?
Those are all tapes
from weddings, bar-mitzvahs...
Have a look. Weddings...
That's a video I shot of Shalom
three years ago.
The guy's got the best
of both worlds.
Lives with his wife,
does you on the side.
Whichever way you look at it,
you're screwed.
I don't see it like that. -Then why'd
you call and leave a message...
that he robbed the jeweler?
-What?
I didn't leave any message.
-I'll take these tapes with me.
I won't let you.
"Search warrant"
Smart detective.
Do you have a box?
Anything else?
Say "Shalom Shalom
of number Queen St.
robbed Abramov the jeweler
and hid the loot in his house."
Do I have to?
-Only if you want to.
I don't feel like babbling nonsense.
I wish.
I wish someone would come
up here and join me.
I wish you a Happy New Year...
Wait... slow down there...
Are you trying to drive me crazy?
Do I need this?
Just a minute. I can't hear.
Rewind it...
So is that how she does it?
-What?
My wife. When she's
cheating on me...
You're driving yourself crazy.
-I'm telling you. She's got someone.
Silvia...
I'm going to score big!
I'll cover you with jewelry.
-We've got him!
Rewind it!
I'll devote whole hours
to you and your cheating wife!
When is her folk dancing class?
Ohana always goes
to his usual suspects.
Robby and Momi, the Holon twins,
then back to Robby and Momi.
Rewind it, will you!
Rewind it yourself,
I have to get home.
I didn't sleep all night.
I played cards with Peretz, Banai
and Darzi all night.
We finished a case of beer.
My head's killing me. -Who won?
Who do you think? -Peretz.
I cleaned them out.
At a.m. Peretz swore...
it was the last time
he'd play with me.
When you retire,
you can open a casino.
What a day I had yesterday.
The washing machine broke,
the plumber didn't show...
Then, my wife stuck
her ass in my face.
I thought you liked that.
-I like your wife's ass in my face.
So what happened yesterday?
Did your suspect confess?
I got a day extension
from the judge.
The way you were talking,
I thought you got at least.
Yeah? Next time he'll be indicted.
I've got a little surprise
for both of you. -What now?
Are you ready?
Ten,
nine,
eight,
seven,
six,
five, four,
I'll cover you with jewelry.
So what does the superstar
have to say?
Did it make you horny?
You can watch it together.
Give each other hand jobs.
How can you prefer
her over your wife.
Leave me alone, jackass.
So what's your explanation?
-I wasn't talking about a robbery.
I was talking about a hit song.
-A hit song?
Yes. A hit album.
-A hit album, huh?
Let see what the judge will say.
-You know what?
I bet he'll ask me for
her telephone number.
We shall see.
-We shall see and see.
"Let my people go!
Let my people go!"
Shut up!
Shut the fuck up!
I said shut the fuck up!
Micha! Let him go!
So what do you have to say now,
Capt. Ohana?
The tape proves nothing,
I have a feeling he's innocent,
Now I understand why
you never got any further.
years and you're still stuck here.
My gut tells me he didn't do it.
Your guts make me sick.
I didn't say you should release him.
-He has no alibi.
They broke his wife's arm.
You saw the tape.
How could he have nothing
to do with it?
I'll arrange
a line up with Abramov,
and end of story.
It'll be some time
before Abramov is well.
Why don't you go fishing
with the other old folks.
I'm still in charge here.
I'm going to interrogate him
properly. -What do you mean?
Wait and see.
-Why are you telling me?
You're in charge.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Keep me out of this.
Great! Let me get my hands dirty,
so you can take the credit
once the case is solved!
Just tell me if these are the guys
who robbed you.
I already told
the other stupid cop
that they were wearing helmets.
But someone was following you
before the robbery. Take a look.
Maybe. Maybe not. I don't know.
Don't tell anybody that l
showed you these pictures.
Where's my coffee, Mary?
Is this anyway to treat a guest?
I told you not to call me Mary?
If I didn't know you since
grade school,
I'd think that you stole
the jewelry and the money.
You know me!
I don't do shit like that!
Yeah, right...
I'd never rip off a friend!
Not even a cigarette!
What about the gold watch
with diamonds
that you stuck in your sock
during the embassy robbery?
You still remember that?
Yeah.
We were kids then!
That doesn't count.
You said you'd never
rip me off.
We pulled this job together,
hid the loot...
I said, if I didn't
know you better
But you still suspect me.
-Of course I don't.
But maybe you told someone
something on the phone.
Who?
Who would I tell?
Don't know you can't trust
anyone anymore.
Am I getting any better?
I don't like that kind of music.
Whoever stole my loot,
is going to pay dearly.
The bastard will wish he
was never born.
Did you think about our
little chat? -I did.
I want to help you, Zohar.
It's dangerous for you here.
-He's done nothing.
He's tricking you.
I've got solid proof.
Proof? Then indict
him and let's go to trial.
Who's Silvia?
-I don't know.
You don't know?
-ls this a pop quiz?
Your husband claims he spent
Thursday night with her.
Maybe a witch who's got him
under her spell.
He promised to take her
to London.
Divide and conquer.
Zohar, believe me, I want
to help you. -I'll be fine.
This is your chance to
get out of here. -Yeah, sure.
Zohar, I'm willing to do
a lot for you.
And what do I have to do
for you?
Decide what you want to do
with your life.
This isn't right.
Think about what I said.
Micha...
I can help...
If you promise to release him.
I promise. After he testifies.
Someone asked him to hide a gun.
Where's the gun?
Will you release him?
-Yes.
If he testifies, I'll release him.
Get it?
Shalom!
The dog from the police squad
is with your wife. -Whaaaaa?
The dog from the police squad is with
your wife, you bastard!
Now give back the package!
What package? What the hell
are you babbling about?
How was that?
You asshole, you son of a bitch...
Give back the package or die.
I'm warning you...
You asshole, you son of a bitch...
Give back the package or die.
I'm warning you! -Go on.
Shalom!
Give back the package or die!
I'm warning you!
-Mary, you pussy!
Tell Robby I don't have anything!
What's that smell?
We've been at the ranch all week.
Horse shit everywhere you look.
Crime is taking over the country.
You can't move
without getting mugged.
You can't trust anybody.
-Shhh...
The fellows make a plan,
Take some risks...
Serious risks!
Then along comes this guy
out of nowhere and takes the loot!
Can't you understand how we feel?
-You can't trust anybody.
I told you the cops started
sniffing around,
so I gave him the loot
and the gun to hide!
His wife must know where it is!
He tells her everything!
We'll go pay her a visit.
If we don't find anything there,
we'll be back.
I'm giving you my word.
I'm not recording any of this.
Just tell me what you know.
It'll stay between us.
As safe as...
what's that place
in America? Port?
Fort Knox.
-That's it. Fort Knox.
Are you friends
with Robby and Momi?
I've got nothing to do with them.
Momi got married and didn't
hire me to sing at his wedding.
He hired some Russian singer
who sings in ltalian.
So tell dumb, old Ohana...
How could you be dating
Silvia Cohen for years,
and not know Robby and Momi.
She hangs out with them.
I have nothing to do with them.
Silvia introduced us once.
You know what?
Strap me to a lie detector.
You'll blow up the machine.
You were here last year. It took
them three months to repair it.
Rake me over hot coals.
What was the "hit" you
told Silvia about?
I thought I'd record a hit album.
But it didn't work out.
Your wife was beaten up! Why?!
I'm trying to figure that out myself.
If it was about the money I owe,
it wouldn't come to that.
Bon appetit!
What's that under your arm?
-What's under my arm?
The other one.
-Oh, that.
This is the gun from the robbery.
So, what does our Song Bird
have to say about this?
Leave him alone. Can't you see
that I'm interrogating him.
Is this how you interrogate him?
Just a moment please.
It's the chief.
He says that he can hear you chewing
all the way upstairs.
Very funny. You should do stand-up
at the squad's party.
The chief wants to see you.
I'll come with you.
I want to speak to him too.
We don't have time for
nobodies like you.
Be thankful that we're even
talking to you. Got it?
I'm very grateful to the police for
hosting a music star.
Be nice to the Captain.
Tell him the whole truth.
Get it?
Got it.
-What did you get?
I should tell him the whole truth,
which is that I'm innocent.
Groovy. Have fun.
What about the gun he found?
Did you get it from Robby and Momi?
I've never seen that gun.
Testify against them
and I'll send you home.
Why won't you understand?
Silvia will tell you.
I was with her all day.
What's up with the investigation?
You said hours.
Like you said "The investigation
must go on."
I'll close the case in the next days.
-How long can we hold him?
Seven days.
Let him finish his time
and go home. You go too.
Overdoing it can be
very harmful.
Home?
This case is closed.
I've got the video, the gun...
He'll come to his senses
and confess,
and even if he doesn't,
Abramov will identify him.
Are there any fingerprints?
-None.
I checked it out. That's not
the gun that shot Abramov.
So it's the other guy's gun.
Micha, you look drained.
Why don't you go home.
Your wife called and asked me
to give you some time off.
Go home.
OK, I'll finish up and go.
You can't win 'em all.
Ohana will close the case.
Where's Ohana?
-He went home.
What's this?
-A vacuum cleaner.
A vacuum cleaner?
-lt must be a new model.
I'll blow your brains out with it!
You've never seen it before?
Stein, it's your wife.
Are you crazy?
Why'd you call the chief?
Have you lost your mind!
You're right, I'm sorry.
I completely forgot.
Yes. Tonight, if it all works out.
I promise. When did I ever
break a promise?
Everything's Ok. It works.
Don't play games!
Are you signing a confession?
-I'm not signing my confession!
Micha? What's that noise?
I want you to surprise her.
She has that folk
dancing class tonight.
Don't worry, Danny.
Everything will be Ok.
You'll sign a confession even if
it's the last thing I do. Got it?
We shall see.
We shall see...
-And see and see and see...
I'll show you
who gets the last word!
Now we'll see
who gets the last laugh!
Up here!
I'll leave you here...
and no one will ever know.
Get it?
I'm sick of nobodies like you.
Shalom!
Shalom, can you hear me?
I'm staying down here.
-Grab the rope. I'll pull you up.
Say you're sorry.
I've got plenty of time.
Grab the rope!
I'll wait for them
to come after you.
I'm leaving.
Say "I'm sorry bro".
What else do you want?
-I want my lawyer.
How about a masseuse?
-A masseuse too.
Bro, say you're sorry.
Ok. I'm sorry.
Don't make it an issue.
No, no. Say "I'm sorry, bro".
I'm sorry, bro.
Pull bro, pull.
You know what bro,
I forgive you.
I've got a feeling
we're making a mistake.
Feelings can't be trusted.
Get it?
I don't like this!
You're going to kill him!
Would you like a transfer?!
I'll do the paperwork tomorrow.
Were you in on the robbery?
I have to know.
-What the fuck do you care?
Tomorrow you'll be
on a new case.
In another month you
you won't even remember me.
You'll be an asshole
like all the others.
Get out of my face!
Go! Bitch! Go!
Hi there. I want my package back.
Who's this? -Tell your husband
to give back the package.
Call the post office.
You and your husband are
making a big mistake. Big...
The whore hung up on me.
Is that it?
-Thanks.
They shot up the house.
I've got to talk to Shalom.
You can't. He's being interrogated.
-I have to.
You have to get out of here
till this is all over.
Not until I speak to him.
Ok, but I have to record
the conversation.
The Midget showed me the gun
I supposedly used in the robbery.
He wanted me to confess...
I don't know where they got
the gun from.
I also don't know.
-You don't know?
I've been shot! Haven't we
played enough games?
It's a mistake. They were
probably after Fat Sammy.
They sprayed the whole house!
Shit! I just painted the
living room. -Enough already!
When this is all over, we'll buy
a house in the mountains.
We'll have fruit trees.
Apples, plums, coconuts...
A little recording studio...
Coconuts won't grow in the
mountains. They need warm weather.
What? I've been dreaming about
coconut trees for ages.
You can grow apples, pears,
avocado, but not coconuts.
I hate avocado.
When you get out, I think
we should take some time off.
You're my life, my soul...
You're the only person
I have left.
What about your mother?
A mother's a mother.
I don't know... This time
I think you went too far.
You don't believe me either?
-What about Silvia?
You believe all their bullshit?
I don't know who
to believe anymore.
Great... My wife doesn't even
believe me.
The world has ended. The fish
are climbing trees.
I think she got you
into this mess.
Why would she do a
thing like that?
It's over between us.
I told you. It's over.
I know you were with her
on Thursday.
What was the Midget doing
with you the other night?
A house call?
Why'd you give him the gun?
How could you do this to me?
You know I'm crazy about you.
I'm mad about you.
I forgive you for everything.
I was trying to help you.
You're hurting me.
Don't hurt me.
You're my life, my soul...
Sure I am...
Zohar, open up. I just want to
make sure that you're Ok.
I know you're in there.
Open up. I want to see you.
You promised you'd let him go!
I gave you the gun!
You promised!
-How could l?
He said he had nothing to do
with the gun!
You promised!
-Open the door! I want to talk!
We have nothing to talk about!
-Open the door, Zohar!
I want to talk to you!
What's going on here?
Go back inside! Get inside
before I arrest you all.
I'll call the cops.
I have connections! -lnside!
Burn in hell. You pig!
Open the door.
I want to talk to you.
Have you calmed down?
I brought you a gift.
Paul Auster.
"The Music of Chance".
I read it already. Go away,
I'm begging you.
Have you calmed down? -I thought
there is something between us.
Last night I dreamt I was
the manager of a club.
A strip joint...
The strippers were dancing,
slowly taking off their clothes...
Bras and panties...
The most beautiful one...
was dancing just for me.
She was naked, but I could feel
her hiding something from me.
Micha, please go away.
You tricked me.
You let me feel...
You were lying to me all along.
You know where the money
and jewelry are!
You know and won't tell me!
The last time I performed
was last month,
at a huge party at a hotel
for a guy...
who just got out of jail.
It was such a blast. They wouldn't
let me leave the stage.
After the show,
me, Silvia and chicks
got a room at the hotel.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Your wife is waiting at home
while you're partying?
It got so hot in there...
the room was on fire.
That seems so far away now.
Like it was years ago...
What's up? Card games
cleaned you out?
The jeweler died.
Now, we're talking homicide.
I brought Silvia in for questioning.
Silvia?
As of this moment you're being
charged with armed robbery & murder.
You and your parties
make me puke.
Who shot the jeweler?
You or your partner?
I never robbed anyone in my life!
Get off my back! Enough!
Adi, leave the room.
-Don't go. Don't go.
Leave the room.
You're the worst kind of scum!
Why'd you get married!
So she could sit at home
and swallow your shit?!
Why'd you get married!
What were your plans for
the money?
To leave for London
with that whore?!
You've the hots for her, huh?
But it won't get you anywhere.
I love her and she loves me.
And I'm innocent! Innocent!
Four years ago,
a guy named Henigstein,
got blown up
with a hand grenade.
He lost an arm and a leg
and couldn't understand,
why this happened to him.
I decided to look into it.
And guess what I found out?
The guy had a girlfriend he
broke up with a month earlier.
So I'm here because of a boyfriend
who got blown up...
four years ago?
-Time passed.
She found a new boyfriend
Robby and Momi are in the picture.
Seems to me there's a
link between the stories.
My intuition tells me,
that you heard about
Robby and Momi's plan,
and wanted a piece of the pie,
so you told Shalom about it.
You planned to go
to London together.
But he decided to leave you
and go back to his wife.
That's a big fat lie!
You wanted revenge,
so you informed the police.
No, I love him.
You can help him.
Where's the jewelry?
I swear I don't know.
All I know is
that Shalom isn't capable
of pulling that off.
How did he get the gun?
A gun?
What gun are you talking about?
-lsn't it a shame?
They are beating the shit
out of him day and night.
An innocent man...
You know what, Ohana?
You've touched my heart.
I robbed the jeweler.
Tomorrow, I'm going
to shave my head.
Enough of this life
of sin and promiscuity.
I'm born again!
God has turned his back on you!
There's no one left
to save you! Get it?!
Sylvia, tell him we were together
on Thursday!
Leave him alone!
He was with me all day!
Leave him alone! He was with me!
I'm crazy about you!
Tell him.
Micha, should I bring him in?
-I need to take a shit.
Get him out of here.
I will get out of here.
Shalom, stop!
Stop! Micha, Ronny,
he's getting away!
Where's the chief?
-At the rehersal.
What's up guys? Have a good show.
Why are you running away,
is it that bad here?
Excuse me, we're in a hurry.
Miriam?
Mom?
Fucking yuppie!
I want my package back!
I don't know
what you're talking about!
He didn't tell you?
He didn't tell me anything!
-He didn't tell you?
He didn't tell me!
I don't know anything! -Bitch!
She turns me on.
Move! I'm going to do her.
-Stop! Stop!
Momi, leave her alone.
"A Ma'alot poem
"l will lift up my eyes
to the hills,
"From whence comes my help?
"My help comes from the Lord,
"who made heaven and earth.
"He will not suffer
thy foot to be moved.
"He who keeps thee
will not slumber.
"Behold, he who keeps Yisra'el
shall neither slumber nor sleep.
"The Lord is thy keeper.
"the Lord is thy shade
upon thy right hand.
I couldn't sleep.
I was up all night thinking
about Zohar and me,
and how all this will end.
My life flashed before my eyes.
Such horrible thoughts...
walked around, got back
in bed... My whole body aches.
You can talk freely.
It'll stay between us.
Not here.
You choose the place.
Wherever you want.
Your underwear too.
-I'm not hiding anything.
I believe you,
but you make me horny.
I can help you.
Is that the best you can do?
You're like a father to me.
Doesn't a father get
to hear the truth?
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
We were informed you
pulled off a robbery.
We have you on tape saying
you're going to score big.
We find a gun you hid
near your house.
What are we
supposed to think?
What was Micha supposed to think?
-That you've framed an innocent man.
Who'd do a thing like that?
I was with her for years.
Last month I decided to end it.
That's not enough. I need more.
The jewelry, the money...
What about the gun?
She gave me the gun. She asked
me to hide it. I'll testify.
I'll arrest Sylvia, Robby and
Momi right away. It'll be Ok.
Nothing will ever be Ok again.
Faggots! The gynecologist is
here to check your assholes!
Shut up!
The cop's on the grass,
opening up his ass...
Lock him back up and go home.
We'll close the case tomorrow.
Want to let our main suspect walk?
-After he testifies.
Take a couple of days off.
Take the family someplace.
Listen to Ohana.
Yeah...
I could use a vacation.
I've accumulated
lots of vacation days.
I've been very tense lately.
I've got stuff to finish up,
and then I'll take a vacation.
We'll wrap up the paperwork
and go home.
Thanks.
Ohana!
Get the car!
We're moving to a place
where we won't be bothered.
Stop it.
Micha, why don't you
give it up?
He's nice and ripe.
Ready to confess...
I don't have time.
-He'll confess. Come.
I have to be home by nine.
I promised my wife I'd go with her
to her folk dance class.
I've been practicing all week.
It's real easy!
Why don't you join us?
You'll be home by nine.
Let's go!
Sometimes I get these
philosophical notions.
For instance,
that the life path
of Micha Stein
just out of millions
and billions,
collides with the life
paths of others.
Get it?
And whosever path collides
with mine,
veers off in a
whole new direction.
I love the silence
of the night.
You know what I mean?
Silence or not,
I'm staying in the car.
Get him out of the car.
Do you recognize this place?
-I live here. -Yeah?
Listen to the sounds.
Nothing but you, me and God.
You know what, Shalom?
Sometimes I feel
like his messenger.
What do you want from me?
-No less then a full confession,
the location of the money,
the jewelry and the gun.
My deal with Ohana is that
I testify and go home.
We're on our way home.
I read your testimony.
Very beautiful indeed.
Just lacking the important details.
Did you think Lt. Micha Stein
would let you win?
I'll shoot you,
saying you tried to escape.
You wouldn't dare.
There's a limit!
You've lost your mind!
I set the limits.
Adi, stop him! He's insane!
I decided to waste you.
I'll confess to it all!
Just leave me alone!
Where's the weapon,
the jewelry, all of it?
Go ahead, Danny!
Roll the tape!
Ronny bring the shovel.
There's nothing and there
never was anything.
Put down the gun!
Shit, what a world...
"How long will evil rejoice"?
Ronny, Adi shoot him!
I have nothing left!
I'll take you all with me!
Drop it before you do
something you'll regret!
You were doing fine until your
life path collided with mine!
You shouldn't have
collided with me!
Did you see that,
he tried to kill me!
He's dead.
English
Dannah Nayblatt, Madeleine Ali