Drive!
Fuck!
Where's Kenny?
Dave, where's your brother?
Dave!
There was nothing I could do.
Mr. De Swaef,
not only have you
refused to cooperate
with the investigation,
you have also consistently
hindered it.
Despite previous convictions
and the chance to get professional help
with your persistent drug problem,
you continue to relapse.
I take note
of your difficult childhood
but that cannot excuse
the excessive violence
and brutality
of the acts committed.
We therefore condemn you
to the maximum sentence of seven years.
It'll be alright.
Stef.
Best of luck.
You sleep on top.
The Ardennes
They paid for part of it,
so in exchange,
I had to trim the hedge.
It's bamboo,
so you have
to do it with a machine.
I'd never used one before.
I'd promised Dad,
so I did it.
I just can't say no.
Something else to work on,
learning to say no.
While I was trimming,
a splinter flew into my ear.
It pierced my eardrum.
I can't swim for a month.
So...
Diving in Bali...
My whole trip is ruined.
I'll just have to live with it...
Thanks for listening,
thanks for the meeting.
Thank you, Cindy.
That's the end
of the meeting, but...
I think we have
something to celebrate today.
Sylvie, don't hide.
You have something to say.
- I'm Sylvie, I'm an addict.
- Hello, Sylvie.
I've been clean
two years today.
I hope it stays that way.
I've fought hard for this.
Each and every day,
even now.
You know, my mom...
she always said
that in life
you can be whatever you want
if you want it hard enough.
What bullshit.
It's bullshit
and she knows it.
She's always sat behind the till
at the supermarket...
well, stood.
I always wanted to be Madonna.
Still do.
You don't always get to choose.
What weather it will be,
what men you fall for...
getting hit by a car
and ending up in a wheelchair.
You don't choose those things.
You can lie in bed all day,
crying.
Or you try to make a go of it,
one day at a time.
That's what I did,
'cos that's a choice I do have.
You all do.
I don't need to use anymore.
I couldn't have made it
without you.
I want to thank you for that.
There...
I wish you all
a good 24 hours.
- Thank you, Sylvie.
- Thank you.
Call for you.
It's your mother.
Your mother, on the phone.
Mom, I'm working.
Get out of the way.
When?
OK.
I'll call you later,
don't worry.
Yeah, OK.
Bye.
Can I see it?
Nice.
- Great, huh?
- How are you, honey?
- You?
- Fine.
Hi, Daisy.
- Turn the heat on.
- Just a second...
Have you been good?
Too good...
- How's that?
- It's just...
I look ridiculous
with a dog like that.
You're more of a pit bull, eh?
- Not a chihuahua, for sure.
- Hear that?
Dave's saying mean things...
What's wrong?
It's been approved.
Really?
That's good news...
When?
He gets out Saturday,
9 a.m.
It'll be OK.
De Swaef, get a move on.
A couple of minutes
won't make any difference.
You OK?
- OK?
- Yeah.
Coming!
Here she is,
the flower of the hood.
What's all this?
- Not like that.
- Hi, Mom.
- I already have a tree, Kenny.
- A plastic one.
- Did Patrick come about the boiler?
- This morning.
- Push, Dave.
- Shoes off!
The plastic tree's good enough.
Dave, off with your shoes!
A plastic tree
is a plastic Christmas, Mom.
And who's going to clean up the needles?
Not me.
- I'll do it.
- Mom, do you still have Cha-Chas?
Bounty bars, in the kitchen.
There you go, Mom.
- Do you even know what a broom looks like?
- Imagine it covered with baubles.
Mom...
Doesn't Kenny get a kiss?
Son...
Come here.
He's jealous.
- The three of us together again.
- OK, OK.
Coffee?
Don't you wish
you were a kid again?
Playing football on the square,
then back home
with dirty shoes
to eat cookies.
No worries.
And those weekends in the Ardennes,
good times!
The Ardennes were nice.
The three of us should
go back there sometime.
You were so good there.
Was it the mountains,
the good air?
Fresh air's good for you...
The air's bad here.
I've always said so.
Hills...
There are hills in the Ardennes,
not mountains.
- How old were you then?
- Twelve.
Here, take one.
- Where are all the photos of me?
- What?
How come there are so few
photos of me?
Maybe you're not photogenic?
Come on, let's go.
I'll just put my stuff upstairs.
Wait, sit down.
- I don't want to go through this again.
- It'll be OK, Mom.
I can't take any more.
I tried everything,
but somehow,
things went wrong with you two.
That's just the way it is.
It's up to you now.
Don't worry,
I'll take care of Kenny.
Promise?
I promise.
Goddam bunch of losers!
Unbelievable.
Still 0-0.
They're paid a fortune.
How much do you stand to win?
- How much do you stand to win?
- 600, if they score a goal.
- Is he a friend?
- My brother.
Keep him away from the TV.
He's bad luck, I can feel it.
And he stinks of sweat,
I can smell him from here.
Does he ever wash?
This is a carwash.
We need to radiate cleanliness.
Mind your passes, dammit!
I'd like to help you,
but times are hard right now.
- In 3 months, I'll fire those foreigners...
- 3 months!
This isn't Social Services.
Nico, I'd like to help,
but like I said, times are hard.
Come on, let's go.
Penalty!
It's a sure thing,
it's gonna be OK.
Don't mess up!
Robert, if he scores,
I'll double up your 600.
- I'll go to the bank right now.
- Kid, it's not worth it.
And if he doesn't?
You hire Kenny.
OK, deal.
1200, huh?
- Who's taking it?
- Simons.
Come on, Simons, focus.
Not in the middle.
Choose a corner.
Goddammit!
Simons, fucking loser!
What was he thinking?
I said, not in the middle!
Pathetic kick!
How did you know?
He's not missed once this season.
Not when it counts.
Under pressure, he misses every time.
- How do you know?
- I played against him as a kid.
- Where?
- Club Antwerp.
From now on,
you fill in my betting slip.
Monday?
Whatever.
Thank your brother, Nico.
You can send Simons a card too.
- Kenny.
- What?
The name's Kenny.
No crap from you, OK?
Fancy going out tonight?
Or don't you party anymore?
I've got something on.
- What?
- Just something.
A chick?
Lady killer.
Bring her with you.
She's not into that.
- What's her name?
- Julie.
- Julie what? Do I know her?
- No.
- What does she do?
- She works at H&M.
H&M?
- Which one?
- On Meir Street.
- Got a photo?
- Not on me.
I'm just curious to know
who has the honour
of playing with your joystick.
Kiddo...
Look at your face!
You're disgusting.
I'm happy for you. Everyone thought
my brother was queer.
Idiot.
Have you heard from Sylvie?
- Have you seen Sylvie?
- No.
You know...
I was hoping
she'd be here today.
But she isn't.
It's those fucking meetings,
making me out to be the bad guy.
Hey, kiddo...
Thanks for coming every Thursday.
I haven't forgotten that.
See you later.
Crap fucking game!
Jacky...
Mom, I'm going out.
- Where are you going?
- Out.
- Tomorrow's your first day, isn't it?
- Yes.
What're you going to do?
Rob a bank.
Jeez!
I'll be back in an hour.
Yes?
I think I know where.
Don't worry.
No, no.
I still fight my demons
every day.
But I got good news today.
I get to see my kid
once a fortnight.
That's better than nothing.
I wanted to say
that I'm grateful for this life.
I wish you all
a good 24 hours.
Thank you, Chris.
Does anybody else
want to share?
I have something to say.
We have a newcomer.
Introduce yourself.
- I'm Kenny.
- Hello, Kenny.
- I heard... what's your name?
- Chris.
I heard Chris use the word grateful.
I've something to say about that.
Grateful for what?
Not living in the bush
where you have to walk
40km for a glass of dirty water?
I don't get what
you have to be grateful for.
Your whole life
in that fucking wheelchair.
Know what I'd do, Chris?
Buy some speed and heroin
and finish yourself off.
- That's the best you can hope for now.
- Kenny...
- I'm talking!
- Kenny, please...
No Sylvie, no...
I kept my mouth shut.
Because I love you.
Four years
that I'll never get back.
Four years...
with Moroccans bossing me around.
Not being able to sleep
'cos the junkie
is always beating off.
All I could think about was you.
And what did you do?
You let me down.
No news from you for two years.
Why?
What would you know,
about gratitude, Sylvie?
Sylvie...
Sylvie, wait!
Did you come
to make me look ridiculous?
Was there someone else?
No.
- I'd just had enough.
- Enough?
Don't you think I'd had enough
of that fucking cell?
Sylvie, it's over.
I accept that.
I'm not proud
of who I used to be.
Can't we just...
forget what happened
and start over?
Wait!
As friends, just friends.
I know I've made mistakes.
But in four years,
a man has time to think.
I want to make a fresh start.
- Sylvie!
- Stay back, pal!
Is everything OK?
- Everything's fine.
- I'm OK.
- You can't expect...
- I expect nothing from you.
Just to see you
from time to time, that's all.
Who else can I talk to?
The kid?
Don't you get it?
What are you doing
for Christmas?
Mom's cooking a stew,
she'd love it if you came.
You'd get a chance to see her again.
And the kid.
Just the four of us,
like it used to be.
As friends.
I can't, I have to work.
In the Mercury?
That's not until 10, is it?
We'll eat at half seven
and you go after. Perfect!
Come on, Sylvie.
- You know me, don't you?
- Yeah, I do.
You know what I mean.
I'll think about it.
- That was an accident.
- Come off it, Kenny.
I'll see you Saturday.
- I'll give you a push.
- No!
It's expensive for such a small flat.
It's got something.
We've been looking for a year,
nothing's ever good enough.
It's not exactly luxurious,
- but we can afford it, can't we?
- Not now, Mom.
What are we going to do?
We'll wait a while,
but this is a possibility.
About Saturday.
He'll find it strange
if you don't come.
Maybe we should tell him now
after all.
I know we agreed
to give it more time.
Give him some time,
he's just got out.
D'you want him
to be born with lung cancer?
So after 10 minutes I thought,
I'll quit,
but the problem was...
Hey, buddy!
I'm talking.
Tough little beggar, huh?
Here, have a crisp.
Fussy too...
- He smells scum.
- It's because she doesn't know him.
Right, Daisy?
She'll get to know me better.
The problem was
that it got stuck between my feet.
I tried to free it
and suddenly, bam!
A piece of my tooth.
See?
And she started crying
'cos my mouth was bleeding.
- True, Mom?
- Yes, it's true.
What?
- I've heard that tale lots of times.
- It's still a good one.
At last.
There you are!
What's up, dude?
Did you bring the mayonnaise?
I invited a homeless man,
'cos I'm so big-hearted.
- You wear this.
- I don't wear bonnets.
- Hello, son.
- Smells good.
Remember Sylvie?
- Hi.
Hey there.
- When are you going to tell him?
- Soon.
That's the problem
with all these big companies.
You have to differentiate
within your own market.
Simple economics.
Ladies first, bro'.
I haven't been idle
these past four years.
She's starting to get to know me.
She's not barking anymore.
- Pass your glass, Mom.
- Thanks, son.
Thanks.
- No thanks.
- Dave's quit drinking. Didn't you know?
What's all this?
You neither?
- Congratulations.
- It's been three years, eh Dave?
You could make an effort for me.
It's Christmas.
In prison
they only celebrate Eid al-Fitr.
No, thanks.
Boys.
Chill out, kiddo.
I am cool.
How about going out tonight?
Sure.
- To a bar?
- We could start there.
But I thought
we'd keep Sylvie company.
- I have to work...
- We won't bother you.
Not too much anyway.
Dave, call your girlfriend.
Julie. Ask if she wants to tag along.
- Julie?
- Works at H&M.
- You have a sweetheart, Dave?
- No, it's nothing.
Just a quick fuck
from time to time?
That's no way to talk.
Dave, now you've got one,
you should marry her right away.
Make it official, before she runs away.
Right, Mom?
Right.
Sylvie, do you still like
working in that club?
I'm doing
a massage course now too.
- Really?
- So if all goes well...
- Is Rudy still running the place?
- Khalid's taken it over.
- Two years ago.
- Khalid?
- Really?
- Yes.
- Wasn't he in Amsterdam?
- He's got two clubs now.
Fuck me. He's doing well.
Does he pay enough
for a princess like you?
Yeah, he takes good care of me.
What do you mean by that?
Just that...
Always pays me on time.
If I need a day off, it's OK.
- So, Khalid looks after you?
- I think Sylvie means...
I heard what she said!
Boys!
Sorry.
I didn't mean anything.
Thank you all for being here.
You're family...
and that's fucking important.
Merckx!
Merckx is gay.
Who then?
Who?
Jean-Claude Van Damme!
- Van Damme, he's a faggot.
- What?
The way he kicks and boxes,
with top acting work.
You think, kiddo?
Van Damme is the best.
- Merckx is the best!
- Get outta here.
- Pure strength of character.
- It's all doping.
Van Damme has mental problems.
Merckx won so many classics.
- Classics?
- Yes, classics!
- Paris-Roubaix, the Tour of Flanders!
- Bloodsport, Kickboxer!
- Lombardy, The Walloon Arrow!
- Timecop, Maximum Risk!
- Those are classics!
- I'd like to see Van Damme race a Tour!
I'd like to see Merckx
kick a cigarette out of someone's mouth.
Then we'll see!
Put your glass down.
Stand here.
Don't move!
Fuck, man...
You OK, Danny?
Kenny...
Things have changed
since you went inside.
I'm not sure
how to tell you this...
A lot can happen in four years...
You don't...
always control things, see?
- Sometimes, things happen...
- Come on.
Hey, how's it going?
- You OK, pal?
- Long time no see.
- Did you fall out with your hairdresser?
- Fuck you, man.
Fucking idiot.
- How are you doing?
- What?
- I'm fine.
- You are?
- Got a job?
- Carwash, with my brother.
Washing cars?
- Look, if you like...
- No, Khalid, I'm done with that.
You need money, don't you?
Look at yourself!
You can say whatever you like,
making out you're
the Tony Montana of the city.
But to me,
you're still that 12-year old
who ran home crying
'cos he'd pissed his pants.
Maybe you should go home, Kenny.
Still can't clean up
your own shit?
Times have changed, Kenny.
Call your little friend over,
I've got nothing to lose.
- No?
- No.
34 years old...
Does Sylvie have to serve drinks
the rest of her life?
Or should I take care of her?
- What?
- Should I take care...
- Come on, we're leaving.
- Why?
I shouldn't have come here.
- Come on, we're leaving.
- Kenny, take it easy.
Sylvie...
I'm sorry for everything.
- Fuck you!
- Kenny...
Keep out of this!
Is this what I come back to?
You, butt naked turning on
that Moroccan scum?
D'you know why
I stopped coming to visit, Kenny?
'Cos every time
I saw your face
I thought about all the bad decisions
I'd ever made in my life.
And that's why I'm
standing here butt naked.
Somebody had to say something.
You're late.
It's not my fault
those fucking buses are so slow.
- What?
- Nothing.
I'm doing my best, aren't I?
Kenny...
- Can we talk later?
- I can do better, I know.
No, about something else.
Out with it.
Later.
Kenny!
Stop, you idiot!
Fuck you, asshole!
- What the fuck was that?
- He attacked me!
What's going on here?
Are you crazy?
You call this normal, Nico?
I said don't bring your crap in here!
- They started it.
- They did, did they?
Get your stuff.
I've had it with your bullshit.
- Robert, they attacked him.
- I don't give a damn!
Robert, you can't do this.
I'm 10 minutes early every day.
I've never had a day off sick.
I need this job.
Poor Dave, what a pretty tale,
very moving.
I don't give a fuck!
I said no crap!
Hand your badges in
at the office.
- Goddammit!
- Robert!
You're going to work
in a state like that?
Someone has to work, Dave.
Do you know how much kids cost?
Kenny can fix something up.
Yeah, right, Kenny's gonna fix it.
- You're such a wimp.
- A wimp?
Do I have to tell him?
He doesn't scare me.
That's not it,
I'm waiting for the right moment.
He's my brother.
Am I a pain in the butt?
- You can tell me if I am.
- No.
Sometimes.
Sometimes...
I don't want to nag.
Will you get me some water?
What?
- The doctor said I should.
- Does he know you're pregnant?
- Don't panic, sweetie.
- Cold hands!
I just thought
things would be different.
And I didn't?
Do you think I like
going from one crap job to another?
I'm trying.
Tell me what you want.
You know what I want.
I just want to be dull.
Come home at 5 p.m.,
put the potatoes on,
watch TV.
Ask my man
about his day at work.
Go swimming with my kid
once a week.
A dull fucking life.
If not with you,
I'll find someone else.
I want to be dull too.
Well, not dull, but...
Really? Getting into a fight
and losing your job
isn't what I'd call dull,
it's stupid.
I couldn't help it.
- Sorry.
- Stop saying sorry all the time.
I have to go, sorry.
OK.
- Tomorrow at 11.
- Where?
That flat.
Bye, Daisy.
Be good.
- Love you.
- I know.
- How are you, Louise?
- Not getting any younger, Dave.
- Give me that.
- That's sweet of you.
Where have you been?
- You OK?
- I need your car a while longer.
What for?
What's this?
- It was an accident.
- An accident?
He fell down...
I just wanted to slap him
and he fell.
Who?
That fucking Khalid.
He had his hands
all over Sylvie.
No one can touch Sylvie.
Kenny...
- Is he dead?
- Stef will help us.
- Us?
- You have to help me, bro'.
- Are you serious?
- It's not my fault he fell.
- Throw him in the river.
- No.
We're going to the Ardennes.
Stef will make him disappear.
You've gotta be kidding, Kenny.
You can't expect me
to do this.
I won't go back inside.
I'll get life for this.
What do you want me to do?
Hand myself in?
Is that what you want?
OK, I'll hand myself in.
I'll tell them what went down
four years ago.
We can share a cell.
- What are you gonna do?
- Get my coat.
Stef?
We're leaving now.
Hello.
- What will you have?
- Nothing.
Beer.
Flemish?
- Where are you off to?
- Toilet.
Don't be cross, sweetie,
I won't be able to make it at 11.
You'll have to go alone.
I have to sort something out.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I'll call again later.
Love you.
I'm in my lesson.
What's up?
- Is that Stef?
- No.
Who is he then?
I dunno.
Kenny...
Drink up and we'll go.
Where's Stef?
Let's go.
A fucking drag queen...
He's going to help us?
They're here.
Come here.
Kenny.
It'll be OK.
Who's this cutie?
My brother.
So this is Dave?
I've heard a lot about you.
What else can you do in the slammer?
Talk, talk, talk.
Stef.
Delighted to meet you.
This is Joyce,
Don't be afraid, she doesn't bite.
Unless you ask for it,
Kenny.
This must be our friend.
We'll deal with him later.
Who fancies...
a pancake?
Understand?
If you see anything, don't play hero.
Call me, OK?
- Another beer?
- No, I must get on.
I have to drop in
on the two weirdos.
Call me, OK? See you.
I don't go near women anymore.
It's not that I can't pull them.
Into my nest, one by one,
if need be.
I think twice
before I stick it in something.
Better than that Moroccan dope,
huh, Kenny?
Can we get on with it?
And you, Dave,
got a ball and chain yet?
Is there a Miss Dave?
Or Mr. Dave?
It's allowed, you know.
You have to watch out for them, Dave.
I mean it.
First, they do anything
to trap you.
And once they've got you,
they break you.
Then they run off
with some Moroccan guy.
Then you hear those echoes...
You're my true love,
I can't live without you.
You're the only one for me.
Kenny...
I once saw an amazing documentary
about cranes.
Do you know those birds?
No?
Let me tell you about them.
D'you know what the male does
when the female dies?
No?
He flies as high as he can,
and at the highest point,
he lets himself fall.
Down to the ground.
Know what the female does
when the male dies, Dave?
No?
I'll give you three guesses, Dave.
Within five minutes,
she's fucking another.
They're all whores.
We've got a visitor.
Who's that?
- Stay calm.
- Stef, who is that?
Just stay calm.
- Hi Stef, how are you?
- Fine. You?
- What's new?
- Not a lot.
- I've got friends round.
- Visitors?
This is Gerard, the gamekeeper.
- Have a seat.
- Thanks.
Know what I fancy, Stef?
- A nice cold beer.
- Sure.
That's enough, Ricardo!
Fucking winter.
Thanks.
Good health.
No, thank you.
They don't speak much French.
Flemish?
Brothers.
You can see the resemblance.
Shut up, Ricardo!
I don't know
what's gotten into him today.
What brings you here, Gerard?
- I've come to warn you...
- Ah?
Sixteen...
Those idiots
left the door open
and sixteen got out.
What a shambles!
People don't realise
how aggressive they are.
Have you ever been face to face
with an ostrich?
When they attack,
you don't stand a chance.
If you guys see one,
don't play the hero.
Get Stef to call me.
Enough, Ricardo!
What's wrong, boy?
Got a scent of something?
What's wrong?
Who's car is this?
Mine.
Got something in the trunk?
Nothing special.
It must be meat.
Ricardo's never wrong.
If there's meat around,
he'll find it.
Sausages.
We're having a barbecue.
A barbecue?
It keeps you warm, Gerard!
Right, I have to warn
the rest of the neighbourhood.
Come, Ricardo.
- Bye, Stefan.
- See you, Gerard.
If we see one of your ostriches,
we'll cook that too.
Good idea.
Kenny!
Kenny, no!
He was on to something,
I swear.
On to what?
That there was something
in the trunk.
Yeah, sausages.
You can chop him up, Kenny.
Stef!
Dave?
Dave!
Fill out this form and I'll...
No need to get upset, sir.
What are you going to say?
The truth.
What do you know
about truth?
Enough.
You really think
you're better than me, brother?
All I know, is that I am
not like you.
Why didn't you tell me, Dave?
Why didn't you tell me?
That Moroccan wouldn't be dead.
What?
Did you really think
you could hide something like that?
You have to tell your brother
a thing like that.
It's not possible
to talk to you.
I've been trying
my whole life.
Did you listen, even once?
Do you know how it feels,
to be humiliated
by a woman?
No...
you don't.
She had to do it.
Don't you get that?
There's just no other way
with you.
Because you're crazy.
What?
Are you going to beat me up
in a police station?
Sir, you can
go to the counter now.
You know, Dave...
Do what you think you must.
Give us up,
if that's what you want.
Or we sort this out together.
As brothers.
And then you're rid of me.
I'll leave you...
and Sylvie in peace.
What's keeping you?
I'm going with Stef to the lab,
to get things ready.
- Lab?
- Those containers.
Go get the other guy
with Joyce.
Kenny...
I'll see you later.
It's probably nothing, but...
Go on, he's in there.
Sit down.
You called me, Kenny.
Don't forget that.
We'll get through this together, pal.
We're brothers.
Will he suffer?
Do you like music?
Do you like this?
Let's dance.
I like Adamo.
Know his stuff?
Sorry about the mess.
I clean up.
Every week.
It's not easy with Stef.
A real pig.
Look where I have to live.
I'm a beautiful woman.
But you're handsome too.
Pity...
A real pity.
I just wanted
to be a welder.
But every time I asked a question,
they sent me into the corridor.
Just because I was having
a bit of trouble
with my ADHD.
What they didn't know,
is how intelligent I am.
When you're too intelligent,
they think you're dangerous.
Then they're surprised
that you make your own drugs.
Does it surprise you?
Not me.
Joyce is here.
Where's Joyce?
I can explain everything...
Kenny, ask your brother
where Joyce is.
It was Stef's idea.
I didn't want this, brother.
I didn't want this.
Come on, put down that gun.
Did you call the cops?
What the fuck?
- Around 4 p.m.?
- Yes.
Did he say
where he was headed?
To see those men.
OK, stay inside.
Sorry, bro'...
What have you done?
She was pregnant!
Police!
Drop your weapon!
Drop your weapon.