(lion roars, snarls)
(chatter)
(chatter, water splashing)
(man coughs)
(chatter)
(bell rings)
(laughing)
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
(funky pop rock music)
(electropop music)
(electropop music continues)
(shrill screeching)
(music fades)
(loud clattering)
(kissy noises)
(bird chitters)
"My dearest niece."
"It’s have been a long time..."
(chuckles)
(soft pop music plays)
(boat horn blows)
(indistinct chatter)
...tenth decimal.
Oh, that’s it!
Damnit! I’ve been trying
to debug that program
for the whole week.
My God!
I don’t know about your guy,
but my guy should be
a nice-looking Chinese guy
who is perfectly circumcised.
-Perfectly?
-Perfectly.
(laughing)
(running footsteps)
(heels clicking)
Thank you, dear.
(slurping) Mm.
(sighs)
What do you have to say
about your report card, son?
Nothing.
Professor Chuang
just called.
He said you only showed up
for his Chinese 1 class once.
Ha.
I have been going
to Chinese class
ever since I can remember.
You know what?
I never got to watch
Bugs Bunny.
Son, nobody should deny
his own cultural background.
Although we sent you
to Chinese school every year,
but you still
don’t speak Chinese!
(chatter)
(soft patting)
(muffled music plays)
(water trickling)
(makes honk noise)
(sighs)
Ahh.
(laughing)
(clears throat)
(sings in Italian)
(laughing)
(continues singing)
(panting)
We’ve been preparing
for a trip to Peking
for the last five years.
He has a standing invitation
from his sister in Peking.
And the China Computer Society.
I even took him
seriously once
and took a class in Chinese.
I thought you spoke Chinese.
Can’t you tell?
I’m an American.
Right.
No, I don’t know
about our President Wilson.
He’s so indecisive.
Ah.
I mean, it’s only natural.
After all, you’ve been in charge
of that PC Division
for the past four years now.
I only did the technical part
of the project.
You have done all this
administrative work, haven’t ya?
Well, somebody
must mop the floor.
Not that I enjoy it.
I was told to do it.
Hey, Jimmy!
How are you doing?
Hey, Leo.
Congratulations,
I heard the word
about you becoming the new
director of the PC Division.
-Thank you.
-You really deserve it.
But it hasn’t been
official yet.
Today, we are going to
have new lesson.
Listen to me carefully.
(laughing)
"My hometown
is a beautiful place.
It stands beside
a wide river
at the foot of low green hills.
It has many fine buildings
and very wide streets.
There are trees and flowers
everywhere."
"But it has not always been
like that."
"In the old days,
it was a sad,
dirty little town."
(giggling)
Do you understand that?
(laughing)
River.
(bell ringing)
(chatter)
(inaudible whispering)
(coin jangles on ground)
(clap)
(giggling)
Ni hao.
(insects chirring)
Well, Jim here’s
already discussed
our income for the year.
Keep it up, gentlemen,
and Frances.
Ah.
Our PC computer,
Comprecot,
has been very competitive
thanks to Leo, Neil,
and their fellow workers.
It therefore should come
as no surprise
that we’ve decided to establish
a new PC Division.
(screen retractor whirring)
The new director
of this PC Division is...
Mr. Neil Mahoney.
(indistinct whispering)
And Comprecot’s inventor,
Leo Fang,
has been promoted
to headquarters
as senior member
of the technical staff
to our senior vice president.
(telephone ringing)
Five years ago, you told me
I didn’t have enough experience
to be the director.
Now, Neil Mahoney
has less experience
than I had five years ago!
There are other considerations.
-Like what?
-Well, such as youth.
Neil is younger than you.
Oh, you’re telling me
I’m too old for this job.
No, I don’t mean that at all.
Now look, Neil has lots
of good qualities.
Now, listen to me, Leo!
Neil. Neil doesn’t know
the system well.
He’ll learn! He’ll learn.
Look, you have a real good job,
very high up in the company.
Hardly any hassle.
Let me tell you
what I think you’re thinking.
Let me tell you.
You don’t believe the Chinaman
is good enough
to be the director,
that’s what you’re thinking.
(soft music)
(door slams)
(telephone ringing)
(dramatic music)
(beeping)
(forcefully sniffs)
Forty years.
(coffee pouring)
(gasps)
Damn.
(music continues)
(softly blows)
(beeping)
Mr. Wilson?
Wilson!
(dramatic musical chord)
(operatic singing)
(soft piano music)
(singing continues)
(insects chirring)
If you want to study
English well,
you must study hard.
(sips)
That means memorizing
the dictionary.
(sips)
When I was young,
I used to memorize
50 words a day.
(urinating)
(grunts)
(giggling)
(moaning)
Let’s get married.
-Come on.
-Now.
Your father
might come home early.
He pretends he’s in China now.
Paul, are you really
going to China this summer?
Actually, I don’t think we’re
ever really gonna get there.
Hm.
You know what?
What?
I don’t think he
really wants to go.
Why not?
Because...
reality often produces
disappointments.
Funny old man.
Hey, everybody!
I have an announcement to make.
I got tickets
for our vacation.
One month or even longer!
-How’s that?
-Pop!
-For real?
-You bet.
(laughing)
What--you--
we’re all going?
We all go. We deserve it.
You deserve it,
I deserve it.
We finally deserve it.
Oh my--
You mean like all four of us?
(laughing)
Oh.
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
(sneakers squeaking)
(soft music)
Bay, B-A-Y.
(giggling)
"Four score
and seven years ago,
our fathers brought forth
on this continent, a new nation,
a new nation,
conceived in Liberty,
and dedicated to the proposition
that all men are created equal.
We here highly resolve
that this nation, under God,
shall have not...
shall have a new birth
of freedom...
and that government
of the people,
by the people,
for the people,
shall not perish
from the earth."
(giggling, clapping)
(chuckling)
(tender music)
Um, I’m leaving.
-Hi.
I’m leaving.
Hi, Mr. Fang.
Have a pleasant trip.
Bye, Linda.
(groans)
(football game plays on TV)
What’s wrong, Romeo?
Father.
(TV chatter continues)
Gimme a break.
(sighs)
Who’s playing?
49ers against Broncos.
Hey, I thought you stopped
seeing Linda.
I will.
When I’m in China.
What ever happened
to that nice Chinese girl,
Margaret Wei?
She’s going out
with some white guy.
(TV chatter continues)
You know...
Why don’t you like
Linda as my friend?
You know, the only reason
why you don’t like her
is ’cause she’s not Chinese.
Come on, I never suggested
anything like that.
It’s true.
All Chinese parents
are racists.
What are you talking about?
Hey!
You use the tradition
and the culture
to cover up the racism.
Really!
Why do we have to do everything
the Chinese way anyway?
It gets you nowhere.
This is America, ya know?
You’ve lived here for so long
and you still talk
with an accent.
What’s wrong with my accent?
I think it’s rather cute.
What’s the weight limit
on each suitcase again?
(grunts)
-44 pounds.
-Yes, yes! Sack him! Sack him!
Sack him--oh.
Here’s an interesting
paragraph
about the city of Peking.
Listen.
"Peking is a city--"
Peking is a city
surrounded by walls.
Big, thick walls.
What? Why?
To keep the invaders out
or to confine the natives in.
It is just as difficult
to leave the city
as to go back.
What does your sister say
in the letter?
Oh...they still didn’t do
anything about father’s grave.
-Oh no.
-(gong rings)
(mellow electronic music)
(traffic passing)
Where’s the wall?
"The Great Wall is located
60 miles northwest of the city."
I don’t mean that wall.
"The wall of Peking City
was torn down
right after liberation
for the purpose of expanding
the nation’s capital."
Gee, what do you know?
China expert, huh?
The guidebook
doesn’t lie all the time.
Those damn high-rises.
(music continues)
(engine buzzing)
Leo told me all about you.
Hey, Lili.
(baby crying)
Sorry.
(murmur of chatter)
(soft music)
(birdsong)
(insects chirring)
(indistinct chatter)
He’s asking about your cooking,
your Chinese cooking.
Oh!
I only know how to cook
beef noodles.
What do you do for fun
at school?
Huh?
Um...for fun?
(giggling)
We don’t play.
We...study.
Do you play sports?
-Sports?
-Sports.
I play ping-pong.
Oh, no kidding?
That’s great. That’s great!
That used to be my sport.
They want us to move in.
Well prepared.
Leo, do you think they like me?
Sure.
They’re crazy about you,
believe me.
I feel like I’ve known them
for a long time.
Of course.
You all belonged to the same
herd of cattle
in your previous lives.
Dad?
Hm?
They don’t have
a shower bath here.
Too bad.
Are you warm enough, Paul?
Are you kidding? I’m hot.
(insects chirring)
They have squat toilets.
Yeah.
I don’t think
I’ve quite developed
the leg muscles for them.
You need practice.
Oh, shut up.
Go to sleep, will ya?
(click)
(crackling)
(commotion)
(insects chirring)
(sighs)
(thunder rumbling)
(gong rings)
(mellow music)
(tender music)
(solemn music)
Sonny? Come here.
Here’s the old man
I told you about.
He’s funnier than you and I
put together.
Funny man.
(birds chittering)
(solemn music)
(rumble of engines)
(upbeat pop music)
(laughs)
(music continues)
(overlapping chatter)
(laughter)
(grunts)
(birds chirping)
(flatulence)
I can’t believe this.
Look at this.
She reads all your mail!
Well, haven’t you ever heard
of a thing called privacy?
Privacy?
-Privacy.
(laughs)
Yeah, all right.
I guess there’s no such a thing
in China.
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
(inaudible)
Thanks.
(indistinct conversation)
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
Thank you.
(upbeat funky music)
-Paul?
-Hm?
(giggling)
Oh, hey, hey, hey,
look at this.
What do you think?
"Put the...
Put the Great Wall
On Your Chest."
(laughing)
Hey? Look.
This is just what Linda needs.
Hey, I’ll buy it.
(indistinct chatter,
playful banter)
He’s running,
he’s zigzagging,
he’s slipping through!
What!
It’s a touchdown! Oh my God!
(birds cawing)
The Great Wall was built
thousands of years ago
to prevent invaders
from the north.
Didn’t work.
Nope.
The invaders are from the south.
(soft music)
(wind blowing)
(cicadas chirring)
(leaves rustling)
(shoes clicking on tile)
(indistinct conversation)
(door squeaks)
(equipment whirring)
(keys clacking)
(shrill whir of printer)
Crazy.
Ah-ha! This character is wrong.
No, this only
simplified version.
(chuckling)
(insects chirring)
(laughing)
He speaks Chinese all the time
with his relatives
and his Chinese friends
in the States.
He earns $0 now.
(laughter)
That was a cup of hot coffee.
Very hot.
Leo! What are you talking about?
Never mind.
(chuckles)
Oh, Chinese fabrics
are so beautiful.
It’s too bad they don’t pay more
attention to fashion design.
Oh, it’s too short.
Too short.
Don’t you think
it’s too long?
Long? Too long?
(she laughs)
I don’t think I could
fit into this.
Gee, I’m too old
for a maternity dress!
Oh, you’re gonna sew it.
(tender music)
(snipping)
(rapid clicking)
Oh, it’s too big!
I haven’t been this big
since I had Paul!
Look at me.
I look pregnant.
Oh, gee.
It’s too--look at it!
(tender music)
Oh, there.
Look. Look!
(giggling)
No, no, no, no!
Oh, you look lovely.
Wrinkles?
No, you don’t have any wrinkles.
Oh, when you were young.
Oh, you had a lot of guys.
Well, he’s a little overweight.
(imitates loud sipping)
Weekends,
he watches TV all weekend.
Watch football, football.
Go, go, go!
(tongue click)
(snores)
-Oh, Leo does the same thing!
-Mama!
(mellow music)
Who’s Linda?
Oh, she’s just one
of Paul’s friends.
Paul has many friends.
He’s very popular.
(cicadas chirring)
(music continues)
(pop music)
(heels clicking)
(giggling)
(chuckling)
(cicadas chirring)
Hey, Mom!
Here she is!
(sings playfully)
(laughing)
(indistinct conversation)
(cicadas chirring)
(soft music plays)
(murmur of crowd chatter)
(music quickens)
(upbeat music)
(clapping)
(soft pop music)
(tender music)
(soft squeak)
(insects chirring)
(door slams)
(soft erhu music)
(murmur of crowd chatter)
(inaudible conversation)
(bell dings)
(rumble of bus engine)
(murmur of crowd chatter)
(rumble of engine)
(traditional music and singing)
(giggles)
-Listen, Dad.
-Huh?
(indistinct whispering)
Running out again?
(indistinct mumbling)
What a guy!
-Too much, Dad.
-Hey, hey, hey, hey.
(Leo chuckles)
Sexually very active.
(bell dings)
(burps, groans)
Gee.
(indistinct, drunken singing)
(laughing)
(giggling)
(dramatic drum music)
(lively traditional music)
(music continues)
(upbeat pop music)
(cicadas chirring)
(handheld game beeping)
Ooh, yeah.
(beep, exclamation)
Fourth down, 15 to go.
You’re dead.
-You want bet?
-Yeah.
-(beeping)
-Hey, touchdown!
-Lili.
-Beginner’s luck.
Lili!
-Broken there?
-Huh?
Oh, this?
No, you know, this, uh...
this is the style, you know?
It’s, uh, fashion.
This is the best, really.
Pierre Cardin,
I’m not kidding you.
(chuckling)
(sighs)
No.
You know, you don’t understand.
You know, these, uh...
you know, these here,
these are Calvin Kleins.
(lively guitar music)
Go
Go, Johnny, go, go
Go, Johnny,
go, go
Johnny B. Goode
(birds chirping)
(groaning)
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
How’s your ping-pong?
My coach says I’m gonna be
the best one in the bunch
if I could just
get my serve down.
You know, that, um...
that singles title coming up?
No problem, man,
I’m gonna take it.
Wow, you gonna play
against Liu?
Lili, didn’t your boyfriend
Liu win the title last year?
All right, this is gonna be hot.
Is it a major match?
I don’t know.
It’s major for me.
Look at those two guys
checking you out.
Look at this, they’re really
Why is a nice Chinese girl
like you
hanging around with
foreign devils like us?
Mom!
Your favorite niece
is in a funny mood.
Again.
Stop teasing her.
Give her some privacy.
Oh, come on, I’m cool.
When are we gonna eat?
Ready to move back
to the hotel tonight?
Huh?
Not really.
I’m kinda getting
used to this place.
Developing my leg muscles.
We’re moving back
to the hotel.
Your father told me
this morning.
Why?
Just because of Lili?
There is one thing
in this country
that causes more concern than
the Super Bowl game back home.
No kidding.
The annual college
entrance examination.
I know, I know.
It’s like a 1 in 100 chance
and, um, if you don’t make it,
then you have to sell tea
in the streets.
Well...I think Lili would make
a beautiful tea peddler.
Go inside and pack!
Okay!
(soft music)
(soft dramatic music)
(birds chirping)
(indistinct conversation)
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
(music fades, ends)
(indistinct whining)
(siren wailing)
(birds chirping)
(murmur of crowd chatter)
(bell ringing)
(soft dramatic music)
(sweepers whirring)
(hammering)
(murmur of crowd chatter)
(insects chirring)
(lively music and singing)
(radio clicks off)
So what?
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
(grunts)
(indistinct conversation)
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
(murmur of crowd chatter)
Next will be the final
for the men’s singles.
The competitors are Paul Fang,
a Chinese American player,
and champion of
the Youth Ping-Pong Tournament
and from Southwest
California, USA.
(whistling, applause)
(tense, dramatic music)
(tense upbeat music)
(applause)
(music continues)
(patter of ball
hitting paddles)
(applause)
(patter of balls
hitting paddles)
(murmur of crowd)
(cheering, applause)
The kid is killing it.
Yeah.
(cheering, applause)
(patter of ball
hitting paddles)
(applause, whistling)
(crowd quiets)
(tense music)
(music intensifies)
(cheering, applause)
(applause, cheering)
(patter of ball
hitting paddles)
(applause)
(patter of ball
hitting paddles)
(applause)
(slow, echoing taps)
(crowd roars
with applause, cheering)
(shower water trickling)
How do you feel,
dick breath?
Oh, great.
Super great.
(sighs)
You had a tough match today,
didn’t you?
You know, I play to win.
I hate losing.
I hate it so much.
Listen, Sonny, see,
you played the best game ever.
Well, you didn’t win
the championship,
but you know, you gave
the best performance
and gave it the best shot,
and that’s a victory
by itself.
Can’t you understand that?
You see, in each tournament,
there’s only one champ
but there are
many, many winners.
I think today
you’re one of them winners.
And the ping-pong game
you should look at this way:
it’s not a game--
Hey, Dad?
I’m kinda hungry, you know?
So, uh...why don’t you
save your bullshit?
Okay.
Okay. Let me treat you
to one of those, uh,
grand Peking duck feasts
with warm Coca-Cola.
Warm Coca-Cola.
Okay.
You know, if you want to
say it right,
you gotta say
"penis breath."
-Yeah?
-It’s penis breath.
How about, uh...
turkey tits?
(laughing)
That’s kinda old.
Yeah, I assume so.
(soft music)
Hi, Grace.
Mr. Wilson.
What a surprise.
My, you look lovely.
Oh, thank you.
It’s a Chinese peasant blouse.
-Elegant, elegant.
-Do come in.
How was your trip to China?
Oh, it was wonderful.
Oh, boy, you were gone
for how long--
People in America
think I’m too Chinese
and then people in China
think I’m too American.
What do you have
to say about that?
(speaks poorly in Chinese)
Bossman.
No, not exactly.
(speaks in Chinese)
(giggles)
(birds chirping)
The Chinese doctor
stuck needles in my back
and there was this
funny tingling sensation,
but it works.
Works like a charm.
Magic, magic.
Looking good, Leo!
(birds chirping)
(grunt, flatulence)
(sighs)
(rhythmic cymbal tapping
and drumming)
(indistinct whispering)
(giggling)
(whistles)
(applause)
(cymbal tapping
and drumming continues)
(chatter, commotion)
(lively traditional music)
(indistinct chatter)
(soft traditional music
and singing)
Quarterback, get up!
Game time.
(music and singing continue)
(soft drumming)
(lively drum music)
(singing and music continue)
(music and singing continue)
(singing ends)
(music ends)
(lion roars, snarls)