FEMALE NARRATOR: There is a charming tradition observed by the Adelie penguins.
Once a year,
during the mating season,
all the male birds gather
on the Antarctic beaches,
and there, each selects
an extraordinary pebble.
With pebble in hand,
each male presents his precious gift to the lady he most desires.
If she accepts it,
they mate for life.
♪ One perfect pebble
♪ Just one humble stone
♪ But, oh, what a stone
♪ Can do
♪ It means that I have
one love forever
♪ And one love alone
♪ A now and forever with you
♪ Now and forever
♪ I'll show her I care
♪ I'll find her
the rarest stone
♪ And maybe if the pebble
is perfect
♪ She'll tell me right there
♪ She's now and forever
♪ My own
Hey. How about you, Hubie?
You got a pebble
for your girl?
Well, you know, it's...
Not really.
♪ Now and forever
♪ We'll do like birds do
♪ We'll cuddle and coo
and kiss
[LAUGHING]
♪ We'll have a little world
where whatever
♪ We dream of comes true
♪ A now and forever
in bliss
Oh, this is all just
so exciting.
It's so romantic.Knock it off.
Romance has nothing
to do with it. Listen.
You know,
I don't think a pebble
should be that important.
Marina, if you don't
care about the pebble,
how will you choose?
How will you know
if it's Mr. Right?
MARINA:
♪ I will know when, Gwynne
♪ 'Cause it's not the pebble
♪ It's the penguin
♪ Now and forever
♪ His heart will be true
♪ That's how I'll know
who he is
♪ No matter if his pebble
is clever
♪ Or borrowed or blue
♪ I'll now and forever be his
Wow!
♪ Do you take this pebble
♪ Now and forever
♪ Do you take this penguin
♪ Do you
♪ I do
♪ We will grow old together
♪ Cozy and cold together
♪ We'll try our best together
♪ Now and forever
♪ As sure as the snow
♪ As long as the ocean roars
♪ I'll love you in a way
♪ That I'll never
♪ Begin to outgrow
♪ I'll now and forever
♪ Be yours
FEMALE NARRATOR: Of all the penguins in all the world, the most romantic was Hubie.
He had a secret
love in his life,
Marina, the most
beautiful girl penguin
in the rookery.
Hi, Hubie. Tell us a story.
Yes. A love story.
Oh, that's mushy stuff.
Oh, Beany!
[SCOFFS]
Well,
once there was a penguin
who fell in love
with the most
beautiful girl penguin
in the whole rookery.
Did she love him back?
They never even met.
You see,
he was painfully shy.
Well, one day,
he--he just swam up
to her and said,
"Hello, Marina. I'm Hubie,
and I think you're fabulous."
[ALL LAUGHING]
[SIGHING]
Who am I k-kidding?
[STUTTERING]
I mean, I never even
talked to the girl.
[SCREAMING]
[STUTTERING]
Goodness glaciers! Marina!
[CHUCKLING]
So, it wasn't an avalanche.
That was some landing, Hubie.
[GROANS]
[STUTTERING]
I'm sorry, Marina.
I'm just so clumsy.
MARINA: Oh,
don't be silly, Hubie.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
FEMALE NARRATOR: But someone else had his eye on the fair Marina.
Drake, an evil penguin
who always got his way.
That little wimp.
I'll knock the s-stutter
right out of him.
Marina doesn't know it yet,
but she's going
to be my wife.
Our children will
be the strongest,
the smartest, the bravest,
not to mention
the best looking.
Why, they'll be just like me.
[LAUGHING]
[GROWLS]
I'm telling you, boys,
Marina is as good as mine.
MARINA:
This is quite a spot, Hubie.
What do you do up here?
Well, um,
[CLEARS THROAT]
[STUTTERING]
I wonder about stuff.
Stuff? What kind of stuff?
I just... No.
You'd think it was silly.
I bet it's not silly at all.
Try me.
♪ Sometimes I wonder
♪ What the colors mean
♪ Why the sea is g-green
♪ Like your eyes
[GASPS]
I'm sorry.
Go on.
♪ Sometimes I wonder
♪ Why the moon is new
♪ Where the stars
are shooting to
♪ When they're
shooting through
♪ The skies
♪ There's wondrous things
♪ That I would like to know
♪ Like how they make the waves
♪ And turn the tides
♪ And then I wonder why
♪ I wonder so
♪ While other guys are busy
♪ Choosing brides
Oh, where was I?
"Choosing brides."
♪ Sometimes I wonder
♪ If there'll ever be
♪ Someone right for me
♪ Someone who may wonder too
♪ Who's wonderful
♪ Like y-y...
♪ I don't know
♪ Like...
[STUTTERING]
You must be bored to tears
with all this wacky nonsense.
Oh, no. I don't think
it's nonsense at all,
even if you are a bit wacky.
NARRATOR: The full moon
mating ceremony
was fast approaching.
The rookery
buzzed with excitement.
All the bachelors
took to the beaches
to find their
engagement pebbles.
And none was more determined
than Hubie.
He dove, scrambled, scrapped
and raced against
the best of them.
But try as he might,
Hubie couldn't hold
on to a single pebble.It's mine.
[PANTING]
I've nothing.
Poor Hubie.
With the day almost done,
and the beach picked clean of the best engagement stones,
how could he ever hope
to find the perfect pebble
for his perfect love, Marina?
"Star light, star bright
First star I see tonight
"Wish I may, wish I might
Have the wish
I wish tonight"
[HUMMING]
♪ Now and forever
♪ I'll show her I care
♪ I'll find her
♪ The rarest s-s-stone
♪ And maybe
if the pebble is... ♪
[GASPS]
Wow.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, my.
It's perfect.
Marina!
Has anyone seen Marina?
I got to find her.
I just got to find her.
Wait till she sees this.
It's perfect. Perfect!
MALE PENGUIN:
Hey, what's the holdup?
Somebody saw a leopard seal.
Oh, not today. I'm starving.
So, nerd.
I hear you want to
be a big ladies' man.
Marina is mine.
[STUTTERING] You big bully!
Wake up and
smell the seaweed,
you little fool.
Nobody's going to
marry a loser like you.
Now give me
that stupid pebble.
No, it's for Marina.
[LAUGHS]
Hope you can swim
better than you can t-talk.
Bye, Hubie.
Sleep with the fishes.
[SCREAMS]
[DRAKE LAUGHING]
Hi, guys.
Hey, look. The water's safe.
Let's eat.
Oh, boy.
Hubie!
[SCREAMS]
[PANTING]
MARINA: Hubie!
HUBIE: Marina!
FEMALE NARRATOR: Huddled against the wind and buffeted by the storm,
Hubie was swept far away
to warmer waters
where there lived an enemy even greater than the leopard seal.
Man.
FEMALE PENGUIN: So sweet.
MALE PENGUIN: Oh, look.
I think he's coming around.
Welcome back, lad.
Where am I?
You're aboard
the good ship Misery.
You've been sleeping
for nearly three days now.
Three days?
I've been asleep
for three days?
I'm sure Marina
thinks I'm lost forever.
Marina?
My girl back home.
[CHUCKLING]
Why, you're our first Adelie.
What's your name?
Yes. Yes. What's your name?
I'm Hubie.
Welcome aboard, Hubie.
Although, "welcome"
probably isn't
the appropriate word.
Outrage!
That's the appropriate word.Yes.
Abomination.
The indignity.The indignity.
The horror.
♪ If you're into pain
and agony
♪ Agony
♪ If you love
the great indoors
♪ Welcome to
the good ship Misery
♪ The misery's all yours
♪ Every day begins with misery
♪ Misery
♪ Breakfast in a rusty cup
♪ Then we all get good
and miserable
♪ And then we all throw up
♪ The boots have got
the place so hot
♪ That soon you'll spot
you've got the rot
♪ And, ooh
♪ There's never sun♪ The rats have run
♪ Does anyone remember fun
♪ No
♪ If you're thinking
this could never be
♪ Think again
♪ If you're thinking
it's the Ritz
♪ Fat chance
♪ Sorry,
but the good ship Misery
♪ Is a reality
♪ Hubie, baby
♪ This is the pits
♪ You sit and think♪ And pray we'll sink
♪ Your muscles shrink♪ You start to stink
♪ And then they drop
that slimy slop
♪ And drop a glop
of slop on top
♪ So every day's
a total tragedy
♪ Tragedy
♪ Then the days begin to blur
♪ Getting bored aboard
the Misery
♪ Is a redundancy
♪ Why?
Is everybody miserable
♪ Now you're talkin'
♪ Yes, sir
MAN: Get a hold of them feet.
Here come the boots.
The boots!The boots!
[ALL CLAMORING]
MAN: Be quiet down there.
Blast it all, mate.
Let's get him down below.
Open the door, man.
Open the door.
Hold still, lad,
or I'll give you
a fist in the beak.
Now get in there
and stay there.
Come back here, you
yellow-bellied landlubbers.
Take a breather, laddie.
That door will
be there later.
I can promise you that.
Save it, old-timer.
Nobody locks up
Rocko the Rockhopper.
Those humans just did.
Hey. When I get out of here,
you're seal bait.
What are you
staring at, birdbrain?
That's Hubie,
and he's heartbroken.
Yes. He was snatched away
from the lady he loves.
Poor, poor pebblehead.
If he had any guts,
he never would've let
them take him alive.
So, where is this
floating scrapheap
headed, anyway?
Our destination
would be difficult to
determine at this juncture.
That means he doesn't know.That means he doesn't know.
Well, we be in warm waters.
We be in Bora Bora, Pops.
I know where we are.
Where do we dock?
That's what I'm asking.
We can't say for sure, lad,
but I've heard stories
of sailors selling
penguins to zoos.
Zoos?
I'm not going to no zoo.
No, no.
I'm going to the helmsman.
I'll go to the first mate.
I'll go all
the way to the captain
of this oversized dinghy.
I'll make him
turn this tug around
if I have to.
But I can't go to a z-zoo.
I've got to get
back to Antarctica.
Who's with me?
Who's for
busting out of here?
Come on, you jellyfish.
How about you, seal bait?
You?
Sorry, Mr. Rockhopper,
but free food
at the zoo sounds
awful good to me.
ROCKO: Bunch of
birdbrains and seal bait.
Get me out of here!
Get me somebody!
WOMAN 1: Marina,
Hubie is gone.
Face it. Forget him.
WOMAN 2: Why don't you
just marry Drake?
No, Priscilla.
I believe Hubie
is still out there somewhere,
and he'll come
home to me in time
for the full moon
mating ceremony.
You're saying you
want to marry him?
I do.
How could you possibly choose a wimp like Hubie over a hunk like Drake?
Hubie's a sweetheart.
He's generous and kind,
and he's always
thoughtful of others,
and...
Good morning, ladies.
[ALL SIGHING]
Marina, my pet.
I want you to be my mate.
Drake. Drake. I love Hubie.
Hubie?
I deeply sympathize, Marina,
but since he is
nowhere to be found,
I offer my own hand.
My answer is still no. Think about it.
Give me your answer later.
But remember.
You must choose a mate
before the full
moon mating ceremony
or be banished.
Gosh. That's the law.
I got just 10
days to get back home
before the full
moon ceremony.
Sir! Sir! Take me with you.
You talking to me?Yes, sir, I am.
Don't call me "sir."
Call me Rocko.
Rocko. Right. Yes.
Well, Rocko,
it's about my girl.
Wait, wait, wait.
You want me to spring you
out of this joint
so you can go home
to Miss Wonderful,
right?
Yes. Yes.
You're right. You see,
there's another guy
who's after my girl.
Forget it.But a moment ago,
you asked who's for
busting out of here.
Well, I am.You're too dumb.
Take me, please.Why should I?
[STUTTERING] Well,
because if the humans see me
tripping all over myself,
that'll divert
their attention to me,
giving you more
time to escape.
Like I really
need a diversion.
I could squawk and yell
and make horrible noises.
[GROANING]
[LAUGHING]
Well, you made me laugh.
Give me a chance, please.
I'll bring the house down.
What's your name?Hubie.
Well, uh, Hubie.
All right. You're on.
Yeah, go for it, Hubie.
But, hey, once we're on deck,
it's every man for himself.
Yes, sir!
Okay, Hubie. Here's how
you're gonna break
out of that cage.
Now,
I want you to pay attention.
Watch my beak.
[BELL RINGING]
Have you got everything?
This is all I need.
[MAN SINGING]
Here come the boots.
Okay, kid.
This is it. Get ready.
Ahoy, mateys.
Get your gullets ready
for the sloppiest slop
that ever graced
a galley's garbage.
You don't know how
lucky you are, matey.
[LAUGHS]
[HUMMING]
Now, I don't want no trouble
from you today.
Well, now.
That's more like it.
[LAUGHING]
Come back here, you...
Come back.
What's going on down there...
ROCKO: Come on, Hubie.
Let's go!
There's two of them out now.
Let me go!
Come on. Take your best shot.
I'm out of here.
Come on, Hubie. Come on.My pebble!
Forget the blasted pebble!
[WHOOPING]
[ALL CHEERING]
Charlie!
He's heading for the side.
Come on! Let's go!
So long, Hubie.
I'm out of here.
Please don't leave me.
Wait till I get
my hands on you.
ROCKO: You can stop
following me now.
You're on your own now.
Come on.
[BOTH GROANING]
Hey. Where are we?
Let's see.
Judging by the heat,
I'd say I'd died
and went to Phoenix.
Rocko, look. People.
Looks like some
private beach.
We must be in
Moorea or Tahiti.
How do they live like this?
They pay for it.
I wonder how far
it is to Antarctica.
Three thousand
miles in that direction,
but you'll never make it.
I will so. I'm fit.
Hey, trust me on this one.
You've got "Eat me"
written all over you.
I'm a good swimmer.
You don't know these waters
like I do, birdbrain.
You're right. I'm lost.
Yep. You're lost.
And I'm looking
at a dead penguin.
Yeah,
I give it two days, tops,
and you'll be in
the belly of anything
from a killer
whale to a sardine.
Getting back to Marina
is all that matters to me.
I mean, Rocko, look.
I dream about
her night and day.
I see her face
when I close my eyes.
And this. Just look at this.
Wow.
Is that an engagement pebble,
or what?
Do you have to
gush like that?
You're probably
asking yourself
where I got it, right?
Yes.Picture this.
Pebble beach,
moonlit sky, gentle breeze.
Come on. Come on. Get to it.
Suddenly,
I look up and there it is.
The first evening star.
Summarize. Summarize.
What do I do? I make a wish.
And, like magic,
it jets across the sky
in a blaze of glory
and comes to rest at my feet.
Really?
I pick it up, and there,
shining deep inside, is...
There is the face
of my own true love, Marina.
Oh, so special.
So unique. So what!
Don't you see?
It's my fate, Rocko.
I'm destined to marry Marina.
It's in the stars.
"I'm destined
to marry Marina.
It's in the stars."
Why don't you get
that thing fixed?
Oh, I'm sorry. I--I guess
nobody likes a blabbermouth,
right?
No. You think?
There.
I'm free of you at last.
Now go away. Shoo. Adios.
Boy.
You're really one grumpy guy
in the morning, aren't you?
No. I'm grumpy all day.
What happened?
Did your girl run off
with another penguin?
No. She did not.
Oh, then she's
waiting for you, right?
Look,
will you stop following me?
You know what you need?
You need a dream.
I got one.What is it?
I'm sure not gonna tell you.
Your secret's safe with me.
I don't even know you.
I won't laugh.
Forget it!It doesn't matter
how silly it sounds.
Get away!I promise.
Cross my heart.
I won't laugh.
All right.
All right. All right.What?
I got something.
What is it?
You're looking at it.
I'm looking at...
[STUTTERING]
You want to fly, do you?
Don't laugh.
Rocko, everybody knows
penguins can't f-fly.
You're wrong!
You are dead wrong.
[CHUCKLING]Our ancestors flew.
They gave us wings,
but we can't fly?
I mean...
I mean, whose idea of
a cruel joke is this?
I mean... I mean,
you've got to just accept it.
No. No.
I don't accept nothing.
But, Rocko,
that's the way things are.
I want to fly. I'm gonna fly,
and no one's gonna stop me.
I'm flying.
Flap them.
Flap them. Flap them.
[SCREAMING]
[WHOOPING]
Don't laugh.
Nobody laughs at
Rocko the Rockhopper.
That's funny.
You see, I expected you to
tell me something big,
really stupendous.
You know,
like hopping up the slopes
of Mt. Everest or something,
you know.
But flying?
Oh, for heaven's sakes.
That's so easy.
Says who?
Waldo, that's who.Waldo?
Yeah. He's-- He's...Who's Waldo?
Waldo is
a short little penguin
back in my rookery.
Yeah? Really?
Yes, really. And listen,
he claims to have gotten
the hang of flying.
And his wings
are a lot
stubbier than yours.
Hey, hey, hey.
These aren't stubs.
Oh, but...
There I go being
a big blabbermouth again.
Wait. Wait. Come back here.
Thank you for
helping me escape, Rocko.
I've got to go, though.
Wait. Wait.
Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
I must be back
before the next full moon.
Marina needs me. Goodbye.
Wait, wait. You're lost.
That way's north.
Oh. I--I just...
I just remembered something.
I think Waldo said
the secret to
flying was wind speed.
Well, anyway.Wind speed.
Off I go.You know, that's right.
That's exactly what I think.
That's what I've
been working on.
That's my theory.
Wind speed, see?
You know, that's amazing,
that there's...
Someone else
knows about that.
Well, come here.
What else did Waldo say?
Can we swim as we talk?
Marina's waiting.
Yeah, sure. Why not?
I got a couple
of days, anyway.
Which way is south?
Uh, that way.
I want to meet
this Waldo character.
Waldo?
You get me and
Waldo together,
and I'll get you
to the Antarctic
by the next full moon.
Oh, I like the sound of that.
DRAKE: Well,
there's only eight days left
before the full
moon mating ceremony,
and Marina still won't agree
to be my mate.
Although,
my faithful servants,
we have seen
that Hubie is
a leopard seal meal.
It's a pleasant thought
that that stupid
little p-p-penguin nerd
will never return.
[LAUGHING]
Silence, you idiots!
Marina is mine.
[HORN BLOWING]
So, what happens
if you don't make it on time?
Oh, that's too
horrible to even think about.
Well, think about it.
Who would Marina marry?
Drake!Drake?
Why, is he any
good with the ladies?Yeah.
Well, Captain,
full speed ahead.
Here we go.
We only have five
days left, Rocko.
We're running out of time.
Look.
We can't swim in this storm,
unless you want to die.
Maybe Drake will
leave Marina alone.
Yeah, well, maybe Drake
has already married Marina.
No. No. I know my girl.
She'll wait.
And if she
accepts this pebble,
we'll be married.
If she accepts the pebble?
You mean, you're not sure
if she's gonna
accept the pebble?
[LAUGHS]
You mean, you're going
through all this trouble
and you're not even sure?
She'll accept it.
Oh, come on.
It's beautiful. It's...
It's perfect.
Yes, it is perfect,
isn't it, Rocko?
There, that ledge.Rocko.
We have discovered
an authentic
ancient "aviarial" airstrip.
What?
This is beautiful.
This is it.
[STUTTERING] You're not gonna
try to fly again, are you?
Oh, you bet your
tail feathers I am.
Rocko, penguins can't fly!
Feel that wind.Rocko!
Where's your
sense of adventure?
This is
the chance of a lifetime.
This is the end
of a lifetime.
Wind speed, perfect.
Altitude, perfect.
Tail feathers, perfect.
Wing, span, wind,
sky, airlift!
Rocko, don't.
You're gonna k-kill yourself.
Hubie, watch.
I'm flying! I'm flying!
Yes. Yes.
Oh, wind speed.
Wind speed,
not enough wind speed.
[GROANING]
HUBIE: Goodness glaciers.
Rocko, are you all right?
Rocko!
Get away from me.But I just...
Don't touch me.
Just get away.
I was just trying to...
I don't need any help.
Just get away from me now.
Fine. S-Suit yourself.
I will. Just keep going.
Go back to little green eyes
or whatever her name is.
[STUTTERING]
Well, maybe I will.
Yeah, go.
See how long you
last on your own.
Hubie. No!
No. I mean, no, wait.
So you decided
to apologize, huh?
Well, then, I...
Don't be stupid.
I don't apologize to anybody.
Look.
[WHALE SCREECHING]
That, pebblebrain,
is a killer whale.
The meanest killing machine
in these waters.
Goodness glaciers!
You saved my life.
No. Come on.
Don't get all whiny about it.
Just go. Go,
go play with your pebble.
It's no big deal. Just go.
Go. Leave me alone.
No, I'm serious.
I could've been killed.
I'm starting to wish you had.
Just go, will you?
Can't you even admit
that you like
me just a little?
What? I don't like you.
I hate you.
I just happen to
hate killer whales
a little bit more
than you, that's all.
Is that so?
Yeah.Well, then, fine.
Fine is right.
When the whale leaves,
we'll just go our
separate ways, then.
Yeah. Well,
sounds good to me.
I don't need to
be seen with...
[SCREAMING]
Fire in the sky!
Hide, hide, hide, hide!
That's it.
Hey, what is that?
Who's that?
What are you doing? Who...
Get your own shelter.
I was here first.
So, I'm here second.
So what? Move!
DRAKE: So, Marina.
When should I
announce our engagement?
Today? Tomorrow? Wednesday?
Drake, I wouldn't marry you
if you were
the last penguin on Earth.
Don't worry.
I'll make it official
with the obligatory
pebble and all that.
The answer is no.
No? No?
Oh, I get it. You're joking.
[LAUGHING]
What's so funny?
♪ Don't make me laugh
[LAUGHING]
♪ My funny friend
♪ Don't make me bend in half
♪ Don't be a card, babe
♪ Don't mess with Drake
♪ Don't make me laugh so hard
♪ That you begin to ache
♪ Don't make me laugh
♪ Don't pull my leg
♪ May I suggest
♪ You would do best to beg
♪ If you say no, Miss
♪ If you refuse
♪ This is your notice
♪ That I refuse to lose
♪ Say yes, my love
♪ And go with a winner
♪ Believe me
♪ That would be wiser
♪ Say no, poor dove
♪ And you're a shark's dinner
♪ And Hubie's the appetizer
[LAUGHING]
♪ Get the picture?
♪ Don't make me laugh
♪ Or slap my knee
♪ I'm no hyena
♪ So, Marina, what'll it be
♪ Right this way
to the Drake estate
♪ Or write your epitaph
♪ You choose your fate
♪ Don't make me wait
♪ And, baby
♪ Don't make me laugh
[LAUGHS]
[SNORING]
Hey, Rocko. Wake up.
Rocko, look.
What? What? Where?
Isn't it beautiful?
Yeah. I mean, it's...
Well, I mean,
it certainly looks better
than a killer whale.
It's our first sight of home.
We're almost there.
Look. It's all right
if--if you wanna split up.
I understand.
No hard feelings.
Well, it's probably
for the best.
Hey, give my regards to Waldo.
Waldo? Waldo.
Oh, yeah. I sure will. I...
Rocko, there's something
you should know.
Waldo...
Waldo isn't real.
What?
I needed you to
show me the way home.
I--I didn't think you'd do it
if I just asked, so I...
So I made up stories
about a make-believe guy
named Waldo.
Well, say something.
You told me a lie?
You dumb penguin nerd.
Rocko, stop!
I could've been
back in Tahiti
with those
people on the beach...I'm sorry.
...feeding me
because I was
a cute little penguin.
I said I'm sorry.
No, you.
You decided to lie to me.Oh. Come on.
To drag me
through 3,000 miles
of water and killer whales.
You're a dead penguin.
You are a...
Clear!
Clear that beak! Clear!
[CHOKING]
[LAUGHING]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
You're either
the greatest romantic hero
of all time,
or you're
the stupidest penguin
who ever lived.
HUBIE: I'm sorry I
lied to you, Rocko.
Who likes a liar? Not me.
I really needed your help.
Look. If--If you're ever down
near the South Pole,
please look me up.
[CHUCKLING]
In four days, birdbrain,
I'll be in Antarctica.
Where will you be, huh?
Rocko!Come on. Try to keep up.
HUBIE: Great.
ROCKO: Looks like I got
me a new student.
You know
anything about fighting?
Well, how do you handle pain?
What?
Oh, just kidding!
How about blood?
♪ Sometimes I close my eyes
♪ And say a prayer
♪ That finally
♪ Today will be the day
♪ I watch the far horizon
♪ No one's there
♪ But somewhere you are safe
♪ And on your way
♪ Oh, Hubie
♪ Sometimes I wonder
♪ If you're still alive
♪ How could you survive
♪ Such a dangerous
world out there
♪ Beware my love
♪ Take care my love
♪ Take care
[GROANS]
Rocko,
I don't think I can walk.
Hey. How big
is this Drake guy?
I could have a broken bone.
You're gonna
have to fight him.
I'm what?You have to put
Drake in his place.
Well, I'm not a fighter.
I'll teach you.I've never hit anyone.
Look, the first
thing you need to know
about winning
is how to bluff.
Rocko, I can't.
Do you love the girl?Of course, I do. I...
Then shut up.
Put your fins up,
your neck back.
Put your feet out.
Balance, balance, balance.
Okay. Now make a face.
Give me your meanest look.
Like this?
No! Like this.
Well, you know what?
That's fantastic.
It's a bluff.
I'm tougher than any bird.
Why, I'm tougher
than any polar bear.
Why, I'm hungry.
What do we have here?
Looks like
a seal's fishing hole.
[STUTTERING]
Do you think it's safe?
I'm too hungry to
care if it's safe or not.
Let's go.
How much farther
to the Antarctic?
I don't know.
It could be a few miles.
It could be a few days.
Who cares? Come on.
A few days.
[STUTTERING] I don't think I
could wait that long.
So, you wanna go first?
What?
Well,
if you're not brave enough...
Hey. Who says I'm
not brave enough?
Then, I'll go.
I'm brave enough.
Come on. Let's go.
One, two, three. Go.
[SCREAMING]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[COUGHING]
You idiot!
You almost got me killed.
What's the matter with you?
You risk your life to
get back to that chick
and give her
that blasted pebble.
You're crazy!
You're insane! You're...
[LAUGHING] You are amazing.
Amazing? Me?
What? No, no,
I didn't say that.
Yes, you did. I heard you.
No, no, no.
I didn't say that.
No, no, no, no.
Get out of my face.
I didn't say
nothing like that.
You do like me.
I don't like anybody.
[STUTTERING] Oh, yes, you do.
And I knew it all along.
Get away from me.
Hey, Rocko.
I guess this means
we've put our
differences on ice.
Get it, huh?
Put our differences on ice?
I'd like to put you on ice.
♪ Look how we
get along together
♪ I think it's great
the way we b-b-blend
♪ You've tried to be
as tough as leather
♪ But now I see
that's just pretend
♪ We'll find our way
through stormy weather
♪ Just you and me
right to the end
♪ Hey, buddy
♪ Looks like we're
two birds of a feather
♪ And gee, it looks like
I've got me a friend
♪ Now you go
Take it, Rocko.
Hey, Rocko.
What do you call
a flower before it opens?
What?
What do you call
a f-flower before it opens?
A bud.
I love it when
you call me bud.
♪ Look how we
get along together
♪ You are incredibly annoying
♪ Just like the way we planned
♪ You're like a bone
stuck in my throat
♪ You've tried to be
as tough as leather
♪ This isn't something
I'm enjoying
♪ But now I see
that's just pretend
♪ I should have left you
on that boat
♪ We'll find our way
through stormy weather
♪ You want a friend
go find a snail
♪ Just you and me
right to the end
♪ Or better yet a killer whale
♪ Looks like we're
two birds of a feather
♪ And gee, it looks like
I've got me a friend
♪ Now you try
Take it, Rocko.
Hey, Rocko.
I caught you a herring.
Where should I put it?
What?I caught you a herring.
Put it there.
Put it there?
All right.
Oh, stop it.
♪ When you're a rebel
you're a rebel
♪ Look, you like me
just admit it
♪ You don't go finding
friends to like
♪ All right.
I'm gonna hold my breath.
♪ Why don't you pack
your blasted pebble
♪ Quit it, admit it
♪ And take yourself
a healthy hike
♪ You know you're gonna
cause my death!
♪ They don't have penguins
up in Juneau
♪ It's getting dark
♪ Why don't you go
and start a trend
Goodbye, Rocko.
Oh, knock it off.
Hey. Hey, you're all blue.
Breathe, you birdbrain.
Hubie!
Say it!
♪ All right, then
♪ I kind of, sort of maybe,
you know
♪ You mean you like me
♪ A little
♪ You mean it♪ Don't push it
BOTH: ♪ Looks like
I got me a friend ♪
[BOTH LAUGHING]
We really showed him.
We showed him? We?
Oh, come on.
You're a terrible fighter.
FEMALE NARRATOR:
As they continued
their journey home,
Rocko was
determined to teach Hubie
that it wasn't enough
simply being in
love with Marina.
The time would come
when he would have
to fight for her.
But with Drake
as his opponent,
would he be up
to the challenge?
[WHOOPING]
I won. I won. I won. I won.
I beat you by a mile.
You're blind as a bat.
I was winning, man.
I won the whole way.
I was way in front of you.
Rocko!I left you in the cold.
Come on.
[THUDDING]
Goodness glaciers!
What was that?
Looked like a killer whale.
[STUTTERING] It was bigger
than a leopard seal.
Twice as big, twice as fast
and twice as mean.
Oh, good.
But that's not
the worst part.
Wonderful.
What's the worst part?
Killer whales
always travel in groups.
What?Groups.
Oh, no.Big groups.
Lots. Oodles and oodles.
What do we do now?
We... We...
You see that iceberg?What iceberg?
That one! Swim for it.
Swim?Or we could fly.
My pebble.Pebble? Your pebble.
My pebble.Forget about
the blasted pebble.
I don't want to
hear "pebble" from you.
All right. Swim for the berg.
I'll lead them away.
No. If you stay, I stay.
No. Go on. Go on.
I'll lead them away. Go on.
Now. Let's go.
Faster. Faster. Come on.
Swim for the berg.
Come on. Go. Go. Go. Go.
Move it. Move it. Move it.
[WHOOPING]
Rocko!
Oh, no. Oh, Rocko.
Marina's gone.
She ran away.
No. Drake kidnapped her.
Hurry up!
He can't force
her to marry him.
I know, but he'll try.
I wish Hubie was here.
[DRAKE LAUGHING]
DRAKE: As I said, my pretty,
I refuse to lose.
You're hurting me.
Then get smart.
Yes, or be banished.
You'll never get me.
But, precious,
you'll only starve.
Stop it.
Let me go.
Get your filthy
flippers off my girl!
Hubie!
What the...
Hubie. We thought
you were dead.
You heard me, Drake!
Now you're gonna
wish that you were.
[LAUGHING]
That was easy enough. Marina.
Let me go!
Hubie! Oh, no!
Come on.
Let's get him on his feet.
Help me, Timmy.
I can't. He's too heavy.
Wake up! Oh, hurry!
Hubie, you must save Marina.
Wake up, Hubie!
Come on, Hubie.
You can do it.
[GRUNTING]
Hubie, come on.Get up.
Get up!Get up!
Now, open your eyes.
Go knock his block off!
I didn't come 3,000 miles
and lose my best buddy
to be stopped by
the likes of you!
Drake!
Come on! Take your best shot!
[YELLING]
Come on!
Hubie!
Drake, let go.
[CRUNCHING]
I'll teach you to bite me.
MARINA: Hubie!
[GROANS]
I'm sorry.
Oh, Marina.
Will you be my mate?
I thought you
would never ask.
Oh, Hubie's wonderful.
ROCKO: Hubie.
Rocko!
Hey, Romeo!
Rocko?
Goodness glaciers. Rocko!
Oh, oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I can't believe you're alive!
[MARINA SCREAMING]
Say your prayers, you...
Help.
Somebody.
Hey, Rocko. Hey, Rocko.
Hold on, good buddy. Hold on.
All right. Give me
some slack. Don't let go.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Hold on, Hubie. Hold on.
Hubie!
I'm flying. I'm flying!
I'm flying!
He made it.
Hip, hip hooray!
[ALL CLAMORING]
Hubie.
Marina, I want you
to meet my best friend,
Rocko.
Rocko, Marina.
The flying Rocko.
Pleased, I'm sure.
Hey, hey, hey, Hubie.
You forgot your
blasted pebble.
My pebble. My pebble.
Rocko, you found it!
Don't just
stand there, Romeo.
Give the girl the pebble.
Do you like it?I love it.
You'd better.
Good.But don't you know?
It's not the pebble.
It's the penguin.
I love you even more.
[ALL CHEERING]
FEMALE NARRATOR:
So Hubie and Marina proved
that neither
distance nor danger
can stand in
the way of true love.
You need only
follow your heart.
And goodness glaciers,
they lived
happily ever after.
♪ It means that I have
♪ One love forever
♪ And one love alone
♪ A now and forever
♪ And ever and ever
♪ With you
♪ One perfect moment
♪ Just one humble stone
♪ But, oh, what a stone can do
♪ It means that I have
one love forever
♪ And one love alone
♪ A now and forever
♪ With you
♪ Now and forever
♪ As sure as the snow
♪ As long as the ocean roars
♪ I'll love you in a way
♪ That I'll never
begin to outgrow
♪ I'll now and forever
♪ Be yours
♪ From this blessed day
♪ All this whole life through
♪ Starting when we say
♪ I do
♪ Forever and ever
♪ And ever
♪ Now and forever
♪ Just one humble stone
♪ But, oh, what a stone can do
♪ It means that I have
♪ One love forever
♪ And one love alone
♪ A now and forever
♪ With you
♪ From this blessed day
♪ All this whole life through
♪ Starting when we said
♪ I do
♪ Forever and ever
♪ And ever
♪ Now and forever
♪ As sure as the sun
♪ As long as the ocean's blue
♪ I'll love you in a way
♪ That I'll never
begin to outgrow
♪ A now and forever
♪ And ever and ever
♪ And ever and ever with you
♪ Now and forever