THE WAY SOUTH
I leave my home In whatpeople call
a moderate cllmate.
The sulklng wolffrom the North
watches me go.
My sons are growlng up.
I am a man, It seems...
journeylng In my mlnd
when I'm standlng stlll.
Marklng tlme when I'm movlng.
I go from face to face.
In the slush of overproductlon,
dlsdaln...
madness and proflt-maklng.
I know
that even those who want to dle...
would rather live.
I belleve...
that everybody would Ilke to eat.
30 Aprll, Amsterdã.
The squat on Klnker street corner.
At flrst we fllmed In black
and whlte, llI at ease, nervous.
Tense about what was golng to happen.
No accommodation, no coronation!
There are going to be bands soon
and theatre groups.
There's going to be beer
and a stage.
Everything. Alcohol and all you need
for a party.
You're there, the house is there.
Form a chain.
Down with the riot squad!
Dlsperse or else we'll be forced
to use vlolence. Get out ofour way.
Llne up agaln. There's relnforcement
for the slde streets.
There was also a coronatlon that day.
The ellte puts the people's feathers
In thelr caps.
Ifonly that could stop.
The squatters still need
all sorts of things.
Mattresses, blankets,
camp beds, furniture...
radios...
toilet paper, cutlery, plates,
mugs...
If you have any of those,
please bring them to us...
so that we can use them.
Thanks a lot.
The city council is going to say
that they're not the owners.
That the squatters must contact
the owner...
and if he isn't planning...
to evict them straight away...
they should try to get him to sell
it to them for a reasonable price.
That's the first thing. Secondly...
we must come up with a plan...
or at least cooperate
in developing a plan...
for redevelopment.
Then there's the reconstruction itself.
I think it's fine to try that...
but we should now
be doing our own restructuring.
The architect only calculated
the cost of the materials.
He expected us
to do the work ourselves.
We must get in touch with people
who have done this before.
I helped friends with the conversion
for another group.
We should get them involved
as soon as possible to help.
But we must also apply
political pressure...
perhaps through friends
we have in local politics...
to find out
what the owner plans to do.
I'd like to round this point off.
You've all got things to do.
The legal help we get is free.
At number 53
they need metal bedsprings...
to use for barricading.
Bring anything you can find.
Beams of up to two metres long.
What do those metal bars look like?
With a 90-degree angle...
and holes to fasten them
to the walls.
I was wondering how we could get
very thick wire mesh...
like they use on the windows
of the riot squad vans.
We could rip it off and use it
in front of our own windows.
Screw it down on the inside.
The grid is too fine to put your hand
through and unscrew it on the inside.
The barricades must be really strong.
It's so easy to knock in the window.
Are there two volunteers
to do it before dinner?
I'll do it.
You promised you were going to cook.
- Ah, yes, that's right.
You? Can you two do it together?
Then there's the list
to be on patrol.
Hands up for patrolling tomorrow.
One, two... three, four... six.
Seven.
- At the door, from nine onwards.
I'll do tonight.
- Tonight as well for you?
All night?
- If there's no other volunteer.
No, no, no.
He's still new to it.
Put him on the list for three hours.
Twelve to three?
Have you got a job?
- No.
Ah, you can lie in.
In that case you can be on patrol
all night.
How long would you like to do?
- Midnight till six.
Got it.
LONG LIVE 1st MAY
FOR PEACE AND SECURITY
Down with the riot squad!
4 May. Remembrance Day
for the World War II dead.
I joined for very personal reasons.
Not as a result
of a histórical analysis.
It's more because...
your housing situation is terrible
and you see the same all around you.
It's the same for lots of people.
And by talking to people
or by reading about it...
or because you get to know
people in a squat...
you take the step...
to be active in a movement
that works for a lot of people.
It's at the same time the solution
of your own housing problem.
If the city policies
are so sluggish...
that we have to wait forever,
we take the initiative ourselves.
But then you've got
your first problem...
with democracy, because you bypass
the system that there is.
But the existing system
for the distribution of housing...
is inadequate.
You can either wait an eternity,
quietly...
until you can live normally...
or join a group, a large group
of people who are prepared...
to take things
into their own hands.
If there was enough housing
there'd be no squatters.
But the authorities aren't
addressing the problem...
so we're forced to.
The authorities have lost the power
to do anything about it.
Or that's what they keep saying.
We think that they can do something.
There's so much vacant office space.
These buildings aren't used while
so many people could live there.
Exactly. But the authorities
pretend to be powerless...
while they grant one planning
permit after another for offices.
It's the opposite of powerlessness.
It's a choice against people
needing accommodation.
That's the only way to look at it.
They had promised there would be
temporary apartments here.
And in some mysterious way...
a year later
there's an office block.
Where we're sitting now?
- Where we are now.
But you feel you are taking action
on behalf of other people, too?
For ordinary people.
- We are ordinary people.
Well, you could be described
as a group of students.
I think it's ridiculous
that they try to label us.
It's not right. There are all sorts
of people here. All young, though.
But most of them are
working young people, I think.
This is a very mixed bunch.
But I think it will happen, or it
already does, that squats arise...
for people
in a different position...
for whom it's a difficult step.
You see that in the women
who are now in refuge homes.
They don't feel capable
of organising a squat themselves...
so they join an existing group
and squat along.
You see that happening for
families, for foreign immigrants...
and that's a good thing.
You deliberately go for
a commune set-up.
What does that imply?
That you deliberately opt
for living
with a group of other people...
and do lots of things communally.
And why is that?
- Why we choose to live like that?
I think that, so far, we've been very
individualistic in our lives...
which was also encouraged
by society: having to have a career.
And then you discover
there are other ways of living...
than in a family home
with a fence and a garden.
That it's also possible to live
together with lots of people.
Loneliness if often the reason why
people live together or get married.
And then you notice
that when you split up...
you get thrown back on your own
resources...
but it's a big step to take.
One reason why I wanted
to live in a group was...
that I could share my fear
with others...
and wouldn't be emotionally
dependent on one person.
And so that one other person
isn't emotionally dependent on me.
But I do like having other people
around me to share things with.
I'd just like to get back to
the subject of violence.
The squatters' movement has decided
to hit back.
You're not going to be
beaten out of here.
It wasn't so much a decision
of the movement as a whole...
as the fact that you don't
just accept a beating.
The only way you can...
fulfil your justified wishes...
is to make sure
you don't get beaten up.
That's why people now say that
squatters are getting more militant.
As if squatters are all armed
with helmets and iron bars, etcetera.
But it's only our reaction
to the threat...
of being attacked by the police
or by a gang of hired thugs...
and thrown out into the street.
That's why we're barricaded.
The only way to feel safe here...
is by turning it
into a kind of fort
for yourself
and the outside world.
I think it's so awful...
when you try to do something
peacefully, you meet with violence.
It's such a disappointment.
I now think: We were such idealists
and so stupid.
Are you bitter about it?
- I am, really.
I'm afraid of what's going to happen
in future.
If you keep seeing uniforms
everywhere...
you feel you could be arrested
any moment.
We're heading for a police state.
I can imagine that
if there's a threat of war...
it must be the same feeling.
The constant threat,
and the continual fear.
You feel threatened?
- Terribly.
You, too?
Certainly, yes.
- Yes.
How does that express itself?
It's a permanent feeling. It takes
over your whole day, your whole week.
The constant possibility
of hired thugs arriving.
And the interpretation in the press
that we provoked them.
It's a round-the-clock thing.
I even lie worrying at night, too.
Do you sleep well?
- Usually I do. I'm so tired.
Tired enough to sleep well.
5 May.
The celebratlons
ofthe '45 Ilberatlon.
Amsterdã.
A street, a square further down...
A hundred Moroccans.
Flrst they were welcomed
as our cleaners, our Illegal workers.
Now they are undeslrables who
have lived In a church for months.
Today they are packlng.
They wlll be spread
across the country.
Some wlll be arrested
and sent back home.
The boss never paid
social contributions for us.
We never got officially laid off,
so we get no benefits.
The Dutch government says:
You must have worked here
for two or three years.
I've worked here for three years.
There are men who've worked here
for seven years, or eight.
You have to have worked with
the same employer for 22 months.
But who stays that long
with one and the same employer?
You don't even get to stay that long
with your wife.
You marry and then
you have to go abroad.
And you see your wife
one month a year.
Why stay with one employer
for 22 months?
You were angry
when we wanted to film?
I was. I had slept badly.
The bed wasn't made
and I was very tired.
I told myself:
This is no way to live.
I was thinking of my children
and of my wasted life.
And right at that moment
a journalist wants to film me!
I won't have it. I didn't want to be
filmed in that state of mind.
I couldn't accept that I was
discovered in the state I was in.
That was all.
Sprlng has been declared In Parls.
The 'Goutte d'Or', the Golden Drop...
Is one or the oldest
Immlgrant areas In Europe.
Four or five generatlons ofAfrlcans
have lived here.
Dlctatlon, part 2.
Good day.
Do you have In front ofyou:
your exerclse book, yourpen...
and your asslgnment paper?
Yes? Then we're golng to do
the second dlctatlon.
We shall apply what we have learnt
In the flrst two lessons.
Down to work!
Here Is your dlctatlon.
Tltle:
the pollcemen and the bandlts.
The pollcemen...
were taklng...
a rest. Full stop.
But suddenly...
the telephone...
alerted them.
Colon.
People were attacklng...
a nelghbourlng agency.
Exclamatlon mark.
It Is Imposslble...
to count...
the attacks. Full stop.
I've been doing a dictation.
A dictation that I have to send in
for correction...
to the school.
I send it in an envelope.
Then it's corrected and the teacher
sends it back to me.
Why are you doing a course
like this?
Because I want to learn
to type-write.
For myself,
or to get a job in a trading company...
or in the civil service.
I do this to learn to type.
Because you want
to make it your career?
It's not just that.
I have no qualifications
and I get bored not working.
You don't work?
- I don't.
Why not?
- Because I'm disabled.
How did that happen?
I had an accident.
A motorbike accident.
How did that happen?
At five in the morning
at my work.
We work in shifts.
There are three eight-hour shifts.
As one shift came off,
I drove into the factory...
and there was a collision.
I lost consciousness.
What kind of work was it?
I worked for Simca-Chrysler
in Poissy.
And since then?
- Since then I worked on and off...
but never for long.
A week or two.
I can't manage any longer.
How do your attacks come about?
I have this handicap...
and that brings on an attack.
Then I am like that for 2 or 3 days.
It's difficult, and dangerous.
That's why I take these medicines...
to stop the attacks.
I always have one of these
in my pocket.
I put it in my pocket, then I go out.
Just drinking a beer...
brings on an attack.
Immediately. But when I take this...
it stops. That's why... Wait.
I don't have many left.
This is for the cough.
I take tranquillizers.
I have this for the metro...
my green card.
My green card for free travel.
And I have my invalid card,
to show to the police.
When the police stop me,
I show them my invalid card...
and they let me through.
I have written letters
mostly to the health services...
twice to the Ministry of Health.
Your case is being dealt with,
they said.
Do you think it's right that
you get less than a Frenchman?
No, it doesn't make sense.
If a Frenchman gets
a disability pension...
he also gets money from
the solidarity fund.
He gets money
from the disability fund...
and he gets
the compensatory benefit.
Then he has to go to a school...
to learn to type or
play the guitar or whatever...
to have a trade.
And he's well paid.
Is that your typewriter?
- No, it belongs to the school.
I have lessons from them.
Blind, like this.
I have to type here.
The third, first and second rows.
And the fingers always here.
This is how I recognise it.
Q, S, D, F...
J, K, L, M.
That's touch typing, isn't it?
Who is that?
- That's my daughter.
I look at her every morning
and evening...
because she is a long way away.
Were all your children born here?
- Yes, in this house.
How long have you been in France?
- Here? Forty-five years.
I've been here forty-seven years.
And have you worked all that time
in the building industry?
Yes.
As a labourer.
When did you stop working?
I haven't worked for
the last three years.
Do you get unemployment benefit?
- Unemployed? I am ill.
You get 1500 francs a month.
Who from?
From the social security.
So you have to live economically.
- We live according to our means.
Do I have to earn my living
as a male whore?
We live from what God gives us.
We put a good face on things.
How many children do you have?
I have had six children.
Three boys and three girls.
I lost two girls and a boy.
Did they die here in France?
I lost one girl when she was eight.
The boy died here in France.
He died at birth.
My oldest son is 36 and married.
And you stay at home?
- Always.
Don't you go shopping?
- Yes, I do the shopping.
Then I come home.
Have you worked in France?
I worked for the railways
for three years.
Then I became ill.
My daughter had died.
I got heart trouble
and had to stop working.
What did you do for the railways?
- Cleaning.
There is something wrong
with your hands.
From working.
It cost me my hands.
But I didn't report it.
I didn't know how to.
Did you only work in building?
- Yes, only in building.
Show us your hands.
Look. I have had several operations.
I spent four months in hospital.
The internist wanted me
to get unemployment benefit...
but the insurance doctor
wanted me to have...
another operation.
I didn't know what to do.
Now I have lost everything.
The early traln.
Ali travels to workjust once more.
On the footbrldge
to the car factory...
we are stopped
by the works pollce.
Ali Is afrald.
I am a man, It seems...
journeylng In my head
when I'm standlng stlll...
and marklng tlme when I'm movlng.
Thejourney goes on, but flrst...
In June, In Amsterdã...
we wltness the vlolent evlctlon
ofsquatters.
The Klnker Street squatters
negotlate wlth the clty councll...
In order to turn empty space
Into space for livlng.
A new woman hasjolned the group.
There was no chance
of a house for me.
I thought that in a refuge home
they would help me.
Why a women's refuge home?
To have somewhere to stay.
- Why there of all places?
I didn't know anywhere else.
But then...
- You couldn't stay at home?
No. I couldn't stay
where I was living.
I couldn't go back to my husband.
- Why not?
We were always at odds.
Too violently at odds.
Then one of the people here asked
the others if it was all right...
for me to stay here.
What is it like
to live with squatters?
I've learnt more than I can say.
I never knew what was behind it all.
I always only heard
the negative stories...
and now I've experienced
lots of positive things.
Such as?
There's been a housing shortage
since the war.
We've always been brought up
to be well-behaved and polite.
We lived with our parents.
Our children did the same.
Now they live way out of town
because there's nothing in Amsterdã.
But these present-day youngsters...
they oppose all that.
They don't just accept it.
And I admire them and I wish
I was a lot younger.
In my marriage I was pushed
into a rut in the way we lived.
When I left I got into another rut
in the way I had to live.
Now I can do as I like
and say what I like.
You'd never have believed it just
by looking at it from the outside.
But because I live here
I know what it's like.
It's quite an experience!
DOWN WITH VIOLENCE
To prove that the squatters
don't want to use violence...
they have removed all throwable
objects from the roof.
We cannot leave the premises.
If the owner is dispossessed,
eviction is unnecessary.
Amsterdã, 19 August, 11. AM.
The evlctlon from the premlses
was not dlscussed by the Mayor.
And the squatters reacted wlth
the gesture ofclearlng the roof.
Anythlng that could be used
to throw down was removed.
We are expectlng a statement
from the Councll of Churches...
What's better
than a calorle-free klss?
Thls Is the two o'clock news.
Sr. Polak, Mayor ofAmsterdam,
Is not plannlng other evlctlons...
than the apartments
on Prlns Hendrlkkade.
Sympathlsers have broken up
the pavlng...
and made plles of the tlles.
Otherwlse the sltuatlon Is qulet.
Jurrlaan, can I have the mlke?
Look, motorcycle police.
Look at them.
- This is it. This is really it.
We have to say this, guys.
This mustn't happen.
Some people have jumped
into the water.
Are they commando units?
- Yes, in the van.
The man at the top of the crane...
Look, commandos with guns.
- Where?
Here, in the skip that's going up
right in front of you.
They've got machine guns.
They're getting on to the roof
with machine guns.
They're carbines.
Still no statement, Moos?
- No.
They're going to use tear gas.
They've got masks.
Look at that skip.
Ready for action, with guns.
They're going to summon us soon.
When they do, I'll open the window.
Yes, now.
It wlll be answered wlth vlolence...
Riot squad, can you hear me?
We reply in the shape
of a statement to the press.
A gigantic unit of the riot squad
has congregated...
so large it is incredible to see.
We're not going to be provoked...
by this display of power.
We have decided...
not to seek a confrontation
with the police force.
We will keep the struggle
in our own hands.
The squats in luxury apartments
have led to a public discussion...
about these empty apartments that
are built all over the inner city.
Again: at least 1100 luxury
apartments are left uninhabited.
Now you want to clear them...
but the squatters have left
long ago.
The squatters have left the premises
a few hours ago.
But those who are looking for housing
can forget about this location...
for new squatters will arrive.
We will carry on!
CARRY ON
The road to the south contlnues.
Amsterdã. Parls. Lyons.
And Into the mountalns.
The Pollsh strlkers are
In a dlfflcult sltuatlon.
The government has accused them
of undermlnlng soclallsm.
What are you doing?
- I am distilling lavender.
How is the lavender trade?
Not so good.
Why is that?
- Because of the price.
It's hard to sell.
I heard that production costs
had risen.
Yes...
nowadays it costs more.
And the retail price?
- The retail price...
that can't rise.
Is that true of all crops?
Nearly all of them.
What are you going to do?
We're not young any more, are we?
Will you stay here?
Yes, we'll stay here
until we retire. And then...
that's it.
And the rest of the people here?
The same applies for just about
everyone here.
I have always lived here.
On this farm?
- Yes.
Did you spend your youth here?
- I was born here, yes.
What did it use to be like here?
People were used to making do
with less.
They made do with less?
Costs were lower,
so we needed less money.
But did people have a good life?
You can't compare it.
Life was very different.
But was life better then
than it is now?
Or is life better now?
I suppose it is better now.
Did life use to be too hard?
- Yes, it was indeed.
It is better now,
but people have to leave their land.
Yes, because...
we cannot keep up to date
technically.
We don't have any machines
to work on the slopes.
Don't they exist?
- Maybe they will one day!
But there are tractors which can
work slopes, aren't there?
Yes, but they are too expensive
for this sort of small farm.
The essence is lighter...
it floats on the surface.
Is it a good product?
- Well...
it used to be a good product.
Is it a question of competition?
- Yes, it must be.
The demand may also have dropped.
What is it used for?
For perfumes.
And soap?
- Yes, also for soap and suchlike.
How did you meet your husband?
I just did by accident.
At a party?
No, by accident.
In a lane.
And then?
- Well...
we got to know each other
and then we got married.
And it was successful?
Yes, because I have been living here
for 27 years.
Are people leaving the area?
Yes, many are leaving.
And what do you think about that?
We take it as it comes.
But it must affect you?
Yes, it does a bit.
But could you tell me...
what the mountains mean to you?
What do you think as you climb them?
We have always lived here.
We think about the children,
about family and friends...
who have left for the city.
But we have always lived here.
We don't want to leave yet.
We have lived here.
And this is our life.
Do you ever think about
how the world changes?
Do you have any ideas about it?
Yes, we think about it sometimes.
What do you think, then?
We wonder what it will be like
for those after us.
Like unemployment, for instance?
Yes, exactly.
Because they talk about progress
and its advantages.
But there are disadvantages too.
Such as?
I wouldn't know.
In the Alps, I thought:
'I'd Ilke sometlmes to be able
to look at slmply. '
Rome.
The Boca della Verlta.
The Mouth of Truth.
Putyour hand In and say: I love you.
Ifyou're Iylng, he'll blte It off.
I got to know my husband...
in...
nineteen...
twenty-one.
I met him...
when he was working
in a tuna fish factory.
He sealed the cans of tuna.
And cans of...
olive oil.
That was in the fascist era, right?
That's when we came back.
We couldn't stay in Africa
any longer, because of the Party.
My husband hadn't seen his relatives
in ten years.
He wanted to see his village again.
So in 1923...
we came back to the area
of Reggio Emilia.
And then you became Italian?
No, I have always been Italian
since I was born.
I was acknowledged straight away
by my father.
It wasn't a fake acknowledgement...
for payment.
He personally went to register me
as his daughter...
with a woman
he wasn't allowed to marry.
They weren't permitted to marry.
They just lived together,
my father and my mother.
They had five children.
Four boys and one girl: me.
All with the Italian nationality?
- All of them.
The boys all joined the army
to do their military service.
In 1923...
you couldn't go out
after nine o'clock in Italy.
The fascist party had set a curfew.
Voting was compulsory then.
Everywhere it said:
Vote!
People who didn't vote
for the fascists didn't get jobs.
I was coloured...
so I always had a crowd
of children following me like flies.
They shouted: 'Look, a black woman,
a Negress. Look at that!'
What about his relatives?
- His parents were terrible.
They didn't want to share a meal
with me...
because I was black.
In despair I said to him:
Either you allow me to go back
or I jump in front of a train.
The family suggested...
I leave one of my daughters
with my husband...
and that I take the other one
with me.
The older one I'd be allowed to keep.
She's not so black.
She's got black hair...
and an olive skin.
The other one had a white skin
and auburn hair.
She was white
and she'd be for her father.
So the whiter one would stay?
- Yes, with her father.
And the dark one
would come to Africa.
But I left for Africa
with my two girls.
I said: I won't have anything to do
with those people.
Give me my daughters...
and I'll be off.
And my husband let me go.
After four months...
I could buy a ticket
for my husband.
He started work straight away.
Who was in power at that time?
Always the Italians.
It was Italy. And Eritrea was...
a dominion, a protectorate.
At first it was better.
There weren't so many differences.
But later on we couldn't sit together
or eat together.
We were always separate.
Was that segregation by colour?
- Yes, colour.
Apartheid?
- Yes, apartheid.
NUCLEAR POWER MEANS
PROFIT FOR BOSSES...
AND CANCER
FOR THE PROLETARIAT
When the Second World War
had broken out...
we received a convocation
from the fascists...
that was addressed to
Comrade Spaggiari.
I said: 'My husband has never been
a comrade of yours.'
'We'll see about that after the war',
they replied.
'We don't know yet
who's going to win or lose.'
God is great.
Do you remember
the end of the Italian era?
The end of the Italian period?
They picked up all the Italians.
They put them all together on lorries
whether they wanted to or not...
and they shaved them bald.
And they abused them terribly.
Many of them died
and many of them escaped.
And many of them got off
and ended up in Kenya.
In Nairobi. In concentration camps.
Were the English in power there then?
Yes, the English.
What did the English do?
The first thing they did was
to start plundering for food.
And there was prostitution
everywhere.
I even shook hands
with Haile Selassie.
And then you returned to Italy?
We had to leave in 1972.
Or we could stay...
at our own risk.
But we had to leave.
Because the Italians
were no longer in power.
Eritrea had become...
independent.
We had become undesirables.
We left everything behind.
Everything.
We only brought some spices...
because we couldn't live without.
And some pea flour.
That's really good.
Only food.
And some jewellery. Gold.
Every year, my husband gave me
a gold bracelet...
on our wedding anniversary.
I had 48 of them.
When he fell ill...
I had about 36 or 37.
They were very heavy.
They called me Lady Pompeii.
When you came back
did you have a housing problem?
For the first 45 days
we were put in a boarding house.
In Rome?
- Yes, in Pensione Claudia.
We had enough to eat and drink.
They treated us well.
We had good food.
But on the 45th day...
they called us all together.
They gave us 500,000 lire
which we signed for...
and the next day
we were out on the street.
WE WON'T LEAVE THIS HOUSE
UNTIL WE'RE DEAD
Nonna Rosa from Erltrea...
elghtyyears old...
lives wlth her great-nlece Alba,
and Ilttle Tonlno on the thlrd floor.
Born from the unlon ofthe colonlser
and the colonlsed...
she has never been at home
anywhere.
Erltrea, sltuated on the Red Sea...
was colonlsed by the Itallans
about a hundred years ago.
Every civlllsed country...
took Its share
from the Afrlcan cake.
Later, Ethlopla was selzed as well.
Flrst by the Itallan fasclsts...
and then by the Engllsh.
Then the colonlal perlod ended
and Emperor Halle Selassle returned.
In 1962 he annexed Erltrea
to Ethlopla...
to have a Ilnk wlth the sea.
Slnce then, Erltrea has been flghtlng
for Its freedom.
Ethlopla bombed wlth napalm bombs.
Flrst wlth ald
from capltallst countrles...
but slnce Ethlopla has become
soclallst, wlth Russlan asslstance.
But for the sufferlng, we wouldn't
have known the name Erltrea.
TH E CHURCH BELONGS
TO TH E PEOPLE
Let us pray.
O Father, we are here together
this morning...
to mourn for the death...
of our sister Catarina Callauti...
on its first anniversary.
In our lives and in our society...
and in our history...
there are so many things...
that speak to us of death.
The evil that rules in the world,
oppression...
injustice, illness...
hunger...
and misery.
Think of our compatriots...
who have risked their lives...
sailing illegally to America.
And why?
Thinking about their families,
hunger and misery...
and their bosses in Calabria.
Perhaps they had just finished
building a house...
when an earthquake destroyed
everything...
and they lost all their capital.
According to St Luke
the same happened to the disciples.
They had put all their hopes...
and all their trust in Jesus.
And it was all gone.
They didn't want to hear of it again.
The world was bad, wicked
and nothing could be done about it.
Tell me Natale, how did the ideia
for this atelier arise?
We wanted to do something
for the people...
for the poor people in Calabria.
We wanted to combat emigration
and unemployment.
So we thought of setting up
a cooperative.
The principle of a cooperative...
is at the same time
a communal cultural evolution.
We are all equal and we take
our decisions communally.
That means emancipation for
the women. Because for women...
it's even more difficult
to find work.
Natale, could you throw
a bit more light on this lady?
Madam, is it true what he's saying?
Yes, I believe in
what Natale was saying.
Because we in Calabria,
and especially in Gioiosa...
have always waited for jobs.
You can work on the land,
but that doesn't pay anything.
I've been looking around for years...
because I did want to work.
Then I heard that Natale
had founded this cooperative...
and I put my name down.
And now I work here.
I hope all turns out well.
Did you want to work
or was it necessary?
I had to work...
because my husband has had
an operation and he can't work.
And I have two daughters.
A family always costs money.
Was it easy as far as
family relationships were concerned?
Has it changed a lot?
No, it hasn't changed much.
I get up, I do the housework,
I come here...
and when I get home
I take care of the family.
Some things get neglected.
I've got two jobs, really.
What do you think
of a priest like Natale?
I think that whatever he says,
he is always right.
The other priests...
don't always say what is right,
I think.
They don't speak the truth?
They think of themselves
and how to get rich...
they and their relatives.
But Natale thinks of us.
He organised this cooperative.
The others didn't do anything.
Not in other villages either.
Natale was really sent by God...
that he created all this for us.
Who would have cared for us
poor people...
if he hadn't?
Glolosa lonlca, a vlllage on the sole
ofthe boot ofltaly.
Halfan hour further down the coast
Is Locrl.
The prlest there Is called Don Stllo.
A powerful man. They say he has a gun
under hls robes.
Natale, you are working
in a structure...
that is corrupt, isn't it?
I have become conscious of it, yes.
Since 1968 I have been working
in Calabria, here in Locri.
First I was a rector in a seminary.
Then I started taking an interest...
in a village in the mountains...
at about 1000 metres
above sea level.
I became interested
in the people there.
I was struck by the fact
that they saw in me, a priest...
a powerful man
who could do them favours.
For instance, they would ask me
for help in finding work for them.
Right away I refused...
to play that role.
I am not a powerful man...
and I don't want to be one.
Then somebody asked:
Do you know Don Stilo?
He has a lot of influence.
They said he was involved in the mafia.
One day, at a meeting of priests
people complained...
that young men
didn't want to become priests.
So I said:
In our diocese there are priests
who are accused...
of being mafia bosses.
We do nothing against the situation.
How can we hope, with
that corrupt image of the Church...
that young men want
to become priests?
Then Don Stilo came to see me
after the meeting and he said:
You are nothing but an ant.
I could crush you.
And in the end...
an old curate said to me:
We know better than you.
You've been here
for too little time...
to know how to conduct yourself.
You'd better keep quiet
if you don't want to be killed.
I think your brother's story
is very revealing.
Could you tell us some more
about your brother?
About what he did for people?
He worked for the common good.
He never took anyone's side.
He was good-natured
and helped everybody.
Friends and family.
Perhaps I should add
that he was a miller.
He took the flour round the villages.
He started out single-handedly.
Later we had our own mill.
Then the mafia came...
and tried to set fire to it
or they burgled us...
so that we would leave the place.
Then one of the mafia bosses
was killed here in Gioiosa...
and everybody was told
to close down their businesses.
But your brother...
remained true to his principles.
He felt it was unjust
that such people...
should force other people
to close down shop.
He did not close down the mill...
and he said that mafia people
were doing this...
and tyrannising people.
One day he was taking flour
to one of his customers.
They attacked him
from behind a hedge.
Your brother denounced
their evil practices...
and he paid for his courage
with his life.
All these people...
were killed
in the last five years...
by the mafia.
I go from face to face.
In the treadmill of overproduction,
madness and profit for the few.
I don't know. Maybe the dead
would rather have lived.
We cross the sea to a country...
whlch can breathe,
eat and drlnk...
thanks to a river: the Nlle.
Its banks,
two narrow strlps ofgreen.
Its delta, where It branches off
before flowlng out Into the sea.
The rest Is sand.
The liveable area Is no blgger
than Holland.
Forty mllllon people live on It.
Each year, one mllllon are added.
FOREVER... MY LOVE
The day before 'Aid al-Kablr',
the Feast ofSacrlflce...
Calro Is full of anlmals
waltlng to be kllled.
Look at him working.
The man's an artist!
A satlsfled man Is looklng out.
Ramadan, born
In the Musllm fastlng month...
Is a civll servant
as well as a taxi drlver.
Slnce the war wlth Israel
whlch wasn't lost, the one In 1973...
thlngs are sald to be golng well.
The doors to the West have been
opened and fast money can be made.
The new trades generate a new class.
Importlng and exportlng luxury goods.
Luxury constructlon.
In Ramadan's famlly there wlll be
lots ofmlnced meat tonlght.
They want to show they can afford It.
Tell them to come back tomorrow...
and eat with us.
We should have invited them tonight.
Who's going to kill for us now?
Can't Ibn Gadanfar come?
He's the one
who killed Saadi's sheep.
Let me do it.
Poor animal!
The bloody hands on the wall...
guard agalnst the evll eye.
The Ilttle boy Is one step closer
to belng a man.
The flrst mornlng ofthe celebratlons
they stuffthemselves wlth meat.
Those who have It.
Mostpeople get less and less.
Less proteln
per head ofthe populatlon.
It's also the day ofthe young.
They swarm out
across the squares, the parks...
among the pyramlds.
Early on the second mornlng
people head for the cemeterles...
to spend the day wlth the dead.
Better-offfamllles have Ilttle
houses on or near thelr graves.
Durlng the rest ofthe year
these are Inhablted by the homeless.
'And He it is...'
'...who made the sleep a rest...'
'...and made the night...'
'...a covering for you...'
Don't go away.
I've got food for you.
We give alms
for the repose of our deceased.
We come here every year
during the Feast of Sacrifice.
On these days
one is meant to go to the graves.
Everyone goes and you meet everybody.
All the family and friends.
We all meet again here.
Ramadan, where are we?
This is our family vault.
We gather here
for religious celebrations.
Our dead are buried here.
My father rests here,
my grandfather...
as well as others.
You give food to the poor people?
We kill animals for the poor...
so they will pray for our dead.
We hire people
to read from the Qur'an.
There are many poor people here?
They're not all poor.
They want alms as souvenirs.
It brings good luck.
It's a gift from God.
Ramadan's brother Gamal...
Is a guard
at the newly bullt Sheraton.
I left the army in 1977.
I was a commando.
They were the best years of my life.
It was tough to leave the service.
I missed my comrades.
After I'd left the army...
I became a guard
at the Sheraton Hotel.
I keep out any unwanted visitors...
to stop them...
from committing offences.
I earn 50 dollars a month.
I would need
at least 120 dollars a month...
to be able to marry.
I've got financial worries.
What can you do with 50 dollars?
Cigarettes cost me
18 dollars a month.
Public transport is 10 dollars.
I spend around 20 dollars on food.
It's hard to get out of this life.
He who worshlps any other than God...
wlll go to hell.
Ifman abuses hls free wlll...
he ceases to be free.
He does not have the rlght...
to use the freedom
God has given hlm...
to declde
whether he wants to belleve or not.
He must use hls freedom...
to hold hls own In thls world.
He cannot choose.
He lives In thls world
accordlng to God's plan.
He must sow and reap.
In heaven, he won't have to any more.
There, all wlll be In abundance.
He who obeys God voluntarlly...
wlll be rewarded In the heavens.
Ifl renounce certaln deslres...
I wlll forever be happy
In heaven.
Sadat:
Llbya, South Yemen
and the Palestlnlans...
support the Sovlet Unlon
agalnstAfghanlstan.
Thelr crlmes
not only concern the Arabs...
but the entlre Musllm world.
That's why we're calllng
for the creatlon...
of an alllance
ofMusllm natlons...
and Arab natlons.
And let us not forget
the civll war In Lebanon...
whlch has been golng on
for seven years.
Lebanon Is divlded.
The Syrlans are In Lebanon.
SaudiArabla, Kuwalt and others...
are flnanclng the activltles...
of the Syrlan army.
Israel has annexed
a plece ofLebanon...
and Is bulldlng roads there.
A doctor frlend...
arranges for us to vlslt Fawzl,
a nlght watchman.
It's hard to get to speak
to a poor man,
though there are mllllons of them.
Fawzi and hls wlfe, brother,
slster-In-law and two chlldren...
Ilve In a 3-by-3-metre room...
In a dlstrlct
belng bullt on the outsklrts.
How is your life?
Bad. Really bad.
I work at night
and sleep during the day.
Why did you move to Cairo?
- I've been here five months now.
I was a farmer.
But that was a very hard life.
Did you go to school?
- No.
There was no one who looked after me.
How old are you?
- I'm 45.
And your wife?
She's 18.
- No, 15.
How much do you earn?
- 25 dollars a month.
How much do you spend?
How much do you save?
The rent is 12 dollars.
I have to live off the rest.
How much do you spend on food?
More than 2 dollars a day.
I work all night.
Till 6 in the morning.
How many hours?
12 hours.
From the night to the morning.
How is life here in this area?
Bad. It's a bad place to live.
Tell them it's certo.
- It's certo.
We mustn't give these people
a bad impression.
Even if it's hard,
tell them it's certo.
Let's keep the truth
between ourselves.
The foreigners don't need to know.
Say it's certo.
What do these people want?
What do they want?
They're foreigners.
The doctor sent them here.
They want to make a film about us.
Is this doctor a foreigner?
- No.
But she knows these foreigners.
There's no danger, don't be scared.
They're just making a film.
No problems?
But at least they're paying you?
They're not paying him anything.
I'm getting 25 dollars, aren't l?
We'll talk about it when we're done.
The new arrivals from the south put
thelrpossesslons on the platform.
Up the rlver Nlle. The Sun Boat.
Accordlng to a poll
In the Washlngton Post...
presldent Carter Is ahead
ofRonald Reagan.
42 percent ofthose canvassed...
sald they were votlng
for Carter...
whlle Reagan got 39 percent.
Edltorlallsts belleve, however...
the dlfference Is too small...
to be able to plck a wlnner.
Irã has announced that Iraq...
has attacked the clty ofAbadan...
Go!
They just want to take a picture.
Tomorrow you'll be on TV.
No, it's not meant for you.
Go!
On my return to the clty,
I'm thlnklng...
It's hard to touch reallty.