THE APPARITION
Memory card (Christophe)
Chapter 1
Rome
"Bring back proof."
Christophe often said,
"I want to bring back proof."
Images.
Images of the injustice,
the violence,
and the madness of men.
Tonight he is no longer here,
yet he's still with us,
for his photos live on.
I think of his friend
and longtime colleague, Jacques.
Together they covered
numerous theatres of operations.
Sudan,
Lebanon, Yugoslavia...
Jacques was only feet away from
Christophe when he heard the explosion.
Fifteen years of complicity...
You have friends
waiting for you downstairs.
I shouldn't have let him go off alone.
He wasn't alone.
It was the first time
we'd ever split up over there.
Have a seat.
Can I go back to work?
Why do you refuse to talk to someone?
It might help.
Can I start working again,
yes or no?
You need rest.
Your wife worries.
You won't leave the house.
Are you still afraid?
Mr. Jacques Mayano?
Speaking.
The reporter for Ouest-France?
Yes. Who's calling?
I'm calling on behalf of
Monsignor Vassilis, Bishop of Valence
and member of the Congregation
for the Doctrine of the Faith.
What do you want?
Monsignor would like to meet you
to discuss a confidential matter.
Meaning?
It's rather delicate.
His Grace prefers to tell you in person.
He invites you to join him in Rome.
Naturally,
your expenses will be covered.
I'm sorry, but why me?
Monsignor is familiar with your work.
He'll explain everything.
Can't you explain now?
Unfortunately, I'm not authorized.
His Grace
would rather tell you himself.
Like I said,
it's a highly confidential matter.
Can I have his name again?
Come in.
Come in!
Thank you
for making the trip, dear sir.
Please, have a seat.
- Were you offered something to drink?
- Yes, thank you.
Ever been to the Vatican?
No, it's the first time.
All this gold...
It's a far cry from the barefoot man
who preached poverty, isn't it?
Probably, yes.
How is your ear?
Better. Thank you.
I heard about your friend
and I'm sorry for your loss.
I knew his work well.
I wrote him a letter
expressing my admiration,
and he kindly sent me
one of his photographs.
It's right over there.
So.
We selected...
a few of your articles.
I'd already read some on the Internet.
You write remarkably well.
Excuse me, but why am I here?
You want me to write something?
Did you have
a religious education, Jacques?
I made my First Communion.
Are you a believer?
No.
I mean, maybe there's something...
but I'm not a practicing Catholic.
Do you know
about canonical investigations?
It's an investigation
to beatify a saint.
It's a commission
designated by church authorities
to investigate a particular event.
For example, a miracle healing,
an apparition,
or a supernatural event.
What's a "supernatural event"?
We've put together several documents.
They might interest you.
So...
Exactly two years ago,
a 16-year-old girl
claimed to have had an apparition
in the Carbarat region
in southeast France.
What's an apparition?
An apparition of the Virgin Mary.
Most of the time
things calm down on their own,
once the parish priest
or a good psychiatrist intervenes.
But sometimes
the phenomenon intensifies
and pilgrims
flood to the apparition site.
That is,
the alleged apparition site.
That's what's happening there.
The police say they're having trouble
maintaining law and order.
The young visionary's name is Anna.
Ever since her "visions,"
she has been overly sheltered
by the parish priest.
A Franciscan who has
cut off communication with us.
Father Borrodine.
He's even refused
to hand over a supposed relic
for us to analyze.
A bloodstained cloth they claim
the Virgin left for the faithful.
They even talk
of building a new church.
In short, the situation is worrying.
I'm sorry, but this isn't my world.
I don't see how I can help you.
I'd like you
to conduct a field investigation.
Gather elements
in favor of
or against these apparitions.
You will be paid.
And you will have total freedom.
There you go.
The Holy Office archives were moved
to another building last year.
We'll take the basement route.
May I please ask you
to give me your phone?
It's switched off.
It's the rules.
Right now, we're under
the courtyard where you came in.
As of the late 19th century,
photographs became more common.
Sound recordings and films came later.
He found some documents
for you in French.
This is the list
of officially recognized apparitions.
For each affair, there is
a file with the original hearings
of the visionaries and witnesses.
From 1961 to 1965, four young
Spanish girls claimed to have apparitions
in Garabandal, Spain.
Within months, hundreds
of thousands of pilgrims showed up.
The girls were questioned,
photographed and filmed.
But these events were not recognized.
There were suspicions of a sham.
Opinions are still divided.
After years of investigation,
the Bishop of Santander judged
that the supernatural nature
of the phenomena
in Garabandal could not be proven.
So, it was all a sham?
Let's say, the Church did not
officially recognize these events
or the supernatural nature
of the apparitions.
Now, a very rare document.
An officially authenticated apparition.
Ask if I can see
a recently authenticated case...
I understood.
L'Île-Bouchard in France.
Jacqueline Aubry, a saintly woman.
You'll find interviews with her
on the Internet
where she describes
her apparitions in great detail.
I met her personally in the late 90s.
She passed away in 2016.
- Was there an investigation?
- Several.
And in 2001, the Archbishop of Tours
officially authorized
pilgrimages to the site.
L'Île-Bouchard Apparitions
So once it's recognized, it's official?
Not really, but it could be a first step
towards authentication.
This is a letter relating the event.
Don't touch.
They're extremely precious.
"I saw the Blessed Virgin
and an angel
and she smiled at Jeanne.
I was with Nicole, Jeanne,
Laura and Sergine,
but Sergine didn't see her."
He can show you documents
on miraculous cures at Lourdes.
Sixty-nine cures
have been officially deemed miraculous.
The most recent dates to 1989.
Danila Castelli.
- Coffee, thank you.
- You too?
The events
the Bishop spoke to me about...
What do you think?
I don't know
what the Bishop spoke to you about.
Do many Christians still believe in
supernatural apparitions and miracles?
The Church would rather
bypass a veritable phenomenon
than validate a sham.
Always.
You mean that in these archives,
there may be stories
they've chosen to forget?
Is that possible?
Anything's possible. Anything.
With the compliments of Monsignor
Apparitions at Lourdes
The Virgin Mary at Medjugorje
The Forgers of God
Chapter 2
The Messenger
He's here. I'll call you back.
Hello, I'm Valérie.
Welcome.
Did you have a nice trip?
It's this way.
You have everything?
Town Hall was supposed to open
another parking lot.
It's getting worse by the day.
The others arrived last night.
Where can I rent a car?
Don't worry, we'll take care of it.
Hear that bell?
Anna rings it herself every day.
The convent is at the town entrance.
Here we are.
This used to be a truck rental company.
When they closed,
the town turned it into warehouses.
You were supposed to wait for me!
This is Mr. Mayano.
Welcome, I'm Father Ezeradot.
Dr. De Villeneuve, our psychiatrist.
Stéphane Mornay, theologian.
Would you like coffee or tea?
Coffee, please.
And Father Gallois,
who represents the Diocese.
I'm very happy to work with you.
A nun will transcribe the interviews
and Paul-Eric here will film them.
- You're filming?
- If the visionary agrees, yes.
She gets to decide?
We can't send in the police
if she refuses to cooperate.
It's this way.
Are your accommodations comfortable?
Fine, thanks.
We've received some of your reports.
I'd love to discuss them with you.
Sure.
There's a coffee machine here
and a fully-equipped kitchen downstairs.
I'll let you settle in.
The apparition allegedly took place
near the so-called "Cabin in the Pines."
It's all indicated
on the map in the appendix.
- Are we free to visit the spot?
- Unfortunately, yes!
The place is crawling with pilgrims.
Like a fairground.
Our dear Stéphane
has a clear-cut opinion on events.
Last time I went to Medjugorje,
I was greeted with a shower of pebbles.
I told you about that, Doctor.
I was with that crazy nun.
Sister Bara or Mara.
Medjugorje is a small town
in ex-Yugoslavia
where apparitions have supposedly
occurred since the 80s.
We've all worked on the case
at some point.
And now they've built churches,
hotels, freeways...
I read about it.
Even fast-food chains!
Do we know who the exorcist is?
The name is in the folder.
Excuse me, but why an exorcist?
They still exist?
There's one in every diocese, yes.
It's the procedure
for supernatural events.
That is, alleged supernatural events.
We must first make sure
it's not the work of Satan.
And that the visionary
is psychologically sound.
Don't worry, Jacques.
I'm not.
I added three questions
concerning the alleged message.
In particular, the Virgin's formulation.
So, I ask the questions
and you can intervene freely.
I should hope so!
It's not Joan of Arc's trial.
Before we break up,
Monsignor would like us
to read this document.
The procedural rules
for the judgement
of supposed apparitions.
Would you read it to us, Jacques?
"According to the 1978
Norms for Judging Alleged Apparitions
published by the Holy Office,
now the Congregation
of the Doctrine of the Faith,
our Canonical Investigation Commission
must ascertain: one,
the personal qualities of the visionary.
Namely, his/her psychological state,
the honesty and uprightness
of his/her moral life,
and his/her sincerity and obedience
to ecclesiastic authorities.
Two, regarding the revelation
of the message,
the theological doctrine must be true
and exempt of errors or inconsistency.
Three,
the commission must recognize
the visionary's healthy devotion,
and continual and abundant
spiritual rewards,
such as certified conversions
or expressions of charity."
That's all.
May God's wisdom guide our work.
More people arrived during the night.
- I saw them at the town entrance.
- They're all over!
Look. They can't handle it.
Come on, there's another entrance.
Brothers and sisters, Anna is with us.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Brothers and sisters,
what a joy to see so many people.
Anna is with us.
Let us thank the Blessed Virgin.
You have no business here.
You shut your door to us?
How dare you?
I know who you are!
Leave us in peace.
Christians don't shut their door!
The Blessed Virgin
gave me a message of love,
for only love will save us.
Today,
I would like to greet all those
who come from afar
and who await so much from us.
Those who come
from countries torn by war and poverty.
I also think about
those who didn't make it this far.
Those who were left on the road.
Those who have died.
They're with us too, forever.
Let us pray for them all.
Hello, could I talk to you?
I know why you're here.
Let's go.
Can you hear... You're cutting out...
It's an English news site.
They want to do
a story on wounded war reporters.
Tell them you can't reach me,
that I'm on sick leave.
That's what I tell everyone.
What are your colleagues like?
They talk about exorcism
and apparitions.
It's routine stuff for them.
Is your place comfortable?
Yeah.
Have you blocked out the windows?
No, not yet.
Look, I need to review my questions.
You take care of yourself.
There you go.
Anna, you can still change your mind.
I'm ready.
OK.
Let's go.
Don't worry,
they can't do anything to you.
Thank you, Mother.
What do you see?
The hands of pilgrims
trying to touch me.
Under no circumstances
may these recordings be made public.
Don't worry.
This will remain confidential.
We have nothing to hide.
I'll leave you now.
This way.
This is the commission.
Dr. De Villeneuve is a psychiatrist.
Stéphane Mornay, a theologian.
Paul-Eric,
Sister Sophie, our stenotypist.
Father Gallois.
And Jacques Mayano, journalist.
Over here.
Please, sit down.
Thank you for accepting our invitation.
Jacques will conduct the interview.
We've all discussed
each of the questions.
Please understand
that no-one here wishes you any harm.
Before starting, Anna,
please put your hand on the Bible
and say "I swear."
I'm not sure I'm allowed to.
Don't worry, it's only a custom.
I swear.
First of all,
please state your identity.
My name is Anna Ferron.
I was born anonymously
on January 20, 1999, in Lagnon.
I'm a novice
at the La Providence convent.
Did you receive a religious education?
I went to church with my grandmother
in my first family.
But when she died, I stopped.
Later, I was placed in a Catholic home
because my family couldn't keep me.
Was religion present
during your early childhood?
No, we didn't talk about it
in my families.
Did you think about God
or the Virgin Mary?
Did you discuss this with grownups?
Father Borrodine
was the first person I talked to.
When I started feeling things.
Could you describe what you felt?
It was like...
Like a calling.
How old were you at the time?
Fifteen.
Had you heard of apparitions?
I knew the story
of Bernadette of Lourdes.
Like everybody else.
Had you read any books on the subject?
Or seen images or films?
For example,
about the apparitions at Fátima.
Or Garabandal and Medjugorje?
I heard about them later
from the pilgrims
and on the Internet.
Did you ever belong
to a Satanic or occult movement,
or anything similar?
No, never.
But I believe the Devil exists.
I'm sure of it. Evil.
Did Father Borrodine
suggest that you enter the Church?
No. That's not how it works.
It has to come from within.
I asked him if I could meet
the sisters, to learn more.
And...
that's when I had the first apparition.
The first one was two years ago,
in September.
It had rained all day long.
I went out for a walk, like I often do.
- Were you alone?
- Yes.
It was cold out.
And when I reached the first refuge,
I saw a glow further down.
What do you mean by "a glow"?
Can you describe it for us?
I thought it was the sun
reflecting off the wet rocks.
Like after a storm.
About how far away were you?
Can you show me?
I don't know.
About here.
Were you blinded?
Did you have to look away
or close your eyes?
It was a soft light.
Very soft.
Did it have a shape?
As I came closer
I saw a human shape.
Did you think it was someone?
I mean, someone real?
No, I knew it was something else.
What?
A woman.
A very beautiful woman.
She wore a very simple veil and cloak.
What color?
The dress was white, or light-colored...
and the cloak was sky blue.
And then?
Then I heard her voice.
A calm voice.
Did she speak to you in French?
Yes.
She said to me,
"You mustn't be afraid."
And did you reply?
No, I couldn't speak.
What was her exact message to you?
Her precise words?
She said,
"I hear the cries of the world."
She asked me to teach people around me
to learn to give of themselves,
to help the poor and the suffering.
Then she asked me
to build a house for her son.
A place of welcome and prayer.
Carry on, Anna.
It didn't last long.
The light faded.
And I was alone again.
Everything was silent.
I went home
and locked myself in my room.
I didn't want to talk to anyone.
You couldn't tell your friends?
It was impossible.
They'd have thought I was crazy.
Later, I decided
to tell Father Borrodine what happened.
- So you told him?
- Yes.
How long afterwards?
A few weeks, maybe a month.
What was his reaction?
He said it was blasphemy.
He said I was proud and self-centered.
How did people around you
find out what happened?
No-one knew.
We kept it secret for over a year.
It was only after the second apparition
that people started talking.
Sister Elisabeth,
can you please get the car?
Go on.
Sister...
Goodbye, dear colleague.
I'm not a liar.
Apparition Site
Chapter 3
Anna
Hello, this is Jacques Mayano.
I'm part of the Canonical
Investigation Commission in Carbarat.
I saw that you wrote articles
on the events.
I'd like to talk to you.
I'll leave you my number.
06-58-68-09-18.
Thank you. That's Jacques Mayano.
Hello.
How are you?
- Well, and you?
- Fine.
This is a gift for you.
It's from the entire
Philadelphia community.
They'd love to see you for real,
not just on the Internet.
I'd be very happy
to pray with them too.
Did you see the items
we published on your website?
They've been copied everywhere.
Benoît is the sound engineer.
Christophe is the cameraman.
People have a great deal
of love and respect for you
over there.
OK.
I'll ask you questions in French.
And of course, you'll answer in French.
You will be dubbed in several languages.
The interview will be on the Internet
in many countries.
Do what you like, I trust you.
Rolling.
Hello, Anna.
I'd like to begin
with a simple question...
How are you?
OK.
Christians from all over the world
are here today to see you.
What does this mean to you?
I don't believe in this relic.
The fabric, the bloodstain...
I never bought it.
Why not?
The Blessed Virgin
has always been an image of love,
kindness and understanding.
She can't be associated
with violence.
It's in total contradiction
with the tradition of apparitions.
Precisely,
perhaps it's a new symbol.
It's absolutely impossible.
It's not because it's new
that it's impossible.
Right, Jacques?
We need to analyze the fabric.
Who can seize the object?
The chief of police.
If he believes
there's a threat to public order,
he can confiscate the relic
and give it to the Bishop for analysis.
Even in a convent?
Convents belong to the State,
not the Diocese.
The State is free
to seize whatever it wants.
Would the pilgrims allow it?
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
Here.
Mother Superior said you should rest.
We could accommodate 800 pilgrims.
Like in Medjugorje.
In the meantime, I'm not even authorized
to say mass in my own parish.
Will the commission question you too?
I've refused.
What's the use?
The Bishop has multiplied
signs of hostility.
Now this commission...
If you need strength, Father,
think of her eyes.
Anna's eyes.
I've never seen a gaze like hers.
She wasn't chosen by chance.
You've shown great support.
We must uphold
the modesty and clarity of her message.
That's the only truth.
I understand, Father.
We must keep our dignity.
Be worthy of the Grace she's received.
I'm Jacques Mayano.
We spoke on the phone about Anna.
Oh yes, hello.
Her hair was lighter at the time.
- How old was she when she got here?
- Six. She was little.
The county commission placed her here.
And before that?
She was in day care and foster care.
Have you taken in many children?
Yes, lots.
They stay a few years and move on.
They go back to their families
or to homes.
I always keep a drawing.
I like to draw too and it's a souvenir.
Have a seat.
Pilgrims come all the way here now
to see the house.
They want to see where the girl slept.
They touch the stones, the trees...
I dug up everything I had.
Did you keep administrative documents,
like report cards or medical records?
When a child leaves,
the paperwork goes with him.
It's important for everyone to cut ties.
They need to move on
when they change families.
Otherwise,
the separations get too painful.
Her report says she had
no particular problems at school.
It didn't interest her much, either.
But she was a good girl.
Never ran away or made trouble.
She was a loner.
Why did she leave?
My husband died and left me
with three foster kids. It was too much.
The older ones were troublemakers.
Anna was 14.
She returned to the State home.
May I take photos
of the documents and photographs?
- Is it legal?
- Yes, don't worry.
This was her room.
Now it's my laundry room.
She slept here for eight years.
We put that there as a mark of respect.
What do you think
about these apparitions?
When I saw her last year,
she swore it was true.
She wouldn't have lied to me.
She's not a liar, you know.
So, you're the one who decides
if it's all true or not?
"Snowdrop" Educational Center
Dear Father,
I've made up my mind to become
a novice at the
La Providence convent.
I wish to devote my life to prayer
and help the suffering.
I know now that I'm meant
for a life in the service of God.
I want to leave the foster home
and enter the convent
as soon as you think it's possible.
I can't live here
with the other girls anymore,
for I am now certain
that my real life is elsewhere.
I have a secret to tell you.
Something extraordinary happened to me.
It's a very big secret.
I don't know who I can share it with,
other than you.
I'm afraid of what might happen.
Even if I know,
I need only look at the immense sky
and my fear disappears.
Help me.
Have pity.
Anna.
Which path did you say she took?
You see that bush?
She followed the ridge
and disappeared on the other side.
- Over there?
- Yeah, right behind there.
She screamed real loud.
A huge scream.
Like someone who was scared?
Yeah, real scared.
A scream you don't forget.
And it was the day of the apparition?
Yes. People talked about it later.
And we put two and two together.
The next day?
No, long after.
When people started talking.
Did you see how she was dressed?
No, we didn't have time to see.
Besides, she was far.
It happened so fast.
- You didn't see her face?
- No.
Her back was facing us
and then she was gone.
How old was she, 10 or 12?
A little more, 14 or 15.
- A young girl?
- Yes, a young girl.
It was a shrill scream, like a child.
"A scream you don't forget."
What's this nonsense
about screams, terror and bloodstains?
She's loony, end of story.
Did you read her foster care file?
Yes, I read it.
She was only 16,
so they concocted an internship
at the convent factory.
She dropped out,
and when she turned 18...
she entered the Church
and no-one could do anything. That's it.
It was sainthood
or hairdressing school.
In any case, she agreed
to take all our medical exams.
And?
For the moment, I've detected
no significant psychological disorders.
She spent her life in foster facilities.
That's got to have
an impact of some sort.
We're only at the start.
Then what's the deal?
She's just some lost girl
who found a way to draw attention?
A poor kid
who can't face school, life...
people... Is that it?
What is this world
where we must learn to live?
What is this world?
Let us remember the words
of our Holy Father Pope Francis,
"Is anyone today still capable
of taking responsibility
for the suffering of others?"
We look at our brother,
half-dead on the side of the road...
Maybe we think,
"poor man," as we stare
at his picture on the Internet.
Nonetheless, we keep walking
and leave him behind.
Our culture of well-being
encourages us to think of ourselves
and makes us insensitive
to the distress of others.
We might live in beautiful bubbles,
they are nothing.
They are the illusion
of the futile,
the temporary.
An illusion that creates
indifference toward others.
We have fallen
into globalized indifference.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
we thank you for the message of mercy
you have sent us.
Hello, Anna.
I saw you on the web.
I didn't realize who you were.
Keep moving, Anna.
Hello, Father.
That was a beautiful speech.
Really.
Your commission will only cause harm.
It's a Church investigation.
You're a priest.
I'll pray for you.
Don't worry about me.
I have to go.
Let's go, Anna.
You haven't understood, Mr. Mayano.
It's Anna who called you here,
to put us to the test.
- You really believe she has that power?
- Yes.
I do.
I truly do.
Where do I pick you up?
Same place as last time?
You'll be careful, OK?
- Hey, dude.
- Hi.
Thanks.
I send you my love, dear Anna.
So does Pavel!
Write soon, Meriem.
- Are you happy working here?
- It's shit.
Did you see the boy again?
- Who?
- The boy you hit.
Oh, him.
His family wouldn't let me
see him at the hospital.
You'll try to see him again
to ask forgiveness?
It's important.
If you say so.
I'm sorry.
Unknown caller
I know you went to see my first family.
I hope they're well.
Why did you scream?
What frightened you?
You're not like the others.
It's for the program
we'll hand out
on the day of the celebration.
I think we should choose something
that's sincere, simple,
and humble.
What do you think?
This one.
Light shines in you.
Or this one. Your gaze...
is very clear. Very pure.
I like this one.
Here.
This is Lucie Marisco, a journalist.
She investigated
Anna's apparitions for years.
Then last year,
she suddenly quit the newspaper.
- Do you know why?
- Not really.
It seems that her editor
wanted to drop this affair.
Is she Catholic?
No, that's the interesting part.
- Why?
- In her email...
she says that no-one really
wanted to know the truth.
The shopkeepers,
the Diocese, the pilgrims, no-one.
She explains
why it's in everyone's interest
to maintain the mystery.
Those who want to believe
and those who don't.
The Bishop wants the truth.
He has no choice anymore.
Borrodine is out of control.
They're scared.
The Diocese requested
an analysis of the stained relic.
What more could they do?
Here's everything I found on Borrodine.
A missionary in India, in Asia...
He even started a humanitarian group
in the Philippines.
But I found nothing compromising.
On the contrary, people speak
of a sincere, devout servant of God.
Oh, c'mon.
He refuses
to submit to his bishop's authority.
That's enough to discredit him.
The prefecture confirms there's no sign
of unlawful conflict of interest.
No hidden funds for him,
the visionary or their entourage.
Nothing.
What about the man
who's always with him...
Anton Meyer.
He's been there from the start too.
Borrodine is increasingly alone.
He needs Meyer's Catholic networks
to put pressure on the Bishop.
Do you think Anna is attached to them?
Does she have any choice?
Chapter 4
The Icon of Kazan
Hello.
Cécile.
That's her with shorter hair.
That's me.
It's crazy,
she already held her secret.
Delphine...
Assata...
Meriem.
Maïa.
She had a serious thyroid problem.
The black guy is Joachim.
He got into trouble and disappeared.
Did Anna have a boyfriend at the time?
No. She never mentioned one.
Not surprising
if she wanted to be a nun.
Look at this list.
Are all the girls who were in the home
from 2010 to 2012 on it?
Amélie Cassaigne...
She went to study in Nancy.
- Glass of water?
- Yes, please.
How do you remember Anna?
We weren't especially friends.
Well, we weren't the same age.
And I was a counselor,
so that creates a distance.
But Anna was distant with everyone.
- No-one knew what happened to her?
- Nope.
If she'd said she'd seen the Virgin,
we'd have thought she was crazy.
Her life would have been hell.
Those girls are tough with each other.
They live in constant fear.
- Who was she closest to?
- Meriem.
Meriem Almedia.
They were roommates towards the end.
They were very close.
Almost inseparable.
Exactly how close?
Not what you think.
They were like two sisters
who had lost their parents.
You get it?
How can I reach Meriem?
No idea.
She went to live with a foster family.
Ask the educational worker here.
Maybe he can help you.
What did you
think of Father Borrodine?
He impressed us with his travel stories.
He was super protective of Anna.
Especially when Meriem left.
Why, what happened?
Anna wouldn't leave her room for weeks.
It was really hard on her.
Then one day, she left the home.
- To join the convent?
- So they said, but who knows.
By becoming a nun,
she escaped administrative checks,
school pressure, and so on.
Do you think there was anything
between Borrodine and Anna?
It always comes down to that?
Sorry, it has to be talked about.
Maybe she made it all up for him.
A lovesick kid latching onto someone.
A lovesick kid
doesn't talk about it so easily.
The paper asked
what you were working on.
It's only natural. They're worried.
I don't want to tell them.
Not now, anyway.
They're clueless.
How's your ear?
Fine.
Any more attacks?
Huh?
Do you feel OK?
Yeah. Why?
- You just don't want to talk to me?
- Of course I do.
Gabriel has exams, right?
I looked up Anna's face on the Internet.
And?
It's scary.
What'll her life be like after this?
I don't know.
I'm investigating
the events at Carbarat.
You were in the same home
as Anna in 2012-13.
It's a canonical investigation.
The Church asked me to investigate
everyone who'd been close to Anna.
I'd like to ask you
a few questions
and hear your memories
of Anna.
Ah, moved.
About half an hour from you.
Stéphanie Berlamont?
OK.
Marie-Amélie Jacob?
Delphine Barjoux?
How can I reach her?
I was told she'd moved away.
...11-24-52.
Where's La Roche des Arnaux?
I'm a bit lost.
Maïa Lonkeu? You're sure?
I can come to your home or workplace.
Paris?
No, no.
I can be there in half an hour.
Don't worry, just a few questions.
It won't take long.
That's Meriem.
And that's her boyfriend.
Who was her boyfriend?
A guy she met in an association.
A Russian guy.
What kind of association?
They help people.
People who are on their own or poor.
Even prisoners.
- Was she a prison visitor?
- Yes.
Did she talk to you about Anna...
and the apparitions?
No.
Never.
We heard it all later.
So, after the foster home,
they lost contact?
Well, I never saw them together.
She never came here.
Maybe they met up, though.
What was his name?
Pavel.
Know his last name?
No. I'm not even sure
Pavel was his real name.
Oh, why do you say that?
Dunno.
What did he do for a living?
He was an ex-soldier.
A drifter.
They're in the top drawer.
Here's a letter we received
after they left.
A prisoner she visited.
Lumio.
He was worried
when he didn't hear from her.
Wanted to know where she'd gone.
Gaspard Lumio.
That's it.
What was her relationship
with the prisoner?
She went to talk to him.
About the Gospels and forgiveness...
She always wanted to help everyone.
Did she say
she wanted to become a nun?
Meriem? On the contrary!
She wanted to travel, see the world.
She was always running around.
And she was in love.
- Mind if I take this letter?
- No.
- Coffee?
- Yes, please.
You'll give it back, right?
What's that?
A gift from Pavel.
When they left, he gave it to us.
Did he say where he found it?
When he was a soldier, I guess.
It was broken. He repaired it.
- May I take a photo of it?
- OK.
What do you mean "by chance"!
A coincidence. It happens.
Coming across this thing, Céline,
in a godforsaken place.
It's impossible!
- You're imagining things!
- No, I'm not!
It's right in front of me!
What are you scared of?
I don't know.
Anna, I have to talk to you.
Who's Meriem?
What happened with Meriem?
Unknown caller
Did he tell you
about his photographer friend?
I know the story,
but not from him personally.
It's unpleasant,
someone who won't answer you.
What do you think, Father?
Faith often travels incognito.
Hello.
I can't be seen here.
Come in.
Want a drink?
- Yes, please.
- A glass of water?
Hang your jacket up.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Are you free to go out
when you like?
Father Borrodine asked me
not to speak to you.
You disobey him?
People saw what happened
at the gymnasium.
You seemed angry.
Father Borrodine talked to me about it.
What did he say?
He'd rather pray
than listen to people who attack us.
Who's attacking you?
People who are afraid.
- Are you afraid of him?
- No.
He's always protected me.
Does all that scare you?
A little, yes.
But I have faith.
I want to help you, Jacques.
Help me?
This investigation
mustn't make you suffer.
The message the Virgin gave me
is one of love and peace.
I know you need a friend.
Sit down.
Tell me about Meriem.
She was my friend in the home.
Why did she leave?
Because she wanted to leave.
Did you know
about her Russian boyfriend, Pavel?
Her boyfriend? No.
How could I have known?
You've never had a sweetheart?
I know I'll always be a virgin.
I've known it for a long time.
It's what gives my life meaning.
It's God I love.
Doesn't it bother you...
not to know...
what it's like to make love
to a boy, or a girl?
Isn't it painful?
It's a beautiful pain.
Very beautiful, even.
There's...
a guy who says he heard you scream
on the path,
after the apparitions.
Scream?
No, I didn't scream.
Why would I scream?
I don't know.
That's what I heard.
I didn't scream.
So he's lying, too?
People make things up
when it comes to apparitions.
I've heard all sorts.
I just want to understand
why he said that.
Why did Meriem suddenly disappear?
And why do I have the feeling
that all your answers are scripted?
There's too much anger in you
to accept what I saw.
I came here to ask you something.
The commission wants to analyze
the bloodstained cloth.
You have no right. It's sacred.
It's not up to me anymore.
I can't help you.
I beg you, don't touch it!
Stand up, Anna.
- I want to help you.
- Stop it.
- Please!
- Stand up, Anna.
- You have no right! Please!
- Don't do this.
Please stand up.
- Promise me.
- Get up.
It's out of my hands.
Are you OK?
Sorry, I'll be right out.
- How will you get home?
- I'll walk.
It's not far.
Will you come
to the celebration next week?
Do you want me to?
Yes. It's important that you be there.
Thank you.
I know
the Mother of God will protect us.
Her name was Safia Ayad.
A-Y-A-D.
It happened in 2005.
I only have his name,
not the name of the prison.
Gaspard Lumio.
Gaspard Lumio. L-U-M-I-O.
Do you have a number
where I can reach his lawyer?
You don't look well.
You haven't finished your food.
Do you want to talk?
We could have a chat.
I'm only asking for a simple blessing.
It won't take long, I promise you.
Look, all our gifts
for the parishes that support us.
Just a simple blessing.
But they need to know
that you touched the objects.
Safia was 25 when she died.
No family came forward.
I was the one who had her buried.
There's the autopsy report.
She was born in '82 in Djelfa, Algeria.
- A Muslim, then.
- Yes.
She lived with some lowlife
who abandoned her with a baby.
She gave it to social services.
Then she drifted here and there,
in the region.
So, she had a baby
in around '97 or '98.
Was it a boy or a girl?
A girl.
A girl of 17 or 18
regularly visited Lumio in prison.
I have her photo.
Look.
Meriem.
Meriem Almedia.
Is that her real name?
I think so. I'm not sure.
- You know nothing else about her?
- No.
Seems she wanted to disappear.
I have to run. I'm due in court.
- Good luck. Call me if...
- OK.
Is there a letter for me?
When did you last eat?
How far will you take this?
I think of you every day.
I'm waiting for you now
and in the next life. Meriem.
I was afraid you'd get lost.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
Do you come here often?
When I want to be alone.
Do you often want to be alone?
Sometimes.
Isn't it beautiful, with the mountains?
Can you hear the river?
Have you been home recently?
Not since I've been here.
Don't you miss your family?
Yes, but... in the meantime
it's better for them I'm far away.
"In the meantime"?
Are you asking the questions today?
I don't know.
I'm trying to get to know you.
We don't have to talk
about your investigation.
You have your notebook with you?
Ever hear the story
of the antique dealer's son?
When the antique dealer died,
his son inherited
his shop and everything in it.
On the desk, he found an envelope
that said "Do not open."
He thought it was his father's last wish,
so he didn't open it.
For years, he wondered what was inside.
When he reached his father's age,
he decided to open
the mysterious envelope.
You know what he found?
Dozens of labels that said
"Do not open."
His father stuck them on the boxes
he sold in his shop.
Not bad.
You never tried to find your parents?
No.
I found a family.
A family I chose.
Are you in pain?
Where?
My ear.
It feels like someone's shoving a...
I thought it was over.
Don't be afraid. It'll pass.
Finally,
I'm filled with love and desire.
I offer You my body and my soul, Lord.
My love has become an inferno.
Like a flame, it will rise to the Heavens
when my time comes,
and I will know love...
at last.
You have no right!
Don't touch it.
Leave it alone.
Careful, sir.
You have no right.
- You're in the house of God!
- Stop!
Stop!
- Don't touch it, it's sacred!
Stop! Stop!
Stop it! Don't touch it!
Stop...
Don't film that.
She refuses to eat, Father.
I know you secretly met
with that reporter from the commission.
What happened between you?
Is there anything I should know about?
Chapter 5
Revelation
Praise be to God!
All the Internet links are working.
Hello, Father.
More than 15 prayer groups
will be connected
with us in the United States.
A dozen in Holland,
in Austria... and in France, obviously.
Look.
How is she today?
It's only when the pilgrims
started coming in great numbers,
that the Church became
interested in Bernadette's apparitions.
The faithful have always been
ahead of the Church.
And it's the same here.
The faithful are with us.
I know.
You think she'll be able to come?
I think that commission is poison.
A test for us.
Evil...
The spirit of Evil.
It's in each of us.
I found your letter
at Meriem's foster home.
I know she came to see you.
Have you heard from her recently?
Do you know where she is?
Is she Safia's daughter?
Can you hear me?
You must eat, Anna.
Do you hear me?
Your attitude is too proud.
Maybe Meriem knew something,
but she left or was forced to go.
We were asked
to investigate an apparition,
not some sordid murder.
What if they were linked?
We'd be far from the
canonical principles of an apparition.
Canonical principles?
Meriem's mother was murdered.
The daughter
visited the murderer in prison.
They became friends.
She wrote him about faith, forgiveness.
Her mother's murderer!
Anna's best friend!
For a Christian, it's only natural.
She disappeared
when the apparitions began.
That's not a sign?
A sign?
You believe in signs now?
- That's new!
- It's none of our business.
It's my business, because it's outside
your frame of reference!
Your "canonical principles"
are perhaps what's obscuring
the simple reality.
You don't understand our mission.
Yes, I do!
If I was asked to investigate,
it was to work differently.
To get back to something concrete.
Oh yes, you're in the "real world."
Only, it doesn't exist.
It's an illusion.
The truth is never what you think.
You don't get it!
I need to know
if I was lied to or not.
If I can believe
what that girl says or not.
I want facts, proof.
Sorry.
Unknown caller
Will you be there tomorrow?
Yes, I will.
Will you come see me?
Yes.
How are you feeling?
Can I do anything?
Martyrdom is a reward, Jacques.
I hope I deserve to suffer this much.
Thank you.
Get back! Give her some air!
Move back.
Give her room to breathe.
Let's get her out of here.
Hold her.
Step aside!
Leave us alone.
Come on!
Out of the way!
Dear brothers and sisters...
It's a very heavy burden
to be chosen by the Mother of God
as her messenger.
Though the soul is strong,
the body is weak.
Let us pray for her.
Breathe normally.
Breathe.
When did you last eat?
Thank you, Doctor.
How is she?
I think you're dangerous.
I think you're empty.
I can see it in your eyes.
The Diocese has authorized me
to share my conclusions,
but my report must remain confidential.
First, the analysis of the fabric.
Undoubtedly a torn sheet,
judging by the edges.
It's a common mass-produced,
contemporary textile.
A cotton and linen blend.
An ordinary sheet
you can buy anywhere.
And the blood?
It belongs to a human male,
but we can't date the sample.
Not with dried blood.
- Did you get a DNA sample?
- Yes.
According to the DNA,
it's a Caucasian male in his thirties.
No matches in your database
or the police files?
I don't have access to police files.
But what seems interesting
for your investigation,
is that the blood type is AB+.
AB+?
Why is that interesting?
It's the same blood type
found in several sacred relics.
And?
The AB+ blood type
has been found on various relics.
The Turin Shroud,
the Holy Tunic of Argenteuil,
and the Shroud of Oviedo.
And they've been scientifically
authenticated as belonging to Christ?
No. The Church allows
the faithful to venerate them,
but does not guarantee
the factual truth.
What were you hoping for? Proof?
Proof of what?
If there were proof,
there'd be no choice.
No mystery.
Faith is a free, enlightened choice.
You choose to believe in the mystery.
You don't need proof, relics,
- blood types...
- There's no mystery.
We've been fed nonsense!
Just a big lie,
with mass-produced fabrics.
And cranks.
Nothing to do with faith!
You've never believed in her sincerity?
Why should I?
Why should I believe in it? Why?
Dear brothers and sisters...
The great sin of the modern world
is perhaps...
its refusal of the invisible.
In its search for banal proof
of the great mystery,
the Canonical Investigation Commission
has multiplied errors,
blunders,
and humiliations.
But...
the Spirit of might is in Anna.
Today, we know
that a great destiny awaits her.
For her...
the truth is obvious.
Sainthood.
It's very simple.
These images of Mother Teresa
moved me,
like many other people.
That was the true reason
I chose to live this life.
WHO ARE THE FRENCH PRIESTS
IN AFRICA?
In 1981, the final report
of the investigation
into the Turin Shroud provided
a decisive answer.
What we know is
that the blood type is clearly AB+.
I'M THE SAME BLOOD TYPE AS CHRIST!
People still have
that blood group today.
I myself am AB+.
What is it, Jacques?
The shroud was him. Anton.
He invented it.
Where are you?
Do you want me to come?
- For the rest, I don't know.
- You need sleep.
What did she see?
What happened with Meriem?
Why do you think she's gone missing?
She'd never go off without telling me.
She's never done that.
Never.
We have no news.
- Have you called the hospital?
- She's not there.
They're trying to silence her.
We must do something. I'll go.
- It doesn't concern us.
- Really?
Unknown caller
Are you Jacques?
Where is she?
Do you know?
She told me to give you this.
Do Not Open
Can you hear me?
Say something.
Miss, keep your eyes open.
Miss!
- Keep your eyes open!
- Her pulse is weak.
Blood pressure: 70/40.
Heart rate: 130.
Respiratory distress syndrome.
- She's desaturating.
- She's cold.
There's still a pulse.
- Pressure drop.
- She's pulling it out!
Bradycardia!
I've got nothing.
Stay with us.
I'm the one who needed her.
Did he give you the cloth?
It was just a symbol.
Who is he?
A charlatan?
Someone who lost his way.
I lost my way, too.
So, did she lie?
That's not for me to say.
But you know?
Not yet.
Chapter 6
Meriem
Your Grace,
I am sending you
the elements of the investigation
for which
you requested my assistance.
They include the interviews,
witness statements,
and reports of the experts
I consulted with
on Anna's alleged apparitions.
You may now draw your own conclusions.
I think of her,
of those who loved her...
of those who want
to believe in her miracle.
I think of what she was for me...
for us.
She took her secret with her.
I'm going back home,
to my family, my life, my work.
Thank you for giving me this mission.
It raised questions I'd never imagined.
I don't have the answers.
I think of the improbable story
of an angel
who came to tell a virgin
that she was carrying God's son.
I think of my late friend,
a photographer who spent his life
searching for visible proof,
images of truth...
What truth?
What images?
Perhaps the truth
is never what you think.
How can we believe
in what eludes our gaze?
I've seen so many things
around the world,
but with Anna,
I discovered a world I didn't know.
I know now, souls have their own world.
I knew nothing of that world.
Please accept, Your Grace,
my very best regards,
Jacques Mayano.
Hello.
Can I help you?
I came to talk about Anna.
She gave me the letters.
Anna didn't see anything.
It was you.
You're the one who screamed.
I screamed because I was afraid.
I don't know...
It was too much for me.
No-one would've believed me.
I wanted to leave,
have a baby.
Not be trapped by it all.
So Anna sacrificed herself.
She did it to save me,
so I could live.
She was my friend.
Do you believe me?
I don't know.
I was there
when your friend took the photo.
With the girl.
I remember him.
We spoke.
He wasn't afraid.
- You remember where the church was?
- Not a church.
A monastery.
They destroyed it.
It's faraway.
The other side of the border.
It's dangerous.
I'll see.
Subtitles: Julie Meyer & John Miller
Subtitling TITRAFILM