Subtitles by explosiveskull
Mom! Mom!
Uncle Jonas is here.
No, it's not Tuesday today.
But he is. He's here.
So, after
the Germans surrendered,
when did our king return
to Norway from exile?
Mm...
June 7, 1945.
And on what date
did the Norwegian parliament
hold its first election
after the war?
Mm...
Um...
- July 6...
- Don't guess.
Uh...
August 3...
On what date
did the Norwegian parliament
hold its first election
since the war?
Mm...
August...
August 12, 1945.
You have to help him more.
I'm going to tell your wife
that he's your son.
And then she can tell
the rest of your family.
Then you'll never see me again.
Stop! Please!
Wait!
- No!
- Jonas!
No! Jonas!
No!
Jonas!
Mom!
Mom?
Mom, come on.
We gotta get out of here.
Open the door!
Mom, come on!
Mom!
No!
Don't leave me!
No...!
Shit.
Morning.
Fuck it!
Piece of shit.
Harry Hole?
Hello.
Dry rot throughout
the whole building,
and I'm afraid we've found
some mold behind the walls.
Aspergillus,
toxic and pathogenic.
Yeah, your landlord let me in
to spray the apartment.
I'm gonna have to take
all these panels off.
And this is above your bed.
Jesus Christ.
Is there anywhere else
that you could stay?
The air in here is so bad,
you're actually killing
your house plants.
I'm not disturbing you, am I?
You are familiar
with Emanuel Vigeland?
The brothers' work
was most likely influenced
by their father,
who turned to drink,
had an illegitimate child
with a younger woman.
Yeah, that's...
yeah, that's a tragedy.
Yeah. I didn't know that
about his background.
You can clearly see
in each artist's case the...
the recurring themes
of love perverted and betrayed.
The good news is that
with this new version
of the EVISYNC,
from version 3.6
to version 4.0,
allows you to manually push
the data back to the server
using the cellular network.
The EVISYNC will automatically
upload all the new data
to the central police server
here every 12 hours.
We've also done some work
on the fingerprint
scanning software.
So you will notice
a significantly faster
opening time after scanning
your fingerprint.
But please make sure
that your fingerprint scans
are done cleanly and clearly
from the start.
If you are experiencing
a high number of false scans,
this is probably because
your fingerprints
were scanned incorrectly
from the start.
That must be nearly
a whole week of mail this time.
Did I miss anything
while I was away?
My uncle died.
Close, were you?
A leave of absence has to be
formally requested...
in writing.
Doesn't matter who you are.
Backdate it,
but I can't keep covering
for you.
I'm dealing with it.
I need a case to work on.
I apologize for Oslo's
low murder rate.
Let's, um, stick
to the uncle story.
You scared my clients away.
I didn't forget
Oleg's birthday.
I got him concert tickets.
What did you do?
We took him for a pizza.
Oleg misses you.
He doesn't get along very well
with Mathias.
What about you?
I'm not going to answer that.
He wants to meet
his real father.
I don't think
he's ready for that.
Thank you
for walking me back home.
See you at the game.
Tell Oleg...
I'm sorry I missed it.
Hi.
The snowman.
Snowman!
I'll take a picture.
Oh, it's beautiful, honey.
Mom!
Yeah, hi.
Hello.
Can I borrow your scarf?
You want my scarf? Okay.
I told you I had
to leave by 8:00.
And I told you that I had
to help one of my students.
Go to sleep. Night-night.
No, thanks.
It's the smoking room.
Yeah, but it's the only place
I can concentrate, so...
I'm, um... I'm Katrine Bratt.
Harry Hole.
I know who you are.
We, um...
We actually studied
your cases at the academy.
I didn't know
they date back that far.
Yeah, you're up there
with the legends, so...
I don't know who you are.
No, I'm new.
I, um...
I transferred from Bergen.
Actually, they put me
in your office.
Okay.
Bye.
Mom?
Mommy?
Okay, where can I
drop you? I'm on a call.
It's okay. I'm in no hurry.
So, why don't you have a car?
I don't have a license.
Missing persons?
Yeah, it's a woman.
The, uh, call just came in.
So, this machine
is called an EVISYNC,
and I will record you,
so there's a little camera
- on the other side. We're aware of it.
- Right.
Would you like to walk me
through what happened?
W-Well, I saw Josephine
in the garden in her pajamas,
and, uh, I thought,
"What is she doing
out in this cold?"
So I came over to check.
And she said she couldn't
find her mother.
I tried calling the father,
but apparently he's away
on business.
How long has she been missing?
Two days.
She said she was going
to visit a friend,
and she never came back.
Why did you come to me?
I've been suspended.
'Cause you're a friend.
And you're a great detective.
And I don't want anyone knowing
about this just yet.
Not yet. I don't want
to go to the police.
Can you tell me...
well, was your wife
seeing anyone?
I, uh, checked
her credit card bills.
She's been to see
a pregnancy doctor.
Well, that...
that's great news, Frederick.
We haven't shared a bed
in three years.
This is Birte Becker.
Please leave a message.
Hello, Mr. Donkey.
Can I sit down?
It's a nice place
you've got here, Mr. Donkey.
Did you do this by yourself?
My mom helped me.
Was she in a good mood
when she got home?
Mm-hmm.
And what about your dad?
He was grumpy again
'cause Mommy was late.
Did she call
to say she'd be late?
My dad doesn't want me
to have a phone.
She didn't phone the house?
Is he grumpy often?
Has your mother
been upset lately
when your father's been grumpy?
Have you ever seen her cry?
No.
But I saw Daddy cry.
When?
A few nights ago.
He saw me, too.
What did he do?
Locked himself in the bathroom.
Where was Mommy
when he was crying?
She'd gone out.
Shit.
Yes. Is this Filip Becker?
Okay, um, yeah, um, I'm gonna
have to call you back.
I better go.
Thank you.
He cried last week.
Why did you build the snowman
facing the house?
I didn't build the snowman.
This is Birte Becker.
Please leave a message.
You want a coffee
or something?
No.
Look, you're not gonna try
and sleep with me, are you?
No.
Okay, good.
She'll show up.
She's having an affair.
She left her coat
and her handbag in the house
and the front doors open.
Even if you're having
an affair,
you do not leave your child
like that.
And, Harry,
she's not the only one.
Look, this is Hege Dahl.
Missing two weeks.
Similar age, young children.
Unhappy marriage.
Talk to the husband.
Uh, 411 to dispatch?
Dispatch, do you receive?
Go ahead, 411.
We're up in Mount Ulriken.
It looks like a homicide.
Uh, adult female.
It's hard to see from here,
but, uh,
there's a lot of blood.
Uh, a group of schoolchildren
found her.
I've got a problem.
Rafto just showed up.
What the hell's he doing there?
He's been suspended.
Yeah, try telling him that.
Uh, we'll send the
kids down with their teacher.
Make sure there's a
care officer to meet them
and someone
to deal with the parents.
One of the children,
they heard a noise,
and they went
to see what, uh...
- what it was.
- Listen, listen, listen, John, John.
I'm gonna need you
to calm down. Calm down.
It's important
that you answer my questions...
- Who's in charge?
- Svenson.
Jesus.
Uh, it gets worse.
Rafto just arrived.
Perfect.
The drunk and the half-wit.
Just keep them apart, will you?
I'll see what I can do.
Whatever.
Where you going?
Rafto!
- We're closed.
- It's all right.
You have something of mine.
It's not yours.
Cold case.
I have clearance
to take it out.
You don't.
So, what,
you're going to report me?
Eli Kvale.
Tell me.
She was married.
She had three children.
The 12th of November,
six years ago,
she went missing.
And the day she vanished,
it was snowing.
Hege Dahl disappeared
the eighth of November.
The day she went missing,
it was snowing.
Not unusual. It's winter.
Now Birte Becker.
The night she disappeared...
- Snowing.
- Yeah.
I think it's the falling snow
that sets the killer off.
And furthermore,
they're all married,
they all have children.
Did you talk to Filip Becker?
Nine times out of ten,
the husband did it.
He was interviewed,
and his alibi is solid.
He was a hundred miles away.
Have you eaten?
No.
No, I haven't. I'm hungry.
28th, handball.
Josephine's handball match.
Third, "F. lunch."
That's lunch
with her friend Frida.
I really... I don't see
the point in doing this.
I won't keep you much longer.
Ninth, Vetlesen.
He's her doctor.
Tenth, yoga.
Do you have any idea
why your wife went to see him?
Who?
Dr. Vetlesen.
No.
Tenth, yoga.
Is there any reason
you can think of
why your wife
might disappear so suddenly?
Your marriage...
was everything all right?
Were either of you
having an affair?
Daddy!
Come on!
I promised her we'd walk
around the neighborhood
to see if we could find
her mother.
I'm just gonna get my jacket,
darling!
Come out!
Dad!
Step inside.
Mm. I thought
you wouldn't remember.
Is he still
giving you a hard time?
If you want, I can talk to him.
Oh!
Just have fun tonight.
He misses you.
Hi, Harry.
Good to see you.
Sorry I'm late, honey.
Have you had anything to eat?
No, I'll-I'll grab
something later.
No, no, no, I've got vouchers.
- Yeah?
- Yep.
Hot dog or hot dog.
Well, hot dog, then.
Harry?
I'll get something to eat
with Oleg after.
So, how are things with you?
- All right.
- Yeah?
Bit tired.
You've been working too hard,
haven't you?
I can't sleep.
You should try Valzetet.
It's a new one.
It'll help you sleep.
I can give you
a prescription right now.
- Really?
- Yeah.
With that?
Yeah.
She won't allow me
to try and find my father.
Your mother
should be the judge of that.
She won't listen to me.
She's worried about you.
All she cares about is herself.
All she cares about is you.
That's why she dumped me.
I'm such a bad influence.
She's concerned.
Concerned about what?
The fact that you run away
from home.
The fact
that you've been drinking.
So you're gonna give me
a lecture about drinking?
Don't be a prick.
Your mum told me
the school's arranged
a father-and-son camping trip.
If you want, I can come.
But you're not
her boyfriend anymore.
So?
Yeah.
I want you to come.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Good.
So, what's the...
the big surprise?
Uh...
Let's find out.
Someone at work
got me the tickets.
You got a message.
Let me see what it says.
I gotta make a call.
You stay here?
Harry, there's another
missing woman...
in Geilo this time.
That's not our jurisdiction.
I think we should have
a look at this.
I'm going to be with you
in two minutes, okay?
Her husband specifically
asked for you.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Oh, I didn't expect you
so early.
- Something came up.
- Oh.
Hi, Harry.
- Hi.
- How was the concert?
Yeah, it was... it was great.
We spoke.
I'm taking him on the
father-and-son camping trip...
thing.
Uh...
See you.
- Hey.
- Bye.
Take me home.
We'll go in the morning.
Who reported her missing?
Her husband last night.
20:05.
Sylvia Ottersen, 33 years old.
Self-employed, married twice.
But no children.
Hello?
Hello!
- Hi.
Can I help you?
Yeah, well,
we're with the Oslo Police.
We got the
missing persons call.
Oh. Who's missing?
Sylvia Ottersen.
I'm Sylvia Ottersen.
What, you're Sylvia Ottersen?
Why... why would your husband
report you missing?
I have no idea.
He's not the kind
to play practical jokes.
- Is he here?
- No.
He's gone to the station
to pick up my sister.
Okay.
Well, I guess it must be
a crank call.
We didn't know where you were,
so we had a look
inside the house.
I turned your music off.
Sorry about that.
Thank you.
Can I just ask you...
is it just
you and your husband,
or do you have any children?
No, it's just us.
Okay. Thank you.
What the hell
do you think you're doing?
You know damn well
what I'm talking about.
Calling the police,
telling them I'm missing.
You think that's funny?
Don't you understand?
It's over.
I don't want to see you again.
No, it wasn't your child.
It was mine.
If you call one more time,
I'm going to the police.
HQ to DC Bratt.
DC Bratt?
Yeah, speaking.
We've had
a missing persons report.
A woman named Sylvia Ottersen.
Oh, no, she's fine.
We-we just left her.
Well, the call
came in two minutes ago.
Her husband asked specifically
for Inspector Hole.
How could...
Turn the car around.
Sylvia?
Sorry we're back,
Mrs. Ottersen.
We just wanted to make sure
you were all right.
I'm Ann Pedersen.
Sylvia's my sister.
We're twins.
Who are you?
- Is that enough?
- Yeah, keep going.
Did you find Hagen?
He's at the dinner
at City Hall.
Let's keep it clear,
if you can.
She was a free spirit.
And she always liked men.
Ever since we were teenagers.
She was a good person.
She didn't want to hurt anyone.
It's just the way she was.
I know your sister
didn't have any children.
It was just that there
was something
in her reaction
that when I asked...
She was pregnant.
She wasn't sure
who the father was.
She got rid of the baby
a few weeks ago.
This way, please.
Thank you very much.
That's it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
introducing our guest of honor,
king of industry,
philanthropist,
and head of Oslo's
Winter Games bid,
Arve Stop.
So lovely of you
to be here for us.
I'm not on the list, but I know
many of these people.
I'm supposed to be on the list.
I'm a close, old friend
of Arve Stop's, you see.
- There's been some kind of misunderstanding.
- I have a...
- a person named Vetlesen.
- Come on up.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
you can come here.
He says he's
a friend of Arve Stop.
- No. Wait, wait.
- No, it's fine, it's fine.
No, just relax, just relax.
I run over a dozen companies.
When people ask me why
I've given up so much
of my time to lead this bid,
I tell them it's because I
never had these opportunities.
When I was a boy, the only
winter sports I engaged in
were the uphill snow shovel
and the 50-meter
firewood carry.
That is why I believe
passionately that this Cup
is about much more than just
publicity for our fair city.
Homicides?
Just missing persons for now,
but the pattern is disturbing.
And...
I received this.
Prints?
It isn't just the letter.
He reported her missing
before he killed her.
He was watching us
the entire time.
What do you need?
Small team.
I'll set up a separate
incident room at the mill.
All right, but I don't want
a word of this to be leaked...
- To the press.
- Press, yeah.
Not until this fucking bid
is over.
Does this strike you as the
proper time and place for this?
Wait.
Idiot.
What?
Arve?
What? No, don't cry.
Listen, what...
Shit.
Hey.
Hey!
Get out.
Get out!
Hey.
Oi, mate!
Annette Elden, 33,
disappeared
12th of December, 2006.
Her head washed ashore
near Arendal.
Rest of the body never found.
Forensic reports indicate
saw marks on her neck.
Status: unmarried.
Two children
by different fathers.
Harry, I got the names
and the addresses
of Sylvia Ottersen's
boyfriends.
Now, she went to the clinic
the second of November,
but they won't break
patient confidentiality.
They do, however,
perform abortions.
What is it?
Magnus, get me the list.
What list?
The list of doctors
at the Gellion.
I'm thinking
that he's going after women
- that he disapproves of.
- Here you go.
All the doctors at Gellion
from the last five years.
How did he know?
How did he know
Sylvia Ottersen was pregnant?
Idar Vetlesen.
Birte Becker had an appointment
with the same doctor.
Dr. Idar Vetlesen?
Yes, that's me.
Step in.
Birte Becker
and Sylvia Ottersen
were both patients of yours?
Uh, no. Uh, they were both
patients at the clinic.
Uh, I never met
Sylvia Ottersen.
Can you tell me
who treated her?
No, I am bound
by patient confidentiality.
She's dead.
Oh.
Oh, no.
Right.
Well, doctor confidentiality.
In theory, would it be possible
for you to access
her medical files?
Even if you didn't
treat her yourself.
Well, in theory, yes.
The doctors at the clinic
have access
to the files of every patient,
should they choose
to look at them.
Which I did not.
What did you see
Birte Becker about?
Well, that is,
uh, confidential.
How do you know Arve Stop?
- Arve?
- Hmm?
Well, I've known Arve
for years.
I do research
in premature birth.
We have a small charity,
and Arve Stop is one of
- our biggest supporters.
- Huh, I wouldn't have thought
that a man who goes on so much
about family values
would support a clinic
that specializes in abortion.
Well, we specialize
in many different areas.
- Hmm.
- And Mr. Stop
supports our research
in premature birth.
So, do you see each other
socially?
Well, yeah, well,
that depends on how you mean.
It's quite simple, actually.
Do you have friends in common?
Yes, we-we mix
in the same circles, so...
- Why-why are you, uh...
- To know if you...
Have you ever practiced
in other parts
of the country, Dr. Vetlesen?
Yes, I have.
In, uh... in Eidsvoll,
in, uh, Lillehammer.
I see you have a picture
of Mon Plaisir pavilion
- in Bergen.
- Yes, yes. In Bergen.
Do you live alone?
Yes, I, uh...
I am a reluctant bachelor.
Is there anyone
in the house right now?
Because I thought I saw someone
in the window when I passed.
Right, well, if you want
to take a look around,
I will need to see
a search warrant.
In fact, if you don't mind,
I would like to call my lawyer
before I answer any more
of your questions.
That won't be necessary,
Dr. Vetlesen.
You can bring your lawyer
when we see you next time.
- Hey.
What was that?
- What?
- He isn't a suspect yet.
We need his permission
to search the house.
I know that.
Why'd you ask him
about Arve Stop?
I saw a picture
of them both together.
And?
And it was
an innocent question.
Jesus, anyone can see
he's trying to hide something.
Why...
Oh, hey.
Cloudberry.
If you hadn't told me
to look out for it,
I'd have assumed
she was attached
to his security detail.
Cloudberry?
It's her password.
Does this strike you
as the proper time
and place for this?
- Arve Stop.
- Idiot.
She filmed him at rallies,
at restaurants, at home.
Hi.
Do you want a ride?
No.
Bye.
The 8:45 train to Bergen
is leaving from platform five.
Oh, sorry.
This is the 8:45 service
to Bergen, stopping at Gol,
Finse, Voss and Bergen.
The next station is Gol.
Hi, Harry.
Hi.
Hiding in the playroom, are we?
Yes.
Don't worry.
I-I'm getting off
at the next stop.
Going far?
Bergen.
Ah, rather you than me.
Then again, I am attending
a three-day conference
on bioidentical
hormone restoration.
I thought you were
a plastic surgeon.
Well, you know,
cosmetic surgery
needs to move
with the times, too.
We're swapping the scalpel for
hormone replacement therapy.
If you can slow down
the aging process,
there won't be any need
for face-lifts, will there?
I'll bear that in mind.
So, how is the prescription
working?
Sleeping like a baby.
Splendid.
So, you...
you canceled the Oleg thing.
The school trip.
Weren't you supposed to...
Oh, shit.
- Shit.
- I'm-I'm sorry, Harry.
- Uh, I'm sure he's fine.
- Oleg, you coming?
- He-he knows how busy you are.
- Come on.
Shit.
Look, look, you're-you're not
his father, Harry.
- What does that mean?
- Well, uh...
I don't have to be his father
to care about him.
I was trying to say that...
it's a big enough
responsibility
for a real father, isn't it?
Let alone you and me.
- Sorry, Harry.
- No.
Did you hear from him?
Why can't I go?
- Can I go with you?
- Just go!
Hi, Oleg. It's Mathias.
You know what?
Uh, I forgot to check
my messages last night,
and, uh, Harry called to say
that he couldn't make
your trip.
No, I know.
No, well, he-he couldn't get
through to you
or your mom, apparently,
so I...
No, it-it's totally
my fault, Oleg.
Yes, yes. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Oleg. Yes.
Yeah.
So, see... see you
in a few days, then,
wh-when I'm back
from the conference. Yeah.
You didn't have to do that.
Ready? That's it!
Stop!
Hey, Aasen, someone here
to speak to you.
Aasen.
My family owned all
of these buildings.
And that house over there, too.
Arve Stop worked
for us back then.
He was, uh, bright, ambitious.
My father really
believed in him.
The business
wasn't going very well,
so we, uh, offered him a stake.
Within a year,
he had forced us out.
Sold the land for a fortune.
Have any of my colleagues been
in touch with you recently?
A young lady?
No.
I look at this picture now,
I see Laila staring at him.
No idea at the time.
Family man, eh?
Do you remember the name
of your wife's doctor?
Sure.
Uh, Morton Freiberg.
Did she ever see someone
called Vetlesen?
Vetlesen? No.
Dr. Idar Vetlesen.
No.
Any idea where I might find
the officer who was
in charge of the case?
Rafto?
He-he died.
Yeah, he-he died
around the same time.
Detective Rafto.
Can you connect me
to Haukeland Hospital?
What is this?
Am I under arrest?
- A cake!
- Yeah.
I need some information
on a patient.
Laila Aasen.
No, I don't... Listen to me.
I don't know
the admitting doctor.
But perhaps she was there
for an abortion?
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
Well, then I'll come down there
- with a fucking warrant myself.
- ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday dear Svenson ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you. ♪
Rafto?
- Idiot.
- Hip, hip, hooray!
- Fucking incompetent sons of bitches.
Hooray!
Oi! Rafto?
Rafto!
What the hell is he doing?
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
In! In!
Get back. Get back in.
Get back in.
♪ Happy birthday to you. ♪
You idiot!
I heard he was
a great detective.
He was a suicidal maniac.
They were gonna
suspend him anyway.
They found stuff
in his drawers.
Items he'd stolen
from various crime scenes.
Is this him?
Where'd you get this?
From a colleague.
Yes, that's him.
He had this cabin
up on the coast.
Used to go up there
to get smashed.
He was probably drunk
when he shot himself.
What's this on the floor?
They look like coffee beans.
Maybe he was trying
to sober up after all.
You didn't check?
The cabin was locked
from the inside,
and he looked like that
when they found him.
There wasn't anything to check.
Did he have any family?
Wife who left him a year
before he killed himself.
Um, I think there was
a daughter.
Do you know where she is now?
Not a clue.
Is the cabin still there?
What are you doing
with my fucking gun, you idiot?
- Here's the papers you asked for.
- Hey.
Where's Harry?
In Bergen.
- Hello?
- Mr. Hole?
This is Harry Hole's phone.
Can I speak to him?
He's not here right now,
but I can take
the message for him.
Right, okay.
Uh, this is Rebecca,
NRS at Telenor.
We picked up a signal
from a missing person's phone,
case number MP2.
Uh, um, I don't have
any files in front of me.
Um, who's that?
I'll check.
Birte Becker.
What, it...
- Is it transmitting now?
- Yeah.
Just got it in minutes ago.
Yeah, but wait, wait. Is it...
is it moving right now?
No. I'll send you
the coordinates.
No, just...
Wh-What's the address?
Uh, Parkway 1, 0139 Oslo.
You're sure that's correct?
Yes, Parkway 1.
Hey, are you all right?
This is Birte Becker.
Please leave a message.
Wednesday, unless you...
Yes?
- In his own garage?
- Yeah.
Ah, the great Harry Hole.
How many bodies?
Birte Becker and Ms. Dahl.
- Where's Katrine?
- Suspended.
She got a call telling her
they traced the Becker phone
and didn't think
to tell anyone.
I asked you where she was.
That's not my problem
right now.
He shot himself straight on.
How do you do that
with a shotgun?
It's too long.
You'd have to angle it.
Pellet marks should be
up there somewhere.
Luckily, we have experts
to determine that.
You sure he was alone?
The garage door was closed.
One set of footprints.
We found two bodies
in the house
and Birte Becker's phone.
It was a suicide.
Case closed.
Mathias, listen.
I have no idea where he's gone.
Yes, I've checked my messages.
He hasn't called.
Oh, well, how can you help?
You're at your
bloody conference!
Can I keep this?
No.
Yeah, sure.
She's not picking up.
Katrine!
Get off!
Stop.
I guess congratulations
are in order.
You know it wasn't that creep.
Vetlesen didn't commit suicide.
Someone killed him
because we got too close.
Like your father.
My father would never
have committed suicide.
He would never
have left me like that.
Get off me.
Get off me. Get off me!
Get off me!
Get off me, you fucking drunk!
Get off.
Yeah.
I'm a drunk.
Like your father.
Laila Aasen and Arve Stop
were having an affair,
and that's the last thing
my father was investigating
before he got killed.
You broke into Vetlesen's house
because you were afraid
I'd find out this was personal
and take you off the case.
Vetlesen was his pimp.
And they were both in Bergen
when the murders started.
I know how much you want this,
but you can't force
the pieces to fit.
I called the Gellion Clinic,
and Vetlesen
wasn't even working
the day he was supposed
to meet Birte Becker.
They found two dead bodies
in his house
and Birte Becker's phone.
Well, isn't that
convenient, then?
So Hagen has his killer
and Arve Stop's safe,
and no questions are asked.
Do you actually think
he killed them?
I don't know.
I don't think
either of us do for sure.
Maybe this will bring
your balls back.
I'm gonna need your weapon.
It's right there
in front of you.
Why did he call you Cloudberry?
Because I liked
cloudberry jam with ice cream.
Oleg ran away again.
It doesn't really matter
if we win or lose
this bid tonight.
What matters most
is that we celebrate
the way this has
brought us together,
and use that energy
to restore the values
that make Norway great.
And so it doesn't matter
if, uh,
56 minutes and 33 seconds from
now... but who's counting...
...if the World Cup
goes to Beijing
or Denver or Montreal.
Because I believe in my heart,
tonight,
Oslo has already won.
I tried calling.
I thought he might be with you.
- Oh.
- He's okay.
He's, uh...
he's at a friend's house.
Just didn't bother calling me.
What did you argue about?
Um, he doesn't want
to leave the city.
I thought that change
would be good for him.
Well, for me, too.
Where?
Um, Mathias has a house,
uh, up in Telemark.
And because he consults
all over the place, uh,
it's not too inconvenient.
I saw him the other day.
He didn't mention anything.
Is that really what you want?
I don't know what I want.
I miss you.
In my head, I know it's 50-50,
but in my heart 100%.
- Thank you for coming.
- Mr. Stop?
Mr. Stop, I'm sorry.
I, um...
I just want to thank you.
I really liked your speech.
I found it very, very moving.
Well, you see, I, um...
I was an orphan myself, so...
Well, it doesn't have to be
a disadvantage, young lady.
It can motivate us, too.
Oh.
Well, yes.
I work in Bergen with...
with young people
in a care center, and I know
how... how very busy you are,
but if you're ever
in the city...
I started my career in Bergen.
Write to me.
- I'll see what I can do.
- Yes. I'm so sorry. I know...
I know people are waiting
to talk to you. Thank you.
- Not at all.
- Oh.
Mr. Stop wanted me
to let you know
how much he enjoyed
your conversation.
- Oh.
- It's, um...
It's room 472.
He'll be free
after the announcement,
if there's anything else
you'd like to ask him.
Thank you.
Mathias.
Where are you?
I just tried calling you
on the landline.
I'm at Harry's.
Yeah?
Because I phoned
Eric's parents,
and Oleg wasn't there,
either, so I fig...
No, no, I found him.
He was with another friend.
Are you okay?
Yes, I-I'm fine now.
Mathias...
Uh, I've got to run, uh,
to one of those
boring dinners, but...
I'll call you in the morning
when I'm back.
Okay?
Shit.
You couldn't have asked
another doctor?
What?
Two minutes,
ladies and gentlemen.
Hello?
And to all our viewers
around the world, thank you
for joining us here tonight
at the hotel...
No! No!
Stop! No!
...of Beijing, Denver, Oslo
and Montreal.
No!
...there can only be
one winner.
...that the 15th
Winter Sports World Cup...
has been awarded to...
Two, one...
Oslo.
Thank you.
Congrats to us all.
Woo-hoo.
That's the last of her files
to download.
There's nothing after that.
Get me a list
of all the phone calls
and appointments she made
while I was away.
Magnus!
Yeah, sure.
- When was this taken?
- Two days ago.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
- I'm late to get her to school.
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- I have to get to work.
- I am sorry.
I have one quick question
I need to ask you.
- We have been over this hundreds of times.
- I know.
I know we have been over this
a hundred times,
but I need to sort
something out.
Dr. Vetlesen was not working
at the clinic
the day your wife
was supposed to see him.
He wasn't there.
- So she got the day wrong.
- I...
- How the...
- Daddy!
Josephine, in the car.
How the hell am I supposed to
remember what day we saw him?
Uh, sir, I'm just trying
to find your wife.
Please help me.
How the hell am I supposed
to remember
what day we saw him?
Uh, sir, I'm just trying
to find your wife.
Please help me. I will...
How the hell am I supposed to
remember what day we saw him?
Sir, I'm trying
to find your wife.
How the hell am I supposed to
remember what day we saw him?
Sir, I'm trying
to find your wife.
- ...what day we saw him?
- Sir...
- ...what day we saw him? ...what day...
Yes, I want all those files.
- Send them to me.
- Give me your car keys.
- What?
- And your phone.
Yes?
You told me Vetlesen
was your wife's doctor
when we spoke.
And that you had no idea
why she'd gone to see him.
Yes.
But you told my colleague
you both went to see him.
She must have misheard me.
She recorded the interview.
Darling, go back inside.
I'll come in
in a minute, okay?
Good girl.
She isn't mine.
Birte and I were trying
for another child.
We thought it might
save our marriage.
We had blood tests done
at the clinic
for hormone treatment.
And it came out that...
she wasn't mine.
I am infertile.
I've always been infertile.
Can't have children.
But she is mine.
Do you understand?
How could I not love her?
But you didn't see Vetlesen
the day you found out.
No, we saw
some hormone specialist.
Visiting consultant.
Do you know his name?
Yes?
Just a second.
Damn it.
I said I'm coming.
You never called.
Is Oleg back?
What? Oleg?
He... he's at school.
And Harry?
Is Harry here?
No.
Oh.
How did he convince you
to give him those pills?
He didn't.
You didn't have
to do it for me.
I didn't do it for you.
It was never about you.
I'm outside his house.
I can't reach Rakel.
Send someone to her apartment.
Oleg.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Why do you have Mom's phone?
Come on.
You and I have more in common
than you think.
I didn't know
who my father was, either.
Magnus, track Rakel's phone.
Sorry, I just...
All right.
Okay, Harry, we just
picked up her signal,
heading west towards Telemark.
It is a red Volvo,
registered to
a Mathias Lund-Helgesen,
Rjukan, 2421.
The house is pretty remote.
There's-there's an access road,
but that's it.
And there's a big lake
around it.
Helicopters are grounded
because of the weather,
but Delta is on their way.
Anything on Mathias's family?
Okay, I've got something here.
Jonas Lund-Helgesen,
former police officer,
lost his job in '89.
A scandal involving
a woman drowning in a car.
Probable suicide.
- She had a son.
- Stop!
Father unknown.
Please!
He was sent to an orphanage.
Who led the investigation
into the woman's disappearance?
Some local talent
in the village nearby.
What's his name?
Jonas Lund-Helgesen.
Jonas! No!
Please stop!
Harry?
Harry? We've lost him.
Sit down, Harry.
Pass me the gun.
I didn't think you'd find me.
Perhaps the pills helped
after all.
I spoke to Filip Becker.
What's going to happen
when Josephine Becker
finds out he isn't her father?
She'll still love him.
Wrong answer.
Let's try again.
Was it right
for Sylvia Ottersen
to kill her unborn child
simply because
she couldn't keep track
of who the father was?
That was her choice.
Too short.
Maybe she was afraid.
What about you, Harry?
You have a woman who loves you.
A boy who's devoted to you.
Why did you abandon them?
They deserve better.
Too easy.
Because...
I'm selfish.
I'm an addict.
There isn't enough room
for them.
You know, when I first saw
your picture in the papers...
...with all those medals,
I thought, "That man
must have a perfect family."
And here you are.
Last question.
This boy, who doesn't even know
who his father is...
...who's had to put up
with so many men
like you and me
taking his place...
...does his mother
deserve to live?
Why don't you ask him?
You all right?
Kill him. Kill him.
Kill him!
Come on!
I'm ready!
I'm here!
Come on!
I know why you blame her.
You've been wrong
the whole time.
It wasn't her.
It wasn't your mother
who didn't want you.
It was your father.
It would have been better
for him...
...had you not been born.
The pathologist detected traces
of the drug Ketanome.
But the direct cause of death
was drowning
as a result of blood
filling her lungs.
24 stab wounds
were found in her mouth,
all at regular intervals,
and at the same depth...
seven centimeters.
Pathologist can't determine
what kind of weapon was used.
And he's never seen
anything like it.
I'll take it.
Subtitles by explosiveskull