Come on all you guys. Get to it.
Hiya Harry. What kept you?
Are you kidding? You know what
you can do with this weather.
What do you care? Next week
you'll be back in the States.
You mean it came through?
- Don't ask me. Ask the Captain.
See you.
Good luck .. you lucky stiff.
Come on all you guys, get moving.
Harry?
Hiya, sweetie.
Daddy .. daddy, daddy.
Daddy. Hi, daddy.
- Hiya, Butch.
Say, you're up awful late.
Way past your bedtime.
He insisted on waiting
up until you came home.
Hi.
- Hi.
Hey Pa, guess what? I shot a bear today.
You did?
- And a lion and a tiger.
Wow.
- We went to the zoo.
Say, Butch.
How would you like to go somewhere
they've got real lions and bears?
Gee, when can we go, Daddy?
Oh, in about a couple of weeks.
We'll be taking a long airplane trip.
You, me and mum.
You mean we're going to America?
- That's right.
Now be a good boy and go to sleep, and
I'll tell you about it in the morning.
Goodnight, Daddy.
- Night.
Goodnight, Mum.
- Goodnight Tommy.
So your discharge came through?
Yeah.
You don't seem very pleased about it.
I'll be very pleased to get
away from this sort of life.
Six years of living in married quarters.
I've begun to feel as if I'd
joined the army myself.
You don't want to go to America do you?
Look, Connie.
I know that we've been
through this before.
But I still don't understand why.
The soup will get cold.
- Why, Connie?
I just don't want to go. That's all.
But Connie, everything is all set.
Al's taking me into his business ..
Al ..
I don't believe Al even has a business.
Are you kidding?
His father left him one of the largest
canning factories in California.
What's he going to do?
Make you a partner?
I don't understand you, Connie. You were
right here in this room the day Al left.
You remember what he said.
- He said a lot of things.
He was a big talker all round.
- Alright, alright.
So he was a big talker, but he's
always played it straight with me.
What do you have against him?
It's nothing to do with Al. It's just ..
- Just what?
Well Harry, couldn't we wait a while?
All we seem to have done these
past six years is pack and unpack.
I've got a home, too.
And a mother that I haven't
seen since we were married.
Couldn't spend a few months in
England before we go to America?
You mean, in Liverpool?
It's my home, Harry.
Alright.
We'll spend a few months in Liverpool.
But what do I do for a job?
Well, uncle George would
find you something.
Uncle George, huh?
Look, Harry.
I love you very much.
I wouldn't want to stand in
your way. You know that.
If you would just do this for me.
Well, it looks like a ..
I'm going to quit working
for Uncle Sam ..
And start working for uncle George.
Thank you.
Come here.
Oh no, Harry. The steak. It will burn.
Ten pound a week plus meals and
lodging allowance for a 44-hour week.
I should have stayed in the army.
Hey, tighten them ropes.
Do you want to lose that load?
You got to watch them all the time.
Well, there you are.
Take it or leave it.
I don't have much of a choice, do I.
Alright. Come on.
This is yours, Miller.
How far is Glasgow?
Two hundred miles.
That'll take about ten hours, huh?
You've been reading them
rules and regulations.
In this game, if you can't make
400 miles a day, you're fired, so ..
Climb aboard my boy and let
your uncle Casey lead the way.
Well, hello.
- Hi.
A coffee.
- A cup of coffee.
Well, we made pretty
good time there, lad.
We sure did.
There's nothing like a strong cup of
tea for keeping the weather out.
Who are your friends?
I never saw them before in my life.
They look kind of sharp.
Sharp as razors.
Well .. I guess I'll get going.
Here.
What's your hurry?
We've a long way to go.
The way you drive
I'll need a head start.
Don't you even have the manners
to wait until I've finished my tea?
See you on the road.
Hey.
What's the idea? Put that stuff back.
You're a bit wet behind the ears
son, aren't you. Go on, beat it.
Holy by Jesus.
Saints preserve us.
What are you after doing?
Two guys were trying to
steal things from your truck.
Boy, you've got a lot to
learn about this game.
Look Casey, they were ..
- Do me a favour.
Get out of here.
- But Casey ..
Come on, come on.
I'll explain later. Come on.
Alright.
Ah, well.
Another time, eh?
Okay, hold it there.
You made good time. We didn't
expect this load until morning.
Where can I get a return
load to Liverpool?
You're new around here, aren't you?
That's right.
There's only one man to see.
Joe Easy.
There isn't much that moves in and out
of this dock that he doesn't handle.
Left at the gate and down the
street there. You cannot miss it.
Thanks.
Aberdeen. Who's to Aberdeen?
Edinburgh. Anyone for Edinburgh?
Yeah. Here.
What's the load?
- Pig iron.
How much?
- Fifteen bob a ton.
Well?
Alright.
- Name?
Grey.
Ta.
Yes?
- Liverpool.
What have you got?
- A ten-tonner.
Name?
- Miller.
Alright. Wait a minute, will you.
- Sure.
Where'd you get that mutt?
I picked him up on the road.
I guess he must have got lost.
What are we going to do with you, eh?
I've a little kid at home who would know
what to do with him. Want to sell him?
Here, you have him.
Say, thanks.
I'd like to pay you for it.
I'm glad to get rid of him.
Who's for Cardiff?
- Yeah. Me.
Name?
- Jones.
Inverness. Anyone for Inverness?
What's the load, mate?
- Fertilizer.
Why don't you mail it?
Liverpool. Liverpool anyone?
- Here.
A load of timber for
Liverpool. Any offers?
I'm right here.
I'm going to Liverpool.
- Name?
Kenny.
Hey, just a minute. Look,
I've been waiting over here.
What's the idea?
- Sorry, chum.
That's his load.
Let him have it. I'll find out
what's going on around here.
We take it in turns here, son.
Look, either you have the
merchandise or you haven't.
If you haven't we can't do business.
We would have, Mr Easy.
But we got into trouble.
That's your headache.
What do you want?
- Look, I just checked in outside.
Okay, put it somewhere else will you.
Come on, come on.
Joe.
- What?
Did you okay this contract?
That's my signature, isn't it?
Look, do you mind?
The man wants to see you, Joe.
What is it? What do you want?
I've an empty truck.
I'd like to fill it.
Get back on the right.
I've tried there. Your man doesn't
want to do business with me.
Well, maybe he doesn't like
your face or something.
Now go on, get out of here.
I've got work to do.
You heard.
- All I want is a job.
Come on, let's go.
- Mind the dog.
Get him out of here.
Come on, out of it ..
You too. Beat it.
One thing I wish I could do without
in this business is truck drivers.
I seem to remember you
drove a truck once yourself.
Things were different then.
No unions, no nothing.
No. It was a real tough game.
No rules.
Except this.
And you're still playing by
the old rules, aren't you.
That brother of yours is
beginning to get in my hair.
He's a smart boy, Joe.
- Oh, sure.
He's probably the smartest bookkeeper
whoever came out of jail.
We all make mistakes.
I made a mistake the day I took him on.
He's still going to go on
working for you, isn't he.
Well, are you coming? Because
I'm tired and I want to go home.
Look.
Why don't you go across the
street and get a cup of coffee?
I'll be five minutes.
Five minutes?
Are you badly hurt?
What's the matter?
What's happened?
Give me a hand with him, will you.
- Sure, sure.
Let's get him inside.
Dad, what happened?
I'll get some brandy.
Ben, get me the brandy. Quick.
You shouldn't have gone in there
like that. It was asking for trouble.
I was only asking for a job.
You were asking for a job and
they gave you the business, eh?
Here.
Thanks.
Hey, hey, hey. That ain't beer.
Are you going to be alright now?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Hey .. hey.
Say ..
How about taking a couple of days off?
Take Connie and the kid away
for the weekend somewhere.
What's the angle? This isn't Christmas.
I'd like you to make a
run into Glasgow tonight.
You got to be kidding.
I've been driving all
day long. I'm bushed.
There is a bonus in it if you'll do it.
Do what?
There are five hundred crates
of whiskey on that vehicle.
That's a new twist.
Taking Scotch into Scotland.
You know, I thought that Casey
was on the Glasgow run this week.
That's just it.
I guess I could use a couple of days.
And a bonus.
I can definitely use that.
Alright then?
- Okay.
Hey .. hey!
As it is, we've missed
the preliminaries.
Hey, Lynn!
Hello?
Yes.
Yes, that's right.
Come on, will you?
We'll miss the main bout.
I should break my neck
to see a boxing match.
Just a moment.
Joe.
It's for you.
- I'm not here.
It's a man called Casey.
He says it's very urgent.
Yep?
Speaking.
Yeah.
Well, who is driving it?
You're sorry?
What is it?
The whole thing is set up.
Then someone has to get smart.
Well, are we working or playing?
Relax, will you.
Ed? Joe.
It's a new deal.
Yes I know. Now, listen.
The truck just left. Get on that road.
Find it. As soon as it stops, ring me.
No. I'll handle this one myself.
Hello, Mr Easy.
Hiya, Mr Easy.
I hear you're an honest man.
So?
It's a pleasure to meet an honest man.
What's your price?
That's quite a load you have out there.
I think we could do a deal.
Look.
Suppose you were to take a walk.
Go out back or have a wash or something.
Hot coffee.
- Coffee.
Ten cigarettes.
I thought I told you to wait in the car.
I'm getting just a little tired
of waiting for you, Joe.
I'm hungry and I want to
go and eat somewhere.
If you want to eat something,
then eat something.
In this pig-house?
Listen. You were serving in a pig-house
like this when I picked you up, baby.
Watch out I don't drop you
right back among the pigs.
You want to walk back to town, Joe?
Because I'm taking the car.
I wouldn't do that.
Hey, fellahs.
This must be the only café on the
road that has a floor show, huh?
Get him out of there.
Never seen anything like it.
Look, lady. I've got enough
trouble of my own. I don't ..
Please, just drive me somewhere.
I can't do it.
- I've got to get away from here.
Please.
Alright.
Here.
Where are we?
You hungry?
Are you in love with that guy?
In love with Joe?
Nobody loves Joe .. except maybe Joe.
You were so upset I thought maybe ..
My old man used to get
drunk and knock me around.
Then I hated him.
But one day the police
came and took him away.
And I cried.
It's funny.
When you don't have much,
you don't like losing it.
It's just Frank I'm worried about.
He's my brother.
You see ..
Joe puts up with him on
account of me, but ..
I don't suppose he'd ever get
himself a job anywhere else.
You're married, aren't you?
Does it show?
I can always tell.
Married men are more ..
Simpatico.
Well that's Italian. It means sort of ..
Sympathetic?
You know something
else I like about you?
You haven't tried to
make one pass at me.
Usually, when fellow takes a
girl out and buys her a meal ..
He thinks that she's the dessert.
Well.
Shall we go?
Okay.
Harry.
Thanks.
What for?
Being simpatico.
Thanks.
You look tired, mister.
Been driving long?
All night.
We got rooms.
Want to rest up a little?
You and the wife?
You'd better close this up.
You'll catch cold.
Coffee, please.
- Okay.
What's the name of this place?
- Wayside.
Give me the police please.
Hello? My name is Miller.
I'm at the Wayside café on the A59.
I've just had my truck stolen.
Harry. What happened?
What's going on? Was it your truck?
Did somebody steal it?
It's quite an act you've put on.
The next time you see
that boyfriend of yours ..
The next time I see him
I'll break both his arms.
No, Harry. You're wrong.
Harry, listen to me, please.
I didn't have anything to do with it.
Harry.
What I can't understand Harry is, why?
If you needed cash ..
- You think I was in on it?
Well, what did you stop for?
- Because I was tired.
How about the girl? Was she tired too?
Harry.
You fell for oldest gag on the road.
- Yeah, yeah.
Well.
You're in for a hard time of it now.
Because the insurance companies
won't touch you after this.
And I don't think Connie is going
to be very happy about it, either.
Who was she, Harry?
Some girl you picked up on the road?
Suppose we don't talk about it.
- Well I want to talk about it.
I don't.
Well, I hope it was worth it.
Well, so now you're out of work.
What are we going to do?
I'll tell you what we're going to do.
Tomorrow morning, I'm going
down to the steamship company.
I'm going to buy three
tickets for America.
Tonight, I'm writing Al to
tell him we're on our way.
I won't go, Harry.
What do you want me to do, Connie?
Stay here and scratch around
trying to make a living?
When I've got a good job
waiting for me back home.
I'm not going.
Alright.
You go to America.
But you'll go without me.
Easy, easy.
Easy, Connie.
I'm with you, baby.
We'll figure something out.
Joe.
Well?
We couldn't find her, Mr Easy.
We went back to the
café but she had gone.
Gone where?
Did she go off with that truck driver?
Well did she or didn't she?
I don't know, Mr Easy.
A truck driver.
Frank.
Yes, Joe?
I want you to go out and find that
sister of yours and bring her back here.
How?
In chains?
I don't care how.
I just want her back here. That's all.
A cup of tea, Joe.
- Right.
Oh, it's real cold. Real cold.
Cold enough to freeze the
head off a brass monkey.
Well, how you been?
Not so good, I hear.
Ah, that's bad, bad.
Nothing is so degrading for a
man as to be looking for work.
Oh and ..
There is something I wanted
to talk to you about.
Care for a drink?
I've a little job on hand.
I need someone to drive a truck.
Someone reliable.
Like yourself for instance.
There is ..
There's two hundred
pounds in it for you.
It sounds pretty crooked.
Crooked? Well a little ..
Bent maybe.
I'll see you later, Casey.
- What's the matter?
You and the family given up eating?
Don't worry about me and
the family. I'll get a job.
Doing what?
You're on the list, Harry.
Once you're on the list, you're dead.
Sorry chum, can't use you.
Alright. Back it onto
the other truck. Come on.
Come on.
Hiya, Harry boy.
Hi, Casey.
Looks like one of Joe Easy's trucks.
You don't say.
Are things getting so tough
he has to rob himself?
Okay Tom, let's have you.
Right.
Looks like they ran out of gas.
Nothing like a nice
fire on a cold night.
Alright Casey, let's go.
Be seeing you, boy.
Get her up to the hedge.
- Right.
Okay. That's enough.
Alright, Casey?
- Okay.
Alright. Let her go!
Come on, let's get out of here.
Well come on, come on.
I can't understand it.
I know that road like
the back of my hand.
There is nothing to it.
Unless something went
wrong with the steering.
We didn't find any skid-marks.
Still, we'll be able to have
a proper look in the morning.
Yeah.
Well?
You will be required to give evidence
at the inquest of course, Mr Easy.
Yes. Yeah, of course.
What do you want?
What's this?
What does it look like?
It's all burnt.
So is Casey.
Now.
Give me my money.
It was too bad about Casey.
Getting killed like that.
It's not going to work out, Joe.
The police aren't stupid and
neither is the insurance company.
Why don't you wrap it up?
You must have really needed that money.
What's the matter?
Can't you afford her anymore?
Is she buying too many dresses?
Going to too many clubs?
Just a little too rich
for your blood, huh?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about Lynn.
That's what I'm talking about.
What's the matter with you, Easy?
Did you lose something?
I don't know where Lynn is.
I thought ..
Well you thought wrong.
Hey.
Lynn wants to see you.
She's in Liverpool.
She's working in a club
called The Congo. Only ..
Don't tell him I told you.
Hey, Frank.
Come in here, will you.
You're cool, baby. Real cool.
- Take it easy.
Come on, let's dance.
- I'm not dancing right now.
Why, what's the matter?
That's what you're here for.
It's what they pay you for, isn't it?
Come on.
The lady is dancing with me.
I owe you an apology.
I thought that ..
- I know.
Are you trying to tell me I
deliberately over-insured a vehicle ..
Had it pushed off the road
then killed the driver?
Is that what you mean?
Well I wouldn't put it exactly
in those words, Mr Easy.
Then how would you put it?
Mr Easy.
All I know is that the insurance company
isn't very happy about this accident.
And they've asked me to investigate
the matter and to make out my report.
Then you'd better get out of here
and make your report, hadn't you.
Very well.
That shipment of furs just come in, Joe.
Okay.
Shall I put an extra
watchman on tonight?
Yeah, sure.
Good day.
Next time you come, let me know.
I've a lawyer here.
I think that would be
advisable, Mr Easy.
Now we've the police and the insurance
company breathing down our necks.
And this came this morning.
What's that?
- A final demand from National Oil.
Eight thousand quid.
Hey, hey!
Those are sable pelts you're
handling, not bananas.
What are we going to do, Joe?
What do you mean 'we'?
You only work here, remember.
Now look ..
I'm the company secretary.
I'm just as eligible to
go to jail as you are.
I've been inside before
and I didn't like it.
"Yes, sir?"
Get me Coastal Steamship
Company, Liverpool.
You know the trouble with you, Frank?
You're in the wrong business.
With your stomach you should be selling
ladies' underwear or something.
[ Buzzer ]
Hello. Is McNaughton in?
Yeah, I'll hold on.
"Yes, Joe?"
Sam, that American.
What's-his-name? Miller?
Know where I can get hold of him?
"I've got no address here, Joe.
All I know is he lives in Liverpool."
Never mind. I'll find him.
Haven't you got some work to do?
Mack? Joe Easy.
Fine.
Say, look. I'm coming down to Liverpool
this afternoon. I want to talk to you.
You're a hard man to find, Miller.
Now that you've found me, so what?
I want to talk to you.
I don't want to talk to you.
I think you will.
I've had enough.
Well?
A proposition that will
make your hair curl.
What is it?
Well .. yes or no?
No.
You've just said no to a
lot of money my friend.
I don't think you'll get away with it.
Those skins will be
so hot they'll sweat.
You'll be stuck with them.
In this country, maybe.
I'm told I can get a very good
price for them in America.
I used to have a friend.
Runs a small cargo boat
between here and Boston.
Plenty of room on board if
you'd like to come along.
I wouldn't advise staying in this
country after doing a job like this.
Well?
You should change your mind.
Get in, Frank.
I've just seen Frank.
He says Joe is looking for you.
I know.
He was just in.
You're not going to get mixed
up with him, are you?
Frank says the police are on to him.
- What do you think?
Honey, what is the matter?
Nothing.
You were going to ring me
last night. What happened?
Look, I ..
I had things to do.
I'll see you around.
But when?
Look baby, I ..
What about this afternoon?
We could meet in the park or something.
Please, Harry.
Okay.
About four?
Butch .. keep it down to a roar.
It's got engine trouble.
Take it to the garage.
Take the dog with you too.
Go and play in the war, Johnny. Go on.
I'm going out for some cigarettes.
Why not take Johnny with you?
He's not been out today.
It's raining.
He will be alright if he wears his coat.
Come on, Johnny. Going out.
All set, Daddy. Let's go.
Let's go, Butch.
Harry.
Take care.
Butch, play on the swings.
I'll be just a minute.
Okay.
You are 'Butch' aren't you?
Yeah .. how do you know?
Is that a dog? I got a dog.
Would you like this one?
Gee, thanks.
There you are.
Thank you.
Alright, Harry. Let's have it.
This is it, isn't it.
Why?
It was alright. It was going along fine.
I didn't try and move in on you.
All I asked was just
a little bit of your life.
Is that too much to ask?
I've tried.
It .. it won't work.
It .. just won't work.
But you're still in love
with me, aren't you?
Well, aren't you?
I don't know.
All I know is I have a wife and
a kid and they both need me.
I need you, Harry.
Not that way.
You can't do this.
You cannot turn me ..
Inside out and just leave me.
Harry.
Do you hear me?
You can't do this to me.
Are you hurt, Butch? Huh?
Any bones broken.
Ah, you'll be alright.
Come on, we'll go home.
Is he hurt?
He's alright.
Goodbye, Lynn.
Lynn, I ..
I'm sorry. I ..
How do you feel, Butch?
- I didn't cry, did I Daddy.
No you didn't, son.
There.
Now you go and get undressed.
Are you alright?
Do you still feel sick?
Go on then.
The police were here.
What did they want?
They wanted to see you.
Something to do with
an accident with a truck.
What's going on, Harry?
You've been like this for days.
You hardly talk to me. You come and go.
You don't tell me where you've been.
I thought a man was coming to fix this.
You don't live here, Harry.
You're just lodging.
Hey, look what I got.
That's nice.
Where did you get that.
- The lady gave it to me.
Lady? What lady?
The lady in the park.
She was crying.
Why was she crying, Daddy?
You'd better go to bed, Butch.
But I ..
- Go to bed, Butch.
Go on, Johnny.
Yes.
I'll come up and see you later.
Okay .. night, Mom.
Goodnight.
Night, Daddy.
- Night.
Do you have to take the boy with you
when you go to meet your girlfriends?
Who was it this time?
Someone else you picked up?
Don't tell me it's the same one?
How romantic.
Are you in love with her?
Look, Connie.
It's over with.
It's finished.
- Are you?
Then why the big sacrifice, Harry?
Why so noble?
- I don't want to break up our marriage.
You're not trying to hold it together.
- You've done nothing to help either.
One thing you did to me no woman should
ever do to a man. You stood in my way.
You knew I didn't want to stay here. The
minute I gave into you, what happened?
Everything went wrong. Everything.
Alright.
If that's the way you want it, I won't
stand in your way any longer.
Go to America if you want to.
And take her with you.
- I'm staying right here.
I don't know that I want you here.
You're forgetting we have a kid.
We can manage without you.
- You're not going to manage without me.
He needs a home doesn't he?
He's as much my kid
as he is yours, isn't he?
Is he?
Is he, Harry?
What do you mean by that?
Honey, I'm asking you.
What did you mean by that?
I'm asking you a question, Connie.
Answer me.
He is ours, isn't he Connie?
He is yours and mine, isn't he Connie?
Answer me!
Who was it?
I love you, Harry.
Who was it, Connie?
It was over before we were married.
I didn't know.
Who was it?
- Al.
It was Al.
Harry.
[ Door knocks ]
Hey, Charlie.
- What?
Get those furs loaded.
We aren't due to go until tomorrow.
- I said get them loaded.
You're the boss.
Ted. Drop that.
Get number 6 back up here.
Never mind that one.
Get number 6 up here.
There's a little harbour down here,
just south of Oban called Penrie.
I've looked up the charts.
And I reckon I can get in there between
six and seven o'clock tomorrow morning.
So, if I can get the truck
there by daybreak ..
We can be away before the tide drops.
After that I'll call at Liverpool
and collect my regular cargo.
Well.
Look who's here.
Come on in.
How is she for gas?
- You've got enough to get to London.
Yeah. Sure.
Thanks.
I'm coming with you, Joe.
You're not going to leave me here?
Look, you got me into this.
You must get me out of it.
"Number please?"
- Give me the police.
"One moment, please."
What are you doing?
Telling them to come and pick you up?
No.
I'm going to report a robbery.
A truck load of furs.
Put down that phone, Frank.
Put it down, Frank.
Do I come with you or don't I?
"Glasgow Central Police Station."
You don't give me much choice, do you.
"Hello there?"
All set?
- Yeah.
Here, I've marked the route.
- Okay.
I'll be waiting for you.
Does Lynn know he's coming?
No.
I don't get it.
Hey.
I got his number.
- You'd better phone the police.
Alright.
Come on, come on.
Where is Frank?
He's driving the truck.
What's all that about?
Now what?
Never mind. Come on.
- Oh look, Joe.
I said, come on.
There is a police trap down the road.
I thought you said Frank was driving.
- Never mind about Frank. Get in.
What happened to him?
- Get in.
There's a side-road
just on the left here.
Get this straight, Joe.
If anything has happened to Frank ..
Frank? I've had a bellyful of Frank.
Here it is.
What have you stopped for?
We're out of road.
You must have taken a wrong turning.
You navigated.
Well back her up.
Are you kidding?
Up this goat track?
Look, we've got this far haven't we.
Another fifteen miles and
you want to give up?
Well, what do we do know? Pitch a tent?
Might as well.
This is as far as we're going tonight.
Look, are you mad?
Look. That boat isn't going to wait.
If we're not there by seven o'clock ..
Look, in two hours it will be daylight.
I don't care what you do.
I'm going to get some sleep.
Harry.
This is a one-way trip.
You know that don't you?
Uhuh.
What does that mean? You've left her?
That's right.
What about you?
What are you doing here?
The same as you. Looking for a way out.
Well, did you find out where we are?
- Yeah.
In the middle of nowhere.
See those hills over there?
Where we want go is fifteen
miles over the top of them.
Steady.
Alright. Come over here
and we'll give it a push.
Okay.
Put our shoulders behind it.
Come on, let's go.
You stay here until I clear.
Do you think they saw us?
I don't know.
- Okay, bring her forward.
Keep her coming.
He's not going to let you get on that
boat. You know that, don't you?
Yeah, I know.
What will you do?
Let's worry about that
when we get to the boat.
There she is.
Keep it going.
Steady.
Hold it.
I said to hold it. I could see
the hole. You just went on.
There are planks there in the back.
- Planks? What for? We've got no time.
You want to get this
out of here or don't you?
Harry.
Joe.
Hurry up, will you.
Harry. Are you alright?
Come on, let's get moving.
Put that plank under that wheel.
Alright, I can do this.
Lay it over that hole.
Go on, get her started.
Okay.
Keep her going.
That's not going to do any good.
- So what do you suggest?
Well there is one thing we can do.
- What?
What are you doing?
Look. Are you out of your mind?
You've got 500 pounds-worth there.
Better than blowing
500,000 pounds isn't it?
Come on.
Come on, shove off.
Hurry up.
Alright. Push off.
Come on.
Don't spin it. Go back!
Go on.
[ Gunshot! ]
We'd just about given
you up. What happened?
Give me a hand with him, will you.
What about Joe?
- What about him?
Alright. Come on.
Get the stuff aboard.
- Aye, alright.
Come on.
Give us your hand, Miss.
There you are.
We'll be pulling into Liverpool
as soon as it gets dark.
You'd better keep well out of sight.
How is he?
He'll be alright.
What's the matter, Harry?
Nothing.
Connie?
Mostly the kid.
Not right.
I left them.
No money .. nothing.
Wait a minute, Harry.
You're not thinking about going
back or anything, are you?
We could send them some money.
Harry, are you mad? The police will pick
you up in five minutes if you go ashore.
Please listen to me, Harry. We can
get somebody to take the money.
Harry, please.
Get away from that door.
Harry.
Harry, don't be silly.
You'll never make it.
Let me go.
Have you lost your senses?
Get back down below.
We're pulling out in half an hour.
You had better be quick.
Harry, let me take it.
Look, Lynn.
This is my responsibility. Not yours.
But Harry, they're bound
to be looking for you.
They may even be watching the house.
Please, Harry.
Alright. Here.
Is it Mrs Miller?
Yes.
Could I come in for a moment?
What do you want?
Harry asked me to give you this.
Are you the ..?
Yes.
Mrs Miller?
Yes, doctor.
I shall have to call an ambulance.
An ambulance?
Why, what's wrong?
What's the matter with him?
The boy has a brain
haemorrhage, Mrs Miller.
He must have banged his head
rather severely somehow.
I see he has got rather a bad bruise.
How did that happen?
The other day, he ..
He .. fell ..
Well, we must get him to
hospital straight away.
Excuse me.
Western docks.
What's the matter?
- Nothing.
Everything go alright?
- Hmm.
How did she take it?
She took it.
The kid .. did you see him?
Well, did you?
Driver, could you go quicker.
We're in a hurry.
Lynn, is .. is there something
wrong with him?
Lynn, I'm asking you. Is there?
Harry.
They're taking him to hospital.
Hospital?
Why?
I don't know. The doctor said
something about banging his head.
Driver, turn around and go back.
Harry, are you crazy?
The police are watching the house.
Please listen to me.
Turn around and go back, driver.
- Harry, don't you understand?
In a couple of days we'll be a
hundred miles away from here.
I love you.
I love you like I never loved
anybody before in my whole life.
I couldn't bear it if you took
it away from me again.
Please, Harry.
Please.
What do you want me to do?
Go back.
Butch?
Butch.
Are you his father?
Yes.
I'm his father.
Will he be alright?
Don't worry. We'll look after him.
Are you coming in the ambulance, madam?
Yes, I'm ..
Back to the docks, Miss?
Do you know the Congo Club?
Yes, Miss.
Just take me there.
..s-d..