After circulation for a while,
a brand new note will be too used.
A $1,000 note
generally has a longer life.
It can averagely circulate for 18 months.
A $100 note may last for 12 months only.
Damn you stay off my foot.
$10 only, come on.
A $10 note has a still shorter life.
It normality circulates
for about 8 months only.
But he's really gone too far!
The old bank-note are shredded daily
through a special machine,
and then sent to an incinerator.
Where they are burnt out in a pyre.
Take it.
No wonder mammy said money has no value.
Then what happens?
I can talk, I can't listen.
They're burnt out in a garbage station.
How often do they burn it?
No! Every week.
- Sometimes even daily.
- Right...
Now let's show you the burning process.
It's like burning garbage.
Come on!
Let's see the boss on TV.
Call me when I am on.
Okay, back to your work.
The plug doesn't work.
Let's me... Let me.
Replace the two wires.
It's playing...
- You're on...
- Really?
Come here... beautiful...
Boss, you're on TV.
Boss something wrong!
How come?
It's machine trouble.
I know! I'm fixing it!
Quiet! The boss is fixing it!
It's going to be alright.
The machine's out of order.
What about these bank-notes?
Put them aside!
$30 million!
Boss!
Fatty, you're late.
We're just leaving.
It's no 1 o'clock yet.
We work to rule, today's Saturday.
We stop the machine at 11:45.
Then we get ready to go at one.
What about the unburnt bank-notes?
They're locked up for next Monday.
Boss Monday is Public Holiday.
Next Tuesday then.
Mr. Thomson, it's for you.
"Opposition to overtime work"
Time's up Fatty, it's too bad.
Come again next Tuesday.
We work to rule.
Why are you moping there?
Are you all right?
I'm feeling
a bit proud of my achievement.
I started with nothing.
But when there's a break,
I may get avoid getting rich
and have a chauffeured
limousine standing by...
It's a bit large, but better than none.
Want to get emigrated?
You won't stand a chance.
We all love Hong Kong Bye-bye.
Maniac, a Hong Kong special.
Sorry.
- What's the matter? Pick it up.
- OK.
Sorry.
- Sorry!
- Mark...
Mark, there's money waiting for us!
I'm busy.
A big $30 million deal.
We're going to be rich.
$30 million?
Get back to work.
Go and bring Tomboy.
Her daddy's tough. You go yourself.
- Get going.
- Why me?
Guess the figure in my mind From 1 to 10.
Three.
It's seven. Go in!
I should have guessed it!
Brother...
Tomboy, waiting to die here?
Who's kicking me?
- Oh! No!
- Damn fatty, how dare you?
Uncle, not my fault!
Go to hell?
Go away!
My daddy's going to kill someone.
- Oh! My car!
- Go away...
Don't go away, bastard!
With $30 million, you can eat anything!
Stop eating, try something.
Replace them with 3 bags of joss money.
It won't work. What now?
I never dreamt of
having such a hell lot of money.
Why not simply let us have it?
It may upset the finance.
You may get shot.
You know how much money
is in circulation?
Over $20 billion!
So $30 million is negligible.
- Sorry.
- Why not?
It ain't easy, did you steal before?
Let me demonstrate to you.
Thief! Show it.
I'm caught. See you at prison!
We can get some help.
There are only three days left.
Have you got thieves in your family?
Your father!
You always said he is a dumb thief.
Eat now!
Where can we find the thieves?
"Government Correctional Services"
We'd better give up.
What's wrong?
The prison scared me.
It seems specially made for me.
Shut up! Someone's coming out.
It's him. I can see he's the one.
Remember,
we're dealing with the big guys.
Show your dare.
Yes, boss.
Come on.
Friend, we have got a tough deal.
Have you got the guts to do it?
What kind of a tough deal?
Have you got the guts?
Morning, warden.
Warden? Finished.
What kind of deal is it?
Clean all the beaches in Hong Kong.
It's voluntary, tough, eh?
Have you got the guts?
Guess you're busy.
Why don't you recommend someone?
Any prisoners discharged today, sir?
- One.
- Thank you.
Let's go.
He looks miserable.
Must have spent years in jail.
Don't get us involved.
Mark give hell. Please!
This is our only chance.
Fatty, let's find out his background.
What's it, kid?
His accent shows he's mainlander.
Did you get jailed for illegal entry?
You can't get going
without even an I.D. Card.
What's it?
We need you for a big deal.
Oh no. I've decided to go straight now.
Find someone else.
Damn Baldy.
Big Mouth! My goodness.
What are you doing?
I can go straight after I get rich.
Go...
What's wrong with that beige car?
It's orange.
- Beige...
- Orange...
It makes no difference.
Orange.
Beige or orange?
Quiet! It's beigy orange!
- Who's he?
- Inspector!
So he's an Inspector!
Let's go!
Bitch, you're more scared.
Is his car stolen?
Yes, it is.
I told you to borrow, not to steal it.
Where to borrow in such a hurry?
Don't... don't go up a slope!
Why didn't you say so?
It's running out of gasoline.
- How do you know?
- Look!
It really is empty.
I'll break the fastest record
of getting caught.
It's reversing!
Pull the handbrake, quick!
Damn! You kids drive me, nuts.
Last time I got caught by Big Mouth
in a similar situation.
Watch out!
Don't...
Damn Baldy!
Don't look! Run!
Run... Quick!
Here's a car!
My goodness!
- What are you doing?
- Snake... I'm afraid of snakes!
It's all right!
- Get in...
- No... I won't even if you killed me.
Why did you get such a wreck, you idiots.
Why didn't you get a good one?
When a good car comes along,
lie down in the road.
The car stops, we take it.
Fatty, lie down,
or you sleep with the snake.
- You, too!
- And you?
I'm coming.
You too!
Lie down!
All lie down! Come on.
No, it's safer here.
Don't be silly!
- Are you all right?
- Where's the car?
My legs are numb!
You're damned!
You're unsympathetic.
Another car's coming!
Let's take this car.
What's so funny?
Tell me how to make money
when you stop laughing.
We don't even know your name.
General Chuen was my godfather.
My last name is Chuen.
Bluffer.
You all know my name already.
Tell me the secret.
Don't tell him the secret.
Unless you take us with you
to vow at the Chuen Temple.
No way, I'm a Catholic!
Good! I'll give you a break?
Stop at any Church.
- Okay!
- Bad!
Quick? Go in! Go in!
Get going...
Do I look sincere?
If I ever betrayed you,
I'd be knocked down by a car,
choked in eating...
get no heir after getting married.
Get pimples on my head...
Sleep in a coffin and die in water bed.
And have no girlfriend before 90.
Wicked enough?
Sure, enough to poison even the listener!
Well, tell us what it's all about.
What sort of windfall you have in mind?
3 bags of bank-notes ready to be burnt.
Right... Locked in the incinerator.
- How much is that?
- $30 million.
Once more.
$30 million.
In that Incinerator Station?
Tsing Yi Incinerator Station.
Where?
An iron cage on the 1st floor.
Anything else hidden from me?
No!
In fact, I should go straight.
Backing out after knowing the secret?
Even a straight forward man needs money.
What do you mean?
Count me in.
Where are you going?
To a sweetheart
I haven't seen in six months.
What shall I get her?
- Money, of course!
- Maniac!
- Diamond.
- You must be crazy.
- Roses.
- You're smart.
I'm rich...
This time I'm rich.
Quick...
Let me get in first!
Sister Maria's brought me trouble again!
I must rush to help 3 lambs
and an old fox.
Sister Maria...
You've come at the right time.
I was looking for you!
Why you gave
so little for family expenses.
Shut up! I played mahjong.
And you said I neglected the children.
I wanted a divorce
and you said God wouldn't agree.
- Did I?
- What should we do?
Quiet! Let me finish.
I, Maria, approve of your divorce.
Effective immediately.
Maria...
- I'm free now!
- Stop dreaming!
What now?
Wait or get out! Bye-bye.
That's your fault to bring an old crook.
Who's backbiting me?
Him! Her!
I'm used to it.
Let's be cooperative.
You two go and get the blueprint.
And wait for me
at the shipyard in Aberdeen.
Okay...
We can't make it.
It's $30 million! No price's too great.
Yes...
- Okay, no problem.
- Don't be cocky.
You take me to that Incinerator Station.
Let me see if there's really $30 million.
And according to rule, it's 30/70.
You get 30 and I get 70.
I'm professional and you're amateur.
As in soccer
you got only travel expenses.
No way?
He's right! I used to get only that.
Hell with you!
Want to fight me? Come on!
Baldhead, it's been a long time.
- Where did you go?
- I've just returned from the sea.
So you're back.
Baldhead, I...
You don't have to tell me,
I know you're lonely.
You do?
I know what to do.
Wait!
Hurry up then! Hurry up!
I've waited for 6 months.
Baldy.
Come on...
What time is it now?
Back from prison?
What? I returned from the sea.
Get out of here.
I live here.
What? When have you moved in?
Never mind, go out and have coffee.
Come on, sweetheart!
Only one minute will do!
Baldy, we've been married for 3 months.
Yes!
You've got guts. All ready made.
Baldy!
Goodbye.
Going to sea again?
Damn...
So soon?
A fast shooter!
An expert must be fast.
Right, no time wasted and nobody hurt.
- What did you say?
- I got an idea.
Fling a snake in
and play the Pest Control.
And you'll look around.
What a lousy idea!
Sir, what a shame.
You're interfering. Where's Baldy?
Over there.
Take him.
He must be up to something.
Follow him.
Sir, last time you framed Baldy up,
and he got 6 months as a result.
He cheated my god sister a diamond ring.
I swore to fix him each time I see him.
I'll never let him go.
Fatty, wait for me at the entrance.
Be ready to go anytime, it's not safe.
Okay, go now.
Reverse! He saw it.
Watch it. Let me go up and see.
You can't get away!
Hello!
I know you, you're that old fox.
Don't run!
I mean you're damned okay.
You're damned! Don't run!
Kid, let me!
- Stop!
- Open the door.
Let me get in first!
Stop!
Go!
Don't run!
Where can you go?
It's killing me!
Well, you've seen
the 3 bags of bank-notes!
We can get it easily!
Snakes... not my business!
Help...
Help.
Sister, help!
Calm down! I'll help you.
God, help me!
Snakes!
My behind!
Leave me alone! I don't want God now!
Blast! Snakes!
Snakes!
Don't... don't tug at me. I can't breathe!
Help! I can't swim!
Don't worry! I'll teach you now!
I'm sinking...
That's no way to swim!
- Who are you?
- Hey!
Why are you hanging on my car?
Well, why am I hanging up here?
Get down!
What? I'm a policeman.
Being pursued by a crook. Go quick!
Don't look! Go!
Okay, sit still.
Your driving technique is not bad.
Nonsense!
Frizzy, pay me back for my glass!
- Bitch you...
- Baldy...
Stop that! Pay me...
Don't go away! Pay me back!
Plenty of dogs! I won't go down!
Baldhead!
I'm not baldheaded.
Frizzy, don't let me see you again.
So it's you! Frizzy kiddo.
So it's you!
This kick is killing!
Stop! Why are you baldheaded?
Why are you baldheaded?
Bitch, stop that!
My head's bald!
Hit me?
Thief...
What are you doing?
Nothing! Nothing at all!
Scream, and I'll gag you!
Thief!
Chuen!
Don't go in!
Come here!
Stand there!
Get rid of your jinx.
Run faster when you're chased again.
Several young men are waiting.
What are you up to?
Stay out of this
and you'll stand to gain.
You've never spoken the truth, kid.
Now it's true, we're rich!
- All fixed.
- Sit down! How's everything?
All fixed.
Sit still, Mr. Lin.
Over here. Take a look at this blueprint.
The best way would be through the gutter.
There's a house right behind the station.
The entrance of the gutter
is in the garden.
How do you know
it leads to the incinerator.
The blueprint was designed by me.
Are you sure it's not clogged?
Never, I drained it 6 times a year.
The female owner of that house
is a designer Feng.
To get in,
we must fix her first.
But it seems she's not easygoing.
It all depends on you.
"She's the girl in my dreams"
"With a figure as shapely as can be"
"I yearn to woo her and marry her"
"And even the it means the hosting of'
"A big wedding party. I'm ready"
"To enslave myself to win her heart"
"But a poor and miserable man like me"
"is only snubbed by her snobbish mother"
"She puts money above anything else"
"And jeers at me for my vain ambition"
"So I really can do nothing"
"till fortune smiles upon me"
"And I need a windfall
to get me off the hook"
"Only if I were rich"
"Could I vent my grievances"
"May the tide turn in my favor"
"May luck be with me from now on"
"So I can make a good showing"
"I swear I'd bring a beautiful world"
"For both you and me"
"At last luck has knocked at my door"
"With unabated vigor to"
"Make you dream come true"
"When it comes to money"
"Everybody is in the same religion"
"You can't raise your head without it"
"I really can do nothing"
"Till fortune smiles upon me"
"And I need a windfall
to get me off the hook"
Cigar...
I feel the smell of cigar.
Are you alone?
You didn't expect me
to bring more people?
How did you get to be like this?
Come...
I kissed a lioness in the zoo.
- Nonsense!
- Liar!
Who are they?
This is an Engineer
who designed the blueprint.
Thank you. You may go home and sleep.
You agreed that I get a cut.
Otherwise, I'll call the police.
Who's he?
He... he drains the gutter.
He'll get a cut too?
Me, too.
Is this blind man going to lead us?
No, he heard of our secret.
And followed us.
Well, let the dough
be split thin among us!
Tell the whole world
to send someone to split it!
Is she going to lead us to Heaven?
She's my benefactor.
Please tell them!
The Lord said we're 3 sheep.
And he's an old fox.
Damn! How dare you curse me?
You use violence, God won't forgive you.
- Sister, watch out for the Lord!
- Sorry!
It hurts! I give up...
Well, the Lord said
a thief can't enter Heaven.
Fatty wants to go to Heaven.
Do you?
Sister, I'd rather not go to Heaven!
Why, Fatty?
I've no friends in Heaven.
Then I must inform the police!
Thank you, Sister, for guiding me.
You made me think back of my past.
I'm now repenting!
The jail was such an ordeal. Thank you.
Have you ever been in jail?
Feel it. It's now creased!
Not you, she!
I wouldn't care to!
Let's disband then.
Okay!
Where's Sister?
What about you three?
I knew I'd never be rich.
Let's go before the police arrive.
Where are you going, old fox?
Easy, Sister.
I don't worry about those 3 lambs.
But you must stick with me for 3 days.
Dare you ever get out of my sight?
- Dare you?
- No!
- You really have a way.
- You're superb!
A Sister's taking Baldhead to Heaven!
Taking him to a motel?
Let's do it ourselves.
Do it ourselves?
Get the blueprint.
We've to get the blueprint all the same.
When will you embrace the faith?
Sister, I must go and talk to my brother.
You don't have to follow me so closely.
Okay!
What to do if someone is in the way?
Just play tough.
Fix her for me.
I don't hit women.
Do it for $30 million?
- How much?
- $30 million.
I can't stand it.
Are you sure you must use violence?
Lock her up for 3 days.
And feed her like a kitten.
Sister, do you eat fish?
I'm afraid of the bones.
Put some more fish bone to choke her.
- How much?
- $30 million.
- Get going!
- Trying to run?
Coming...
- Fixed.
- Get going!
Fixed. Where's Baldy?
My back!
My back! Oh, my back!
Master! Help!
Don't ruin me like that!
- Let me off.
- Okay!
You're dumb! Tell her to let go.
Put me down quick!
Fan... Come...
She's terrific!
- Come on!
- What are you doing?
Kill her.
Oh no,
not in the presence of General Kwan.
She's a nun, she's a Sister.
Anna? I must never do it then!
I'm now a common female! Come on!
Bitch, how dare you?
I'm Boxer Liang!
Bastard Liang? Boxer Liang! Show power!
She's terrific!
$30 million!
I wouldn't starve even if I were maimed.
Hit her!
You're good for nothing.
I'm not yet ready! Stop!
Get her!
My back!
Hold on!
Where's the money? Tell me!
- Knock her down first.
- Nonsense.
Have you got a light?
Take your cigarette away!
Where's the money?
Damn, you're tough!
You're so mean.
You're not a nun.
You're a witch, a shrew.
An old maid... A hag, a jilted woman.
Go on! I'll "electrocute" you...
I'll electrocute you!
Sorry... Stop that!
- I'll kill you...
- Sorry.
It's fun! Damn bitch! Damn old maid!
Someone's slipping away.
You kicked me!
So what?
Dare you do it again?
- He's beating up a woman.
- I didn't!
My back!
Trying to run? I'll kill you!
Baldy, don't come to me again on this!
Bitch, you don't care a damn about me!
My head! Is it alright?
- Lots of stars!
- Are you sure?
Is there no place for me
in this wide world?
Sister, what do you think?
God is fair.
Heaven's spacious and beautiful.
I don't want to go to Heaven.
Waste of energy!
Well, let's forsake him,
let's do it ourselves.
Cheers!
Wait, we may be accused of betrayal.
Idiot.
At worst we'll give them a cut.
Right, we won't let them down.
How much?
$10,000 each?
So much? You're mad? Are you rich?
How much then?
$10,000 for all of them.
Our conscience is clear! Let's drink!
It's cold!
What are you doing?
It was cold last night.
Didn't want you to catch cold.
You're nice. Thank you.
Blessed be the Lord!
Something's wrong?
I've decided to give up.
And I'm going to persuade my friends too.
Are you going or not?
Of course!
But I can't with the suit I'm wearing.
Lend me some money to redeem my tuxedo.
What about these gold watches and chains?
They're all fakes.
Okay!
Wait a minute.
My late wife's photo.
I must print a few for souvenir.
Photo-finishing.
- Print 2 dozen, I'll come this afternoon.
- Yes!
Merry Villa - To Let only.
Pimp Tak! This is Bluffer.
Wrong number!
Don't hang up!
I'm not calling up for money.
I'll introduce you a beautiful bird.
You're not in this line. Any good birds?
I've changed after six months in prison.
I now have a new gimmick.
A new breakthrough.
What breakthrough? Tell me!
Great! Now new packing is in vogue.
I'll have her packaged from head to toe.
Is she beautiful?
Better than Lin Ching-hsia.
Really? What about her figure?
Great! Like a hairy ape!
- What!
- Never mind.
Stop nagging.
Inform those old clients to try.
Hurry up then.
Coming now!
Why are you so late?
Why such a crowd?
We need men to make money.
- Watch out!
- I know.
I know you need me now.
- Well.
- Sit down first.
Don't be in the way.
- Go in.
- Okay.
Calm down.
Go in and get ready.
One grand!
I must call the police! There's a fight!
Let's go...
Police! Got a ticket from the police!
- Assaulting police?
- No, reporting!
There's a fight at the hotel upstairs.
A Sister was injured by whore mongers.
Those whore mongers were hit by police!
You're more eloquent, say it! Excuse me!
Don't bluff! Stay!
I'll be waiting in the car.
Who's it? Coming!
It's you!
Open up! Feng,
I've brought you a fortune.
What are you doing?
Coming in if you dare!
My vase is expensive!
It's expensive.
- This is more expensive!
- I don't care.
- Catch!
- Don't.
- You're clumsy.
- Baldy, I'll call the police.
I'll make good for you.
My hard-earned dough. Take it!
Please take it.
I'll be grateful if you do.
I'm despicable.
Since I met you,
I've been thinking of you,
yearn to be with you...
And go to your bedroom to...
do what I'd like to do with you.
Let me lie down and put it in!
What a clumsy sex crook I am.
I'll find her soon.
I've found it.
Having a good time?
Kick!
I'll support it!
Great!
Wait! Let me say something first.
It concerns a wind fall of $30 million.
You'll get a cut of $1 million Okay?
So little for me? He'll with you!
- Ouch! I'm finished!
- Don't finish!
Damn...
Are you alright? Why didn't you tell me?
With $30 million everything's okay.
I never thought you'd be so tough.
I thought we were now two in one.
What?
Here it is! Turn!
We're going to get this woman.
Okay!
If she reacts normally, I'll do it.
If she's pervert, Fatty goes.
If she's lesbian, let Tomboy do it.
Where's Tomboy?
Do it for the sake of the dough.
I know you don't have the taste.
But for $30 million, anything goes.
Come on...
Isn't that great?
Is Baldy here?
Remember to fix these!
- What about my cut?
- How much did I say just now?
$10 million.
- Would I be so generous?
- Yes.
Okay, go and make a cup of coffee.
Okay.
Add sugar and milk!
We're rich!
This time we aren't going to miss.
It's okay. Everything's okay!
What are you doing?
- To make fun of you! Come here!
- What?
Come here and you'll see.
Dress up in one minute.
Or I'll have someone to castrate you.
A slip again!
Quiet!
Game over!
He's dressing.
You're not like match.
Quiet! I'm racking my brains.
Well, you won't get hurt!
Sorry!
Big Mouth?
Bluffer...
Big Mouth's here!
I'm going!
Hurry! Bye-bye!
What are you up to?
Get in quick!
You bastards again!
What's your offence?
Robbing a jewelry shop?
So serious?
What's your offence now?
Attempt to have sex
with ill-gotten money.
What do you mean?
Whore mongering? Stop being so highbrow.
- Are you the Inspector?
- Yes. Miss.
Why give me such a hell?
My duty requires that.
Inspector, we can't find Baldy.
Let me out! Don't do that!
Here...
What's going on...
Close the door!
Excuse me!
Sorry for putting you in here for.
One night, so you won't be in our way.
Don't worry,
we'll reserve one cut for you.
We won't keep it
all for ourselves like you.
- He can't hear us.
- He can't.
You talk and you act,
let him die comforted.
Sorry, we had no choice.
You tried to get rid of us first!
You made it... Jump!
Waves!
Damn, you're dirty!
Look!
How come?
Can't be opened! It's spinning!
He may get drowned!
How long will it go on?
Five minutes for a tablecloth.
A dirty man may take longer.
If this goes on,
he may die.
Stop...
It won't stop, it will turn back.
How are you?
Poor Baldhead. Try to stop it!
Let's take a chance.
It's stopped!
Careful!
Help him.
No need.
The room's spinning.
- Be careful!
- Sit tight!
Sorry to have caused you this.
Out of my way! Don't touch me!
Are you repenting now,
after the brainwashing?
Why are you so crafty?
What? It's a fight for an ideal.
Have you got any ideal?
Which school did you come from?
I do have an ideal.
What's this?
Hawaii! That's not much of a demand!
When I was 20, I yearned for a sum of
money to settle down in Hawaii.
No reason for you to hog our shares too.
What?
I wanted to be the vanguard.
What do you mean?
You don't even know that?
Which school do you came from?
Look you're the country's mainstay.
You can't be a thief?
Only I am fit for this job.
Did I ever say I won't give you your cut?
- Yes.
- I'm not talking to you.
Miss, you're understanding.
Did I say that?
- Yes.
- Lousy bitch!
Speak up! Answer 'Yes' or 'No'.
Did I ever say that?
Say 'Yes',
and I'll strangle you to death!
- Yes or No?
- No!
No...
My gold chain has faded.
The glass has cracked.
Even this fake jade is lost. Happy.
And the watchcase too.
I'll find it for you. It's getting short!
It's wet. Don't catch cold.
Be nice and find the watchcase for me.
What's it?
Would he ever slip away?
What?
Trying to hog everything again?
Don't be suspicious.
Man is by nature kind.
- He's muttering nonsense.
- People can change.
Come here.
- I was right!
- A good man!
Something to see.
- The watchcase has been found.
- Good boy.
- Mr. Chuen, sorry.
- Never mind.
Sorry for the misunderstanding.
Never mind.
- To see what?
- Go in and you'll see.
Why is it missing?
What do you want?
Kids, stay here for the night.
I must make money.
- What a fox!
- Tso Sho.
- Shih Chien.
- Chiang Chung-ping.
- Mar Ka!
Is Mar Ka crafty?
Who isn't crafty, idiot?
There are big and small villains.
But I was forced by circumstances.
My mammy wouldn't feed me
when I was a child.
And I had someone else feed me.
When my teacher expelled me from school,
I forced him to join the underworld.
When I got nothing to eat,
I eat everything.
- Where's that smart guy.
- Go on!
As I said. I'm not crafty at all.
Crafty is not enough, you must be wicked.
You must be extremely wicked.
Small wickedness builds up the country.
Big wickedness conquers the world.
But sometimes it won't work.
Let me give you the antidote.
There's no key! What now?
Damn Baldy!
Don't close the door! You...
Bye-bye.
Don't say bye-bye!
I was only joking. Damn...
My father!
I'll go to steal upstairs.
Lure him away.
- Me to lure her father away?
- Yes!
Go now! He wants to send you away.
Get going!
Get going! You'll be alright!
Only an accident!
What can you do?
Come up and have a fight! Come...
Who are you? Why are you kicking me?
Sorry, I thought it was someone else.
Trying to run?
Are they really worth $1,000?
Sure, but I must give 10% to my father.
10% of $30 million?
- That means...
- $3 million!
Otherwise, I'll take them back upstairs.
Okay, we have no choice. Let's go.
Father, I'll repay you $3 million.
$3 million? For me?
Bad, she's blocking the gutter.
Lure her away.
- Me again?
- You're better for the job.
For the sake of the money.
- The money?
- Go now.
- Who's it?
- Baldy!
I'm rich...
Hello! How are you?
Red and green beans
bring you lots of gas.
Oh, My god!
Guardroom.
- Mr. Wang!
- I'm Chiang!
Just now I saw a monster!
Hurry up! She might see us
after she finishes calling.
Keep calm! She won't finish so soon.
Wearing a bikini!
Why has she got that?
I didn't notice it.
What a woman!
- What's it?
- Wait, let me see more of it.
What are you doing? What about the money?
With the money, we can see anything.
Well, I've gone too far.
Forget it, you won't believe it anyway.
Who cares?
Why is the floor dry?
You scared me!
It came from outside!
Just now I saw monster.
Forget it!
What are we going to do?
Well, shut up and start.
Dose everything get ready?
Yes, they're all there.
Darling, let's have a kiss.
Wait till we get the money.
What are you doing?
I am a thief!
Now?
Yes, I designed it myself.
Maniac!
They've all gone to steal the money.
It's finished.
What do you mean?
You tried your best to help them.
I'll take over from now on.
No, it's not yet finished.
It's the police responsibility.
No, it's the god's responsibility.
Wang, come and see.
What's it?
Anyway it's kicks... Quick!
Great!
Over there.
Come on quick!
Up there!
- $30 million!
- Hurry up!
$30 million.
Hurry up!
"There's none better than mammy"
What has that to do with your mammy?
Mammy brought me to this beautiful world.
Nothing?
Let's go over there and see.
- What should we do?
- Hide up.
Over there.
Run!
No hurry. A good show.
Look at the expert you brought.
Hurry up!
Over there is a hole.
Go now!
Close the door.
Out of the way...
Quick!
Bastard, it's all joss money!
- Hush! Quiet!
- Damn you!
I've an idea.
Up above.
Over there.
Little Fatty.
Over here... quick...
- Go!
- Quick!
Quick!
- Mu Lan-hua.
- Catch!
Here, quick. Not here... over there.
My god! Baldy.
Catch.
- Throw it!
- Catch!
Don't move! Don't run. Grab it! Hurry!
Baldy...
Don't fight! Every has a cut!
Let me mix them
and split into 2 portions.
We get 1 portion;
You 3, 1 portion, Fair?
- Never! There are only two of you.
- Yes.
Let me tell you in secret.
She's got my child in her womb.
What an insult!
One more portion!
Right... Im pregnant!
- Tell him.
- What?
She's got our twins inside too.
Hell with you!
Let's not quarrel and fight over.
A little money. You'll suffer.
Come on...
You're big brother, you decide.
Right! We're only your coolies.
We'll help ourselves then.
- More partners.
- Damn, more parasites.
It's been a long time.
They're trying to run.
Get back the money! Trying to desert me
over such a big deal!
Had Sister Maria not warned me.
You'd have mad of with the fortune.
- Who's she?
- No idea.
I told him that.
I don't want you to follow this old fox.
You sold me to that pimp.
Stop!
- Old fox...
- Maria!
Don't follow that old fox.
Now it's up to you! Be fair! Speak up!
He's a villain, he tried to take all.
Damn you!
You tried to ruin me!
Damn Baldy.
Don't shoot, I'll call the police.
- Okay!
- Don't!
Don't run away or he'll kill us.
Don't.
- Shut up!
- I won't.
As I said, he's no good.
If you go on, I'll kill you.
Shoot, I've dedicated myself to the Lord.
Don't if you have the guts.
Shoot...
We'll all spring over you if you shoot.
Right! We're only your coolies.
A bully like him can stand 6 shots.
Right! Don't be scared.
I'm silent! Is that against the law?
Bewitch him.
- What's his name?
- Inspector Chu!
Insp. Chu, we can never spend it all.
Take 3 bags. They may be real.
Shut up, Cutie!
Look, even be calls me a cutie.
He's blind.
Stay where you are!
Hand over the dough.
Or I'll break his bald head.
Don't...
I'm finished...
Let's stay for a little longer.
Well, see how he'll end up.
To punish him for his lie.
I'll count up to three... One...
Two...
Don't! I submit.
And the other three?
Three.
- Wait!
- Let's come down!
Let's go.
Open all the bags!
- Open them!
- Wait!
Okay! Don't get tough!
Open it!
How come?
You fooled us again!
No, it was he.
How dare you, Damn Fatty?
Damn fatty, I'll kill you!
Don't...
Thank God, only misunderstanding.
We committed no offence.
We've a bright future.
Please get out of
this criminal world with me.
Okay...
Stop! Is there really $30 million?
- Where's the money?
- Yes, it's true.
Speak...
I swear... if I lie,
my whole family will...
If I ever cheat you, my family will...
Say it.
Get Aids.
Stand up!
Who took it?
You really are incorrigible.
I think of it now.
Who? Speak up.
Bye-bye, Penniless.
I'm rich!
Are you all here to see me off?
Old bore, you're pulling my legs.
Don't let him get away... Open up...
Behind quick!
Quiet!
Let's move him out and "mutilate" him.
I mean to split the money into 9 shares.
No... Don't repeat the same mistake!
Right, Sister's right!
Move him to the hillside.
Hey! He's gone!
After him!
Don't run!
Come down if you dare! Come down...
Trying to run?
Don't run...
Toilet paper.
Stop!
There.
Go up! Quick!
You can't get away!
Police behind you!
Police behind you too!
- You can't fool me.
- You can't fool me either.
I'll kill you, I'll...
I have your cut ready.
So nice?
- Let's split it, okay?
- Show me.
Stop dreaming.
Don't get away.
You can't get over!
What a double dealer.
Brother, see you in Hawaii.
The board! The board's here.
Show me... Quick...
Let go.
Put it on.
Damn! Who's so dumb? So short!
It's too short. It won't work.
It's her.
Bitch.
Why didn't you get a longer one?
See if you can get away!
It could be fatal!
What are you doing? Me down the sea.
Quiet! Look!
Bye-bye!
You still say bye to him. You're stupid.
- Think of something.
- Try to get over!
Miracle...
- What miracle?
- Look!
Let's order it to rise further, okay?
Yes...
Oh, no!
- Who say?
- I didn't...
I do. It has risen to the top.
How are you going to go up?
Over there is a drawbridge!
Go and see!
- Go away!
- Don't be in the way!
Come down...
Put him down. Let's kill him.
I can't sail it!
I'm only playing with it!
It doesn't work!
Trying to rob?
Let me come up to break your head.
Want money? Come up and get it!
You'll have to kill me to get it!
You wanted me to go down, idiots.
Where are the idiots?
So high! I'm scared.
Don't be afraid.
I'll take care of it here.
Come over if you dare.
Stop ballyhooing!
Why not? I'll fight with you.
I'll kill you, Baldy.
Sister, I'm damn scared!
Don't worry. God bless you.
He may hit me.
Don't worry. He never hits a female.
Don't worry! Go down!
Go down! I'll pray for you.
- She said you never hit a woman!
- $30 million!
What are you doing?
- Child turn back.
- Nonsense!
Trying to run?
Come over if you've the guts.
Sure, with $30 million!
Don't!
I'm coming!
My goodness! What's wrong?
What are you afraid of?
Many jelly-fish down below.
Don't worry! I'll put you up.
Hold close...
Damn, how clumsy I am.
- I 'm coming.
- Who?
Don't run!
Get it back.
Don't let him get away!
Stop...
Don't run! Get it back.
- Lend him a hand, please.
- Coming.
Throw it to me!
Lord, please give me strength
to save them.
God be blessed!
Thank you...
Stop him...
Don't scramble... It's dangerous.
Look, it's so high!
It's dangerous! Don't fight!
You can't get away!
Quick! I've it!
$30 million! It's with me, it's here...
- Hell with you!
- Don't! Stop that!
May the Lord give me strength
to save these lost sheep.
Hope on earth.
God loved the world.
Say that again...
What did you say just now?
God loved the world.
Before that!
Hope on earth.
Hope on earth, we're rich!
"In order to secure your work"
"You can't help but to work hard"
"See what the boss looks"
"He looks discontented"
"In order to make a living,
you're willing to be slaves"
"Being obedience make me unhappy"
"Work until all parts of my body hurts"
"Hope one day I would be rich"
"When it comes to money"
"Everybody is in the same religion"
"You can't raise your head without it"
"I really can do nothing"
"till fortune smiles upon me"
"And I need a windfall
to get me off the hook"
"Only if I were rich"
"Could I vent my grievances"
"May the tide turn in my favor"
"May luck be with me"
"to enable me to make a good showing"
"I swear I'd bring a beautiful world"
"For both you and me"