(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
("I CAN'T STAND THE RAIN"
BY ANN PEEBLES PLAYING)
I can't stand the rain
Against my window...
I love a good fire. Mmm.
Bringing back
sweet memories...
Let's get this place set.
Hey, window pane...
Ooh, this can go right here.
Well, y'all gonna have to go,
just for the weekend, though.
Cheers to us.
When we was together...
-(DOOR CREAKING)
-(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Hello?
Hello? Shawn?
Yo, stop playing.
(IN DEEP VOICE) I got a gun!
(WHISPERING) God damn it.
(DEEP VOICE) Hey yo... (WHISPERING)
That's too DMX. What are you doing?
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
Baby, is that you?
-(MUSIC SPIKES)
-(SCREAMS)
-Damn, Morgan!
-Nigga!
See, I knew I shouldn't have
got you them Muay Thai class for Christmas.
You strong, strong.
You strong with a C.
But why the hell
didn't you say something?
Damn, you almost made me
spill my wine.
So, you almost
break your man nose,
but, "Oh, no, my wine"?
Baby, we are all alone
in a cabin in the woods.
Until the others get here,
you got to announce yourself.
-You asking for too much.
-Am I?
I'll touch your penis later.
-Deal.
-(SCOFFS) So predictable.
Okay, okay, but you gotta
check out this room.
-This shit is wild.
-How wild?
-Come on.
-Oh, you like it sick. Okay.
SHAWN: Follow me.
Follow the leader, huh?
-MORGAN: Yeah.
-(SHAWN CHUCKLES)
-Tch! Tch! Tch! Ah-ah-ah!
-Stop playing.
Is it Blade's house?
Where's Wesley? I want to talk to Wesley.
If it is, you know what they
pay you for. Wait, hold up.
-I know I left this door open.
-Uh-uh. I'mma go get my sage.
Uh-uh. Uh-uh.
Come on, come on, come on, now.
-We good.
-Listen, I won't play.
I watched a whole entire
Dateline episode
with this psycho
brother and sister
who kept their incest-bred kids
hidden under the stairs
of their Airbnb.
Also, that wasn't Dateline.
That was just the plot from the
movie People Under the Stairs.
-You might be right.
-(GRUNTS) Oh!
(SUCKS TEETH) Kinda fucked
myself up, but here you go.
-You okay?
-Enter my port of doom.
-Wow.
-Come on, come, come.
Did you know this house
was gonna have
this cool-ass game room?
No, I did not.
But that's not why
I brought you in here.
You gotta check this out.
-The Blackening. Seriously?
-Yup.
Whoa!
What in
the Jim Crow fuck, right?
Uh-uh.
This is hella disturbing.
Why the hell is this
in this house?
This was not in any
of the reviews, but guess what?
It's about to be.
I don't know,
but as soon as I get a signal,
I'm fittin' to cancel
their asses immediately.
Yo, AirDrop me all of that.
I got you.
Say, "Cheese," motherfucker.
-MORGAN: Baby, this is wild.
-Yeah.
How do you even play this game?
-Like, what are the rules?
-You tryna play?
I mean, I'm a little curious.
Aren't you?
I can't even get you
to play Spades,
but you all over Sambo.
Oh. At least Sambo don't renege.
Nigga, if you say you don't
have hearts, guess what?
You shouldn't have hearts.
THE GAME: Pick a card.
(DISTANT SCREAM)
At least we know it's working.
-(SIGHS)
-Shit probably runs on racism.
(LAUGHS DRYLY) Now, that is one battery
that ain't dying no time soon.
-That's a sober comment right there, baby.
-Pick a card!
Okay, nigga, calm down.
I just did.
Yeah, and you better watch how
you talking to my lady, okay?
-Okay.
-What you got?
"You are a Black character
in a horror movie.
Prove that you can stay alive.
Name one Black character
that survived a horror movie.
You must answer correctly,
or you die." What the hell?
So this is just an aggressively
themed trivia game.
Hold up. Were there even niggas in
horror movies when this game was created?
Baby, you're thinking too much
about this, all right?
I know the answer. It is Jada
Pinkett, Omar Epps, Scream 2.
-Boom, Sambo.
-(IMITATES BUZZER)
Them niggas was the first to die.
What are you talking about?
I honestly think that the studio
didn't have the budget
to keep 'em the whole movie.
That's why
they had to die first.
All right, let's see
what we got here.
-We got game pieces.
-Mmm-hmm.
MORGAN: Wait a minute.
Don't this look like my earring?
Let me see.
Yeah, like,
it's the same but different.
-(TIMER DINGS)
-Your time has run out.
-You did not answer correctly.
-MORGAN: But hold up.
How the hell does a game know
if we answer correctly or not?
It don't. Watch this.
You watching us, Sambo?
Well, yes, I am.
It's time to die.
(GAME LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
-(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
-Fuck!
(GAME CONTINUES LAUGHING
MANIACALLY)
I can't see. Where are you?
Baby? Baby? Keep talking.
Morgan, baby, follow my voice.
Follow my voice. I'm over here.
Okay, you got me. You got me.
Come on, come on, come on.
Okay, okay, okay, you got me.
You got me.
I'm so scared.
(SHAWN SHUSHING)
Listen.
Is that... Is that breathing?
Wait. Let me get my phone.
Let me get my phone.
Okay.
-Okay. Okay, okay.
-Okay.
Okay.
Hello?
-(ARROW FIRES)
-(SHAWN GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Shawn? Shawn?
Shawn?
(GASPS, SCREAMS)
Run, nigga.
(MORGAN CRYING)
MAN: Hey!
Peekaboo. I see you!
-(THE GAME LAUGHING)
-(BLOWS LANDING)
(MORGAN CRYING)
THE GAME: Time to die!
Time to die! Time to die!
Time to die!
(SCREAMING)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
I can't stand the rain
("RUN" BY CUT THE LIGHTS
and ROCHESTER PLAYING)
I got 'em, I got 'em
I got 'em, run
Can't stop, not yet
Push through, never rest
Till I'm in the safe zone
I know I can make it home
Can't breathe, legs weak
Got no time to think about it
Ain't no other way around it
-They catch up?
-Forget about it
Turn the corner
Jump the fence
Thank God I wore Timbs
Tore my jackets into shreds
Just so I can get the bag
Now I see the Benz pulling up
Where you gon' hide?
Where you gon' go?
Where you gon' rest?
Yeah, you out of breath
You can feel it
in your heart
Pumping out your chest
You can feel it in your heart
They right behind ya
Never let 'em find ya
You gotta run
Run
Run, I got 'em, I got 'em
I got 'em, I got 'em
I got 'em
I got 'em, I got 'em, run
I got my finger
on the trigger pointed at you
Never been a quitter
I'm forever like a tattoo
Diamond in the rough
and you're looking Fugazi
You ain't tough enough
Try your luck, outrace me
What you scared of?
I'm right here, dog
Like a werewolf
Never fearful
Only eat what I kill, so...
-Who want it with me?
-(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
MORGAN: Hey, guys! Listen,
I cannot wait to see you guys.
Oh, remember,
when you turn on Valley Lane,
it's gonna feel like you've gone too far
because you in the woods.
But just keep coming. Shawn
almost got us lost earlier.
SHAWN: Man, no, I didn't,
Morgan. Don't tell 'em that.
MORGAN: Anyway,
I got the games ready.
Time to get it cracking!
-Oh, shit.
-God damn.
This whole reunion
about to crack,
and you know
Morgan ain't playing
when it comes
to the party planning.
Okay, because we about
to turn it all the way up.
-I got some shrooms, molly.
-Oh, that sounds good.
Oh, and I got
some nice herb in the back.
I don't even care. We got
the whole crew back, okay?
Got all eight of us.
We did that, y'all.
Pause. Pause, pause. Eight?
What do you mean, eight?
I know seven.
Who all gon' be there?
WOMAN 1: Bitch, you didn't tell
him that Nnamdi was coming?
-WOMAN 2: I was going to.
-WOMAN 1: Really?
-WOMAN 2: Hell no!
-WOMAN 1: I knew it.
By the way,
I like this haircut on you.
-WOMAN 2: Thanks, girl.
-Hello, bitches.
I see y'all exchanging looks.
What are y'all shady asses hiding?
-BOTH: Nothing.
-Matter of fact, y'all are hiding someone.
Again, answer my question,
who all gon' be there?
Who cares who's going?
It's been ten years
since we all hung out.
-We came to have fun.
-Yes, please.
We need some reckless,
unadulterated fun.
We all desperately need it.
-Especially you, Dewayne.
-Especially you.
Okay, you ain't gotta
say it like that.
(LAUGHS DRYLY)
But, yes, you are right.
I do need fun, and I am
very excited to see everybody.
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
As long as Nnamdi's not there.
He not gonna be there, right?
("WAY UP" BY
DAISHA MCBRIDE PLAYING)
They lucky
to be in the crew
Tell 'em we coming in hot
Skrrt, skrrt, move
See we out choppin' the block
See we got something to prove
-We on the way
-We on the way up
-I want a team
-That don't want to play us
-We on the way, way, way, way up
-Way, way, way up
We on the way,
way, way, way up
-We on the way
-We on the way up
-I want a team
-That don't want to play us
We on the way,
way, way, way up
(DOOR CHIMES)
(LAUGHS)
Yes, it's that good shit.
(GASPS) No, they don't.
Rap Snack?
Okay, Chainsaw Massacre man,
I see you.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Stranger danger.
-Sorry.
-Shanika?
Carlton?
-Clifton.
-Clifton. Yes!
Oh, my God, what you doing out here
in the middle of nowhere?
Oh, come on.
Aren't you here for the reunion?
Yeah, yes, the reunion.
-Yes, I am.
-(DOOR CHIMES)
Wow. Anyhoo, I was actually
on my way to the soiree.
But I forgot my phone charger,
and then my phone died.
It's not the end of the world.
It's okay. It's fine, right?
But then my Hyundai
died up the road.
-Your what?
-Hyundai died up the road.
And I get here,
they don't even have my charger.
They have iPhone,
I have Android.
Damn. I'm sorry.
-That does suck.
-It does.
-Not the car, the Android.
-You're funny.
We all know Androids have
the superior operating systems.
Wrong!
That's wrong. But it's okay.
I'm gonna help yo ass get gas
despite your opinions.
Come on. Let's go.
And why do you got so much damn toilet paper?
You got so many Rap Snacks.
That's a lot of salt.
Okay, is it just me or is this giving
Texas Chainsaw Massacre?
I don't know. I never seen that
film. White people scare me.
-But your daddy is white.
-Exactly.
And, girl, that's why
every single time he gets mad,
I'm like, "Oh, Lord,
here it comes: murder-suicide."
-(BOTH LAUGH)
-WOMAN 1: You know I'm serious.
(DEWAYNE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(WOMAN 1 LAUGHS) Oh, God!
No! Oh, my God, really, bitch?
-A cabin in the woods?
-It's technically a house.
-(FAKES LAUGHTER)
-I think it's cute.
But she got money. We could have
went to, like, a five-star resort.
MAN: I already told you.
You're wasting your time.
MAN 2: Just answer the question
so I can find out...
What seems to be the problem?
I'm trying to explain to him
that I'm staying here
for the week,
I just didn't
have the code, but...
-Who are you?
-Are you a cop?
I'm a park ranger, and
your friend here is trespassing.
No, he's not. See? Right here.
All of our names are listed.
We have the home
for the weekend.
-Told you.
-And here is my license.
Excuse me.
Normally, the Connors
only rent to...
White people?
-Families.
-White families.
Mmm.
You all have a wonderful stay.
"You have a wonderful time."
He sounds like my dad.
Ew. I didn't know park rangers
have guns. That is unsettling.
Well, that was
completely unnecessary.
Don't even trip.
Can't let the ignorance
of his prejudice
disrupt our inner peace.
-What?
-Okay, Gandhi.
When did you get
all namaste, King?
Is this the same King
we went to college with?
Of course it is.
What is this sensitive energy?
(KING SIGHS)
-Where are Shawn and Morgan at?
-They texted me.
They probably just went out.
They'll be back soon.
Anyway,
happy Juneteenth, niggas!
-Happy Juneteenth!
Happy Juneteenth, Ranger White!
-Hey!
-(LAUGHING)
-Whose car is this?
-NNAMDI: Hey, yo!
It's... I'm gonna go get my bag.
WOMAN 1: Brother Nnamdi.
NNAMDI: Sister Allison Tubman.
ALLISON: Good to see you.
Sister.
-What's up?
-Hey.
(LAUGHS DRYLY) 'Sup.
I gotta go get my bag.
So, what's up?
Y'all ready to party?
Yup.
Sorry.
I should have told you that
Nnamdi and I are friends again.
Yeah, you should have.
But honestly, at this point,
it is what it is.
But friends. I'm confused.
When did that happen?
Because last time I checked,
that was the nigga
that cheated on you
again, and again.
I'm over that.
College was a long time ago.
-People can grow, Dewayne.
-Are you saying I haven't grown?
Look, Nnamdi and I are
just friends, so you can relax.
Can we please enjoy this?
It'll be like the old days.
Party, play
some of Morgan's games,
party some more.
-Fine.
-Close your eyes.
-Do you trust me?
-(INHALES) With my life.
Take a deep breath.
Now, inhale through your mouth.
(INHALES)
-Swallow.
-Mmm. What is this?
Molly. Now, stop being
sad and pressed.
Time to party, bitch.
-Molly?
-Yep.
You know
that's my drug of choice.
Let's do it!
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
ALLISON: Hello?
Yo!
Oh, my gosh. This is so cute!
I bet you Morgan did this.
You know she loves decorating.
I bet you they already took
the best rooms, too.
-Oh, my gosh.
-Shit, look, Allison.
Even got a picture of you
on the wall, too.
Fuck you, Nnamdi.
That's your ex-girlfriend.
You know,
the one with the teeth?
-Okay.
-Uh-oh.
You know what time it is
when these cards come out?
You taking all the Spade fades.
You still like losing?
If this is how you wanna start the weekend,
that's fine with me, gentlemen.
Because me and Lisa
about to come back
and issue that smackdown.
Let me go drop my bags,
and I will be right back.
This is nice. I bet you this
is all repurposed wood, too.
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CREAKING)
(DISTANT SCREAM)
(DOORKNOB RATTLES)
Hmm. This must be where
they keep their personal items. It's locked.
Or maybe it's the master
bedroom, and Morgan and Shawn,
the couple of the friend group,
took it.
Okay. Speaking of couples.
A little birdy told me
that another couple
may be in our friend group.
I'm not saying,
I'm just saying.
You're not saying, but you're
just saying what, Allison?
I'm just saying, Nnamdi,
do not break her heart again,
and I mean that.
I got you.
And remember, you gonna have to
deal with Dewayne, too.
KING: Mix it up, baby. Oh, yeah.
Mmm-hmm. This ain't
the Blackest shit ever?
You know what else
is real Black? Diabetes.
Ain't nobody drinking that.
-We're good.
-You know what?
I'mma pray that you get
all that hate out your heart.
And why would you do that?
That's what keeps me
nice and young. (LAUGHS)
Stop playing.
You gonna make me drop these.
Okay.
(WOOD CREAKING)
-My brotha.
-Hey. Let's go.
I call it King's Kool-Ayyy.
The fuck, brother.
Call it King's Kool-No.
-Is it that bad?
-Yes, bro. You tripping.
Sugar fuck around
and give you a cramp.
God damn! Shit!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Damn. But, shit, bro,
how you been?
I've been good, you know.
I feel like everything's
starting to fall into place.
-Okay.
-Got steady clients at the gym.
-I'm seeing this girl now.
-Oh, shit. Only one?
Yes, bro. Only one.
-I'm a new man.
-Wow.
-You know what I call that?
-Mmm. Growth.
-Delusion.
-What?
You been saying that same thing
like every two years
since we met.
You do some fuck shit,
you feel bad,
you reflect, become a new man.
But then the new nigga
do some fuck shit,
and the whole cycle
just start over again.
-Come on, bruh. This time is different.
-This time is different.
(LAUGHING)
Nigga, you say the same thing
every time. You ain't changed.
Man, fuck all that bull.
What about you?
What, you still a slave
to the white man?
Y'all gonna stop calling my
wife the white man, all right?
-Her name is Jenny.
-Okay.
And she ain't white white.
She ethnic white.
-She Armenian.
-Come on, man.
That bitch
is dog kisses on the mouth,
pumpkin spice latte, "Sweet
Caroline", "Bye Bye Bye" white.
So, you just gon'
call my wife a bitch?
Just, come on, bruh.
Nah, I meant bitch in the colloquial sense.
You know, like, "Hey, bitch. You
gon' finish that quesadilla?"
Yeah, no,
that was a bad example.
All right, look, bruh,
I didn't mean...
I'm fucking with you.
(LAUGHS)
-Fuck outta here, bro.
-I'm fucking with you.
I'm a changed man.
Shit, look at me.
So, you telling me she wrung
every bit of the thug
out of you, bro?
There's not even
a little bit left?
Like, you really
ain't packing right now?
(SIGHS) Nah, man.
Man, you really
in the Sunken Place.
Balls deep, my brother.
Balls deep.
(ANIMAL HOWLING IN DISTANCE)
-LISA: You got a heart?
-ALLISON: Nope.
LISA: You got that last club,
don't you?
-ALLISON: Yup, and it's low.
-LISA: Got you.
Oh, yeah, she love the club.
Let me see.
Yo, I hate these dudes.
I hate 'em.
Got a good time. Aye! Aye!
I knew it,
and that might be board.
Five?
That may be the dagger.
Shit. All I got is a...
Dang, bitch!
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
That's my partner, okay?
That is what we do
on Juneteenth, motherfuckers.
-Y'all cheated, man.
-So now we cheated?
Congratulations.
Chivalry's not dead.
Oh, oh. Take your L and go.
Nnam, that's something
a loser would say, Nnamdi.
Don't be a sore loser.
(CHATTER AND LAUGHTER)
Hey, Dewayne,
you wanna run one?
-Come on, Dewayne.
-Come on, bro, let's run one.
Dewayne, did you just
shift in your seat at me,
you little moody ass?
What is wrong with Dewayne?
He always does this.
First, he gets
all introspective and shit,
and then 20 minutes later...
("777" BY BRUNO MARS, ANDERSON
.PAAK AND SILK SONIC PLAYING)
I fucking love this song.
Are y'all hot? Kinda hot.
KING: Oh, he needs some water.
Yup, that molly
finally got his ass.
Oh, my God, he is wilding.
Oh, I feel like the music
is kissing me on my neck.
-(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
-KING: Nobody kissing your neck.
ALLISON: Yes, Dewayne. Come on!
Big booty hoes meet me
in the penthouse...
You better
rip those pants off, Dewayne.
It's gon' get weird tonight
So no pictures...
Come on,
who needs clothes, boo? Yes!
No. No.
KING: You got it going, Dewayne.
(ALLISON LAUGHS)
(MUSIC AND PARTYING CONTINUE
IN OTHER ROOM)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
-(OBJECT CLATTERS)
-(WOOD CREAKS)
Nnamdi, is that you?
(DOOR CLOSING)
(METAL CREAKING)
Shit! You scared me.
("CAN'T GET ENOUGH"
BY DAVID BASSELIZ PLAYING)
Feel like this is crazy
What's on right now
Don't worry about
your troubles, babe...
-Hey, what's the problem?
-I feel bad.
Dewayne still doesn't know
we got back together.
Dewayne?
(SCOFFS, CLEARS THROAT)
Maybe if you tell him,
you might realize
that you outgrew your friend.
Boy. You really thought
you just said something.
"You realize
you've outgrown your friend."
You don't know shit
about my friendship.
-(SIGHS)
-Okay.
-(SIGHING) Oh, my God.
-Are you okay?
My molly just hit.
Look, I'm sorry I lashed out.
I was projecting a bit,
but you were overstepping.
Now...
-Take your pants off.
-(PANTS UNZIP)
(WASHING MACHINE CHIMES
AND STARTS RUNNING)
(SOFT METALLIC CLINKING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR LOCK CLICKS,
DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
(LOCK CLICKS)
Boo, motherfucker!
(LAUGHING)
Bitch, you play too much.
I almost hit you.
-Is you high?
-A little bit.
-You on molly?
-Yeah.
Gimme some.
Where you got some at?
-Go in the house.
-Okay. Get me...
-Get me some molly.
-Ow. You so late. Move.
Hold on!
'Bout to fuck up my Moscato.
-This is peach lavender.
-Go through the front door.
-I love you.
-Love you.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
Happy Juneteenth, niggas!
-Shanika in the hizzouse.
-Hey.
-What's up, Ally?
-Girlfriend, hi!
Yes, how are ya?
It's so good to see you, boo.
Put that on ice.
What's up, Shanika?
Where you been?
What up, nigga? I got lost.
And then my car couldn't
make it up that fucking hill.
-Y'all, I ran into, um...
-Clifton.
I have not seen you
since we were at the...
-SHANIKA: At the one...
-I don't know that nigga.
-At the...
-School.
-School!
That's what it was.
-All right.
-Yeah.
-Well, welcome.
-Thanks. I appreciate it.
I mean, I'm surprised
I was invited, too.
Anyway, do you guys
have an Android charger?
I told you,
we don't support that.
All right, well,
you can't win 'em all.
-Thanks for having me.
-Y'all, where's Lisa?
Y'all motherfuckers didn't start
numbing reality without me,
'cause if you did...
(SQUEALING) What up, Lis?
You smell like dick.
What the fuck you been doing?
Oh. That's who you been doing.
I accidentally
smelled some of the dick.
(SHANIKA LAUGHING)
Oh, wow.
So, Lisa the new girl
you was telling me about?
(DEWAYNE CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, so suddenly it's quiet
and all eyes are on me.
Is that my reputation?
Something happens
and y'all just waiting on me
to be combative?
(EXCLAIMS, LAUGHS)
Guys, I'm not even mad,
I promise.
Lis, I'm tryna be
as fucked up as he is.
ALLISON: Let's get
this party started.
We should all take shots, right?
Yes. Please.
Get back to handing out
these ass whoopings in Spades.
ALLISON: Who are you talking to?
Oh, puh-lease.
'Cause you know good and well
we've been whooping your ass
all night, right, Lisa?
Y'all got lucky.
Don't let it go to your heads.
(ALLISON LAUGHS)
-Hey, Dewayne.
-Hey.
Oh, my God. Gal,
it's so nice to see you again.
-It's Clifton.
-Oh... Yes.
Oh, my God, I'm so...
I knew that.
I'm so sorry.
I've taken a lot of drugs.
Do you know where
I can put my bag?
Mmm-mmm.
Where's Morgan and Shawn?
I got a text last night
saying that they made it here.
They texted us
earlier, actually,
and told us that
they were gonna come back
later on this evening.
-Hey, thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Here, Clifton.
-Thank you, baby.
No, hold it, nigga.
-I have a toast.
-Yes!
On this Juneteenth Day,
I would like
to celebrate freedom.
-Freedom.
Freedom from caring about people
more than they care
about themselves.
A friend of mine once told me,
"People can grow."
At the time,
I didn't know what she meant,
but now I know
that she meant, "Grow apart."
Uh-huh. And then they die.
-And that's called fate.
-Dewayne.
Mmm. Cheers to having
standards and self-respect.
(CHUCKLES)
To friendship for life.
-For life.
Lovely. That sounds awesome.
(INHALES SHARPLY, EXCLAIMS)
Oh, my God, holy shit, King.
That tastes like pure sugar.
I call it King's Kool-Ayyy.
You drink it,
it make you go, "Ayyy."
Bruh, I love you, but
you gonna have to give it up.
Okay, you know what?
Keep drinking that shit
and watch yourself
get some cramps.
Shut up.
Let's get into these Spades.
-That's why we came here, right?
-ALLISON: Let's do it.
So, look, it's gonna be Allison
and Lisa, and me and Nnamdi.
-Can I play?
-I don't know. Can you?
Well, can you teach me?
Ain't nobody ever teach you
how to play Spades?
I've played before, I just...
-I forgot some of the...
-King?
Look, man, we ain't got time
to be teaching you how to play.
You can sit on the sideline,
you can watch.
If you learn, cool, if not...
Yeah, sure, of course.
I'll watch.
You know what? You can learn,
but it's just that
you gonna have to be
on a team in order to learn.
And this weekend,
it is women against boys.
So, I mean, if you're learning,
you got to learn
from your gender folk.
That ain't gonna happen.
Yeah, learn from the losers
'cause we finna getting that ass, right?
Okay! Bussin', baby.
(ELECTRICITY CUTS OUT)
ALLISON: Where are you going?
I'm gonna look for the fuse box.
-What the hell was that?
-What was what?
-I see nothing.
-DEWAYNE: Was it a raccoon?
No, it was bigger
than a raccoon.
-DEWAYNE: Was it a bear?
-We gotta find the lights.
Yeah, I'm with King.
I'm not gonna...
-Like a bear-sized raccoon?
-Shut up. Come on.
I don't know this house
like that.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
It's locked.
This one, too.
Why are all the doors locked?
Let's try this one.
Uh, that one's locked too, bruh.
-Well...
-Wait, wait.
Who put that sign on the door?
That was not there earlier,
you guys.
"Game room."
Probably Morgan and Shawn.
Probably just came back earlier
and are trying to scare
the shit out of us.
DEWAYNE: Well, it's not funny.
I think it's a prank
or something. Morgan!
Yo, Shawn, stop playing.
KING: It's locked, bruh.
It's locked.
No, it ain't.
Come on.
What's this?
Oh, hell no.
So, the lights just come on
when they want to?
That works.
Game room?
Yeah, this is some
Morgan next-level
party-planning shit, right?
They got all the games, too.
Ah! Etch A Sketch.
I used to love this.
Oh, hey. I love Ouija boards.
One time I tried to summon Gary
Coleman and he was not happy.
Hey, look at this.
It's us from college.
Oh, let me see me.
Um, I found
Morgan's earring earlier.
What? These are
her great grandmother's.
-She never takes these off.
-She's definitely here, then.
See, y'all?
Morgan just fucking with us.
-NNAMDI: Yeah.
-ALLISON: The Blackening?
Yo, what is this?
Jim Crow Monopoly?
-Whoa.
-DEWAYNE: Uh-uh. This game got bad vibes.
No. No, thank you.
Yeah, Morgan would not plan
some stupid shit
like this, bruh.
Nah, she wouldn't.
King... I think
this must be yours.
-It's a crown. That makes sense.
-Huh.
A purse. That's fitting.
-Nnamdi.
-A pyramid? Why's that fitting?
Because, nigga,
you're literally from Africa.
Shanika.
Why I gotta get a bottle?
'Cause you're literally a drunk.
So, wait,
they made one of these
specifically for each of us?
Yeah, I guess.
(CHUCKLES)
No, no, no. What are you doing?
We literally came all this way
to party and play games,
so that's what I'm doing.
Oh, come on,
this is clearly Morgan's work.
I am not even tripping.
Let's just play.
I'm with Allison.
Everybody falling for this fake creepiness.
But I'mma beat her
at her own game.
Yeah, Morgan, I see you.
Game on, bitch.
I guess.
KING: All right, let's get it.
Yeah, let's get it.
So, I guess the question is
how do we play?
Ask the little
racist nigga here.
THE GAME:
Pick a card and save Morgan.
The hell?
What it mean, save Morgan?
(LOCK CLICKS)
-Shit. It's locked.
-That's not funny, King.
See, that makes me nervous,
and I throw up when I'm nervous.
-Move, King.
-Maybe it's a push.
-Maybe push it.
-Talking about it's locked.
Your ass couldn't open it,
that's why. If you just, um...
Did you try pushing it?
I think you should push.
You just jerk it off.
There you go.
Nigga, kill yourself.
Y'all, it's locked.
See? See, I told you. That's why
I don't go to fucking cabins...
-I'm about to snap. -Everyone calm down
so we can figure out what's going on.
(STATIC)
(LIVELY BANJO MUSIC PLAYING)
Wait. What the...?
-LISA: Oh, God, no.
-KING: Is that Morgan?
-Oh, no, Morgan.
-Oh, my God.
Y'all, we gotta get
the fuck up outta here.
ALLISON: Oh, my God, Morgan!
Allison, you're gonna have
to shut the hell up!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please...
THE GAME: Lisa, Nnamdi,
Allison, Dewayne,
Shanika, King, Clifton.
It said our names, y'all.
This shit is personal, personal.
-How the fuck is it doing this?
-The rules are simple.
Answer correctly
before the second hand
completes one revolution,
you move a space.
If you answer
ten questions correctly,
she lives
and you're all free to go.
Get one wrong, she dies.
Oh, my God, guys, look.
There is someone with her.
Refuse to play, and you die,
just like Shawn did.
SHANIKA: Oh, shit!
DEWAYNE: No! Shawn.
-Oh, my God.
-Fuck. Fuck.
-Fuck.
-KING: Now, what?
Well, guys, I'm scared too,
uh, but the voice
made it very clear.
We have an opportunity
to save Morgan,
so why don't we
just play the game?
So, shall we begin?
(LIVELY BANJO MUSIC PLAYING)
I think we have to play
the game.
Pick a card.
Okay. "Question one.
Who's Sojourner Truth?
A: An abolitionist,
and women's rights activist.
B: An entrepreneur.
Or C: Harriet Tubman.
Right answer or death."
-What the fuck? Are you serious? -So, he
just gon' force us to do a Black history test?
I don't understand.
Why make us play this game?
If you just gonna kill us,
just kill us.
-Shut the fuck up, Dewayne.
-Look, just answer the question.
-It's A, of course.
-Good for you. You have a point.
What you doing?
Move all our pieces.
Oh, my bad.
Pick a card.
"How many seasons
did dark Aunt Viv
play Aunt Viv
in The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air
before being replaced
by light-skinned Aunt Viv?
Right answer or death."
Okay, so, Tyra Banks came
in the college years.
-And then Ashley started singing.
-I know the answer...
Little Nicky came in season four,
and it was light skin Aunt Viv,
so it had to be before that.
-It's three.
-Are you sure?
Yes, nigga. I'm sure.
It's three.
-That is correct.
-Whoo!
Yeah, team, we're on a roll.
We're doing it, really,
we're moving and grooving.
-Okay.
-Let's go.
"What does the NAACP stand for?
A. Negroes At Applebee's
Cooking Pasta."
Oh, my God,
this is so offensive.
Uh, the National Association
for the Advancement of Colored People.
-Fuck you.
-Correct. Pick another card.
(SIGHS) All right. "Every Black
person should be familiar
with the Black national anthem,
"Lift Every Voice and Sing.
While every Black person
knows the first verse,
sing the second verse, or else."
I only know the first verse.
Yeah, same. Honestly,
I just be making up words.
Nigga, I know
the Pledge of Allegiance.
That song has like 14 verses.
Somebody better
fucking sing something.
Stony the road we trod
Bitter the chastening rod
Felt in the days
When hope unborn had died
Yet with a steady beat
Have not our weary feet
Come to the place
For which our fathers sighed?
Is that right?
-Correct.
-Whoo! Yes!
-Yo!
-Yes!
CLIFTON: I'm in love.
I'm in love.
Al, that was gorgeous.
Swag, the gas mask,
and the motherfucking pacemaker.
That's 15 Black inventions,
right? Let's go.
-(GAME TIMER DINGS)
-(CHEERING AND CLAPPING)
-Okay.
-Pick a card.
Whoo! Come on.
"In Nas's "One Mic,"
subtract the number of blunts,
pages and pens that Nas needs
from the number of shots..."
-It's Nas.
-Nas.
"Nas needs from the number
of shots that hit the crew."
Why y'all looking at me?
You finna die y'all expect me to answer that.
Wait, wait, wait, no,
I know this one.
All right, so,
you'll need one blunt,
one page, one pen,
right, which is three.
And two twin Glocks,
which is 16, which is 32.
Jesus was 33, six hit the
crew, but 27 went into you.
27 minus 3 is 24. It's 24.
-Are you sure?
-Positive!
That is correct.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
And I like your math.
Pick another card.
"Name five Black actors
that have appeared
on the hit TV show Friends."
This is a trick question, right?
I should know this, but I was
more of a Becker kind of guy.
Why y'all looking at me?
I ain't never seen the show.
But I do know Aisha Tyler
was on it once,
playing the love interest
of Joey and Ross, so that's one.
I never watched the show either,
but I do know Gabrielle Union was on the show.
She was also a love interest
for Joey and Ross.
Wait, is that the show about all
the white people in New York?
-Yeah, on the couch.
-Yeah, I didn't watch that shit either.
But I do know that
Craig Robinson was on it,
but I don't know
who he played, though.
And Mr. Moseby.
He played Chandler's boss.
-Phill Lewis.
-Shit, yeah, that's four.
-So all y'all watched that show?
-We need one more.
Your time is almost up.
Um, um, um,
dark-skinned Aunt Viv
also played
one of Chandler's bosses.
You know,
they were very "plug and play"
with the Black people
on that show.
So, y'all did watch that show?
Okay, but
what was her name again?
-Um...
-Queen Janet Hubert.
-That's five!
-Yes!
Come on now, my girl.
Wrong. The correct answer was,
"I don't know.
I don't watch that show.
-I watch Living Single."
-Aw, you can't do that.
-That ain't what you asked.
-SHANIKA: Damn!
MORGAN: Help! Help me, please!
-SHANIKA: Is that thing attached to her head?
-No, no, no, no, Morgan.
KING: Oh, shit,
he about to scalp her.
(RIPPING)
-(SCREAMING)
-Shit!
Oh, bitch,
that's some good-ass wig glue.
Now, get the fuck up
out of there!
(ALL CHEERING)
Come on, bitch, you gotta
fight for your fucking' life!
ALLISON: Morgan,
get the hell out of there!
(ALL YELLING)
We gotta get the fuck
outta here. We gotta go.
Nnamdi, come help me
with the door.
I got you.
Let's break this thing down.
What the...?
Oh, shit. It's open.
It's open? Let's get out of
here, guys. Come on, let's go.
-Move, Clifton. Let's go.
-None of us motherfucking dying today.
DEWAYNE: Move, bitch.
Get out of my way.
Come on. Check the doors.
Fuck! It's locked.
Somebody break the window.
Yeah, break it.
Y'all, move. Duck!
(CLIFTON SCREAMS)
Fuck!
DEWAYNE: What type of glass
is that?
(PANTING)
-This place is like a prison.
-Oh, my God.
Guys.
Look at our cars.
(LIVELY BANJO MUSIC PLAYING)
LISA: Morgan.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
MORGAN: Somebody! Open the door!
(BANGING)
-She's in the basement!
-DEWAYNE: Come on. Move!
-LISA: Morgan, we're coming!
-NNAMDI: Morgan, hold on! We got it.
KING: Morgan, hold tight.
We gonna get you out.
-KING: Let me try.
-NNAMDI: On three. Ready? Pull.
-Morgan, he's behind you.
-Oh, my God, he's behind you.
-He's behind her!
-He's right behind you.
-Hey, Morgan, he's right behind you.
-(SCREAMS) No, please!
-He's walking up the stairs.
-Oh, my God, he's walking up the stairs.
Hurry up!
He's walking up the stairs!
He's coming up the stairs.
Watch out!
Oh, my God, I'mma throw up.
I'm gonna throw up.
Oh, my God, I'm gonna throw up.
-Somebody, do something.
-Somebody better...
Do something!
NNAMDI: King, where you going?
Come on, man, I need help.
Morgan, we got you.
-You got a gun?
-Bruh, I knew you had a gun.
-Wow, that's profiling.
-How come you didn't use it before?
On what? The TV, nigga?
Move out the way.
Morgan, stand back.
I'mma shoot the lock off.
Y'all be shooting in here.
Morgan.
-Y'all see something?
-No.
You wanna borrow my glasses?
Morgan!
Hold tight, yo.
I'm coming to get you.
Morgan, we right here.
We gon' get you out.
Morgan!
Maybe try her last name.
-Morgan!
-Morgan.
(ALL SCREAMING)
-SHANIKA: Get your...
Hey, get your... -Fuck!
Will somebody fucking help me?
Okay!
-Oh, shit! Oh, God!
-Did I get him?
You're like King Arthur.
This motherfucker shot me
in my shoulder.
Take this shit out.
-Lisa, get a knife.
-(SCREAMS)
-Okay. This is too big.
-Allison, you pull it out.
I'm not pulling that shit out.
You pull it out.
LISA: Wait. Okay.
I got a good one! Here you go.
-Stab him!
-Who, me?
Yes, you, bitch. Gimme that.
(MAN CRYING OUT IN PAIN)
(ALL BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMS)
Put it back in.
Put it back in!
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Are you guys okay?
-I stabbed him.
-It's over.
Everybody, get down!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Stay down!
(GUN CLICKS)
He's gone, y'all!
DEWAYNE: Okay, let's go.
LISA: Get back to the game room.
ALLISON: Yes,
oh, my God, let's go!
Oh, wait, Nnamdi!
We need to bring King.
Come on, come on. Oh, shit.
-SHANIKA: Go.
-CLIFTON: I'm fine.
(KING GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
Okay. Fuck, fuck.
Allison, get this shit
outta my back.
-ALLISON: I don't know how.
-KING: Allison!
-What?
-Get this shit out!
-Take the shit out of his back!
-Okay!
I'm gonna do it on three.
One, two...
(SCREAMS)
-KING: Shit, shit, shit!
-Oh, shit!
What happened to you, Allison?
-(DOOR BANGS SHUT)
-(LOCK CLICKS)
Bad news. They...
He locked us in again.
-What?
-He locked us in again.
-What the fuck?
-Oh, God. King! King.
-Oh, my God, we lost him!
-Nigga, fuck.
Shit, I'm resting my eyes.
God damn! Keep talking.
Okay, great.
Guys, guys, we need a plan.
If the killer comes
back in here, we're next.
Girl, how the fuck
did this happen?
I was trying to help King.
Hey, babe, she's gonna need
something to wrap that.
Damn.
Painkillers.
Anybody got any painkillers?
-Shit.
-DEWAYNE: Listen, think.
-Are there any white people who wanna kill us?
-Potentially all of 'em.
I mean, a white guy said
he wanted to kill me yesterday.
-What? Who? -I don't know. He was
just some stranger on Twitter.
He was mad at me because I said
that the O'Reilly Auto Parts theme song
was more culturally relevant
than the "Star-Spangled Banner."
I mean, you're not wrong.
O, O, O, O'Reilly's
-ALL: Auto parts
-Ow! Ooh, that's a good song.
-THE GAME: Pick a card.
-We're not picking any more cards, bruh.
Are you sure?
The outcome of this situation
depends on your participation.
Wait. What are you doing?
-We gotta finish the game.
-No, we don't.
I would suggest
you pick a card.
DEWAYNE: You heard what he said.
Girl, pick a card.
"In your predicament,
the Black character
is always the first to die.
I will spare your lives
if you sacrifice the person
you deem the Blackest to me."
The Blackest?
"Choose someone to sacrifice.
You don't play my game, you all die.
-You have two minutes." -No, we're not
playing the fucking game. We're done.
You have two minutes to decide.
(TIMER TICKING)
It don't even make sense,
"the Blackest." That is so subjective.
Well, shit, Shanika.
She say "Nigga" the most.
-Nigga!
-See?
Well, someone has to get picked
or we all end up
like Morgan and Shawn.
Nobody should judge anybody
in here, bruh.
I know you ain't
trying to argue about
who should be
the Blackest here, Nnamdi.
-What? Why?
-Because you are a literal African, Nnamdi.
You are, like, still
in its original packaging Black.
I'm sorry, boo, but on paper,
you the Blackest.
First of all,
I'm from Oakland, all right,
and my daddy is
from South Africa.
So, Townbiz,
Raider Nation, Go A's,
Michael B. Jordan, Fruitvale
Station off top, bruh.
Mmm. That just
makes you Blacker.
ALLISON: Mmm-hmm.
But if anybody
is the Blackest here,
it's African diaspora,
Angela Rye head ass over here.
-Wow, Nnamdi, really?
-Yeah!
Okay. So, that's what we doing?
Because every single time
one of y'all make a joke,
it's always, "Oh, Allison, you white this.
Allison, you white that."
But now, when it is
the most convenient for you,
you wanna use my Blackness?
-Absolutely.
-Absolutely not, nigga.
Because guess what?
If we playing this game,
my daddy is white with "wha",
so it's surely not me.
-King?
-Yeah, King. -'Cause you the
one with the gun and you gangsta.
I'm a ex-gangsta, all right?
I changed my life.
And I'm married
to a white woman, so...
-That does not help.
-You right. I'mma shut up.
-Ninety seconds.
-Oh, my God, this is not working.
I'mma need so much therapy
if we get through this.
-What about Dewayne?
-Girl, shut your ass up.
Did you not hear what I said?
Therapy. Black people
don't do therapy.
Well, actually, Black people
are slowly but surely
adopting healthier
mental health lifestyles.
Hey, big fucking deal.
No, deadass, big fucking deal.
We've come a long way.
It's a beautiful thing.
-Yeah.
-We have.
But that's not the point.
The point is
y'all can't pick me. I'm gay.
-(ALL GROAN)
-You always using that shit.
No, no, and just like my
homophobic family member says,
"Gayness is just whiteness wrapped up
in a bunch of dicks," and today, I agree.
-"Bunch of dicks"?
-Seventy seconds left.
-Look, we gotta pick somebody.
-We can't.
You know what?
What about Clifton?
SHANIKA: Yeah, why we can't
pick his little weak-ass?
You over there
quiet in the corner,
but you did not get invited
to this event,
but yet you showed up.
That is some Black shit, nigga.
Blackity Black, bro.
Guys, I... I was invited
by Morgan.
-How?
-Sixty seconds.
Morgan sent me an e-vite.
Guys, I can prove
I'm not the Blackest.
-Prove it.
-(SWALLOWS)
-I've never seen Friday.
-What the fuck?
I thought Black Twitter
was a type of seasoning.
Um, I like Jimmy Fallon
without The Roots.
-That's wrong.
-Um...
Beyonc's Super Bowl
performance made me unsafe.
Same.
-I voted for Trump.
-(GASPING)
-What?
-Twice.
-(SCREAMING)
DEWAYNE: Stop. Stop. Stop.
Stop. Stop. Stop. Stop. Stop.
Get your hands... Stop!
We have a minute left.
Somebody trying to kill us.
And arguing is only
gonna make it easier.
We need a plan.
Our ancestors did not die
for us to abandon each other,
our morals and our Blackness
at the moment's notice
in the face of adversity.
Boy, I know you did not just
go into some complete dramatic-ass monologue
when you knew
we only had one minute left.
-Time is almost out.
-Girl, you talking just as long as me. Shit.
-Twenty seconds. -Look, y'all, we just
need to pick somebody, all right, and...
I'm sorry, Clifton,
for that dumb-ass shit
that you just said,
I pick you, bruh.
-No.
-I pick your MAGA ass, too.
-(GROANS) No.
-Allison?
I... I vote for Clifton.
-King?
-This nigga.
Bae.
I mean, I guess I don't
have a choice. I pick Clifton.
-Dewayne?
-Five seconds.
I'm so sorry, Clifton.
-I pick you.
-(TIMER DINGS)
-Your time is up.
-Wow.
You know, I really thought
we connected.
You know, if you guys
had any more sense,
you'd know that this is what
the game wanted us to do.
To turn on each other.
To act like animals.
You gave it what it wanted.
All right.
Nigga!
All lives matter.
(DOOR LOCK CLICKS)
(WHIMPERS)
-(DOOR SHUTS, LOCK CLICKS)
-Oh!
-That didn't feel right.
-I'll go get him.
It's locked again.
(LIVELY BANJO MUSIC PLAYING)
Do you like Hunger Games?
I love the books, but
you probably don't even read.
Uh, maybe we can
talk this out, you know. Um...
Dang it.
(ROD CLATTERS)
(ARROW WHOOSHING)
(DISTANT SCREAM)
Fuck.
(LAUGHS MENACINGLY)
Oh, my God.
Oh, no.
Well, I mean,
he did vote for Trump.
-Twice.
-LISA: Oh, my God, is it over?
THE GAME:
You did not follow the rules.
Clifton did not vote.
Space revoked. Pick a card.
Oh, my God, this game
is impossible to win.
Hell, no! I'm not playing
this fucking game anymore, man.
You have to save yourself...
yourself... yourself...
-So, you don't want to play?
-We refuse. No more fucking games.
That would mean
you automatically move into sudden death.
-Sudden death?
-What?
The rules are simple. Survive.
The door to the game room
is open.
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
You'll have
three minutes of safety
before I open the rest
of the doors in the house.
Now, are your chances better
outside or in?
You must choose
or face the consequences.
Ugh. I hate this bitch's voice!
-Three minutes. (LAUGHS)
-(STATIC)
-So, what do we do?
-What do you mean, what do we do, girl?
I'm not gonna stay
in this fucking mouse trap.
We gotta get the hell up
out of here.
Why? So he can
just attack us outside?
Look, Clifton was right,
this game has rules,
and whatever the hell they are,
they have stuck by them, okay?
So, if we really do have
three minutes, y'all, we should just run.
I agree. We got
more room to run outside.
We stay here,
we just sitting ducks.
I don't know about you,
but I have no interest
in getting hunt down
in the woods by that psycho!
Look, I'm with Allison. We need
to take our fucking chances.
Listen. We can cut across the woods
and make it to the other side of the road.
If we all make it,
then we'll all be safe.
What movies have you seen?
'Cause that's fucking stupid.
Bruh, I haven't watched
any movies.
I'm just trying to save my girl!
(ALL SHOUT AT ONCE)
Boo, I love you.
Why you yelling at me?
Listen, arguing
is not gon' help us.
Everybody, let's go at least
get some fucking weapons.
-ALLISON: All right.
-Are you kidding me?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Somebody gon' help me
the fuck up?
Shit, my bad, bruh.
SHANIKA: Y'all better
come in this kitchen and find something! Shit!
-Hey, find some weapons.
-DEWAYNE: Look for something sharp.
-Here.
-Oh, thanks.
Wait. Chili powder?
Girl, what I'm finna do, cook?
Sorry, girl,
we ran out of knives.
Really? A candlestick?
You think you in Clue?
Don't start with me. I could
fuck somebody up with this.
What are you gonna do?
Tenderize his ass?
At least it's metal, Colonel
Mustard. That looks plastic.
At least this has a little
weight to it. It has some girth.
Shanika, I need
some of them painkillers.
I got you now. Here you go.
-This is Adderall.
-What?
This is Adderall.
-Is this what you gave her?
-Yes.
I need something else.
Here, you can take this.
Vicodin.
-I'm going. -Whoa, what?
No, you supposed to be dead, bruh.
This ain't that movie. Look, man,
let's go before this Vicodin wear off.
Wait, are you crazy?
Look at yourself.
-I got shot once.
-Twice!
In the same spot. One hole.
It hurt like hell,
but I can run. My legs work.
You can come with us, but if you
start lagging, we ain't carrying your ass.
-Fine.
-It's real dark out there and I'm still high.
I can't go out there.
-Me, too, I'm staying.
-Lisa!
Baby, then I'm staying with you.
I understand
if you have to leave.
-Yeah, go.
-Baby, I wanna stay with you.
I wanna show you that I'm
committed. Look, we a "us" now.
This Larenz Tate
chasing the train ass nigga.
-Not now, Nnamdi.
-I'm boots for Nina ass, nigga.
Okay, we all know
what this means.
-Don't you dare, Allison.
-I'mma say it.
Don't say this dumb shit.
-We... (GAGS)
-Allison.
-Oh, my God.
We have to split up.
-Oh, my God!
-Why?
He's not gon' be
in two places at once.
Allison, I knew
you was gonna say that shit,
but I figured that was just
your white side talking.
This is not my white half
talking, Nnamdi.
This is me talking
as a whole-ass Black person
who just so happens
to be biracial.
My "Blackness"
should not be in question
just because
I am simply suggesting
that separating might
actually help us stay alive.
Allison, yes,
you do have a point.
But do you really think your
Black side did them air quotes?
That feels
exclusively Caucasian.
MAN: Twenty seconds left!
-I love you.
-I love you, too.
-Stay alive.
-Mmm-hmm.
Shanika, run them pills, girl.
They good.
I don't know how much time
we have,
but if the door does open,
this is the one
closest to the woods.
I didn't know that
a psycho killer in blackface
was gonna be
the person that was here
when I asked
who all was gonna be here.
This feels like
the end of Set it Off.
(CRYING) I hate this.
It feels so sad.
You are my sister.
My strength.
-And my pride.
(ALL CRYING)
It'll be all right.
(LOCK CLICKS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay, we good.
Bye, y'all.
Hey, yo. We should hide.
Wait.
No, I don't wanna go in the basement.
I don't wanna see Morgan like that.
Hey, baby, I'm with Dewayne.
I don't wanna see her like that, either.
LISA: I'm going to find Morgan.
DEWAYNE: Yo, when did we become
the kind of people
that walk into
dark-ass basements?
LISA: Nice of you to join me.
DEWAYNE: Is that a well?
What kind of house is this?
NNAMDI: Shit. I'm impressed.
Motherfucker's crazy.
-Wait, wait, wait.
-What? The road is that way.
No. The road is this way.
The lake is that way.
What?
What the fuck is you doing?
Okay, hold up,
I feel weird as shit!
Okay, I think I need to stop.
Guys, just go. I'm just gonna
sit here with my feelings.
Your feelings? What?
Allison, that Adderall got you
bugging the fuck out.
Come on, Allison.
We not finna leave you here.
No, just go.
Look, I need you
to breathe with me, all right?
Inhale, exhale.
There's a crazy motherfucker out here
hunting us like we animals.
This ain't the time
to be sitting down.
I need you to be strong.
You got Rosa Parks
on your shirt, right?
Would she be
sitting down right now?
I mean,
that's exactly what she did.
Man, nigga, shut up!
Look at me.
If you wanna be somebody
and if you wanna go somewhere,
then you better wake up and...
-Pay attention.
-That's right, bitch.
Now, come on
with your injured ass.
-(GROANS IN DISGUST)
-DEWAYNE: Oh, my God.
Please tell me
that's some of King's Kool-Ayyy.
We both know what that is, man.
-Okay.
-Go. Go. Shit.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
DEWAYNE: Okay,
but where's Morgan?
Let's see if we can figure out
how this fucker operates
before he gets back.
(DISTANT SPLASH)
(COMPUTER CHIRPS)
DEWAYNE: Oh, my God. There are
cameras all over this house.
He's been watching
our every move this entire time.
Y'all, look.
I thought we were
above the Mason-Dixon.
-(DOOR CLOSES UPSTAIRS)
-What was that?
Fucking 'course he'd go after
the darkest people first.
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
-We gotta go back upstairs.
-Really?
Okay.
Fuck! No.
We went the wrong way.
See? Allison, I told you.
Allison?
Allison! Fuck, where is she?
Her ass probably high.
I don't blame her.
I might do the same thing.
No, King, you gotta
stay with me, okay?
Look, I can see houses
in the distance.
Okay, I'mma swim across.
They won't suspect it.
They probably assume
we can't swim anyway.
They be assuming right,
'cause I can't.
Wow! Way to be
a fucking stereotype.
You go ahead and hop
your little privileged ass
in that dark, mysterious water.
I'mma climb up this tree.
You give me a signal
when you get across.
Is that something
you can even do?
I ran from cops, I dodged
bullets, I jumped gates.
This is easy, all right?
-Oh, shit.
-This is really embarrassing.
-Get up and help me, God damn it!
-Nigga, come on.
(GROANS) Don't put your finger
in my asshole.
-Wasn't this door open?
-It don't even matter, yo.
We gon' go straight through.
Ready?
Nigga, move, I'll go first.
Okay. Here we go.
Okay, I see why
you didn't wanna go first.
Oh, my God, are you guys
fucking line dancing?
Wait, hold on.
One, two, three.
(SCREAMING)
I heard screaming.
Is everything okay?
-Ranger White? Is that you?
-In the flesh.
Oh, shit. Is this good or bad?
Wait. How do we know
we can trust him?
-No offense.
-I'm one of the good ones.
That does not help.
They all say that.
That actually makes you seem
more suspicious.
You can trust me. Seriously.
If I got an invite
to the cookout,
-I'd be honored, but I wouldn't go.
-And why the fuck not?
Because I know my presence
in that all-Black space
would be a disturbance and undo
it being an all-Black space.
That's a pretty good answer.
-I'm sold.
-Mmm-hmm. Works for me.
-Look, we're gonna lower our hands.
-Lower away.
Okay, great. Look, I've never been
so happy to see a white savior.
-Somebody's trying to kill us. Please help us.
-Whoa. Slow down.
A masked killer is after us
and two of our friends are dead.
-What do you mean, dead?
-Meet your maker dead, dead.
-Where are the rest of your friends?
-We split up.
You split up?
But you all are Black.
Whoa. Do not get comfortable.
-I know you didn't.
-Bold move, bro.
-Sorry.
-Don't you need to call for help or something?
Okay, try to calm down.
I'll get some help.
This is White to base.
(STATIC)
White to base. This is White.
White.
(STATIC)
That's weird. Runs on a satellite system.
Should always work.
The signal is actively
being blocked.
That's why we couldn't call out.
You gotta believe us.
Come with me.
All right, get in quick.
-Okay.
I'll be right back. Lock the doors,
get down, and don't worry.
Dude, where are you...
Can we just go?
-Where are you going?
-Where is he going?
Why white people always gotta
go where they shouldn't go?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(ARROWS WHOOSH)
What?
Nigga, are you
shooting arrows at me?
No! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Stop it! Stop!
King! Stop!
("MADE YOU LOOK"
BY NAS PLAYING)
Let's see what you got
without that bitch-ass crossbow.
What's up? What's up?
Come on.
Fuck! I'm gonna beat
your ass now.
-(GRUNTS)
-Aw, hell, you can't even fight?
-What?
-What's good?
You a slave to a page
in my rhyme book
Gettin' big money, playboy
Your time's up...
Get your bitch ass up.
This one's for Morgan.
(MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY)
Oh! Cramp! Ah! Ah! Shit.
(CRIES OUT)
Don't hurt my...
Nigga, you can't fucking...
KING: Time out. Time out.
Oh, fuck!
(MAN GRUNTS)
SHANIKA: Hey! Stop it!
First off, you're gonna watch me
kill your friend.
-No, no, no...
-ALLISON: Hey!
Asshole.
-MAN: Well, come and have a go.
-("SEE ME" BY RORO PLAYING)
Rockstar, young Ro
'Bout to spit it like a pro
Bad bitch, new breed
Yeah, you heard about me...
All right, bitch.
Let's do this.
Wanna feel my high
but ya vibe too low...
(ALLISON GRUNTS)
-(MAN GROANS)
-Hell, yeah.
Step to me real light
Me no afraid fi bite
Yo fear for ya life
Do this shit for spite
Step to me real light
Me no afraid fi bite
Oh, like left hook,
right hook...
-(SCREAMING)
-(GROANS)
Beat his motherfucking ass!
Hell, yeah!
(GRUNTING)
Goddamn, beat your ass now.
Come with the thing, yeah
Come with the thing
Oh, shit.
Nigga.
You sure he's not gonna
come back to life?
-No, girl, he's dead.
-Hell yeah.
You beat that nigga ass.
(SHANIKA GASPS)
That's the one-eyed nigga
I saw at the store.
-Hell yeah, run his pockets.
-What the hell?
Wait a minute. He's got asthma.
That's why
he was breathing like that.
Camden Connor. 555 Valley Lane.
-That's our address.
-Hey, I feel a bit woozy here.
See, this why
I don't come to the woods
because of crazy white
motherfuckers like this.
And they always got
some dirty-ass shoes on.
Wait, the nigga that
was chasing us in the house
had a different
pair of boots on.
Remember?
I stabbed him in the foot.
So, unless this motherfucker
got costume changes...
That means that
there's more than one of them.
-We gotta warn the others.
-Okay.
-KING: Oh, fuck.
-BOTH: King!
NNAMDI: Okay, look, y'all,
we might actually
make it out of this, okay?
If he comes back. Why the fuck
is he looking for the killer?
Can we just go? Oh, my God.
Maybe to convince us
that the killer isn't him?
-NNAMDI: What the fuck?
-We gotta go.
(CAR LOCK SLIDING)
Stop. Stop. Stop.
Stop pressing the button.
Both of y'all,
stop fucking with the door!
-LISA: Shit.
-DEWAYNE: Ah, shit!
Unlock the door.
I don't think I stopped him.
He's coming. Unlock the door
and let me in. Quick!
I know how that looks,
but I found that mask
in the woods close to here.
It's why I came to check on you.
Let me help you.
You have to trust me.
-No, we don't.
-Let me in! Let me in!
(SCREAMING)
Come on, man. We're
sitting ducks out here, y'all.
Maybe we should have
trusted him.
He's gonna reload at some point.
Should we go back in there?
-We go back in there for what?
-What other choice do we have?
I don't know. I don't know.
I don't... Fuck!
Okay, now!
DEWAYNE: Go, go, go, go, go!
Come on, come on, come on.
Oh, shit. He's shooting!
Stay right there.
Oh.
Just go. Save yourself. Go.
-We can't...
-Let's go.
We can't.
I was joking. Shit!
We just left him. What if
he's just somewhere bleeding?
No, baby, he told us...
he told us to leave him.
He didn't mean it.
Okay, Lis, look, all of us ain't
gonna make it through the night.
We know that, right?
-I'm just saying.
-I'm gonna go get my friend.
(SHUSHING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
I can't stand the rain
Against my window
Bringing back sweet memories
Hey, windowpane...
-Who's playing music?
-Do you remember...
Wait. Shh.
How sweet...
(MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY)
You shady motherfuckers
left me to die!
And I just saved y'all asses.
But fuck me, though, right?
-You told us to leave you.
-Nigga, you know I didn't mean that shit.
-Told you.
-Told you, my ass.
-You didn't have to follow him.
-(CLATTERING)
Move! Let me get up there.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
How long do y'all think
we should wait in here?
I don't know.
Probably till morning?
The fucker
a vampire or something?
Why the fuck
is morning more better?
I don't know. 'Cause
it's bright out and less scary.
NNAMDI: That makes sense.
I'm sorry we left you,
but it's not every day
I'm faced with fucking
life-or-death decisions.
It's good to know
when it comes to me
the decision is death.
What is your problem?
You've been pressed
this entire trip.
You have something to say, say
it. No time like the present.
I disagree. There is a better time
than the present, and it is not right now.
Every time
this nigga broke your heart,
I was the one there to mend it.
I never asked you to do that.
You chose to do that.
-(SIGNAL BLOCKER BEEPS)
-(CELL PHONE CHIMES)
Fuck. What the fuck?
Oh, my God.
Keke Palmer retweeted my tweet.
(CHUCKLES MENACINGLY)
Okay.
(SHUSHING)
(GULPS)
-Keep that shit together.
-I'm trying.
Oh, shit.
(WHIMPERING)
Peekaboo.
(SCREAMS)
-(GRUNTS)
-(EXCLAIMS)
Ooh, shit!
I'm going to jail.
Oh, shit, are you okay?
He kicked the shit outta you.
(WHEEZING) How'd you know
how to do that?
That seems like
an exclusively white weapon.
That's another thing. Y'all
are always underestimating me.
Maybe that's why
you left me at the car.
This is exactly why I didn't tell
you me and Nnamdi were back together.
-I just didn't need this negativity.
-Oh, no, no, no.
You didn't tell me about Nnamdi
because you are ashamed.
Ashamed?
DEWAYNE: Be real. You have
always used my friendship
as some fucked-up replacement
as a rebound guy
whenever y'all broke up
because it was safe.
You knew I would be there.
I feel like I wasted my fucking time.
'Cause look at you now,
you got your man, your house,
and I'm pushed
to the curb, again.
You have never treated me
like a best friend.
You've treated me
like a gay side chick.
You leaving me and picking him
proves exactly that.
-(ARROW WHOOSHES)
-(GROANS)
-That was a good shot.
-That was the last one.
Oh, you're gonna
pay for that, bitch.
-Ooh.
-I got you, bitch. Hey!
You got
the right one today, bitch.
That's for Morgan and Shawn!
-This is for King.
-His ass. That's what you fucking get.
-LISA: Carlton.
-It's Clifton.
Why the fuck Black women
gotta save everyone
all the God damn time?
-Get him, girl.
-Fuck him up.
I'm tired! I'm tired!
I'm fucking tired.
See, that's why I married
a white woman.
-And suck my dick! -You're acting
just... I don't think you need to...
-He good.
-Girl, he dead. It's fine.
Lisa.
Earlier, did you
have something to say
about my choice in weapons?
Oh, no. No, no, no, no.
Nnamdi? Nnamdi?
No. No. Hell...
Absolutely not.
Look.
Maybe I was a little worked up
after I realized
what my part was
in what was wrong with us.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you
me and Nnamdi
were back together.
-I love you, okay?
-I love you too.
You got guts
all over your face, so...
(WHISPERS)
Look, I'm sorry for pressuring you to commit
before you were ready.
I was worried that if you kept
me waiting for so long
that I was gonna...
I'm gonna mess up.
I love you, all right?
(GIGGLES)
Dewayne, um,
I apologize to you too.
Yeah, I wasn't a good dude
in college. Sorry.
Are y'all for real? Y'all doing this right
now? Y'all ain't worked out y'all shit yet?
Didn't you see how long he was talking?
Why you interrupt my apology?
Nigga, there's another motherfucking killer
in the woods that we killed.
-That's what I'm trying to tell y'all.
-Okay, I did not know that.
SHANIKA: Yeah, so, now let's find out
who this motherfucker is.
Oh, I can't.
Dewayne, look in his pockets.
Mmm. Player, you got it.
This is on you.
-You two gonna figure it out!
-Okay, I'mma do it. Fuck!
Clive Connor.
This look like the other nigga
we saw in the woods.
DEWAYNE: Who the fuck are they?
We found this shit
on the other one. Read it.
Oh, shit.
They're twins.
We also found this on him.
-DEWAYNE: I don't get it.
-ALLISON: Someone must have been paying them.
KING:
Yeah, that seems about right.
They've got
all our initials on here, too.
So, somebody paid these evil
racist twins to kill us all.
-Is that it?
-And this is all we worth?
It's like $1,000.
This is offensive. Oh, my God.
-We need to get the fuck outta here.
-I'm still not going out there.
Okay, you know what?
Why don't we just stay here?
Because they've got to come back
for Ranger White at some point.
I still need to know what
happened to Morgan and Shawn.
Yeah, which means that
they might still be downstairs.
Right. He had a whole command
center down there, y'all.
Like TVs and everything. We can
use that to call for help.
Y'all are acting real white
right now.
I think we've already
proven ourselves.
If there's someone else
down there, we'll handle it.
Okay, you know what?
I'm gonna stay up here and just keep watch.
With my eyes. Oh, wait.
I'm sorry.
When you go down there,
take this.
-Just in case.
-Okay, thank you.
What the fuck is wrong with her?
-Nigga, it's the Adderall.
-I'm on Adderall?
No, baby, you're not on nothing.
-Okay.
-Shh.
(SCREAMING)
Stop yelling! Stop yelling!
Stop yelling!
I've been thinking, they keep
locking the doors on us.
While we got 'em unlocked, maybe we should
prop 'em open, so they don't keep locking 'em.
Right, right, right.
Great idea. Right.
I'm just gonna...
We just have to...
-I'm gonna need this one.
-Ouch.
Hey, Lisa, he's got a note.
It says,
"You're getting warmer."
Poor Clifton.
"Fatal accident claims life
of local nurse
Lateesha Paine, age 29."
-What?
-"Arrested on the scene,
Clifton Franklin James
was driving under the influence
of alcohol and struck Ms. Paine.
Mr. James is to be arraigned
on manslaughter "
(LIVELY BANJO MUSIC PLAYING)
What the hell
did he have to do with this?
(GASPS)
-What the fuck?
-(INHALES)
-(EXCLAIMING)
No, no, no, no, no.
I got this whole basement
riddled with plastic explosives.
Now, one of you guys move
and poof!
So, if you don't mind, I think
I'll give us some privacy.
Wait! No! No! Fuck.
King. Shit. King!
They locked 'em in.
So, drop your weapons.
Now!
And, big guy, do you mind
kicking that over to me?
The crossbow? Slowly.
I really appreciate it.
Okay.
This is heavy.
Wait, Clifton,
you did all of this, why?
I would love to answer
that question, truly.
But in order to do that, you're
gonna have to play my game.
-Hell no. -No? You don't wanna play?
You don't wanna play?
-Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
-Come on.
Question one.
Why am I doing this?
Now, listen, you should be
familiar with the rules by now.
It's been a long night.
Right answers only.
-But we don't know.
-(IMITATES BUZZER)
-Wrong answer.
-Shit!
So, hey, Dewayne,
the next one won't miss.
Gonna ask you
just one more time.
Question one!
Why am I doing this?
The article
about the girl you killed?
Ding, ding, ding, ding.
Good job, Lis.
Good job. Right.
Per the article, that happened
ten years ago tonight.
Question two, what else happened
ten years ago tonight?
It was... It was, uh...
It was...
The what? The what? Come on.
The party. It was the party.
It was the Juneteenth party.
Ding fucking ding.
-I remember you got really drunk.
-Okay.
Lisa and I kept trying
to give your ass shots,
but all you wanted to do
was fucking play Spades.
The pot was up to $1,000
that night
and everybody
was acting fucking crazy.
Yeah, motherfuckers
were fucking tripping.
You know,
I was just so excited
to be around people
that looked like me.
And I'll be the first to admit,
I was never
the best dancer, Dewayne,
or the funniest, Shanika,
or the best cheater, Nnamdi.
Relax. Or whatever you do, Lisa.
-I'm an attorney.
-Congrats.
But you know, one thing I love
more than all that is games.
Monopoly, chess,
checkers, Connect Four,
whatever you wanna play me in,
I'm a monster at, you know.
But the one game I could never,
ever really get a handle on
was Spades.
Because nobody
plays Spades in Vermont!
So, that night
I made one honest mistake.
I thought I was out of clubs.
Oh, shit, shit. I remember that.
You fucked around and you reneged.
And it could have happened
to anybody.
Not to niggas
who know how to play.
-It was an honest mistake!
-Whoa, whoa, whoa.
-What you doing?
-Yes!
-Motherfucker.
-Clifton? I thought he was dead.
I guess he's better at games
than we thought.
It was a simple mistake.
A mistake that
you all couldn't let go.
You turned it into some
ultimatum about how Black I was.
And you laughed at me, and you
attacked me about my Blackness.
And then you ruined my life.
Everyone gets shit over Spades.
It's not like someone revoked
your Black card.
No, Lisa, you're incorrect.
That's exactly what you said.
Your exact words. I remember.
You said, "Yeah, nigga,
your Black card's revoked."
That's what you said.
You know, that... that tracks.
You know, I was really honored
to be your friend, you know.
Until you said what you said.
And then I became
embarrassed, rejected.
And you know what I did?
I drank for the first time ever
that night,
and I drove away
to escape the ridicule.
And I didn't see this woman
in front of me
until her body hit my car.
If he controlling the locks,
who was controlling them
when he was with us?
I served four years in jail.
Four years for manslaughter?
That's like grad school, man.
You know,
I got a little jealous
of seeing
the lives you were living,
the amazing lives
you were living,
because my life got taken away.
Because I wasn't
Black enough for you.
I honestly thought
that those redneck twins
would have gotten the job done,
but they didn't.
I guess cheap labor
is cheap for a reason.
Anyway, I'm gonna
kill you guys now,
and I'm gonna dispose of
your bodies the same way I did
Morgan and Shawn's, in the well.
ALL: Nigga!
Nigga indeed.
-Got it.
-Yeah.
Oh, fuck.
Okay.
I don't know which one...
-I don't know which one.
-Try that one.
How about once and for all
we find out which one of you
is the Blackest?
I'm gonna call this round
Black Sophie's Choice.
And remember, you brought this
on yourselves.
You know, for a moment,
I actually thought
maybe you changed, maybe,
until you sent me out to die.
And why?
Because I wasn't Black enough?
It was mainly
just the Trump thing.
Shut up! Lisa, pick!
Who is the Blackest?
And remember, the one you choose
is gonna die.
We're not playing your game.
You just gonna kill us anyway.
-So just do it.
-NNAMDI: Fuck your game, bruh.
-I think we should keep playing.
-I'm with Shanika and Nnamdi.
You've been fucking with us
this entire night.
That's right, so your non-Black,
coon, MAGA ass
can kiss my Black ass.
Matter of fact...
-DEWAYNE: Do you trust me?
-LISA: With my life.
-DEWAYNE: Then play the game.
-SHANIKA: ...your little ass crossbow.
I should flick your little ass
across this goddamn basement.
-Okay, I'll play your game.
-Wait, what? Baby, what?
How the fuck you just gon'
change your mind like that?
-I'll play your game.
-Yes!
Finally, we have a competitor.
Now, go ahead, choose.
Which one's the Blackest?
-I choose myself.
-Wait, baby, what?
What? No, no, that's not
what I... what I said.
I said choose one of them,
one of them.
Choose one of them! Go! Now!
Those are the fucking rules,
Lisa! Pick!
-DWAYNE: Psst. Nnamdi.
-NNAMDI: You talking to me?
-DEWAYNE: Yes.
-NNAMDI: Yo, this is trippy.
I didn't think this mind
talking worked for the guys.
-But go ahead.
-I need you to hit him low.
NNAMDI: Wait a minute. What?
DEWAYNE: I said hit him low
and I'm gonna hit him high.
Choose one of them!
Choose one of 'em!
Choose one of 'em, Lisa!
NNAMDI: He's crazy.
Are you sure?
DEWAYNE: Yes, nigga. I'm sure.
LISA: You heard me,
I choose myself.
-NNAMDI: Okay.
-I refuse to play your game.
DEWAYNE: Wait,
did you hear all of that?
CLIFTON:
Yes, motherfucker, I did.
DEWAYNE: Oh...
CLIFTON: You done fucked up now!
(NNAMDI GULPS)
You guys just gave away
the only thing
you had going for you.
And that was
the element of surprise.
It's fine, Dewayne. It's okay.
Because luckily...
I still have mine.
No, no, no!
-Shit!
-Oh, my God!
No, no, let him bleed.
Let him go!
Let him go! Let him bleed.
-Fuck you.
-Okay?
Lisa, I don't think
you've fully grasped
the gravity of this situation.
So I'm going to repeat myself
one last time!
Which one of your friends
is the Blackest?
I... I... I...
-Um, shit.
-Shall we try two at a time?
What was that? Hey. Stay
right there. Stay right there!
Oh! No! Oh, my...
Okay. Time out, time out.
-What the fuck?
-Oh, my ear! Let go!
Shoot him!
-Shoot who?
-Him!
-Shoot him!
-Who's him?
-Shoot him, Shanika!
-Nigga, it's dark!
-The one on the left.
-The one on the right!
Who's on the right?
Who's on the left?
-To the left!
-CLIFTON: Your right.
-SHANIKA: My right?
-DEWAYNE: Your left!
Dewayne, I don't wanna
shoot you. Say something gay.
Bitch, that is offensive.
How fucking dare you?
Got it!
You're gay?
-Wait, wait, wait.
-What, what?
KING: I don't know.
I can't see anything.
(EXCLAIMS)
Yes, motherfucker! Yes.
(CLIFTON SCREAMING)
(DISTANT SPLASH)
-Okay, come on, we fucking did it.
-Let's get it!
(BOTH GROAN IN PAIN)
-Fuck, wait a minute! Damn!
-Fuck.
(DISTANT SPLASH)
Ain't that some
poetic fucking justice.
I guess he's not
doing too well.
-Dewayne.
-You see what I did there?
Somebody's dead, nigga.
-That's a good kick, bruh.
-Thanks.
Told you we'd handle it.
-There is an arrow. It's okay.
-I'm sorry.
(CLIFTON LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
We did it. We survived.
-So, what do we do now?
-Call the cops?
(ALL LAUGHING)
SHANIKA: Oh, shit!
Hey, but for real, though.
I don't know no better
I'm on this every day
You cannot run with me, boy
I'm a heavyweight...
We can always call
and act like white women.
-Mmm.
-(GIGGLING)
When they get here expecting
Hannah, Kailey and Kimberley
and see our Black asses
and it's bang, bang, then what?
You right.
Any other ideas
on how to get help
without getting shot
in the process?
I got it. I'm a genius.
(CHUCKLES)
Come with me, boy
I'm a heavyweight
Heavy, heavy, heavyweight...
So, why did we decide
to do this?
Oh, because firemen
won't shoot you. You see?
It's called beating the system.
I know I'm high as fuck,
but, nigga,
did you change your clothes?
Yes, I did! The news might come.
-We might be on TV.
-As a highlighter?
Oh, shit. SHANIKA: Dewayne, you was right.
Here they come now.
(ALL GROAN)
I don't be wit em'
He so basic
Boy, you the opp
and your bro's hatin'
All of them fake
I see both faces
Scared of the whip
It's a ghost racin'
I knock 'em down
till they cold cases
Marathon run
I'mma slow pace it
They did not want me
to go places
Foil plans
like the gold plates
Said if we pullin' up
with the whole squad
I already done told y'all
that you better be runnin'
I'm in my goyard
when I walk
And I know y'all niggas
tellin' me nothin'
Bitch, I'm the man
Mmm mmm mmm
Suck it if y'all in denial
I get the chip on 'em
And I bust out the southside
It's that pico de gallo
Who are you? Stop it, quiet
If it's new, I don' got it
See my jewels
shinin', shinin'
White diamonds, Miley Cyrus
Private jet, private pilot
Look at me, stylish, stylish
Masterpiece
Bout it, bout it, young
I don't know no better
I'm on this every day
You cannot run with me, boy
I'm a heavyweight
Baby, I know what's comin'
I can barely wait
And when it was on,
they wanted me gone
Boy, I'm here to stay
Come with me, boy
I'm a heavyweight
Heavy, heavy, heavyweight
I don't know no better
I'm on this every day
You cannot run with me, boy
I'm a heavyweight
Heavy, heavy, heavyweight
Walked in with the whole team
and we ridin' on it
Couple of bands
up in my pocket
I don't want parts
of your wild nonsense
We got momentum
Don't try to stop it
Diamonds are clearer
than my conscience
I don't let
bygones be bygones
It's fuck you
That's when I'm honest
Penthouse built to reach
heaven's heights
Now that's what you call
a God complex
Remember the days
I was down low
When a nigga was out col'
But I went out and got it
Look at my milestones
Man, it feel like the Dow Jones
When you look in my pocket
Look at the flex shit
Whippin' the Teslas
Bitch, I'm a mess
It's all a finesse
Who are you? Stop it, quiet
If it's new, I don' got it
See my jewels
shinin', shinin'
White diamonds, Miley Cyrus
Private jet, private pilot
Look at me, stylish, stylish
Masterpiece
Bout it, bout it, young
I don't know no better
I'm on this every day
You cannot run with me, boy
I'm a heavyweight
Baby, I know what's comin'
I can barely wait
And when it was on,
they wanted me gone
Boy, I'm here to stay
Boy, I'm a heavyweight
Heavy, heavy, heavyweight
Better I'm on this every day
Boy, I'm a heavyweight
Heavy, heavy, heavyweight
Subtitles (English CC): Plint