Look, dinner!
Don't drop it again!
Just watch, if you drop it, I'll drop you too.
Quick.
It's right ahead.
Right there, behind the door.
Why'd you put it-
I told you to be careful, that's expensive.
Why can't you get it?
It's so simple!
And you! You too, you're so clumsy
Sorry, ma'am.
Why do you keep dropping it?
It slipped.
Just go upstairs first.
You'll tire yourse-
I'm not tired, I'm asthmatic.
Why can't you-
It's fine, just go ahead. I'll just-
That's right, go first.
Ok Ok, just go.
Alright, there's more downstairs.
Here, let me help.
Wait, let me prop it up.
Where?
Ah, here. Here's fine.
You live here too?
Nico.
Sorry, my hands are dirty.
Jewel.
Kuya, let's put that there.
Ok, I'll go now.
Do I still need to prove myself?
Motherfucker.
Janine.
What else do you want me to do?
Hello?
Janine?
Fuck!
Are you okay?
You? Are you okay?
Yeah.
You don't eat the baby chick?
Nope.
Lemme have it.
What's it taste like?
Hm?
Chicken.
That's...
a bit slimy.
You know, frogs,
also taste like chicken.
Why is that,
everything tastes like chicken?
I bet you that people
also taste like chicken.
Really?
Well, you said...
that we taste like chicken.
I meant maybe. I've obviously never tried it.
I thought you might've.
Wanna try?
One shot?
Let's dance!
No, I'm okay.
Babe. Babe.
What are we doing?
Where?
Let's go out again.
Okay.
Oh, we're here.
Yeah.
What about Jewel?
I'll drive her. It's on the way anyways.
Is that so?
Then, I'll tag along.
It's still early, and I don't have work tommorow.
And I'll have to come back here?
Um. Ok. Just... text me when you get home?
Bye babe.
Night.
You're staying there?
Maybe you want to sit here?
I look like your Uber.
How long have you two been friends?
Are you two close?
Not really.
Amy's like that isn't she?
You know...
She never lets me meet her friends.
especially the pretty ones.
She probably thinks that I'm going to cheat on her.
What's wrong?
It's just a joke.
Relax.
Smile.
Get out.
Are you okay?
Ate, a bowl of beef mami.
Thanks.
You don't want anything?
I don't know what to order.
Try this. Try the beef mami.
Okay.
Ate, One beef mami please.
How long ago did you breakup?
A month ago.
One month?
That's hard.
Super hard.
Even more when you're dumped.
It hurts, no?
Like your heart is going to explode.
So you should just cry and cry because
you don't know what else to do.
Happened to you too?
What did?
Got dumped.
Ah, nope. I just saw it on TV.
Why?
Nothing.
It's cuz I've never had a boyfriend.
Really?
Mhmm.
You're probably picky.
Or maybe... your standards are too high.
I think,
that,
I don't have a boyfriend because no one loves me.
Because I'm a bad person.
Huh?
I don't think so?
I am a bad person.
You just don't know it.
Really? Okay.
What's the worst thing you've done?
Too many to count.
Tell me.
You stole things?
Nope.
Oh wait, I know.
Talked back to your parents.
Wrong again.
Then what?
I've killed people.
Joke! Look at you. It's just a joke.
You almost had me.
There we go.
Have you met my turtle?
What's their name?
Edward.
Edward?
Why Edward?
No reason.
I just liked the name Edward.
Why did you choose Dumbledore?
Janine chose the name.
You know, Edward
he's like my best friend.
You two always hang out?
I talk to him when I'm sad.
We're similar then.
2 bodies were found yesterday at 4am on the intersection of New York and Annapolis street.
A sign saying "I'm a drug pusher, don't follow me" was found on one of the bodies.
The victims were indentified by their relatives, Miko Dominguez and Dominic Baez.
I know it deep down, Christine. You're the one I love.
I love you too, Gabriel.
But we can't be together.
Why not?
You don't know who I am.
There's a lot that you don't know about me.
I don't care.
You know that I'll accept you,
regardless of what you've done.
I love you.
That's all that matters.
We can't just rely on our love!
What are you saying?
I'm a bad person Gabriel.
Let's eat?
You first.
Then tell me who's the better cook.
Me or the lady at the stall.
Yes, ma'am.
Yours.
This tastes better.
I told you.
You'll never be able to go back.
Because my mami is the best.
You know, if you're wondering why,
my grandson's face is so unique-
Lola,
Don't-
No one said that.
Well maybe she's thinking it.
Should I just wait for her to ask?
No need to ask.
I'll just tell you why his face is so different.
It's because his grandfather is German.
-Here we go again.
His grandfather?
German.
He was German?
Are you doubting me?
No, it's not like that.
- Are you saying that that German didn't find me pretty?
Ah, no-
-You don't think that a German person would chase after me?
It's not like that-
I didn't look like a Goodwill yet.
I believe you.
You know, I remember it like yesterday
Henry Otto.
He told me:
I said, what?
What does it mean?
What? What was it again?
He said that. Heinrich told me that.
What's that?
It means "Trinidad, you're very beautiful."
Amazing.
She believes me.
It's convincing isn't it?
Obviously.
Hopefully one day you can say that to Jewel.
Because, of course,
she's much prettier than Janine.
Try it.
Try telling her that
Just try it once.
Okay practice.
Jewel
What do you mean Malisongsong?
Now it sounds like Chinese.
What's that? Malisongsong?
No! What the heck?
Oh my.
Let's just eat the noodles before they get cold.
But it tastes good right? Yes ma'am.
You two should slurp.
Educated people slurp noodles.
Let me turn the TV on.
A man by the name of Marcos Dehada
was found dead today, at 6am, in Quezon City.
He was torn to pieces and his heart was missing
and he held a sign saying "I'm a drug lord."
The last time anyone saw the victim, he was insi-
Should we turn it off?
Leave it.
Leave it. We have to get used to it.
Let them kill each other.
Jewel, want more soup?
Yes, please.
The mother, Gina, is adamant that her son had nothing to do with the drug trade
and that this slander against her son was painful.
As for her family, they won't stop until they find justice, and they won't stop unti-
It's pretty isn't it?
It looks nice.
You know, my nails are so important to me.
I never forget to take care of them, even if it's hard
Even if I go hungry, I'll buy nail polish.
Like those aristocrats since their nails are always so nice.
They never forget their nails.
There. That's why,
you should take care of your nails too.
The shape of your nails are very pretty.
Yeah. Keep it that way huh?
Forever like that.
Poor Jewel, you're rambling about your Cutex again.
I was just complimenting her nails
Take this. It suits you, red.
I have a lot of these.
You're roping Jewel into your Cutex obsession.
Why? Are you trying to keep me to yourself?
Oh, look Jewel-
I'll try this.
It's pretty see
Ah, stop it.
You should slow down.
Let me enjoy life.
People need to enjoy life.
I can handle it.
Here take this.
Take it, I'm going to dance.
Go. go. go
Careful, careful.
The monsters always look younger no?
Because they're wearing makeup, ha!
Lola!
This costume is perfect for you.
It is, isn't it?
I went to France and bought this in '71 before Martial Law was declared!
Slow down.
Just watch, later-
No!
As long as I want to dance I'll-
C'mere, let's go there! I'll leave this to you.
Who're you? Tarzan?
Nope. Wait. Lemme vape.
Are you okay?
Kapre
A Filipino monster known for sitting in trees and smoking a cigar.
You're...
It's obvious.
Manananggal.
You know,
You're the prettiest manananggal I've ever met.
Jewel.
Can I borrow a light?
Thanks.
Good party?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Don't imitate me, I'm a drug pusher.
Jewel?
Jewel.
Nico.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Why?
You never came back to
the Halloween party.
Sorry.
I got a stomachache.
Are you ok?
Do you need...
medicine?
No.
I'm okay, thanks.
See you. I'm going to sleep.
Another corpse was discovered in a back alley.
The victim was one Jaime Perez.
This murder follows a similar pattern to others this month.
His insides were ripped apart, and his heart was missing.
The victim was probably related to the drug war.
A sign saying, "Don't imitate me, I'm a drug pusher" was found on his body.
Jewel.
Did you know the man who was murdered recently?
Jaime Perez.
Jaime?
You don't know them?
No.
I thought that,
I saw you get in his car.
I don't think that was me.
I think it was.
It's just your imagination.
Jewel's been waiting for you.
Nico.
I wanted to show you
this bridge I bought for Dumbledore and Edward.
That, and this turtle,
This,
No fishing.
Can you leave for a bit?
I need to talk to Grandma
I already paid the electricity bill. It's fine.
I was just thinking-
C'mon. Go.
Okay.
W-w-w-
Jewel! Wait!
Hey, tell her sorry!
Dinnertime.
Lola
Let's eat.
Wake up!
Help!
Lola Lola
Nico.
You're late. Again.
Sorry, boss.
I have to take care of my grandmother.
Don't make excuses.
Fine. Just hurry up.
Boss.
Maybe,
I can get an advance?
I don't have enough money for my grandmother's
surgery, sir.
You want an advance?
When you don't have any clients?
I'll get them back.
Even if you don't pay me for a month.
I just really need the money.
Sorry. I can't help you.
Why are you here?
I heard what happened to Lola.
What's this?
Do you know,
red is actually her favorite color?
Will she ever wake up again?
Of course.
She's like you in a lot of ways.
Do you think that if we play music,
she'll hear it?
Let's dance?
How do we start again?
Like this.
Feet spread like that.
Jewel.
You had nothing to do with,
those murders, right?
Jewel.
Thank you.
Jewel!
Look, there!
Where? Where is it? We'll take care of it.
Out of the way.
Subbed by Siantlark