Your eclairs, Mr. Ferrand.
-How many times do I have to tell you:
I'm not Mr. Ferrand!
-Why ? -because Mr. Ferrand is dead.
He no longer eats cakes. -OK, Mr. Ferrand.
Good-bye, Mr. Ferrand.
-So you told me that you are newcomer?
Yes, I just got appointed as a college supervisor.
I'm not from here, I'm from Brest,
on the other side of France.
- I am not from here either.
-Oh no ?
-I was born here. -Right here ?
-Yes, down here on the other side of the earth, Australia.
Little compatriots. -Hello my dear.
Do not bother. Blanche is up there?
-She is out. She had urgent errands.
-But she knew I was coming!
-Oh, women!
The temptation of stores!
It's really not nice.
Tell her I'll call at dinner time.
Do not forget.
-I'll do it for sure.
-Goodbye.
-Bye.
So, do you want them?
- I'm hesitant.
-I understand.
I hate birds, they are messy and noisy.
-Noisy ? -It's true,
I have no musical culture.
It's a whim of my niece.
Before, we only sold vegetable seeds here.
I'll take the little one.
She looks more lively.
-I'm afraid that is not possible. Wait.
Blanche !
Blanche, would you come down?
- One moment, I'm coming!
-What do you want sir?
What do you want sir?
-I would have wanted. Which means..
I would have liked...
I would like...
- Sir would like to take one of the birds.
-These? Ah! I'm sorry sir, but it's impossible.
It is a species that can only live in pairs.
If we separate them, they die.
-Well, then, I'll take both.
-Very well.
They are very cautious, give them lots of sun.
I am always a little sad when I part with my birds.
-I am sorry.
It's 100 Francs.
-Oh sorry.
Thank you.
Excuse me madam. -Yes.
Sir ! Your birds.
So it's over with the deputy mayor?
What exactly happened?
-He doesn't like the phone.
-As soon as the phone rings here, it turns white.
It turns out that it's his wife.
-Put yourself in his shoes.
- This is all ridiculous. I'm tired of this little town
..of this petty life, this furniture, this store ...
-And the consul? The store is our facade,
don't forget that.
-Ah ! Facade, facade !
- We must keep up appearances.
If you sell the store, you lose the consul.
After 2 years of patience,
it would be too stupid to spoil everything on a whim.
-I can't take it anymore, I'm suffocating here.
I understand, of course. But think about what it means.
... The wealth! Definitive security!
Where are you going?
You're leaving?
-Yes, I'm going to get some fresh air.
- Get up, Snowy! Stand up !
- Can't you see it's over?
-He's finished !
-René Ribeau,
..winner by KO.
-So my little guy?
-He's well sounded. -I told you so.
Your Snowy is not serious. He trains in daisies.
- I send him my condolences. Save my place, Martin.
-Dupuy, defend our colors! -Do not worry.
-Well, aim at the corner of the stairs.
-It's not for us.
-Mlle, in the 3rd row there is a place,
if that's what you're looking for.
-Thank you.
-I was sure of it.
I saw him box when they saw those from Breteuil.
-Is the place vacant?
-No...
But you can still sit down.
-Great fight, in 6 times.
..of 3 min, between Joseph Redeuil
of the Laval Boxing Club, 65 kg,
..and Etienne Dupuy from
the Clairval ring, 66 kg 200.
Joseph Redeuil!
-Etienne Dupuy.
-Did you lose something?
-A four leaf clover.
-What ?
-The 4 leaf clover in silver.
Here it is !
It's pretty, but it's a shame it's in silver.
-Why ?
-Because they say that money does not buy happiness.
-The pin doesn't want to hold.
What is happiness ?
As long as you stay here, I could answer you.
-The Dupuy guy is in good shape.
-Yes, but Redeuil is mean.
-Bad ! But the other one is boxing
Do you like boxing, Miss?
-I do not know yet.
-Is this the first time you've come?
-Yes.
- Did you see the footwork?
-Go on!
-Go on Dupuy!
-Come on Dupuy boy!
Did you see how beautiful that is?
Look what your Redeuil takes!
Go on !
-Have you seen what your Redeuil needs to correct?
-It's not over.
-Yes.
What do you think ?
I'm not saying anything.
- Come on Dupuy, what are you waiting for?
You go!
Well done. Go on !
Get up! Get up!
-Six, seven, eight ...
-It's disgusting, it's butchery!
-From the butcher's shop!
If you don't like it, go to Marie's children.
It's true ! He's never been to boxing.
- Can I take my place again?
-If you want.
-Martin! I looked for you everywhere. Where have you been?
I don't see you anymore.
What have I done to you?
-it's only a month.  I'm going..
-What's got Martin?
-I dunno. You ask me that. I do not know anything !
-Hey! Good evening Roumagnac.
-Good evening M. Ribot.
-I'm not the only one late.
I must see you tomorrow for this contract award.
-Yes. - Meet at the cafe, 11 a.m.
-Okay. Good evening, M. Ribot.
-Good evening Mr. Ladjouan.
-So, the bird flew away? -Yes, she left a feather.
-Oh, a four-leaf clover!
-Oh Paulot! Oh!
Do you need me anymore?
-No.
-I'm going to Clairval to see Ribot for the hospice.
-Okay.
Say, it's nice! - Come on, I'm happy
When I built my first house, I was not proud.
-A rabbit hut. -Yes.
-It seemed like the town hall. -Oh there !
-You've made progress.
-Yes, thanks to you.
Without you, I would still be an associate
I'll give you the money.
-There is nothing urgent. We'll settle this as usual.
Whether my money is with you or in the bank,
it's the same. Bye.
-Goodbye see you soon.
-Goodbye, old man.
-Hey ! -Eh ?
-I'm doing something that you like.
-Yes? - Tripe.
- Have you put my shoes away?
I get off at Clairval.
I have an appointment with the deputy mayor.
I put them out to dry last night, they were muddy.
Well then!
-What time do you come home for lunch ?
Is it convenient to cook for you ?
-Do not worry about the tripe, it's better reheated.
What did I do with my shoes?
-Look under the buffet. -
Ah!
Oh ! Bravo for the polish!
You're not just my sister...
... you're a real priestess.
-In any case, you're my purgatory on earth.
You go to Clairval, take mustard.
-Okay.
- In short, the kid presents himself well.
The plans are satisfactory.
Satisfied Bonnemain ?
Give it to me.
Your quotes are reasonable.
-I can do it for less, but there is much work and materials.
I do not agree with your architect.
-Why?
-Look at your windows.
Real skylights!
It's not because old people see nothing,
..that we must not give them light!
Here, the 4 leaf clover!
Excuse me.
Miss !
You went to the village hall.
-Yes, last night ...
-I had the pleasure of finding your four-leaf clover.
-Oh thank you. I was very keen on it.
What a pleasure, that gives me!
- It would make me happy if you have a drink with us.
-Gladly.
-allow me?
Mr. Ribot, Miss ...
-Mr. Ribot could introduce us.
-You know each other ?
-You don't know each other?
-Yes and no. -Martin Roumagnac,
..building contractor, Mme Blanche Ferrand.
- What are you having? It seems they have a good port,
..i prefer the Pernod.
-A Pernod.
Oh, Bonnemain!
Another Pernod here!
-We met yesterday at the boxing.
- Oh! do you like boxing?
-No.
The evenings are so long in the provinces.
Loneliness!
-Yes, I understand.
Here is my wife.
-A little port, Mrs.?
-I never drink.
We're going to be late for the DA.
The meeting is at noon.
- I know what I'm talking about. Hurry up!
Goodbye M. Roumagnac.
-Goodbye ma'am.
-Excuse us.
-If you like the company of happy widows,
... at least have the modesty not to go to the cafe.
-The deputy hasn't finished his drink.
He must still have liver trouble.
Are you going to build this hospice?
-Yes.
We'll save you a bed for when you go bankrupt.
What a joker!
-Well, I am beautiful!
- Forcibly by bike.
Do you live far away?
-At the other end of town.
I run a bird store with my uncle.
- I didn't see you running a business.
Are you a foreigner?
-No, I was born in Australia. -It is far.
Have you been here since?
-Three years.
-Three years !
It took 3 years for me to meet you.
3 years and a 4 leaf clover.
.. When I leave the site,
... it's not for going to bird shops.
-Don't you like birds?
-Ah yes, but ...
In the trees like fruit.
I like natural things.
-That's true.
-I'm not complicated.
I think life is good, don't you?
-Yes, but ...
I find people sad.
-Oh, the point is that sometimes!
Often they don't know what do with their 10 fingers.
I have my hands. With my bricks,
..I'm happy as a kid. You know, a stone is beautiful,
..a beautiful stone.
-Yes I understand you.
-We say it's cold, hard,
but it's soft, it's hot.
-And it gets better with age.
-To say that,
..you have a house in the countryside.
-No.
-You should.
- I do not intend to settle in this country.
-You want to go ?
There is nothing more beautiful than here.
There are amazing places around here.
-Yes I know.
- I have to go home, they are expecting me for lunch.
-Already ? Can I accompany you a bit?
-Yes.
-Hey, I'm leaving the money here.
I would be happy to build you a pretty villa with a beautiful view.
-From our house in Australia, we could see the hills.
There was a pond surrounded by trees, it was pretty.
-In France too, we have ponds. I know a beautiful area.
If you saw it ...
-Really?
-Yes, it's nearby. 15 minutes by car.
Shall we go after lunch?
-I have a store.
-It is a landscape to worship.  Let's go ?
- Can't it wait another day? The landscape will not fly away.
-Well, shall I pick you up Sunday, 2pm at your place?
-I can't resist you... So, see you on Sunday.
-Then goodbye and thank you again for the clover.
- Be careful. Don't forget Sunday!
-No.
-What are you looking for ?
-A clover. It only has 3 leaves.
-We do what we can.
So this villa? Indulge.
-I have no sense of ownership.
-It comes by possessing, like appetite by eating.
-It's hot. -Terrible.
Take off my jacket.
- If we sit in the shade there? -
Yes.
-You who don't like caged birds,
-a house is also some kind of cage?
-No, a cage is when you don't have the key, like a prison,
..a barracks, a school.
The funny thing is, I don't have a house. I do not have the time..
.. to build one for me. By building it for others,
I imagine that they are mine.
-Look.
Looks like a nest up there.
Yes, it is indeed a nest.
There, look, on the last branch.
-Oh yes. Oh, it's been a long time since there's been a tenant.
This is a titpecker's nest.
-We breathe badly, even in the shade.
-It's the storm.
-Yes, it's coming fast.
-Yes and it comes up quickly.
-It would be wise to go.
- You are right, it would be wiser.
-Let's go quickly to the car.
-It is better to take shelter in the barn.
Let's hurry.
- You made me run. I am not used to it.
You are trained.
Provided that this storm does not last too long.
At what time will that bring us home?
No, because ... There already, it must be at least ...
-It did not rain.
-No, it's moved away.
Jean ! -
Yes.
-When you're done, you'll go there.
-Good.
- Guys, get up to speed. We may sink soon.
-Hello.
-Oh !
-Wow ! How did you get here?
-By the bus. Am I bothering you ?
-Not at all, but I'm not presentable.
-It's a huge job.
I don't do all the work.
I am a subcontractor.
Since you're here, I'll show you the plans for your villa?
You really want to build me one?
-Come and see.
- She's the bird seller. The client for the villa.
Oh yes ? Martin is not thinking of anything else.
However, this villa is not Chartres Cathedral!
Thank you.
-I'm going back to work now.
-Not yet, stay a little.
I hardly see you anymore.
I'll end up being jealous of the villa.
-Why ?
-I waited for you again last night.
-Do not blame me.
I work late. Look, your house is progressing. Tomorrow
..I demolished the loft.
-Why ?
-It doesn't match the villa.
-Oh ! That's a shame !
-There's more space inside.
-Let me see.
Oh, there is a bed. Someone is sleeping there,
probably a vagabond.
Hey! Be polite, darling! That vagabond is me.
-You ?
-Yes because...
In the evening when all the guys are gone I like to stay and
..work myself at the villa. When it's too late
..I'm sleeping there.
So ? Are you going to see your house?
After your snack, go to the port to meet Paulot.
-OK Boss.
-Here, you see, the living room with two bathrooms on each side.
Here, the large staircase which leads to the 3 rooms.
You know, overlooking the pond ...
Towards the sun.
Here you can dine, eat, cook in the back
-It's big. It's marvelous.
-Eh ? My things will wait. I never take ..
..holiday. Eh ?
It makes me happy to be with you for a few days.
Yes I heard. Eh?
Yes, tonight as usual. Goodbye.
Jeanne !
What is it?
- I need the suitcase.
The crocodile skin.
-No need to scream like that.
- I don't know where it is.
-In the barn.
-You can't say it right away, right?
Where is it?
-There. What do you want it for?
-I'm going to Paris tomorrow. -What is this story ?
-I have to buy supplies for the villa,
.. wall lights, odds and ends.
-Missing more than that.
-What do you mean?
- I don't understand you.
- I don't like hints very much.
You're completely insane.
- How?
Mister buys the land, Mister offers a villa!
And now Mister is going to Paris.
- You think you're a millionaire!
- Ah, that's it!
-You don't see her spinning the money.
Nothing is too good for her.
- I know what I'm doing.
- Yes, and your wallet will be empty.
- Do you earn the money?
It the one who earns that has the right to spend.
- So, with clean clothes
- You only think about money!
-All for a bit of ...
-of what?
-imbecile!
-All the same when it comes to another woman!
They are all the same.
Your problem, you'll have to see it again.
- Yes, sir. - Goodbye.
-Do you have a light ?
-Attention, please.
-Oh dear ! It's full to bursting.
- If we leave?
-Hey Martin! -Look !
- Hi Martin. How are you ?
- Are you okay?
I need to see you for the hospital radiators.
It's not urgent. Talk to the architect.
- So we're leaving? - Hey!
She looks ridiculous in those eccentric outfits.
Maybe you don't agree?
- Completely ridiculous.
-Roumagnac refuses nothing.
He has offered the merry widow the masonry now.
This is called buying a villa in installments.
-That's great. The whole town is going to know about it.
-And after ?
-How after?
Well, the consul! His wife is going to make up her mind to die.
I hope so. Then at that moment ...
- Come in young man. Sorry.
Hello Martin!
-So, we won't see you anymore.
-Bah, the job.
-Hey ! Hey ! You wear out your health.
-How it goes!
I thought you never drank.
I do not drink. I like good music.
-And this hospice?
When is the ribbon cut on the mound?
I talked to Leper about heating.
I'm sorry, but the award was made ...
.. to the combined sites.
-I was counting on it.
I turned down another job. I supported you.
But you're busy, this house you're building for ...
Mrs. Ferrand. It is said to be very beautiful.
Yes, I hope.
When the consul finds out about it.
Or tell me you're more interested in the consul!
-Don't say that, you're exaggerating.
You are here out of interest and
Roumagnac will build me a villa.
It's normal that we see each other.
- Foreigners have no taste!
-They are not like us.
You're a popular man.
- Friends, sorry.
Did you order?
-No.
-Émile -Mr Roumagnac right away.
-Good, come back.
-They make a curious couple.
It won't take long to wear the horns.
-Like all the fools who have worshiped her.
-This is the package you asked for. I hope it'll be OK.
-I thank you. Bonnemain who grows fat from the sweat of the people.
- Are you going for a walk in Paris?
-We are shopping for the villa tomorrow.
-For stores, there is only Paris.
-Let's talk about stores in Paris.
We can look for new things for the provinces!
What are you looking at ?
-Nothing. Paris.
Oh! Then it's stone!
- Do you see there? It is Montparnasse.
-Yes.
Do you know that area well?
We should hurry ..
..if you want to go to the Casino de Paris.
Oh, 8 pm already! We won't have time for dinner.
What are you thinking about ?
Ah nothing. Everything that can happen to people in a hotel.
- People in a hurry who have lots of things to do.
- Or nothing more to do.
Nothing to look forward to.
The poor who have nothing to do with them,
only old newspapers ...
..and cigarette ends.
-And after ? It means nothing.
-You don't know what Paris is. -No, Paris ...
And you, you don't know the province. The province is patience.
Patience, you understand.
Because here, we pass. All these walls, that has nothing to say.
It's not a matter of time.
-In any case, we agree: we found what we wanted ..
..for the villa. Look at this.
-What do you say ?
-Nothing, I wanted to...
-What did you want ?
- The Casino de Paris is over, it's too late. We're going to have supper.
..in a funny little thing. Eh ? If you look at me like that
..we may also miss supper.
You look like a princess.
You don't think I look funny. I borrowed it from ..
Bonnemain, my friend. - No, you're fine.
-Me, I do not find myself ... -You look very good
-It's nice here?
-It is because you look beautiful.
- Sorry Mr. Excuse.
-You're bored. We shouldn't have come.
-But no ! Do you think !
All the people here get bored during the day
and try hard to have fun at night.
It's very warm!
-Madam, do you have a musical desire?
- Play "I have two big oxen in my barn",
that will be great.
-You absolutely want your music to flow in ..
..my coffee ? Do you find that it is not sweet enough?
I'm making you live. I'm like to hear nice music.
That's what we came for, right?
I beg your pardon, I am spoiling your evening.
I'm a brute.
-Let's see.
-You want to dance?
You know I don't know how to dance. Dancing in the style ...
..from Clairval. -My God, you are freaking out.
- Sir, madame dancing?
-It's me. -Also, I said to myself ...
Did you sell your house? You did not have ...
too many problems?
- Not at all.
I got married.
- No! With whom?  This man?
-Oh no. With another who has since died.
-Oh yes. So?
-So, I'm a widow.
-Miss. Do you have Blue Gauls, please?
-I do not have any. Chesterfield, Players, Rio tobacco ...
-I don't smoke that stuff. Aren't you hot here?
-I am used to it.
Tell the Delage driver that his boss called.
At least here we can breathe, it's not like inside.
You have the best job.  Are you making a good living?
Oh yes ! But this is not a job. I used to be a watchmaker.
-Ah!
-I had to stop. The eyes.
I made a small watch the size of a cherry seed.
Seriously ? The things I do are not so small.
I am a bricklayer, I build houses.
But in house building
You also have to use your hands to make watches.
That's how it works!
Wouldn't you have a blue Gallic?
Inside, they only have foreigners.
-With pleasure.
-Ah thank you.
-My dream would be to have a home.
In the countryside, with a garden and a small craftsman's workshop.
-You're right, you are so right.
I went out to breathe. You're having fun ?
-Not at all. - Are we going elsewhere?
-No. Let's go back to the hotel.
-I'm going to get the bill. Oh, tell me!
Here is the wall lamp for the villa. I'll ask where ..
..they bought it. She's fine.
-They are beautiful.
-Are they looking well?
-The house, the furniture, the view,
..everything is wonderful!
-It's thanks to you. You were a bit of an architect.
Now I want to tell you something.
Here, I find you in Paris when I thought I had lost you.
You were elsewhere.
-I can never thank you enough.
-Why ?
To do something I love ...
..for someone I love.
I should thank you.
-Do you believe in four-leaf clovers?
-No, but this one, yes.
-Me too.
It has given us real luck. Take it.
No, you appreciate it very much.
-That's why I'm giving it to you.
-You or I who have it, it's the same.
-Exactly ! As it works for both of us.
-You could knock.
-I did knock.
Mrs. Your uncle gave me this..
He needs you after lunch.
-Thank you Annette.
Catalog of seeds, bird magazine.
An obituary.
Is it a family member?
-No. The wife of a diplomat, a consul.
An old friend of my parents.
Oh ! It is touching.
-Oh that ! I bet it's your college sweetheart.
-He is not a student, he is a supervisor.
-He must ruin himself in stamps. When he doesn't write to you,
..he wanders around the store dreaming of you. How funny.
-That's so boring !
-Why ?
Do you have to go to the funeral?
No, but the consul is coming to see my uncle.
-So what ?
-We cannot be quiet any longer, the two of us.
Maybe he won't stay long, huh?
-Oh !  It's eleven o'clock already!
Oh dear !
-Do I make you forget about your business?
-Don't talk nonsense.
But before you leave, give me a little signature here.
What's this ?
-It's for the notary. This little piece of paper, dear madam,
It makes you the owner.
-But I haven't paid anything yet,
neither for the land or the villa. I want...
-I want ! The king said: We want!
Sign.
- Is the room ready for Mr De Laubrie?
He's coming tonight.
-Yes, Mrs.
-I will bring the flowers myself.
-Very good, madam.
Ma'am, I beg your pardon
I know ... I realise my audacity and my impropriety.
But I had to talk to you. For so long...
I have wanted to tell you ...
-Don't say it.
Besides, I know you wrote to me.
You must not longer write to me anymore.
-Since the first day I saw you ...
-I have loved you.
But I do not love you.
Don't be sad.
What matters is not so much to be loved, it is to love.
You think of me.
When you are alone, you talk to me.
You dream of doing wonderful things for me,
.. extraordinary things. So ?
Why be sad?
You're very lucky.
There are so few people who can love.
-I find you so beautiful.
Now you have to go.
No, no, don't say anything more.
Go on.
-Bonnemain, have you seen Gargame?
- Yes, he's at billiards.
-I can see him.
It is a stroke of champion!, Hello Mr. Gargame.
-Hello. This is not billiards. We should be able to practice.
..every day, but I have other things to do.
-Oh yes. I stopped by your house, I was told you were here.
- There it is, still too strong.
Did you want to talk to me?
-It's about our end of month deadline.
Can we delay it for another month?
What a question! Two months if you want.
Have you finished on the bridge?
I'm almost finished, but I'm a little frustrated ...
because I have nothing interesting for later.
-That's a nice shot, yes!
I was offered the construction of the combined stores.
- What? Aren't you going to do it?
- Why?
The project that everyone refused:
was taken by Richard and Patterson ...
They have better quality than you.
Some folk are afraid of everything.
- Come on! They are not crazy. It's not a building site,
..It's a disaster.
Do you know anything about the investigations that were done?
Infiltrations everywhere.
If I don't get something,
I will have to lay off my workers temporarily.
-I'm not in the habit of meddling in things that don't concern me.
It's not my style to lecture, but you do stupid things.
-Who risks nothing, has nothing.
-Is that so ! I don't mind, if it amuses you doing nonsense.
There you are, you made me miss my shot.
Are you happy?
-Hello Blanche?
Yes.
How does that matter? Bah!
For eight days since your consul arrived,
there has been no way to see you.
It's all for him. Eh ?
My dear, obviously I can understand, I'm not crazy.
But there are limits.
Eh ?
At 8 o'clock this evening at the villa?
Okay.
-See you tonight then.
Did you invite him to dinner?
I tell you bluntly, you're crazy.
-I'm doing it to calm him down otherwise
God knows what nonsense he would do.
And besides, yes, I'm looking forward to seeing him!
-By the way, has he talked yet of marriage?
-Roumagnac?
-No, the consul!
-Not yet.
-For the moment, he talks to me about politics.
-The same evening, the minister was overthrown..
...and I was unfortunate to be ambassador.
-But ... I'm chatting and it's late.
Yes, I took a long walk in the afternoon.
You must be tired. -I can see that...
Delighted to have met you.
-Me too. Sorry, I offer sincerely..
..my condolences. -Yes. The death of my wife.
..was a great misfortune for me. It has left an immense void.
She had long been condemned by doctors.
Some deaths are deliverance.
- Alas!
Bye. -Good evening.
-Good evening. -I accompany you.
-Yes.
That is someone, your consul.
I like his mentality,
..but he has education and he does not abuse it.
- Discretion is what characterises well-bred people.
-Ah well! Goodnight uncle.
-Uncle ?
-Uncle cake.
This Roumagnac is interesting,
quite a character.
Good evening dear friend. As Shakespeare says:
.. "May sweet dreams rock your cradle".
-Thank you. -Blanche.
-Excuse me, I didn't say goodnight to you.
-Goodnight Mr. consul.
-Goodnight.
-The shock was not too severe, but we should continue.
Uncle cake, uncle cake!
-There you are !
I was worried, I thought you weren't coming.
My dear!
You don't know how much I missed you!
When I don't see you I feel lost.
-I'm cold.
Hold me, I will warm you up.
-Next time, make a fire.
Good thing your consul returns to his consulate.
You are much better than the others.
-No,  I love you.
I love you.
That's it !
Here. -Thank you Mr. Roumagnac.
-It's nothing, just a spark plug.
- Are you going to the villa?
-Yes.
-Mrs Ferrand is gone. -Yes ?
-Yes, with a man in the car. They asked me for direction.
..from the Charmettes mill. -Oh good, thank you.
Goodbye Mrs. Percheron.
-These cakes are exquisite, your uncle would love them.
What a lovely bouquet.
In the language of flowers, the daisy says: Do you love me?
The buttercup: Don't make fun of me,
Let's take advantage of youth. -
This language is also part of your studies?
The duty of a diplomat is to speak flowery language.
Listen. How about uniting a widow with a widower?
Would you like to be Madame de Laubrie?
But you have never told me that you love me.
The proposal is a bit steep.
-For 2 years, I have been waiting for you, you know it.
Unfortunately there was an obstacle for 2 years,
- my poor wife.
We did everything to save her, but doctors cannot work miracles.
Now I am free.
And rich. -Yes I understand.
Think of the advantage of joining forces.
Ambition alone equates to the seven deadly sins.
-What pleasure is there in dominating what one despises?
-This is the proverb:
divide and you will triumph.  It is government based on police reports,
..learning what separates humanity, raises them up..
. against others, using hatred.
And their vices.
-But you're terrible.
Do not jest. I'm not talking about selling birds.
I never believed it. - You could have said it earlier.
Because the birds are beautiful, but the seeds ...
-I'm talking to a woman who has seen and experienced a lot.
As smart as she is beautiful.
You could help me by bringing grace,
..the warmth of your seduction.
I offer you something better than love.
Seriously, he's following us everywhere.
-But he didn't know we were here.
-Hello. I was passing by and saw your car.
-as chance would have it.
-I was having engine trouble. Am I bothering you ?
- Not at all. -You mind?
-Pardon.
Miss.
Tea ? -Eh ?
You want tea?
-No. You know my tastes.
Bring me a Pernod.
How are you ?
Fine, thanks.
-Oh Lucette!
You lost your working tool.
-Thank you Mr. Roumagnac.
-Such beautiful weather today. -Very nice day.
- It's nice here. - Very pleasant.
I have remodelled everything here.
-Oh yes ? -Yes.
Ah! Very cold water.
I don't know if water drinkers are bad, but I ...
-Oh ! I only drink water, so judge for yourself...
-She is really nice.
You look agitated, what's wrong?
-Me ? What an idea !
What are you doing here?
Paulot, my foreman.
-Hello. Madame, Mr. Ferrand, told me you were here.
-So ?
-There was an accident at the construction site.
-What ?
-The bridge has collapsed
How could this happen?
-I don't know. Fate.
Fate does not exist.
Have there been any injuries?
- One.
- Who?
-Perrin.
-It's serious ?
-The poor man looks pretty messed up.
-Good God ! I beg your pardon.
- I hope it's not serious.
-Excuse me.
-He knew perfectly well how to find us here.
- Is he in love with you...
-Roumagnac? Oh ! You are kidding.
-Oh ! A dog has every right to look at royalty.
By the way, because of him, you didn't respond.
..at my proposal. -When we speak about the soul,
..he responds immediately.
It has been addressed to the intellect.
- And that calls for reflection.
- Exactly.
Since it is a partnership.
At first glance, the matter seems feasible.
- You will see, you will soon be on your feet.
-Come on, step aside.
-I told you it would end like this.
- You will go slowly.
-Will you save him?
-You know, the spine ...
- Don't worry François, we'll get you out of here.
I wonder how this could have happened.
-Yes.
- What's up?
-Nothing, there would be too much to say.
-Let's see that. -Martin.
- What is it?
- Come here a minute.
-What is it? -A crossbar gave way.
I discovered it was weak, I told you.
- Stop!
I'll call the insurance.
- Damn it !
- What is it?
- I didn't pay the insurance premium.
-You didn't pay it?
If he stays there?
With three kids. -I know he has three kids!
-Oh, it's you! I was sleeping.
-Excuse me, but I spent the whole night waiting for you.
Why didn't you come?
- Don't speak so loud.
-Ah! It's true ! I forgot:
- the consul!
His Majesty the Consul is sleeping!
I hope the wind has not disturbed you.
There has been a very strong wind tonight.
It's ridiculous
-Ridiculous.
..I was waiting for you.
Why didn't you come?
- Do you want to wake him up?
- God! We can't do that!
Since he's been here, I can't see you anymore.
Why didn't you come?
-I could not.
- Has he spent the night with you?
-You are too stupid !
- I don't have the education.
- Leave. If you have trouble at work,
I have nothing to do with it.
I assure you, it is better if you leave.
- You did that in the stable.
You're right, I had better go.
-Mr. De Laubrie is coming down.
-Thank you Annette.
Hello.
-I hope he didn't hear anything.
- Heard what?
-Unfortunately, I heard everything.
- And what else?
- I would like to stop you from doing ...
Nonsense. I know myself,
I've been doing this my whole life.
There are silly things that's what one can do best
- but you shouldn't do them foolishly.
- I know.
-Your mason is leading us to disaster.
-Remain silent.
-Hello good friend. -Hello.
- Did you sleep well?
-Admirably.
However, I was awakened very early by a noise.
...like a slamming door.
That maid.
That crazy old woman takes pleasure by making drafts
-There is no maid without fault.
I even seemed to hear bursts of voices
-It was me.
I went downstairs to tell him to leave.
-It's curious.
I could have sworn it was our friend's voice.
Roumagnac.
-Well yes, it was Roumagnac.
-You had a business discussion?
- Leave us.
This is absurd, an absurd misunderstanding.
-I asked you to leave us.
-Roumagnac is familiar with you?
I thought he offered me a partnership,
it was not a sentimental matter...
-Exactly.
So? As long as it's not Mrs. De Laubrie.
-But ... Even if you were, you would be free.
You still have to choose your partners.
I agree that Roumagnac is the best of men,
..but what bothers me about him,
forgive me, he is a mason.
Obviously, that degrades us.
-He only has good feelings, but good feelings,
..with syntax errors.
-Not everyone can juggle vocabulary.
Of course.
His heart is in his hand,
but his hands are questionably clean.
It is less serious than a dirty soul.
In a salon,
a black soul is less noticeable than black nails in mourning.
Let's talk seriously.
This worker who smells of red wine and mortar.
Doesn't the smell of mortar bother you?
- Less than that of a corpse.
-Seriously, I don't understand.
-Your wife whose millions you have been eagerly stalking.
This dying woman, whom you buried every day for 2 years ...
..in thoughts. Nice engagement gift.
..that you brought me there. A corpse!
-That's an informative interview!
I understand the type of partner
..which suits you.
Today the house builder, tomorrow
Servants.
The butler, the driver.
Disgusting! Roumagnac is 100 times better than you.
-It's unfortunate to end this game.
-congratulatiions, Bonnemain.
What did you say about Roumagnac?
The injured worker, from the construction site, died in hospital.
Talk of the devil...
-Hello Martin.
-Hello Roumagnac.
-How are you ?
-Good
-Hello.
- Can I say a word to you?
-Yes.
-Excuse us?
Give us two white wines.
I have a financial problem. Can you lend me ...
..50 thousand? For a month,
enough time to turn it around.
As you're a friend ...
-you have done well.
Only, I had big outgoings this week.
-Oh yes ?
-In trade, there are invoices ...
The money did not come in quickly.
-I understand.
-We never have enough cash.
-Understood.
I had forgotten that in commerce, there is no cashflow.
I appreciate it anyway. How much do I owe you?
- You're kidding.
- Oh no.
-It's on me.
-This wine is good.
Thank you.
-Ah finally !
-The trade! La Ferrand is also in the business.
All he has to do is ask him for money. I didn't give him any.
..build a villa by eye. -You don't have the courage.
-She is with him out of interest. She sells birds.
The pigeons, she feathers them.
-It seems that in the evening above the store,
there are mysterious meetings.
-Don't even bother us!
- Well, you go ?.
- Yes.
- What did you say?
-What ? -What did you say ?
-I told the truth.
Damn you bastard! You are all bastards.
You slander him ...
After something you can't have. Yell at the bourgeoisie,
..but when isomeone like me touches a girl like that,
..that pisses you off even more. Rotten!
-What's wrong with him?
Who is it?
-A ghost.
-I don't believe in ghosts.
Hey! You have moved the dressing table.
Blanche. Since Roumagnac is in your life, you don't want to ...
..see me.
-What is finished is finished.
-But I can't do without you. I am married, I have no right ..
..to ask for more than I can give. You don't even listen to me.
I am here, I exist!
Barely
Am I at least in your game?
The jack of diamonds
-You have never been in the game
-my poor friend.
- I know that you are very attached to Roumagnac.
-Attached? These are your words.
Now he has money problems.
He's a man I admire. I have influence in the council.
If I spoke for him ...
-You would do that?
Yes, for you.
If necessary, I'm ready ... to accept...
-The sharing ?
-Anything, rather than losing you.  Blanche!
-Go home. You are just a petty little man.
A pathetic man.
Well, I think I'm very good!
My patience has limits, enough is enough!
I promise you will hear from me.
-Oh let's see! Dear friend !
- Oh, come on, here is the mason, now!
-Is Blanche up there? - Wait, no.
I think ... -I'm sure she's there.
I'm coming down.
- Who were you with ?
- Who was I with?
-Yes.
Maybe you weren't alone up there. Dare to admit it!
-What does that mean ? -How? 'Or' What ?
The uncle prevents me from going up,
..you come down quickly.
Don't look at me like that, don't play innocent!
I know what happens up there.
-You are crazy.
-No. I understand now.
What do you understand? You fool!
Yes, it starts here and then ends up there in your room!
-You are despicable! -Is that perhaps not true?
-You are despicable.
Go away.
Go away and never come back.
Never !
Bitch!
-What's the matter with you ?
-I have enough ! I can't take it anymore!
I'm sick of this town!
I've had enough of this stupid life! I can not stand it anymore !
It's over, we're leaving!
What about the store?
The store is over. I can't take it anymore! We will sell everything.
- No more store, no more consul.
We start over as before:
hotel rooms that no one knows.
..how to pay.
-I do not care.
I just want to leave.
What are you doing?
Come on, stop! It's silly, madness!
-To leave ! Do you understand what it means to leave?
-This is madness. They are going to die!
Maybe they will die, but in freedom.
-You have to be courageous. -Yes, but still.
Three children. It's not fair.
-You can count on my brother, he won't let you down.
It's good that you came. He was a good guy.
-Yes. I want to talk to you.
Is it true what I was told, that you borrowed from Bonnemain?
- You could have thought of me.
- I already thought about it,
... but I already still owe him a lot, plus a few favors ...
You know the other day ... -I lectured you, and after?
We've known each other for 20 years and I can't talk to you !?
-Yes, of course, but I haven't ... -What?
Come see me for the money. -Thank you.
I have no illusions, I'll give it to you as a lost fund
-Why do you say that ?
- I've lost confidence in you.
- But ... - Let me speak.
You can do what you want afterwards. You are an imbecile.
- How? - An idiot.
She makes you crazy.
-What ?
Yes, Blanche Ferrand makes fun of you.
She is a bitch. Everyone...
.. knows it and you don't see it.
We all laugh about it and we are right.
- It's unfortunate. - People tell stories.
-Stories ? Did she tell you she sold her store?
-Sold?
-You see, you didn't even know that.
-It's not true.
-She signed yesterday.
-It's not true !
-It does not amuse me to tell you that.
I would like to see you react, be a man!
-It's impossible!
- Let's go... the service has started.
-I'm going back, I forgot...
-You forgot what?
Some documents in my car. I'll be back in two minutes.
You want something, sir. ?
-Nothing sir.
- I was passing by and ...
- I'm the new owner.
I have bought the store. You are undoubtedly a friend of the Ferrands.
Yes, they are friends of mine.
Mrs. Ferrand's uncle is coming back right away.
We will make an estimate to buy the furniture also.
They're leaving the district and they're
not interested in packing all that.
-Are they leaving the region?
-Yes. I don't consider the birds..
... they are are too much care for.
-Ah !
There you are.
Thank you. I take it into account.
Have a nice day!
-Yes magnificent.
Can I give you a hand?
If I'm bothering you, just tell me.
I am used to it.
I hope you sold your store at a good price.
Don't be fooled by the villa. It's worth the money!
I know something about it myself.
Like that, you\re getting into politics now.
Are you going to see your Consul again..
Consul? - What a fool you are.
No, I'm not going to find him. I'm going alone.
-I do not believe you.
You're only good at lying.
You've been doing it from the beginning!
You made me look ridiculous.
You will never see your consul again!
-Poor idiot !
Do not touch me !
-How so ?
-Do not touch me with your dirty hands anymore.
-You haven't always said that.
-You hurt me !
- I am not educated.
-You are nothing but a poor, ridiculous bastard!!
- Shut your mouth?
-No ! With your words smelling of Pernod!
- Are you going to shut up?
-You will shut up!
You're just a poor man!
-Consul is over! -Leave me ! You hurt me !
No one else! It's over ! It's over !
It's finished ! Over!
Filthy liar!
-Where have you been ?
It's been almost an hour since I got home by the bus.
It is shameful what you have done.
You left the funeral without any explanation.
You made a very good impression.
- I was ashamed.
- Leave me alone.
- Have you eaten?
- No, I am not hungry.
What have you done to your hand?
You fell ?
Did you fight? Something must have happened.
-Leave me alone.
- Still in trouble because of her? Surely.
I understand where you have been.
And you hit her.
-Never talk to me about her again. It's over now.
-It's not possible ! It would be too good!
-I killed her.
- Did you kill her?
Martin, that's not true, you didn't do that.
-Yes, I killed her.
Then they will come. They will take you!
Don't bother me! This is not the time!
-Martin. Tell me how it happened. Say.
Were you at the store?
-No.
-At the villa?
- Has anyone seen you? -No, it was just the two of us.
-When you left?
-No, nobody after...
It was starting to burn.
-Ah...
But then, if no one has seen you ...
Don't stay like that. You have to shake yourself up!
-I do not care ! -There were lots of men around her.
Why should they suspect you?
The Roumagnacs are not murderers. Think about your father.
-It's nothing, it's just the postman making his rounds.
- Hey, he's coming down from the bridge, he's coming over here.
Gett yourself together. Come on!
It's one o'clock, do you understand?
It's been a long time since you've come and eaten with me.
- Good day.
- Hello.
Hello. Enjoy your meal.
We're done. I'll serve you coffee right now.
A glass of wine ?
Well, that never killed anyone!
Oh ! My god, how hot it is.
-It is because you did it quickly.
-How, it's only one o'clock?
Have you thrown the mail into the river?
To your health! -Cheers !
-We don't drink coffee.
I don't want to go back with my head on the ground.
Another that the Prussians will not have!
Goodbye.
Come on.
-Bye. -See you tomorrow.
-Did you understand ? If necessary, it will give us an alibi.
It’s terrible what happened. If you had listened to me ...
She wasn't a woman for you.
-Ah you too!
That's why it happened. Everyone said:
.. "She's not a woman for you".
-It's not true ? - For his part too, her uncle,
..the consul who was supposed to say: "He's not a man for you!"
-If you'd listened.
-It's everyone's fault:
..Gargame, Paulot and you!
-Me ?
-Yes. When people are happy, others have to spoil everything.
-She did not wait ..
..the consul laughed at you. She told you he was a friend.
She wasn't kidding you?
And the day of the funeral, she had just given you the shamrock.
I didn't invent it, you told me.
A famous lucky charm this clover!
At the same time, she said to herself,
..the consul's wife.
Isn't that true?
-Bah yes, she was pretending! to love me!
-She must have laughed. -I know, she made me a fool.
My dirty hands she said! -If that's not a whore ..
If they accuse you, don't weaken.
You will defend yourself. -Yes, I'll defend myself.
Yes! They won't get me. I'm telling you: they won't get me.
-Well Roumagnac, have you changed your mind?
-You are a funny lawyer. You want me to be guilty.
-But no, I would like to do the best.
If we could plead guilty I'm sure we would get the minimum.
-I can't tell you it's not me, since it's not me!
-You can say that, but you will not have made it easy for me.
-Ask for The Dispatch! Yes Madam. Thank you Madam.
The Dispatch! Here Mr.
-Thank you. -Ask for La Dépêche!
Ask for La Dépêche!
Here Mr.
Ask for La Dépêche! Ask for La Dépêche!
-Do you think he'll get away with it? -He is very strong.
-One second Mr., I can't serve everyone at the same time.
There it is, thanks.
- "Mr. Roumagnac persists in denying against the evidence."
-The evidence ? It remains to prove the obvious.
-For me, it's proven.
* - Yesterday, victory of the Belgian Vonherbek in the criterium of the road.
* Today in Clairval, 3rd hearing of the Roumagnac trial.
* The president read a letter from one of the main witnesses,
* .. Mr. de Laubrie, consul at ..
* .. Rotterdam, who held back, apologized for not being able to respond to ..
* .. the convocation of justice. The testimony of the forensic scientist.
* .. was overwhelming for the accused. End of our information.
-Doctor ! Not to mention all their mistakes.
-She has been strangled. What about the footprints?
- There is none since everything burned down and she with it.
-It was necessary to look at the hands of Roumagnac!
-I've worked with him for 10 years, he's never had 2 cents.
..of nastiness.
-Mrs Percheron, please specify for the jurors, the location.
..from your petrol station.
-It's simple. My post is right at the corner of the main road,
..and the path that leads to the villa.
-You certify that you saw the Roumagnac car on the day of the crime.
.. leave the road ..
..and go in the path? -Yes, it's the truth.
-It's not true.
I was not at the villa that day.
-I have nothing against you, I say what is.
-He's in bad shape.
-The witness claimed to have seen Roumagnac's car driving up...
.. the road to the villa, but did he see that car pass by?
-Oh no. I had no reason to watch him.
I have lunch too!
-Excuse me madam,
..that day, I did not go to the villa. I'm not saying you're lying
..but you are wrong. How many times have I been there?
-That's also true. -So !
-Think well madam.
Your answer depends on the verdict.
Can you swear it was that day and not the day before?
-Yes.
It was surely that day.
-It is not a question of knowing if it was surely that day, but ..
..to swear it under the faith of the oath.
-On the oath? Everyone can make mistakes.
- Gentlemen of the jury will appreciate that.
-You can retire madam. The hearing is adjourned.
-What a mule head! He just said no.
-If it wasn't him who killed her.
-So Roumagnac? -He denies of course.
-In front of the uncle, he will not be able to deny.
-We don't know where he is. -The deposition of Mrs. Percheron.
..is clear, she saw Roumagnac.
- Me too, I saw it.
Not in the same place. I will speak.
I can tell you that on the day of the crime at 1 p.m.
..I saw Roumagnac at his place.
He was finishing lunch with his sister,
I even had a drink with them.
-Mr. Gardin, I don't mean to offend you,
but you have the reputation of a man who rarely refuses to drink.
-I protest against these innuendos ..
..who want to weaken the witness.
-I have been drinking for 40 years.
-It's alcoholism.
-No, it's not alcoholism, it's a habit.
-I was never a minute late because of that.
The day you die,
..I will drink too. It won't stop me ..
..to distribute your invitations on time, if that worries you.
-Good boy ! Bravo Gardin!
-After the funeral, how did you get home?
-By the bus. -What was your brother doing?
-What was he doing?
-He had not attended the funeral
and claims to have returned home by car.
So it happened before you returned?
What was he doing ?
-Yes, he got home before me.
-Yet you don't know what he was doing.
Your hesitation condemns him.
-I'm not hesitating, but it's a funny question.
He was at his construction site, of course.
-All the workers were at the funeral. The site was not active
-That was no reason for him not to go!
It's his life.
I repeat, there has never been a murderer among us.
-You can withdraw.
-I want to tell you gentlemen of the jury and even shout at you,
..that I am completely convinced that Mr. Roumagnac is guilty ..
..of the crime for which he is accused!
-Why, instead of looking for the criminal among so many people.
.. ambiguities that were attracted to her, why do you want to ..
.. to reject the responsibility of the crime on Roumagnac?
At the time of the crime,
..Roumagnac was having lunch quietly at home.
I will go further: on the day of the crime, Roumagnac got
..gasoline at the dispenser station.
I want to show you there, the best proof of his innocence.
Here is a man, whose heart is full of sinister designs,
.. we say. A man,
.. quivering with murderous rage. Regardless..
.. to attract attention ..
..on him, he stops to get gasoline like a tourist!
Is it plausible? Conceivable? Come on!
But he would have driven until his last drop of gasoline and ...
... he would have finished the journey on foot, carried away by hatred,
..he would have done it by running.
Think of the Roumagnacs you know.
..for generations! MM. the jurors, strong in agreement.
..of my conscience, strong in the force of the truth,
..I can not finish better than by quoting the words of the sister ..
..of the accused: "There were never any assassins among the Roumagnacs!"
You will acquit M. Roumagnac!
- Come on, let's see, silence!
What does it mean ?
Roumagnac.
Do you want to add anything?
-I have nothing to say, I'm innocent.
-Ah! Well !
The uncle of the victim,
. cited as the main witness for the prosecution
and who did not answer.
..to our quotes, introduces himself.
-I protest ! The last voice that must be raised here
is that of defence.
However, I have delivered my argument.
-Yes, but hearing this witness is of capital interest.
I order that it be done.
-You swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
..nothing but the truth, raise your right hand,
.. said: I swear.
-I swear.
-Why did you not respond to the invitations sent?
-For 5 months, I was between life and death.
They didn't relieve me until the day before yesterday,
.. when I left the hospital.
- Bring a chair to the witness.
About 2 hours before the crime, Roumagnac presented himself.
..to the apartment you occupied with your niece.
He had just left the funeral of one of these workers.
-And then ?
It wasn't a crime! My sister told you,
I was at the worksite.
-It's a suspicious attitude.
Roumagnac seemed to you to be in ..
..a state of particular excitement?
-No.
I must say that Roumagnac ..
..didn't give me the impression that he was planning a crime.
-The investigation made in Paris on your niece established that her past ..
..was quite cloudy.
-That's the sad truth, Mr. President.
-You say that now,
..it made you eat!
-I let myself be fed but I liked it.
-Funny way to love!
-From Roumagnac moderation.
Let's see. Dancer in nightclubs, she shot.
.. his subsistence of companions ..
.. of orgies or meetings. -It was necessary to live well!
-How do we get there?
She was from an excellent family.
-Eh yes ! Sadly,
..because excellent families have a fad.
They like young girls to study the arts of entertainment,
..painting for example.
And in Paris, painting goes through ..
..Montmartre or Montparnasse.
She goes there and the young girl stays.
..to a café terrace.
This is where we met Blanche and me.
I was a famous bohemian!
It's even funny how we can change.
I ran the world for 40 years and now I can't sleep anymore.
..if we only change my place bed.
- Come on, continue.
-One evening, in the Latin Quarter, she met Ferrand,
..the seedman of Clairval.
At one point, I must admit ...
There are times like that.
-In plain language,
Ferrand saved her that day and married her.
Poor naive! -You, please!
You are not here to smear it, but to defend me.
It's already painful ...
-For the second time,
..control yourself!
-What do I have to do with the past! My life has started ..
..the day I met her! So, the past!
-A man who talks like that, I will never admit that he could ...
- Come on, that's enough!
Tell us more about your niece's relationship with ..
..Mr De Laubrie. -The consul ?
He wanted to marry her, he offered her his fortune.
-There!
..the proof of the crime!
You murdered your mistress to
.. prevent him from joining the consul.
-Not at all. She wasn't going to join him,
..Mr. the prosecutor.
On the contrary, she had broken up.
..with him because he had engaged in attacks against Roumagnac.
She even threw a violent insult at him!
An insult that cost us millions.
During her lifetime, enough bad words have been said about her.
It was the truth, alas.
It is not because she is dead that we should not continue.
..to tell the truth.
Especially since it's clean for once.
If only for the memory.
-After such a deposition, if I had not delivered my plea,
..I would give up pronouncing it.
When have we seen a lover kill ...
.. his mistress when the latter has just given him ..
.. such a beautiful proof of love?
-Vive Roumagnac!
-Roumagnac is innocent!
-Unanimously, the jury answered "No" to the 1st question which it ..
..was asked.
-Mr. Roumagnac, you are free.
-Bravo master, that's great.
-You come ? We're going to the registry. -Yes.
-He! Here is the wine!
-Well done !
-When there's more, there's more.
-Martin must be released.
- There is still justice.
- My poor Jeanne, you've had some hard times.
-Yes, don't think about it anymore.
He is going to feast, I made him truffles.
It's been a long time since he ate it.
- Fortunately, there is your testimony.
-I told the truth.
I said to the prosecutor: "When I got here,
"..it was sharp 1 p.m."
-Bravo, bravo! -I have the dispatches!
Who wants the dispatches?
Special edition !
-Who wants fresh news? Ask for La Dépêche!
-Me ! - I have more.
-We say what ? Read aloud.
- "Martin Roumagnac freed."
-Here they are !
-There's Martin!
-Bravo Martin. I am happy.
Its nice to see you again.
- I can't even kiss him.
It's over, you're with us.
You have to forget now.
-We will drink to that.
-He is right.
It's nice to be home.
-What did he say ?
He didn't say a word.
-What do you want him to say?
It is the emotion.
-Come on, yours! -Cheers !
-You showed them what a Roumagnac is.
-Shake yourself!
-Read this: "Roumagnac, freed."
- Let's drink to the health of the prosecutor.
-He would have had him condemned ..
..for that hen.
- Shut up all of you!
Give me a break !
-But what's wrong with him?
-Speak !
-Calm down.
-People who talk around me, it doesn't stop.
Everyone needs to talk and no one knows anything!
They all talk about what they don't know!
-It's the nerves. Don't blame him.
-It's best to leave it.
When he has slept, he will be better.
- Am I taking you on my motorbike?
-Yes, but watch out for the bends.
- Shall we drink?
- To the health of Roumagnac!
-See you soon. -Bye.
Good evening.
-You no longer embarrass yourself!
-She doesn't start the first time.
-Oh, Martin!
-Good evening Jeanne. - Let him rest.
Life is good now, don't worry.
-Martin, your friends say goodbye to you.