the last time I gave my heart to the
Lord was in 1959 I was 16 then I guess I
was in the habit all in all I gave my
heart to the Lord eight times eight and
a half if you count the time I tripped
over a cocker spaniel and had to be
carried from the church with a broken
ankle
then I lost my virginity and I got more
cagey about where I put my ah how often
it wasn't right then actually it was
three years later when I was 19 and one
month old which was the national average
then was a long time ago showing no
we're leaving yeah I'm soaking up it
McCallister's floor it's it's one of
these long I'll just move them out of
his bed hey Mike hunt we're old friends
went to school together in Lismore
nothing you says well this is it okay
that must be the one next door yes all
right
oh all right
ah gets my religion yeah well not
anymore but it's against the religion I
used to have don't think I'll follow
well I'm trying to break things gently
to myself about what the world's really
like oh yeah
I'm glad I'm really glad I met you
yeah yeah it's funny it's the same case
the Vice doors and it doesn't fit maybe
we're in the wrong house I don't know we
got in the front door maybe it's the
wrong room no it's number four look
don't worry
I'm gonna come push cat-burglar I'll fix
it
I really like the room I usually do this
you know
not in the first date yeah that's nice
this isn't it a 30g I hope we finally
because this is the only Keon
McCallister's gonna have to sleep out in
the cold
you know there's one place where we know
the key feeds I'm sobering up I don't
want to do it
good what's wrong really worried about
the mix lighting exhibition gee thanks
what's really nice you were disappointed
weren't you well it was like getting
baptized I mean you're totally immersed
and you come up spitting water expecting
the Holy Spirit to land on you hidden
choirs of angels exalting and then
things just dead still silence and
nothing's happened everything's just as
it was except you're soaking wet
oh thanks thanks very much what's wrong
with you thanks a whole lot did I say
something wrong I think you in some way
please don't see me home Dan will kill
you he's got this 12-bore shotgun and
all these unresolved incestuous feelings
towards me oh well maybe she's getting
gauge them engaged that's not what I had
in mind
ty Romero please driver
what happened to you one man has the
same question
well forgot what number you're looking
in Victoria Street so I'm good I got the
flower in the wrong house and it took
four hours I don't live in Victoria
Street yes you do
no I don't know it's a house in Victoria
Street
does anybody told you lately that you're
hopeless it's something tardy I did get
98 in the end maybe Atlantan test before
I gave it up because I couldn't stay Mrs
Murphy where do you leave nowhere
anymore waited up on the doorstep the
freezing cold will 3 a.m. and Andy
running her cigarettes I rang the
doorbell the landlord came down looked
me up and down ordered me to vacate the
premises big uproarious Hungarian person
740 piece of dyed built like a brick
chef
I mean well this is our like my humble
view we've fucked and far from home 500
miles thanks for breakfast I'm beginning
to appreciate Lismore house showing so
much year 5 and 6 spent the rest on
Black Label champagne did you don't
drink yeah maybe I should take it up
MacAlister and i had this special
relationship
I helped him burn his poems he
shoplifted I cooked I gave him half my
earnings as a part-time cat I let him
eat my chips in the Union refectory at
Sydney University we didn't get on all
that well I decided in retrospect
somehow that night there we were
country boys in the big city looking for
a warm dry life and place in vain and a
bed for the night and sleep
we fetched up at long last one of the
places we used to go to you sleeping
rough round Sydney the big Roman column
which was also the Bondi sewer outlet
under it played again some games we had
left over for a war - and embarked again
on an agent conversation we've been
gnawing away since we were 10 what's it
all about McAllister no stars up there
are fools like us on their own bondo
Golf Links they're looking up and up and
saying what's it all about McAllister
I don't know I'm an atheist I believe in
mathematical probability with film birth
I believe in Robert Mitchum triggered
fan the Living God Phil said is Today
Tomorrow forever from apart not
believing me
hardly adds up to a theology yeah I know
what is needed in the modern age is not
so much a theology as a plan of attack
gee if we know I did one of them just
flames Sam yeah
before the not info missile it isn't a
godless universe I'm sir I'm reliably
informed think that give us some kind of
warning before a whole world ends maybe
they do you know Jurong you who's your
real Superman's father yeah
Oh
we've got sleep in the office tonight
Google the staff club again on Saturday
yeah you're very Mecosta still no around
yeah think I miss all that
look you were a virgin until quite
recently you must remember how rotten it
was 14 hours ago yes
worse wasn't it oh well
hello I'd like to work on a lease for
the University newspaper knockin
features editor I'm Jamie O'Brien
pleased to meet you
you wanna fuck ah no but I'd quite enjoy
a cup of coffee I think people should be
open about these things
thank you no no I don't but I was very
well brought up
oh well well soon knock that out of you
I mean you're very confident aren't you
I mean since this morning I'm very tired
and when you're very tired you say what
you think
we could go to the truth they Phil
Johnson Jim yes
five o'clock session
it's time to fool around after what
wouldn't after yeah we get the bus we
could get before 3:00 I pass I could
drive us if you like
so probably like no daddy says we having
any money at all
Oh
by nutrition that they need
I like you but if anything's going to
happen it's got to be my own decision in
my own time yeah I'm very impatient I
mean the end of the world is nigh
extremely neither
there are signs and portents
yeah climb up the drainpipe sleep on the
floor McAllister when we're between
marchings Ted McAllister the poet
yeah well the banning versa fire I love
his stuff yeah
I think you're a very interesting person
good night
am I
all right look get irregular eyes your
habits losing weight did you she's
terrific this one even Richard manana
you have my warmest congratulations
yeah you don't think I might have six
student McAlister yes you could be right
perhaps our voice was
the sisters fathers pastor Anderson
thanks yeah
you're English
nobody else had those big complexions
yeah I've got skin like that wouldn't
mind it
Vince girls get married at 16 and I want
to see the world first
Bri spinner James used to kill only my
cousin Thelma yeah in the greenhouse
we've got cool
did you bring up against the teeth must
be deformed well who'd you kiss cousin
Thelma down the green house Sunday and
old brethren time is short the Good Book
says he know not the day nor the hour
justice was prophesied knowledge shall
be increased men run to and fro
television jet air travel the atomic
bomb why there is even a move to open
the pub
so 10 o clock at night the signs of the
time sister the signs of the times and
heresy why heresy is everywhere the
Jehovah's Witnesses have doubled their
numbers in New South Wales in only three
years by breed like rabbits that's right
brother Ellison but heresy breeds faster
than rabbits and Alwyn who death the
shepherds robbed once an honored member
of our church in Coffs Harbour now
unlost so doomed by God's gentlemen to
thrash and rise and scream forever in
the great lake of fire wickedness
abounds and the time of God's coming is
near
I can L control is more hi mr. Anderson
this is my sister Sarah nice here
this is wailing Gibson sir I you spell
it with an SAR a I come again so lovely
nice thank you wait from Liz more yes
you said I'm deputy you Slater thee oh
really
ah we just wanted to tell you how much
we enjoyed your father's sermon and
appreciated it Oh giggling all the way
through not three the good beats which
were they what about the rabbits you're
from England oh yeah yes we came out
four years ago
I'm the orchid ease warm enough for you
over here yes good well we'd better be
going to bed
what on earth were you doing I think
late don't you know what time it is
girl you're too young to be writing
notice two girls put the light out your
burners down
leather six years said it amount of the
pictures I'll give up comics for six
months if you make a seat with me at the
beaches though I speak with the tongues
of men and of angels and have not love
and and become as sounding brass or a
tinkling because you know first signing
off now bless mom and dad and Graham and
he ate and uncle Claude and barium
Island Gibson pigmentosa bring him to
your truth he's a good soul really
integrates Ambala
Jesus sick
will you say Amen for me alright and a
questions in in Matthew 24:34 it says
verily I say unto you this generation
shall not pass till all these things be
fulfilled and he's prophesying a 10 last
place in the end of the world
yes brother white question well that
generation has all passed they're all
dead aren't they I mean the whole bang a
lot of them so are you implying brother
now Lord was mistaken no I just mean
that if all the Bible's true and we
believe that and this is not true well
it makes the whole thing so go on
brother speak out the sin in your heart
no no no it's just a question enough I
think there should be an answer in there
how do you know brother that there may
not still be a 2000 year old man on the
jungles of Sumatra living today stranger
things have happened
yeah well they could be and if only one
such man has survived that generation
has not passed I think that's good
enough he doesn't think that's good
enough is it good enough for you then
it's good enough for me will you say
Amen for me beware heresy my dear young
brother it's an easy trap ever open
waiting next question
what's wrong it's a beautiful later
thank you I don't think I ever could
why not I look at you and I don't think
you're a true Adventist you have a
doubts I could learn to overcome them
really if you could find it in your
heart to help me know it's your struggle
you must ask God for help
well with me on the pictures on Saturday
pick me up something Billy teenie he
drinks like a fish it's quite a struggle
how'd you do no good at all sir I won't
sit with me either
a tough fear yeah funny species all
right I had this story where they could
blow smoke rings through their Queens
right what I want to do that for all a
day I ponder the question of women my
dad reckoned out all bloodsuckers and
you saw them standing outside the church
at every wedding rubbing their hands and
snickering here comes another poor mug
into our clutches but I certainly had
their attractions
so ship its right couldn't be when there
would he think he would he's pregame
that's him all right look he's only got
one hand he said the adventists cut it
off and fed it to the dogs
I don't know hey - pretty funny mob down
coughs either way I'm gonna call it ten
days just a camp loss that wall yeah
well it's two million Adventists I'm on
really I put it on the index Wow
what we put in it six violence bless me
novel ratings has seen anyway is
according to mrs. what our founding
prophet is does that include Biggles
reckon of course it does hmm
I've always heard the side to you but
one day that in business my mission
where they can look at the facts
they decide to look at me some ways sort
of playing for the cameras they want to
look at you I don't know they might why
you I'm gonna give them reasons to I'm
gonna be a great novelist movie director
Test cricketer what do you want to be
when you got greatest man who ever lived
yeah same spit right musical knees
laughs the pleasure of this Breck
over there dancing isn't it there's no
Dancing's a sin God climbed me it's not
us get off the floor
hmm who said that whoever said that get
off the floor immediately you do
something if I ask you
yeah sure anything later quicker on
whatever you say
would you mind another liter okay
I thought this was my kid it's a later
phase - is it gone
you're a really lucky in that dress
gone
for three whole days the rider was on
that bucking Brumby and at the end of
the fourth day something flew off and a
bystander simply with a Dibley and the
owner said no that was his brand he
backed off his brand but Dibley was
still there
thank you brother and we must hold on to
the faith as surely as I held on for
those four terrible days for brethren
the great tempter is ever at the door
who tells the Shepherd's rod himself
encounter his infamous Caliban yay
verily in the vacant lot across the road
a mere 100 yards from where I stand and
the Lord presides
and sisters the Lord enjoins us against
all violence even unto who death must we
turn the other cheek show courtesy and
civility but never let his evil doctrine
into our hearts
young brother
elke I understand that you have been
writing letters to my daughter mr. C
well what have you got to say for
yourself might happen again sir
she thinks you're funny anyway hmm
decided much the same when I was young
but not as young as you head tonight
gets here as I married the girl I've
heard about you young hooking your your
colorful young people's meetings your
questions from the floor your doubts
about the Trinity well Jacob wrestled
with the angel too soon he turned out
alright father of the chosen people hmm
you can write letters to my daughter if
you want to but I would prefer it if you
did not deliver them in person or
perhaps it would be better if you wrote
them to the whole family yes sir if you
wish I write a very good letter
just not good enough even ones a heaven
full of seventh-day adventists the other
end of the court drink dance crank out
of the pictures can't gamble can't eat
prawns can't tell a joke unless it has a
moral purpose it's not good enough or
can dad was right I see a day when young
people of all persuasions can go to the
Saturday dance I see a day when a godly
person he wants to can either licorice
strap or a freddo frog and not feel
guilty I'm just curious would smart
don't you think you must pay for
everything we're not pretty this might
be a mistake we've been putting off all
the good things we could have been doing
before we died it's cuz this stupid
bitch got hit on the head and started
having visions yes I have trying to
shape what's wrong I have you tried the
Catholics all that sounds okay way there
it all makes sense they all found out
there making says they might all be
wrong all of them you tried to ship it
to rot yes what are you saying luck very
convincing
cavitus
I see a day when a woman will love a man
for his you know
not for how he looks but for who he is
did you say buggerin yes ma'am
you mind your mouth young man I'll wash
it out with soap yes
morning
is anything wrong I think I saw the
beautiful big dream oh uh I just thought
I'd come in early and learn a few things
before my first lecture this is the rich
one is it yeah I really like your poetry
it's ease off spin he's a very talented
man it's all part of the same gift
really mathematical strategic precision
oh I see she can stay
first off the fresh pink one spill at
first but it gets better
yes I know my father's a newspaperman oh
that oh god yes indeed coffee which
shineth in your article on barry
goldwater you employ the word bullshit
I've had anguish conference with a
distraught printer and my fellow
directors when we decided almost
unanimously the dust history will judge
you harshly Kevin are stiffing myself
against Ed eventualities
that's a hard world we live in young
Alcon but it's the only one there is
history is watching
what do you think of me I think you're
very improbable I thought I was down
with a boring I think you fear you are
but you don't have to it's good and I
think you need looking after
ken yes I've been thinking what about
about my own good time you know time's
up you reckon thought oh well Em's the
world you know extremely nice
I've decided well we better secure some
accommodation yes unless you prefer the
office floor are we doing
I can appointment yes
well have in the past
miss bounty no nineteen that's the
national average that's me
so funny better because she teased know
my face that you've got an excuse of you
really
Dave Mackay nah this is all servants
quarters
Tippett entrances locks my territory
but that was once upon a time
once upon a time
Oh
it's good exercise
go swimming instead what is your Colin
city I come from a temperate climate you
you angry with me
yes yes yes it's mommy and daddy's
anniversary party daddy are you alright
Jeanne I love you you too
mr. prime good night sir I can't stay
got to get a newspaper yes
really good my self up how do you do
that
I think we put the collide
it's nothing serious it's just holding
the loins you know just another girl
just graces three times
we reach for you and the court of louis
xiii
so sorry
and you're being ridiculous well I'm not
yes
oh come on it's gotta be around here
someplace we supposed to be having a
picnic we haven't got it dear Ken I've
been thinking things through this past
week and I've decided we shouldn't see
each other for a while I know I could go
steady with you or whatever the phrase
is for the rest of my life but I'm not
sure I should I won't be coming in to a
nice fire anymore and if we do run into
each other in the quad I'd rather we
didn't speak I want to sort out my
priorities that's all I still sort of
love you but I don't think I want to see
you if that makes any sense you'll be
pleased to hear I've been at long last
pronounced free of the clap I wish you
equal fortune you're sincerely Jenny
O'Brien
now let's got him a drink
you don't drink three minutes until he
spills no gas song and a grilled cheese
I'm toast
no no I said yourself was forever
Rosalie
you've always had a distorted idea when
it's your view is it yeah I was thinking
the souls to conquer you should let him
be like campaign yes the way you were
brought out the end of the world is mine
you have a will she lay off are you off
but I love her but I might get hit by a
bus tomorrow will die of terminal
sickness fall out a third-story window
eventually you'll have to face the
terrible possibility that you might live
to be 90 my planes how can anyone live
like them listen it's very simple she
shot through and I'm gonna get it back
you treated like some converted soul
how dare she banks but I love it can't
lay off on when you love them that's
right you're glad you did man you must
be out of your mind
I stepped horse excuse
hey mommy a cup of coffee no I think
your little mad can I think you need
help
see that's my thing I don't think so you
please let me go
just leave the lady alone son okay
here's one with the 20th century in
jails and proof walk we see the ordinary
post-christian wallet humanity
if dirty dicks sloppy joes we drank on
Durga's straight some went upstairs with
Marjorie and some are less with and two
by two like cat and mouse the homeless
played at keeping house won't he make
the sailors friend of Mary our open
their arms that I refused to step inside
I was not looking for a cage that's cool
I like that
w insure him wise man from 30-day
fuckers I was brought up a cannibal now
I wait for the ABC I'm a radio announcer
you just remind you for good old days
naked savages Tom coming around the fire
no no but it is good to remember those
things to say Mary Miller quickly said
probably used to
what is wrong nightingales are sobbing
in the orchards of our mothers in the
hearts that we broke long term have long
been breaking others
tears are round sees all and overboard
last night your face came to me in a
dream it's really the Queen's God gives
us our purpose but we have to okay it is
you isn't it yeah it's not my name
anymore a professional name's sinnamon
entertainer entertainer economy thing
for sure so what happened you
I'm a university student second year
exams in three weeks for a second time
it's pretty thick you stripping here
yeah pretty hard Yakka no I'm the one
after next what a person yeah thought
you might
being Merrill do Iraq may be uncertain
as to whether she wasn't better off back
in church
not that she could in advance not that
she wasn't happy in her own way
I think all of us are more or less
equally happy whatever we do in life
there's a sort of flimsy line and we
don't go above or below it most of the
time I had it away with her of course it
was a historical inevitability in anyway
I was drunk with Randy far from home no
reason
yeah voice my creaks your money they
have a gentleman slide on down the
Caterine slight one of it Jim Devils Wow
I thought Borderlands Thomas strain
mmm
as yours okay got home for holidays
brother and me to be on the church steps
and says that was the battle going
brother half times with a try
if you didn't charge me for old times
sake the old times we never had I now
regret not having but I had to leave
early because her pimp was coming back I
never saw her again
someone killed her a year later choked
her to death in flagrante
once more I missed out on something that
would have been good with someone I
should have got to know better
McAllister used to call them witnesses
people who knew you when who were
irreplaceable and you have to seek them
out I didn't seek her out I had other
fool things on my mind
I paid your bail
Thanks I came all the way down on a
train from Armidale to pay your bail I
emphasize that yes sorry I calles the
rainy Jesus brokers you I'm I'm the only
one that's not so governor train because
I'm a good friend in spite of everything
yeah
yeah you are well explain yourself that
was sleeping a window soldier now how
did it into climbing and rape the girl I
love
oh and we wanted to feel the need to
write this later
well a florida makers see sense right I
was wrong
bring out drinking alcohol how'd you all
wait hitting on a done steak to write a
city boy stirs natural unknown sinful
effort is yet became a because I worry
about you you can get five years and all
this tripe you're right in the honey
swatch Jesus Christ was a homosexual
runes on the beloved I mean really deep
if you were legal evil oh yeah well
suppose either beloved the disciple whom
Jesus loved what else does it mean you
were really on the downhill slide Devils
gunning to me you reckon cotton oh come
on we gotta go see a lawyer he's really
good you'll get now can I put it to
gently that if you're under the
impression only the impression that the
young lady in question wanted to have
sexual congress with you on that
particular night in that particular
bedroom and the gate moreover was open
was the gate open okay I don't remember
I'm not asking you to fill so that your
testimony in any way but if the gate was
open and the gate moreover was open
your worship the defendant will stop
eating grapes and projecting the pips at
prosecution counsel your worship may
counsel approach the bench is that
agreeable to you mr. cabman certainly it
was and to your grep Everest glass eye
defendant of the bar
I was thereupon commanded to keep away
from Jenny on pain of being hung drawn
and quartered or something I was tired
frightened and far from home and agreed
am i hard what minute then we went to
the pub
well respectfully concluded you sure you
don't want a drink
yeah I'm sure really lemon squash maps
that something
that's been nice to see her
I'll be frank quick no thanks house
happy though
what's all right I'm still waiting on
tables getting pretty time I had her up
in second here you see anything a sir
I'll yes sir
yeah sorry is still in armored our still
see you sometimes Podesta she went to
Tasmania she gonna be funny in the head
now she's teaching kindergarten
I'll sing Christmas at the bait
so how are you this evening
Walter look lovely I mean revolt against
Authority however many young men are
with good cause
young in a passionate they must say they
say how Idina you're a cannibal yes the
certain wisdom is randomly it's very
good sometimes to come into real life
from an unusual angle you see things
clearly yeah I didn't know what you mean
what do you see me clearly
lots of hypocrisy of women their
teaching of English from literature at
university level is what it's like the
seventh-day adventists interpreting the
Book of Ezekiel what did the author
Jehovah mean by this myth for here and I
know governor beats me sangeeta am beat
it's a lean wasted years knocking on
people's doors from the age of 18
Sharlee mentioning the end of the world
is not sorry we're Catholics ed saying
close the door on top of that English
literature is like playing the bagpipes
to sheer waste understand you in good
stead in your chosen career yeah
what do you see mommy futility of career
like you you prefer to sit under a
coconut tree be stoked on kava picking
your teeth with somebody else's finger I
dunno you must be career is everything
achieved man is everything man is a
challenge seeking animals you don't deny
them I only remark on this futility what
are you gonna be when you grow up
greatest manner with a lift and they
were dyed you mean deaf makes it all
pointless
don't you see just that tropical lie
about this we'll send up a couple of
missionaries all soon sort you air oh
yes seventh-day Adventists I remember
them
l can we're getting a divorce
oh why it's time you grew up and I'm
damn sure you won't
after years of revolting intimacy brain
numbing contortions of needless belief
I've decided to beyond hope
fight for me my caste all either uni
rational people are asking me for you
also a rapist as a child after we've met
upon reflection you probably work well
just that one night apart from which
I've been offered a room rent-free by
rich patroness of ERT thinks I'm a poet
all right
she'll pull the wool out of her ass
see
my world seemed to be falling apart my
best maid at school and my best mate at
church didn't like me anymore
I was prevented by court order from
raping the girl I loved and reduced to
having philosophical conversations in a
strip joint with a cannibal on the sofa
room and with some money mum got from
selling her old car I put a down payment
on a television set which in turn became
the author of my doom and a tape
recorder on which I practiced my
Laurence Olivier imitation I went about
discontent made glorious summer by this
son of DOC all ships of any kind bound
for Cuba from whatever nation or port
I spent long nights on the lounge room
floor chewing methedrine which we all
did in those days while studying for
exams and grinding my teeth which was
the byproduct of the same drug later
known as speed as never before to move
forward it stand tall and move sideways
and stand tall on the frontier of
necessity in a twilight of desire to
heed the command of Isaiah to go to the
humble cockroach and seek his advice ask
not what you can do for pretty girls now
your own core is dead ask what pretty
girls can do for you and how often and
what in their view it's the ultimate
cost sometimes in waking dreams there
were certain events that came back into
my mind from that fateful seventh day
adventists
camp in 1956 and furthermore in ezekiel
35 8 you see now will fill his mountains
but his slain men and in thy heels and
in high valleys and in all thy rivers
shall they fall and that's we received
the word on the first day of the ninth
month cripes it's right so that means
okay the seventh-day Adventist will be
wiped out on September the first in the
mountain where they dwell the campground
it will be a very of dry bones
that's next Saturday no so time is short
you must make a commitment now before
the Lord come it's like a thief in the
night with power and great glory and
watch the destruction from across the
road look I'll come back in the morning
alright I'm gonna be bonkers and he's
gotta be made theorists I write this
under the horrific share of the
probability of the knowledge that I'm
writing to you of my feelings for you
for the last time on this earth what it
says so much about what you mean - man
what unending happiness it's lasted a
few days and I'd like a can of Netflix
and if you got enough chicken you know
we're out of not chicken box Turkey no
the world looked just the same I
couldn't believe it was coming to me
maybe it wasn't but it'll write it up
last chance in the world
no sorry
in the end I just couldn't run out on my
own people for a joker with one arm a
dish mop and a magpie on his roof
however spot on he might have been which
I truly suspected he was mourning yeah
yeah possibly
tell me did you ever go to church school
no I didn't quite right to advise your
mother not to send you there on the
ground that it would rot your mind you
know no thanks I never went look at me
president of the Australasian communion
I think you have a good mind to young
Elkin and God has a purpose for it
he'll let you know what it is faster
deeply man
did you really stone that horse for five
days yeah it was just a dramatic effect
the week moved in eggs durably towards
Saturday I felt very alone I kept a
straight face through my remaining days
on this troubled planet and tried to
enjoy myself but the old pleasures
didn't seem the same thou Lord who
knoweth all things because thou wert a
man thyself and did suffer even as we do
something
yay even a toothache probably Lord look
down upon us with thy mercy what
eighteen and sixth circuit's of them
that don't sound much like since I'll
tell you what you best keep Albert you
give me the odd eighteenpence this would
be on the stage yeah but being on the
stage is a sin my father was a musical
the flow is converted get away luck you
saw the light few papers sister white
says it's a sin to tell a joke with no
moral purpose just to raise enough yeah
have y'all beat say that lots of things
you mustn't do out there when you sit
with me Saturday yes but I won't hold
him
not before you engaged or kiss before
you marry that's right that never
happened you reckon never happen again
no no what's wrong with you it's it's a
free country isn't it well will you sit
with me Saturday
I want you to get up out of your seat
every man-jack off you for tiny joy and
out of your seats for time is fleeting
the Son of man cometh like a thief in
the night and you know about the hour
when the son of man cometh hip hop that
of your seats wood is nigh oh yes the
day is high the clear blue sky and on a
cloud no bigger than a man's hand
strange I thought I was in gold on the
Lord he's risen
raise the Lord praise the Lord
let the earth hear his boys worry Jim up
its the Lords will miss you all
well we're for it you reckon yep
tomorrow will be all of us did like
flies it's in Ezekiel what you like to
join our visit
oh yeah it's to like started well it's
our last night on earth how do you
reckon the order spender let's rifle the
wingman
what let's rape all the women all of
them
what do you may not I'll hold him down
what we want right two of them yeah yeah
that's right
on the last night of the world then our
wonder fired act one last rage against
the dying of the light was to change the
laboratory signs around and write up
some rude graffiti and go quite early to
bed I tried to write up my diary for you
know posterity what it was like to be
one who knew the end had come but I soon
dozed off and mum turned off the life
no one died the next day or the next
they took up the collection and that
night I said well Esther at the pictures
we are certain de Bruyne me a good seven
go go ahead other blokes old bugger up
me a said and a boy
this man had two wives before God's
light came into his life he had to
choose which one to send away he said it
made him sad but God's will must be done
this is his second her name is mom to
them all he knows
did you do that for didn't show respect
that's what I said I wouldn't do what
sister white says we mustn't do you're
not really Christian don't think I
should sit with you again well next year
maybe no not ever
right yeah no can't stop me
are they old sport as you go Sarah
terrific we've just been there kissing
around the corner geez can't pick him
Kenya I mean he choked up the armadale
next Christmas
see you sir I did good with you
committed a mortal sin
what when the gravedigger some don't
like it should right there neither
chance I think we ought to figure B even
thought of that all right if you can't
why forget anything I think we ought to
decide something's just didn't happen
okay didn't happen
didn't happen you you're all flaming mad
you have this fantasy like I live in the
real world see you next year
okay bye
don't take it out on me okay and so the
two beautiful sisters walked away out of
my life I wrote to Esther for the next
two years and she wrote primly back to
me and the next year at camp she sat
with Allen Rawlins and the pictures a
good clean Christian boy
whose dad was also a minister and the
next year she didn't come because she
was in the loony bin for a while I
watched her walk away and knew how much
I had lost by taking her hand being a
seventh-day adventists was hard but it
was kind of fair they quickly sorted out
the ones they couldn't trust like Meryl
and me branded us with the Mark of Cain
and sent us wandering fugitive sinners
through the Land of Nod for all our days
at dawn next day after his long
all-night vigil the Shepherd's rod
packed up his gear and drove south he
drove to a green hill near cost Harbor
one that he used to run on as a kid
he walked for half a mile down long
trodden paths towards the sea and on a
rocky headland he used to pray on when
he was a troubled kid like me he blew
his head off he was a true believer you
see he truly believed
the next day the camp packed up and we
all went home that afternoon I went to
see Deb in Lismore Base Hospital
doing his deathbed scene though he lived
for 20 more years they've never missed
an opportunity to be memorable an
adequate definition of love and I found
it yesterday when a reader's digest the
nice brought to me and what could have
been the last hour of me life it's this
fullness of response yes it's good it's
not only good it is sufficient our young
yokomen although we speak with the
tongues of men and of angels and have
not that fullness of response we're not
worth to you understand
yesterday good
a good man positively thank you my boy
within the past week unmistakable
evidence has established the fact that a
series of offensive missile sites is now
in preparation on that imprisoned Island
acting therefore the defense of our own
security and of the entire Western
Hemisphere in denied the second
denominator
hello Ken yeah I can't talk to you now
yes you can
what's there to talk about yeah what do
you think about Cuba yes it's terrible
isn't it the end of the world isn't I
come over where are you
Whaley 50y strict led to you left a pair
of socks behind yeah I was just dreaming
about you just did are you yes you're a
lot nicer in dreams than you are in real
life
yeah well come on over
no it's a big line in the papers this
morning the Russian down out of Cuba by
the in a time kike what I can't see you
Ken of course you can there's a court on
this phone call I didn't mean that to
happen
yeah well somehow you could have stopped
it was daddy he was very angry he
believes in the sanctity of private
property including you maybe I could
come over for an hour I've got a lecture
at 10:00
I'll see you in 20 minutes
this is miss I can touch I know where
everything is this way accessible at the
leftover food okay
joining coffee or what some some oyster
I've got some oysters No
mr. what no summer both people I'm a
doubt anybody in particular
mommy's been matchmaking she wants me to
marry Kerry Packer
don't decide should I marry
yeah in the seventh-day adventists well
Christ comes back sharp sword and raises
all the righteous did
thanks love to heaven Christmas I stand
on a safe glass before the throne of God
sing a song that under your lip did God
cannot then Jerusalem comes back dress
and the wicked are all set cast and were
like a fire which cleanses us and turns
it into a beautiful green place the
throne of God the elephant the lion lays
down with the lamb no happily ever after
you stay with me today
at last
she lay there in my arms through the
long warm moon sometimes moving nearer
turning smiling in her sleep her breath
was the purest Pepsodent i watched with
burning eyes and grinding teeth and took
another methedrine so as to be all
bright and witty again when she woke up
why one o'clock my mind was running far
ahead of me I developed a desire to get
in some provisions for the impending
atomic attack it's not true Catholic
Catholic doesn't commit suicide he'll be
all right
he'll be in his concrete bunker drinking
champagne
I couldn't believe it Sydney had to be
the prime target area in the southern
hemisphere and everyone was sustained
portable exactly the kind of place they
bombed showing in business
I walked down familiar streets for an
hour and then other streets I saw people
walking shopping I saw things very
clearly and then I knew what I must do
look move go West miles waste away from
the fall oh dear what's wrong I haven't
done my essay is it so soon as your
priorities woman concentrate I don't
like this it feels like money arms
control yourself it's a reasonable
precaution
hang on we've got to see McAllister what
McAllister he's a friend we had this
appointment at 7:30 to watch a Bob
Mitchum movie man with a gun
have you got a roadmap No
hang on ins down here I think no it's
not
Callister hang on no I just watched his
third shot of the riding into terrible
touch a cup of coffee you know we're
going to the mountains in case the city
gets hurt amide bond please come with us
that's a great beach a movie she's best
performance it's true this obsession
with Bob Mitchum McAlister there are
greater things at stake the survival of
poetry as an art form and devastated
continent I think I've seen you in one
of these moods before gee I really hate
your place
listen it's free and she's a nice lady
look you're pairing kind I won't dignify
that she like some coffee genuine tea
d please dad teabags and the Thomas
Aquinas Thomas Aquinas teabags my all
views of the world are worth at least
considering had that before
even those of Nostradamus that's a cruel
thrust as recently as the Suez Crisis of
1956 you saw a Nostradamus proof of the
worlds it was a reasonable mistake has
you done this before
oh yes by turning the tap you'll get
water it's the latest modern invention
but I fall in the water you'll get see
what am I making pay for the end of the
world is nigh and do you mean that
sincerely
absolutely Jenny don't listen to this
elite social-climbing presbyterian I
really liked your poem spring Hale now
listen the water in the jug
let us what's this gunfire it's like
Japanese belly MacAlister it's nine
o'clock
I don't like Japanese ballet and there
are ships moving towards each other in
the Caribbean Sea this is lovely
nuclear submarines Mitchum's really got
something and that's all I'm gonna do a
sequence of Eddie's implications here
abductors pterodactyls for all I care
I'm leaving we're leaving
speak for yourself I'd like to watch the
end of the movie no come on now a
Callister it's fruitless to say a bitten
and desirable to pronounce it correctly
forever and forever farewell Brutus if
you meet again
then we shall smile if not why then this
party was rolling you took the words
right out of my mouth what do you mean
you're a fucking idiot
you're not that dungeon baby
it's something wrong with you shut up
and light me a cigarette you push that
thing down there
but you don't smoke I started again
we drove on up through the calm spring
night towards Kitumba
I felt very heroic very much in love
what a crumble bar
no thanks hey there's no radio in this
car no daddy said he needed his thinking
time
the street lamps in the suburbs receded
behind us I thought of all the good days
I had had on the cricket field today
McAllister got his hat track my triumph
is bottom in our cut down high school
version of Midsummer Night's Dream the
long afternoons riding home of Whelan
and McAlister talking about teachers and
lard and girls my young people's meeting
about the Shroud of Turin and how the
resurrection was thereby proved with the
aid of modern science I thought of the
life ahead with Jenny and her Jaguar
radiator driving west hopping blood
getting married in Burke or Broken Hill
it felt very good somehow
I must have dozed off I remember the
methedrine lights on the back of my
eyelids when I woke up the car was
stopped and Jenny was on the verge of
crying what's happy
that's King's College Parramatta
Johnnie's there my brother
why do you ring your father yes maybe
once your father in the place yes
let's go on I began to wonder if I was
driving less with the wrong girl
she was markedly different in her mood
from how she was that afternoon in bed I
thought of her submission to her
father's desire to have me put in you Jo
I thought of rich girls in general their
fickleness and passion for transitory
thrills could I this long night be like
that now to her
on the mountaintop at a scenic lookout
with a handy view of the mushroom cloud
over Sydney we made love I changed my
mind
I knew she loved me and we were destined
for this moment you do it better than
anyone else' sippy a couple sins are you
angry I think it makes me more excited
good
vaguely over my shoulder I was waiting
for an explosion that will wipe away the
old world as I made love again it's
easier when you're 19
I found myself growing impatient what
did you think we're ready here my father
went in at d-day with the first wave he
was a war correspondent he went all the
way with the 8th army to the Elbe linked
up at the Elbe he I didn't get to know
him better yes it is
he wasn't afraid of a big war
I didn't know
seven about the wall what war we're in
Cuba
Dina Conan in a ballistic missiles and
then ships heading towards one another
beats me mate
around with ago I realized it wasn't
going to happen it was good news I guess
we could go back to Sydney and do our
exams get on with our careers get
married there suddenly that didn't seem
like a guy It was as though we were
tuned up for the end of the world and
nothing else wouldn't do it all
I'm not sure if it was the loss of his
daughter or the loss of his Jagua that
annoy data Brian the most there was a
rough night overall
are you playing fine
I was first charged with kidnapping and
then car theft and then driving without
a license but Jenny said that was all
wrong and in the end they let me go with
extreme bad grace I rang up Jenny and
asked if she'd marry me she said she
think about it I never heard from her
again I saw her across the room at the
exams but then she got away and the next
thing I heard she was on a world trip
with her mother I started going to
parties now there are other girls in the
world what's about then just return as
it was and a spirit shall return
auntie auntie save the preacher
I went north on the train to armoured I
obviously whale and Mary survived she
was a nursing sister already and
supporting him while he finished college
it was strange being welcomed there as
the pen friend of their crazy daughter
these were my own people I felt at home
and not at home at the same time I
wasn't one of them anymore but I should
have been hello mr. Elkin yes Thornton
you've gone crazy I'm better now
no this breakdance I don't know things
everything
where are you teaching you has mania but
I'm new things are Sydney in January
you thinking
I should have died when I tried
don't do this again
if you would do
did you keep my business
one Sunday soon after that I got a fall
from Macalester and you spent the Sunday
together the way we used to
I burgled the staff club when we got in
drank wine and ate cheese and Jats
crackers and talked long hours in our
old companionable way eventually
McCallister's said My dear chap do you
the first day of the period from the
first days of period why do you ask
well oh no that's all it's only the 13th
day 13th day what's right isn't in the
girl no yes I think she did funny
Twilight came down over the quadrangle
by a coincidence we found a
contraceptive on the flagstones and we
blew it up and tied it off like a
balloon and chased it all over the
quadrangle hitting at it with sticks it
was the last day of McCallister's youth
it was just another day of mine some of
us hang on to our childhood longer some
of us give it up willingly I don't know
who is the wise
I think it came down to how McAllister
was better behaved than I was that was
where the Presbyterians had it over the
adventists when they came down to the
big city the Adventists by contrast had
this problem of fullness of response I
don't think I ever got over
we did know what I want your thought I
can feel you really there I can't say
anything I am Alpha and Omega the
beginning and the end man comes to the
Father but by me it's easy for you to
say we were both brought up in primitive
religions I can be a comfort sometimes
back if I could see wait wait you will
see
wasted and wounded I waited out the next
15 years but the disease got worse I
fell in love eight times I went to war I
got fired from four newspapers on points
of principle fought with collaborators
and producers addressed political
rallies lost friends lost hope regained
never attempted suicide never fulfilled
the potential that Dibley finally dying
said I became that kind of weekly
columnist you love to hate chaste women
grew older neglected my teeth turned 40
it happened fairly quickly all of it and
there I was two weeks after my birthday
I was eating at the Opera House
oh hi sorry happy happy birthday
you two sit down oh yeah of course
Esther's still in salon in the leper
colony she's lost weight system yeah a
couple of fingers her nose don't say
that it's bad luck
so how's your wife and kids great right
you prefer to eat without them well I
write a lot of cafes this apply at my
nan yeah oh can I buy you a drink
yes you can
so well what happened well don't you
know how mrs. white is supposed to be
inspired by God
yeah I turned out half of what she wrote
was copied off other people other
writers that much couldn't have been
inspired could it and she said it was
my old bitch say the whole church is
falling apart we left two months ago
we're trying to catch up on wine and
things like that you done I appreciate
your advice anytime geez
well it's a long way from Gunilla bar
campground yeah everyone else believes
in the end of the world now
Tomic war Nostradamus terminal pollution
McAllister and generating Bane's shoots
of building a fallout shelter in their
own backyard
well everyone needs a hobby
we won didn't we convince small end of
the world is nigh maybe these no no I
reckon no apocalypse never
I don't like the sound of that
I looked out and across the lights of
the civilization I still wasn't a part
of I thought about everything and didn't
help
it said to me this is the moment don't
you see me seize the moment seize me out
there were simple hearts back there and
so true
and took the music and did not be too
wise but today when all this and the
human heart is stone there is no more
comfort to be heard from romantic lies
I saw things clear by how young love can
stand us out to die we make use to die
true but we understand
and beyond my love is yours find out
there is one
yes sir it will all be right someday we
will take the road together to the gate