(film reel whirring)
(chimes jingling)
(shining music)
{ominous music)
(horn honking)
(door clicking)
(sighs)
(pills rattling)
(door grating)
(sizzling)
(knocking)
- Just a minute.
(sirens wailing in the distance)
(posh music)
Hi.
- [Josef] Hi.
- Come on in.
- And uh, somebody let
me inside the building.
Uh, and I'm sorry I'm
late, but the trains were--
- No problem.
- This is a really nice place.
- Thanks.
- And, uh, 1, I brought some wine.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Very nice of you.
Can I take your jacket?
- (laughs) Yeah.
Yeah.
- You know you're really very cute, Joe.
- Usually I don't like it
when people call me that.
(Josef chuckles)
Uh, can 1 use your bathroom?
- It's right in there.
(water sloshing)
(thudding)
Make yourself at home.
I'll be ready in a minute.
(sophisticated music)
(knife grating)
- Isn't it hard to find what you want?
- T like how it looks.
- This, uh, (laughs)
this feels all grown up.
(Josef laughs)
- Yeah.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
Oh, this is good. (laughs)
um,
and um, how long you been living here for?
- About five years.
- [Josef] Ah, (laughs)
I've only been here a year
and I already moved out twice.
- Uh-huh, T know how it goes, man.
Twas like that when 1
first moved here too.
Where did you say you were from again?
- Um, Murmage.
- Excuse me?
- [Josef] Murmage?
- I'love Murmage.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
I love to murmage.
I love murmaging.
There's nothing I love more
than a cold murmage on the Murmage.
(Josef laughs)
That's just about Mississippi, actually.
Most of us only say our own
name, like uh, like Pokemon.
(John laughs)
Yeah. (laughs)
- How's the wine?
- It's way better than the
seven bucks I spent on it.
And uh, it's exactly
the right temperature.
- Yours is in the fridge.
(Josef laughs)
- And um, is this your usual routine?
- (laughs) Excuse me?
- [Josef] I mean, you know.
- [John] No.
- For dates.
- [John] Oh.
- For uh, guys who come in here.
- [John] Mm-hm.
- The, the, the food, the wine, the music,
I mean.
- Mm-hm, yeah.
- It's good!
(Josef laughs)
It is good.
I'm sorry, it's not a bad thing.
Um, I'm uh, (laughs) I'm feeling seduced.
(John and Josef laughing)
- Well, I'm not sure you can seduce
somebody you've already fucked.
Would you like some more wine?
- Yeah.
- All right.
(elegant music)
(gentle music)
- I'm on the couch. (laughs)
- (laughs) Apparently.
Oh hey, hey, hey.
(glasses clinking)
(Josef chuckles)
- Okay, what's your deal, all right?
- I'm sorry?
- I mean who, who are you?
1, I know who you are, I, I think.
1, 1don't know, 1 was
pretty drunk that night.
- I don't know, you seemed like
you were having a good time.
It was nice.
- You live in the city.
Uh, you work at a hedge fund.
Blah, blah, and blah, that, that's boring.
I mean, that's really boring.
I wanna know the real you.
Like who are you?
What makes John tick?
- So young.
I don't know.
Why don't you start?
- All right.
I wanna change the world.
- From the reception desk?
- Whoa, hold on, I don't do that anymore.
1, I told you that?
T work in film now.
- Okay.
Okay, so, I guess, you know,
1 grew up in the middle of nowhere.
Right?
My parents were born there.
Their parents were born there.
Nobody ever left.
Ever wanted to leave,
ever thought of thinking of
leaving in the first place,
I think, I don't know.
But I was different.
But it still took me 20 years, really.
And um, now I'm here
and I see all this hot, great mess,
and, and it makes you think differently.
It's um, one thing to know
something else is out there.
It's another to see it.
To feel it.
- Mm-hm.
- Damn, I don't know, man, I don't know.
I know I sound really naive or idealistic
or you know, whatever,
but that's why--
- Whatever, that's beautiful.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You're something, you know that?
(Josef laughs)
- Shut up, what about you?
- Seriously.
(Josef laughs)
- What about me?
- Yeah.
- Ugh, I don't know.
- Whoa, whoa, come on, I (laughs)
I just sat here and told you my whole
you know, shebang, the whole thing.
You gotta give me something.
- Uh,
I guess,
for me, it's about the little things.
- What do you mean?
- What do you mean what do I mean?
I mean the little things, I
mean like my stuff, my house.
My friends, my family,
having a me-shaped place in the world.
- [Josef] That's it?
- What do you mean that's it?
Yeah.
You're kind of a dick, Joe.
- Oh whoa, I mean, in a cute way right?
That's what matters. (laughs)
- You know you actually remind me
of a guy 1 used to party
With back in the day.
He was a lot of fun at
three in the morning.
(door rattling)
- Um, what do you mean you
used to party with him?
- [John] You know.
We went out sometimes.
- Did you, um, did you
guys do stuff together?
- [John] Uh, yeah, we, uh, hooked up.
- No, no, I mean, you know.
Did you guys take stuff together?
- Occasionally.
(wine sloshing)
I mean, you're young in the city,
it seems like the obvious thing to do.
- I mean, yeah, tell me more, I wanna...
Like, what did you do?
Like, what was the best experience?
- Best part is
um, forgetting everything.
Everything heavy just falls away.
And nothing is frightening.
And everything is possible.
Aside from that, you're not missing much.
- (laughs) Wow.
Wow, um, I think I left my phone upstairs.
You mind if I check if it's--
- Sure, it's on the bed.
- Thanks.
(gentle music)
(zipper whirring)
(Josef sighs)
(melancholy rock music)
- [John] Did you find it?
- Yeah.
(dark shoegaze music)
I'm not feeling too great actually
you know, I think I might head...
- Dessert.
J Satisfaction J
(Josef chuckles)
- Sure.
2 T will come J
- [Josef] Thanks.
- No problem.
J Stay !
J Til the end
7 You'll be my lust for end J
- You made this yourself?
- I did.
- Do you, you make it often?
- Watch it.
(Josef laughs)
7 Please rewind J
7 Our perception of this night
J You compare J
& My position J
2 T will be your other side J
71 feel your gentle voice inside »
- Uh, you know this is directly pointed
at some dude's apartment, right?
- Tall blond?
- Uh, yeah.
7T hope I'm to your satisfaction
- What's he doing?
7 Woken it's time for
discussion I decide &
- He's, uh, he's talking to
someone on the couch, uh,
a guy.
It looks like he's getting intimate.
- Is he hot?
Not the blond guy, the other guy.
- Very.
7 Your gentle voice inside J
- Well what are they doing?
- Oh, Tdon't, uh, Tdon't
think 1 should keep watching.
- Come on.
Humor me.
- Okay.
Um, they're getting closer.
Now they're kissing.
Now the blond guy put his head up.
He just gave me a thumbs up!
What?
He lets you watch him?
- He watches me too!
Don't worry, not tonight, he's on a date.
(John laughs)
Relax, it's fine.
It's New York.
I always assume everybody's watching.
- That kind of weirds me out.
I don't know.
- I've nothing to hide.
- It's not about hiding, you
know, it's, it's about privacy.
- I bet you get embarrassed
kissing in public too.
I just assume these days
everybody has my information.
- That's different.
- Idon't know, I think,
there's a certain power
to living out in the open, you know?
7 Would you take it off ;
- You want some more wine?
1 mean, you barely touched
your chocolate cake.
- You know, um...
7 Decision J
7 And the road will 7
- Yeah.
J By today J
- Sure.
7 Lay me down }
7 To the final decision J
J And the road will break off today »
- Your head okay?
- [Josef] My, uh,
(laughs) my head is fine.
It's, um, (laughs)
oh, it's great.
- Are you okay?
(Josef grunts)
- Yeah, mm-hm.
- Josef.
- Hm?
Huh?
- What's going on?
- [Josef] Nothing. (laughs)
- Did you take something, Josef?
Josef, did you take something, Josef?
- [Josef] Uh...
- What did you take?
- Uh--
- You need to tell me what you took.
- It was, uh, it was
small and, uh, and white.
- Did you find it in my bedroom?
Fuck's sake.
You shouldn't have done that, Josef.
That wasn't for you.
- I'm sorry, what's it for?
- [John] It's hard to explain.
- I mean, what?
- It's experimental.
- Cool.
(laughs) I don't know what that means.
- You're gonna be okay.
All right?
I'm gonna take care of you. (laughs)
Just
give me your phone.
- [Josef] Huh?
- Give me your phone.
Come on, hand it over.
All right.
Come on.
You just, just lie here
for a minute, all right?
And, uh, I'm gonna get a drink.
- [Josef] Okay.
- [John] Don't worry too much.
Side effects shouldn't be too bad.
You only took one.
(dreamlike music)
- Oh wow!
- All right.
- [Josef] You look, um, you look great.
- You've seen me before.
- [Josef] (laughs) Oh no,
it was dark that night,
and it was, I couldn't see nothing.
- You really don't remember
anything of that night,
sure you don't?
- [Josef] Um, not a single detail.
(laughs) Oh, did I do
anything embarrassing then?
- No.
No, it was cute actually,
you were having a good time.
It was nice.
- [Josef] Mm-hm.
Who were you texting?
- Somebody I had on backup.
- Ah, okay.
You got changed.
T want to get changed too.
- Be my guest.
(Josef laughs)
(expressive music)
(Josef clears his throat)
(John chuckles)
Wow.
Yeah.
It's the belt really, actually,
that kind ties it all together, you know?
- (laughs) I know, I know, right?
This song, it's good!
- You like this song?
- Like it's, it's, it's, I
mean it's really good, like--
- How you feeling?
- T'want to dance.
- You wanna dance?
- Yeah.
- Let's dance.
Let's dance.
(Josef giggles)
How could you be a worse dancer than I am?
- Huh, it's not loud enough.
- Fuck, Joe, Jesus!
That's stupid!
I have neighbors, you know.
- Now it's too quiet.
- Okay!
All right, all right, all right.
- Yeah.
- Okay?
- Yeah, that's good.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- Feeling good?
- Feeling good.
- All, right, okay.
So now can you just--
- Huh?
- Okay, just like that, nice and slow.
All right?
Just follow my lead.
All right.
Nice and slow.
(shadowy music)
(thudding)
Oh fuck!
- I'm so sorry, John, are you okay?
You okay, hm?
(John groans)
Come on, John.
- I'm fine.
- Okay, um--
- Ah!
- [Josef] I'm gonna get
you some ice, all right,
but you gotta get up first, come on.
- I'm okay, I'm all right.
- Okay okay okay.
- I'm all right.
- Come on, get up.
Get up, please.
Sit you down right here.
Okay?
John, come on, sit down.
You okay?
(heavy breathing)
John?
(labored breathing)
(John cries out)
(heavy thudding)
Fuck!
(John grunts)
(heavy thudding)
(body thuds)
(phone rings)
- [Dispatcher] 911, what's your emergency?
Hello?
(pounding on the door)
- Hello?
It's the police!
(pounding on the door)
We received a noise complaint!
Please open the door!
(pounding on the door)
Sir, we're gonna count to five
and then we'll have to
force this door open.
Onel
Twol
Three!
Four!
Five!
(door bangs)
(troubled music)
(people murmuring)
(sirens wailing)
(chattering on police radio)
- Hey.
Word of advice.
You act like you're guilty,
they're gonna treat you like it.
Understand?
- I'm Detective Locarno.
That's Detective Matthews.
What's, ah--
- What,
what time is it?
- It's a little after one.
- (laughs) Okay.
- What's your name?
- Josef.
Uh, Josef King.
- How you feeling tonight, Joe?
- I'm, I'm okay,
I guess.
- You want anything?
You want, like, water or coffee?
- Ah, I'm okay.
Yeah.
- Can't imagine how you must
be feeling tonight, Joe--
- Josef.
T know this must be hard for you
but I'm just gonna have to
ask you a couple questions.
All right?
- Yeah, I, I can do that, mm-hm.
- There's no wrong answers here, Joe.
Just need you to tell me
to the best of your ability
exactly what happened tonight.
Do you think you can do that?
- Okay.
Um, I went on a date, all right?
Uh, we got a little dinner.
Got a little drunk.
Then we started to dance.
And then he went crazy!
Uh, he started to,
started to scream, bashing
his head against the wall.
1 tried to help him, but
I didn't know what to do!
He kept doing it again and again,
and then he wasn't moving anymore.
1 tried to call an ambulance, but
I panicked.
1, I didn't know what to do!
Uh, when the police showed up
1, I didn't open the door because
I was scared that you might think
I had something to do with it.
- I see, okay.
Um, you're doing great, Joe.
Great job.
Um, how much did you
have to drink tonight?
- Uh, a, a few glasses of wine.
- Did you know that there
were psychoactive drugs
in the apartment?
- What?
(laughs) Nah, nah, no.
Um,
psychoactive?
- It's all right if you did!
It's all right if you did.
I just need to know exactly what happened.
-1, I didn't know that.
- Good job, Joe.
You're doing fine.
- Am I under arrest?
- No, not, not right now, no.
- Can I have some water?
- Not right now.
I'm gonna ask you to do
something for me, Josef.
It's totally within your
right to refuse to do this.
But if you do,
I'm gonna have to start treating
you more like a suspect.
- Okay.
- T want to examine your clothing.
T want to just see if everything lines up,
if your story checks out.
All right, do I have
your consent to do that?
- Okay.
- That's all right?
- Uh-huh.
- All right.
Excellent.
- [Detective Locarno] Well?
- Um, yeah, I'll get changed now.
- There you go.
No, no!
You can keep those.
Thank you, Josef.
I just need some biographical
information now on you.
Uh, for the records.
When I ask you a question
I need you to answer out loud.
- [Josef] Yeah.
- Full sentences, please.
- Yeah, uh, you can, uh,
(laughs) ask me some questions.
- Thank you, Josef.
Not so difficult, right?
Uh, state and spell your name for me.
(door clicking)
- Um, Josef.
J-O-S-E-F.
-
- Yeah.
- Why not P-H?
- (laughs) I don't know.
Uh, Josef King.
L TN-G. I.
- T'know how to spell King.
Uh, what's your occupation?
- Um, I work in film.
- What do you do?
- Uh, I'm an assistant manager
slash associate producer.
- What does that mean?
- Oh, uh, well a manager's
kind of like an agent
and a producer--
- T know what managers and producers do.
What I'm asking you is what does it mean
to be an associate manager
slash assistant producer?
- Well, um,
uh, well, um,
T work at a boutique
agency, and what we do--
- How big?
- What?
- How big's your agency?
- Well, there's the owner.
- [Detective Locarno] Okay.
- And then
there's me.
- Two people, that's it?
- [Josef] Yeah.
- How much talent do you manage?
Clients, Joe.
How many clients you got?
- Uh, (laughs) we're in
discussion with a number
of potential clients at this--
- How many?
- Uh,
at present,
we currently have
a single, primary client.
- One client.
So let me get this straight.
You
and one guy--
- Woman.
A woman.
- You work with one
woman, who has one client.
That's it.
What do you do?
- T identify possible projects
and implement outreach strategies.
- How much money you make?
- Why does that matter?
- You really want to be telling me
what matters right now, Joe?
All right, we'll let that one go.
Uh, how old are you?
-21
(Detective Matthews laughs)
25.
- Hm.
- (laughs) All right, 26!
(laughs) Okay, okay.
- Isn't your late 20s still, like
a little old to be trying
to make it in film?
- I think 26 is still your mid-twenties?
- Is that true?
- How well did you know Jesse Burstner?
- Who?
- The deceased.
So,
not well.
- Uh,
he didn't, didn't, um--
- How did you know Jesse?
- I,
I--
- That's John to you.
- I'mean, I knew him obviously, you know?
But I didn't really know him.
We were just starting to get
to know each other, you know.
- What was the nature
of your relationship?
- Uh, too soon to say.
- Was it sexual?
- Was what sexual?
- Was the relationship with
John, Jesse, was it sexual?
- I think so? (laughs)
- You don't know if you
had a sexual relationship?
- (laughs) Of course I do.
I think.
Yes we did have a sexual relationship.
(laughs) I mean--
- Are you a,
are you a top?
Are you a top?
- Idon't, I mean--
- It's a simple question, really.
Do you fuck or do you get fucked?
- Oh, I don't accept the dichotomy
implied by your question. (laughs)
- Josef.
- Yeah.
- I'need an answer to my question, Josef.
- Are you allowed to ask that?
- Sure, why not?
- Privacy?
- Joe.
Privacy is for people
in houses and offices.
Privacy isn't for people like you.
So I'll just, I'll ask you again.
Um, you know.
Uh, do you fuck or do you get fucked?
- I guess
I'm more of a bottom.
- So your preferred sexual activity
is just bend over and let
another man fuck you in the ass.
- Uh, (laughs) I don't
think I'd put it that way.
- How would you put it?
- What?
- How would you describe your
preferred sexual activity?
- Oh, um, I guess
I would say that,
hm,
I like to
dick-tate the terms?
(Josef laughs)
Right?!
(Detective Matthews laughs fakely)
That's great!
Can I have some water? (laughs)
Oh! (laughs)
Oh, dick-tate.
'Can 1, can 1 please have some water? '?
Oh man.
- Uh, come with me.
- Oh.
- Her, not you.
Get in.
You asked for water?!
(water splashing)
Three times!
Uh, so Josef.
What time did you get to
Jesse's apartment tonight?
Why don't you sit down?
You're gonna get tired
just standing there.
- T'want a lawyer.
- Josef, think about what
you're asking for, all right?
Up to now, it's been two guys,
just you and me talking, all right?
As soon as you ask for a lawyer
it becomes something totally different.
Something serious.
- I
Want a lawyer.
- It's your choice.
- And uh,
weren't you supposed to read
me my rights or something?
- We did, you don't remember?
(knocking)
- Hello?
- [Amanda] Hello?
This is Amanda Hastler.
Do I have your permission to enter?
- Um, I, I, I guess so?
- [Amanda] This is Amanda Hastler.
Do I have your permission to enter?
- Yes, you have my permission!
- Mr. King?
(eerie music)
Hello, Mr. King.
I'm Amanda Hastler.
I'm a public defender.
I'm your lawyer.
- Ow.
Okay then.
(strange music)
Won't you have a seat?
(perplexed music)
The county has briefed me on
the particulars of your case.
It's all gonna be okay.
- They tortured someone just
because 1 asked for water.
- That must have been very hard.
- They can't do that.
Well?
- What?
- Aren't you gonna tell
somebody, or do something?
- T'want you to focus on you, Josef.
(shadowy music)
This is the defense 1
have prepared for you.
(questioning music)
- Um, don't you want me to
tell you what happened first?
- No, absolutely not.
Please, just read it, Mr. King.
You'll find it's very good.
(bizarre music)
What's the matter with you?
- Oh, uh, sorry.
(Josef coughs)
(mysterious music)
- The county seems to think
they have a strong case against you.
- Oh, um,
they're only confident
because they're so stupid.
(creepy music)
- I'm gonna arrange for you
to speak with the prosecutor tonight.
We need to convince them
that you're a good person.
- Mm-hm.
(shadowy music)
- Have you made your phone call?
- Uh, I don't think so.
- Oh, do I not.
You should call someone.
- [Josef] Who?
- I don't know.
Your family, your employer.
Isn't anyone gonna miss you tomorrow?
- Not really.
(perplexed music)
- I'm gonna have them bring a phone.
{ominous music)
(knocking)
(beeping)
(phone ringing)
- [Dispatcher] 911, what's your emergency?
Hello?
- I think they're sleeping.
(knocking)
- Hey.
- Hello?
(phone beeps)
(phone ringing)
- [Dispatcher] 911, what's your emergency?
Hello?
(dial tone droning)
(phone beeps)
(Detective Matthews laughs)
- Joe, Joey, Josef.
Are you surprised?
- Not really.
- Not even a little?
- Aren't there people watching?
- Silly Joey.
We don't have the budget for that.
You people turn me on so much.
- Gays?
(Detective Matthews laughs)
(head thudding)
- No.
- Blacks?
- Guess again.
- Men?
- Suspects.
Watching you
all scared and
guilty and helpless
quivering under the
harsh light of the law.
It gets me
ah
Every
single
time.
(Detective Matthews groans)
(Detective Matthews screeches)
(Josef coughs)
Josef.
I could tell them anything
and they would believe me over you.
I could say
you tried to escape,
that you assaulted me.
You wouldn't want that.
Would you?
(dramatic music)
No!
No, you don't know what's out there!
(urgent music)
Ma'am.
- Who are you talking to?
- Her.
(scary music)
Bow.
(foreboding music)
- Listen, we...
Good evening, ma'am.
(strange music)
We need his lawyer present.
(spooky music)
Counselor.
- Detective.
(bizarre music)
Your move.
(suspenseful music)
(Detective Locarno snorts)
You don't have to answer
that if you don't want to.
(mysterious music)
Sh!
Careful.
(strange music)
(terrifying music)
(head thuds)
(birds chirping)
(door bangs)
- (laughs) I don't think you're
supposed to smoke in here.
- What are they gonna do, arrest me?
(flame crackling)
- What did you do?
- Nothing.
- Then why are you here?
- That's a good question.
They think that I killed someone.
- Did you?
- Potato, potahto.
(Joshua and Josef laughing)
- Can I have one?
- Inhale.
Look, just take this one.
(flame crackling)
Enough, enough!
- That's it? (laughs)
- Did you inhale?
Did you breathe the smoke into your lungs
or did you just hold it in your mouth?
(flame crackling)
Now exhale.
(Josef coughs)
(Josef laughs)
- Never got it before.
(door clicks)
- Hello, Josef.
How are you feeling?
- Okay, I, uh...
- We need a new strategy.
Liesje Burstner wants to meet you.
1 think that's a good idea.
- Who?
- Jesse's sister.
- Oh.
- Her support could mean a lot.
Josef?
Is it all right with you?
- Yeah.
Okay, yeah, yeah.
- Wait here a moment.
(knocking)
(door clicking)
Try this on.
Raise your arms.
Roll it up.
There.
- You see a lot of cases like mine?
- I see cases like yours all the time.
Take a seat.
Get up.
- Good to meet you.
- I was wrong.
- What?
What do you mean?
- Idon't want to talk to him.
- [Detective Locarno] Are you sure?
- I don't want to talk about Jesse.
- He told me his name was John.
- Of course he did.
I want to go now.
- I'll take you to another room.
We just have a few more questions.
- No.
- [Detective Locarno] Ma'am.
- Oh I can't.
I can't.
I've been answering your
questions all night.
1 was his sister.
I want to hold on to
the person that he was.
With me.
T want my grief.
My sadness.
If I tell you about him
he becomes the person
that you can understand.
The facts that I can tell you,
but he was much more than that.
I want to hold on to
the person that he was.
T want to remember him for everything.
Not just part of it.
I knew more than anyone else,
and with every little bit that fades,
and he dies again.
And again and again.
1 don't want to talk about him anymore.
- I'm, I'm sorry.
(knocking)
Um, Detective Locarno?
Um, I wanted to make a complaint
about inappropriate treatment.
Um, Detective Matthews really--
- Who?
What?
Who are you talking about?
- Detective Matthews.
- Idon't know what
incident you're referring to
but there is no Detective Matthews here.
- She looks just like my lawyer and,
but um,
she
didn't have any pants on.
Um, those questions were
inappropriate.
Those question you asked me about my job
and being gay
and sex and
what I like.
It was,
it was homophobic.
- Kid, I've been a cop
in the city for 23 years.
I don't know what you were doing tonight
but I was doing my job.
If you think otherwise, call your lawyer.
1 like her, she's very good.
Listen, it's been a long night.
Let's just forget about this.
- Well.
That didn't go as well
as I would have liked.
Now what happens is
the county decides whether
or not to release you
or charge you.
Depending on the decision
after that your options can be--
- Ms. Hayser.
- Hastler.
- Oh, sorry.
Um,
Ms. Hastler.
1 think I should tell you something.
- Go ahead.
- Um, my parents,
my family
are kind of
kind of important.
In the city.
In politics.
We're kind of a
important family
here.
And you know my last name is King, right?
- Mm-hm.
- My parents are Kings.
They are the Kings.
I'm adopted.
- You're a King.
- Yeah.
- You're the adopted son
of David and Jessica King?
- Yeah.
- Are you shitting me?
- No, no!
No, they really are my parents.
You can look it up and see everything.
I mean there's, there's
pictures and stuff, you know.
- And you thought this
might be helpful to mention?
Why didn't you say something earlier?
- Idon't like using it.
They're just my parents.
- I have to go tell them.
There's no way the county will
bring charges against a King.
Not now.
Give me a few minutes,
I'll see what I can do.
Would you mention my name to your father?
If you feel like it's
appropriate, of course.
- Uh, yeah.
Yeah, of course.
- Great.
(knocking)
(banging)
- You're free to go, Mr. King.
- Where's, um,
Ms. Hastler?
I wanted to thank her.
- She's busy.
I'll let her know.
- Okay.
Hello?
(perplexing music)