They doubted I'd live long enough
to see him start school.
But I did...
I was there.
Apparently,
he's made lots of friends.
He's more sociable than I thought.
I'd love to watch him grow up.
Wish I could have a little longer...
Although I know it won't happen.
Matsuri, my dear...
live every minute to the fullest.
The Last 10 Years
August 14th, 2013.
It's sunny... incredibly sunny.
Perfect weather to leave hospital.
My lengthy stay is finally over.
What are you doing? Lend a hand.
Here is my totally
unsympathetic sister.
Mom, you're talking too much,
hurry up.
OK...
You owe her a lot.
We should thank her properly.
Hello.
Dr Hirata.
Thank you for everything.
Congratulations on
going home, Matsuri.
Doctor, we're so grateful
for all you have done.
Not at all.
It's a new chapter.
Is that the SkyTree?
Yep, finished last year.
Wow, it's massive.
I want to go see it.
Sis, let's go together.
No way. I can't stand heights.
That's not fair.
I'll write in my will
that you wouldn't take me.
Hey, don't guilt trip me.
Enough filming. Give it here.
Two years on, home sweet home.
Wait.
I'm home.
It's much tidier than when I left.
First Prize:
Story Writing Competition
Takabayashi Matsuri
Happy 20th Birthday
Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension
or PAH
Usually terminal, limited treatment
Incidence: 1 or 2 cases per million
High risk of sudden mortality
Show-Your-Belly-Button contest!
An older woman with PAH
joins our ward
BFF's... Matsuri & Sanae
Cultural Festival
Life expectancy: 10 years
Matsuri!
Welcome back, Matsuri!
Thank you, guys!
Two, three.
Thank you so much...
This is Akira,
the restaurant manager.
Congratulations.
- Much appreciated.
- Thank you very much.
- Shall I cut the cake?
- Please.
- Alright.
- Thank you.
- Is that him?
- He's the boyfriend?
Yes, he is.
Are you serious?
- So?
- Put it away!
How annoying!
This really takes me back.
It's just like college.
You're right.
I just wish the school
had been more helpful.
They should've made
a special exception for you.
I wish we could've
graduated together.
Thank you.
But everything's good now?
I still need a monthly check-up.
I never imagined you'd be in
that long. We were so worried.
In any case, you're out now.
Get a boyfriend, get to work...
Your whole life's ahead of you!
You've got to embrace it.
Heck, I hate my job.
They want a meeting
at this hour? Forget it.
- Bye, gals.
- Bye-bye!
They haven't changed at all.
Taking it easy at home for a while?
I guess.
By the way, are you still writing?
Your novel?
I gave up while I was in hospital.
There was nothing to write about.
I always loved your writing.
I've become an editor
and I find we're always
short of writers.
If you could lend a hand,
it'd be amazing.
I wouldn't want to disappoint you.
That's not likely.
I'll take this.
Dad?
I see you, yeah.
I'd better go.
Thanks for today.
Anyway, call me
if you change your mind.
- See you.
- Bye-bye.
- I'm home.
- Welcome back.
Nice to see the old gang?
It was fun.
Something came for you in the mail.
What's that?
"Disability allowance"?
That's a lot!
In exchange for my body and soul.
Don't say that.
They chose a nostalgic spot.
What is it? A class reunion?
Invitation to Mishima M.S. Reunion
Haven't seen them
since graduating middle school.
Sounds like fun.
Class reunions are great for
finding your future husband.
I'm never falling in love.
You never know.
But it might be fun.
Nobody there knows about my illness.
2020 Summer Olympics
to be held in Tokyo
Tokyo will be hosting.
56 years since the last time.
The Tokyo Olympics
are seven years off.
What kind of event will it be?
This takes me back...
You haven't seen them since?
Right.
I wonder how they're doing?
Call if you don't feel well, OK?
I know that.
Say something.
It takes me back.
Is that all you can say?
Sorry.
I'll be fine, OK?
You going in?
Sorry, go ahead.
Takabayashi?
You are...
Matsuri? Is it you?
Miyuki?
It's been a while!
You haven't changed at all!
Really?
Matsuri...
Miyuki, show me your daughter...
- Here.
- Let me see.
She's grown even more.
But she's quite a handful.
But adorable, too.
No, she's a little monster.
Matsuri, you're in Tokyo, right?
Yes.
Lucky you. What do you do?
Well... just a regular office job.
Wow. An office gig in Tokyo.
What kind of office?
Publishing related.
Publishing!
Us Tokyo folks should hang out.
It'll be the three of us. Eh, Kazu?
Let's get together in Tokyo.
Sure...
You're still in Tokyo?
Didn't you take over
your dad's company?
It's a total mystery.
He'd be set for life.
Why don't you?
Well, it's not
as easy as you think.
- Unbelievable...
- What's the problem?
Takeru, it's time for the main event.
Oh, you're right.
Listen everyone, check this out.
Do you remember this?
Our time capsules!
"Letters to Our Future Selves!"
I'll call out your names
and hand them out.
Here we go!
Nabe, your turn!
Takabayashi Matsuri
Here you go, Matsuri!
Matsuri, here.
Manabe Kazuto, here you go!
To myself ten years from now:
How are you? I'm exhausted
with studies and sports.
But I'm happy and working hard.
What job do you do, I wonder?
Any boyfriends?
Did you become a writer?
Please have a great life.
This way to the next bar!
This way, everyone!
Manabe.
Everyone's going to the next place.
Are you OK?
I'll get you some water.
Here...
It's been ages since I saw anyone.
I was so nervous,
I drank way too much.
You must wonder why I even came...
Takabayashi...
You don't remember me, do you?
That's not true.
When we were in eighth grade...
you fixed a button for me
and I never forgot
how happy that made me.
Oh yeah, I think I remember that.
There's no way you'd remember.
You're right. Sorry.
We're off.
Leave each other alone.
They've all grown up.
We used to have so much fun.
Today was fun.
See you.
Dismissal Notice
To myself ten years from now:
I guess you're slaving away
at Dad's company
busy at work and in love.
Have fun as an adult.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, these are the ones.
Yellow in the front.
Why are you dressed like that?
Job interview.
Anything to do with the reunion?
Not particularly.
Just don't want to die of boredom.
Don't talk about dying
in front of them, OK?
I know that.
Don't be in a rush.
Go at your own pace.
Yes. See you later.
Good luck.
Let's see.
You quit college in your junior year.
Yes.
Any part-time work experience?
None.
I see.
By the way, are you fully recovered?
Well...
Mother
Hello?
Matsuri, sorry I'm late.
Traffic was terrible.
Thank you so much for coming.
What's going on?
Well...
I don't really know myself.
Seems like he jumped off his veranda.
It's not life-threatening
but his folks called
asking me to go see him.
Why the hell don't they go?
Excuse me.
Why are you here?
Your dad got in touch.
What's going on?
I see.
Sorry to bother you.
Both of you.
Heck...
Did you have a fight with your folks?
They ought to be here.
Ought to...
I basically cut all ties.
They're better off
without me, I guess.
That's your reason?
I don't know.
Buddy.
Is this about your job?
I got fired last month.
That's no reason to jump...
I had fun the other day.
Seeing everyone...
All living a good life.
Except me.
What do you mean?
In my time capsule
I wrote, "Have fun as an adult."
Sounds stupid, doesn't it?
Here's me running away
from my parents' plans.
Still not knowing
the meaning of living.
The thought of my life going on
this way with no end in sight...
I just felt...
Felt like what, you jerk?
Matsuri?
Sorry, I'm heading home.
What's the matter?
I don't really know you...
but what you did
seems incredibly selfish.
Take care.
Takabayashi.
Here's your card. Take care.
Things are looking good.
No change to the meds
but keep your salt intake low
and don't overexert yourself.
Got it.
How is it being back home?
I'm bored and I can't work.
I'm just counting the days really.
Matsuri, I know you've read up
about this disease
but there are no absolutes.
Treatments are evolving,
so let's keep our spirits up.
I'm waiting for you
to create a wonder drug.
Of course, I'll do my best.
It's for you, Matsuri.
Is it from the reunion?
Let me see.
Is that Miyuki?
She looks totally different.
They're all so grown-up...
Yes?
It's me, Manabe.
I got out of hospital last week.
I wonder if we could talk.
Let's celebrate his recovery!
I'll text you.
- Got it? I'm going now. See you.
- What... wait a sec...
I feel like having everything here.
Everything this guy cooks is amazing.
- There you are.
- Thank you!
So these are friends from
middle school.
Welcome.
Gen is like my Tokyo dad.
He's been my mentor forever.
Enjoy yourselves.
OK... let's make a toast.
Well...
Congratulations on
your discharge. Cheers!
Tonight, we're here to listen.
Right, Matsuri?
Why me?
It ended awkwardly last time.
So he said he wanted to talk.
Go ahead.
What? Am I in your way?
Could you... just give me a sec?
Sorry about this.
- OK...
- Sorry.
Sure... I get it.
Sorry for the other day.
I'm the one who should apologize.
I'm glad you're out of hospital.
I mean...
I saw you at the hospital.
Is it a serious illness?
Your poor mother...
I thought about what you said.
About being selfish...
Some folk want to live but can't.
I was inconsiderate and
I blabbered on like a spoiled jerk.
I'm truly sorry.
Don't kill off my mum just like that.
Sorry, it came out all wrong.
Then, tell me what you meant.
Well, I mean...
How should I put it...
- Hey, Takeru.
- Are you done?
This guy's killing off my mother.
What do you mean?
No, no, that's not it.
I didn't mean that.
- What the hell?
- Explain, please.
- What's up?
- Well, it's just...
- Kazu, see her home, OK?
- Yes, I get it.
- I'll be fine.
- Got it?
- You may drive. Thanks.
- See you soon.
Sorry, it's my dad.
Yes.
I'm heading home now.
Don't worry.
I can get home by myself.
OK.
You get on with your folks.
They're over-protective.
I'm an adult by now.
That's so beautiful.
Why do you have a camera?
I want to leave a record
of every beautiful thing I see.
That's kinda nice.
So, what's the plan now?
That's unexpected.
The plan now...
I don't really know.
For a start...
get a job...
pay the rent...
What the heck?
Give me something more profound.
Something else?
What could it be?
OK then...
I'm going to hang in there
so no more thoughts of dying.
OK.
- Wow...
- That was unexpected.
OK.
Really? The guy sounds like a weirdo.
I wonder...
Over here.
I'm surprised.
If I were you, I'd be angry with him.
Yes. But I almost felt like
I understood him a little.
The feeling of wanting to run away.
Just one unemployed slacker
looking out for another.
But as of today, you're...
I love you so much, Sanae.
Thank you.
In return, you find me a cute guy.
Let's meet the chief editor.
- Chief.
- Yes?
This is Takabayashi Matsuri,
our new writer.
I'm Namigawa. Nice to meet you.
I'm happy you're on board.
Sanae's been praising your writing.
Well, I'll do my best.
Good to hear. Show her around.
I will. Thank you very much.
I hope it's good.
It looks tasty.
I've got something to tell you.
Anything wrong?
I've got a job.
What sort of job?
Writing articles. Working from
home so it's low-stress.
That's good. But don't overdo it.
I'll be fine.
Hey there.
Hi, what's going on?
Like this...
Manabe?
Funny, huh?
Welcome.
- Sorry for the wait.
- Thank you.
- A lot of froth, isn't it?
- Sorry. You're right.
Does it suit me?
I'm at a loss for words...
The boss is getting old
and was looking for a helper.
So, I presented
our unemployed buddy.
Right, Gen?
He forced him on me actually.
Yeah, maybe.
You know...
I've been thinking after we talked...
I figured...
it was time to do what I could.
That's great.
It does suit you.
Excuse me.
Hey, you're on duty.
Thanks.
Sorry.
I'd like to order
sliced onions and...
- Yes, sliced onions...
- potatoes...
- mountain yams and...
Mountain yams...
- And spicy cod roe as well.
- Got it.
- One beer...
- You like beer?
Run!
Let's race to the water.
The waves are great.
Surf's up!
It's fantastic.
I'm soaked.
Book Review by Takabayashi Matsuri
Awesome!
Reduced salt recipe.
Behold!
Congratulations.
You should come next year, Matsuri!
Are you two...
Are you serious? Really?
This book made me rethink
the meaning of summer.
Merry Christmas!
I won!
She did it!
It's time to cut the cake.
Congratulations!
Congratulations.
Now, it's the bride's turn
to give a slice to the groom.
The bigger the slice,
the more she loves him!
Didn't the bride look lovely?
I'm glad she's settled but it makes
you wonder about the little sister.
But I thought
Matsuri looked well today.
I heard...
she's got three to four years
at most.
Is that right?
I feel sorry for my sister
having to face the loss of a child.
The poor thing's so young.
I'm starving.
Your own restaurant, for real?
Not right away.
I need to study first.
Gen said
it'd take a couple of years.
But I'm having my doubts.
Why?
Because...
I'm happy the way things are now.
I wish everything could
stay the same.
That's your character flaw,
right there.
But it's endearing, too.
- Thanks for coming.
- Thank you, guys.
- I'll call you.
- Sure.
Make sure you seal the deal.
- Leave him alone.
- See you.
Good night.
Good night, then. Bye.
Good night, thanks.
Let me do that.
It's OK.
Takeru and Sanae make a nice couple.
I knew they'd get along well.
It's all thanks to you, Matsuri.
Thank you.
You're being weird.
The thing is...
What do I mean to you?
"Mean"?
I don't know.
I should tidy up.
Sorry, I've got to go.
We'll try different medication.
I'll up the furosemide
and let's add another drug.
Nothing to worry about.
Sometimes you develop a tolerance
so it's best to try another.
This new one is called Uptravi...
Kazu: I need to talk.
Meet tomorrow?
Sorry things got weird the other day.
I just want things to be clear.
I like how we are now.
You yourself said you wanted
things to stay the same.
That's something totally different.
That's just personal opinion.
Wait a second, will you?
Did I do anything to upset you?
I'm not upset.
It's odd to drag things on like this.
If I'm not boyfriend material to you,
just tell me so.
Because... I really like you.
I want to be with you.
That's just how you feel right now.
Your life is full.
It's nice having me around.
How could you even say that?
I'm warning you.
You might regret
meeting this odd woman.
That's not a normal thing to say.
- "Normal"... what is that?
- It's just... normal is normal.
You don't know me,
so don't make assumptions!
Matsuri, are you OK?
Sorry...
Wait...
Hey, Matsuri...
What's going on, Matsuri?
Matsuri?
Kazu...
Are you OK?
It's just a touch of anemia.
Your dad told me...
"Stick with her through this."
Talk to me.
I got really sick when I was 20.
I had two operations.
I have the scars here.
There's a risk of seizure...
so I can't play sports or anything.
Sorry.
I acted all tough but look at me.
It's like a joke.
Not at all.
First, get some rest.
You don't understand.
I'm not who you think I am.
Don't come see me anymore.
I don't want to see you.
See you later.
Where are you off to?
Just around the corner.
You've only just got out of hospital.
It's fine. Stop worrying.
Matsuri...
Can we talk?
What is it?
I've had an idea. Dad, come too.
This place has opened
a transplant facility.
What is a lung transplant?
I thought I'd have a chat
with your doctor.
See if it's a good idea
to switch hospitals.
What do you think?
My body can't handle this.
We've already tried so much.
That may be so but...
every day medical knowledge advances
and maybe
your prognosis changes too?
If it makes sense to you,
I'd like to talk to him.
- Even a slim chance...
- Let it go.
If there's a cure, I don't mind
toughing out any treatment.
But what I've got is incurable.
It's not that I gave up the fight.
There's just no way to fight.
Matsuri...
What you're saying isn't wrong.
And I'm so proud of
how you're bearing up.
But try to understand
how your sister feels.
She's always thinking of you...
Of course I know that!
Sometimes I wonder...
who deserves
the sympathy in this family.
Sorry, I take that back.
I've got to go meet my friends.
Wait, Matsuri...
Congratulations on tying the knot!
- Congratulations, buddy.
- Thank you.
Surely she hasn't
tricked you into it?
Shut up!
What does that mean?
- Look, it's the real deal.
- Yeah, whatever.
- Cute, right?
- Yeah, sure.
By the way...
Matsuri, you're not
seeing anyone, right?
We want you to meet someone.
Right...
a friend from middle school.
He did the design work on this place.
A first-class architect,
a really great guy.
No way... I'm jealous!
Although there's one thing...
It's no big deal really...
Since he was a kid...
How can I put it?
He's had this heart defect...
It doesn't affect
his daily life at all.
We figured you might
understand his struggle
and find a mutual connection.
But I thought you were seeing...
Sounds great. Hook us up.
I'm so glad.
How old? Is he good-looking?
- I think so...
- We've got a recent photo.
Where is it? Show me, show me.
Kazu...
you've spaced out.
Sorry.
Having trouble with Matsuri?
Yes.
I see.
Well then, it's time
to move on to the next.
Next?
There is no next for me.
That's a good line.
But I know just what you mean.
Ending up with regrets or not,
you only live once.
Meeting the one you love...
that's a miracle in itself.
You're a lucky lad...
to have even come across her.
Kazu.
You can knock off for the day.
Thank you so much.
Damn.
Matsuri.
I'm so glad I found you.
What are you doing?
I...
I don't know your address,
only your nearest train station
so I've been going around
hoping to run into you.
Matsuri, are you OK?
Yes.
What's up?
Matsuri, listen.
I've figured things out.
What do you mean?
My life...
might just look like
nothing special.
Just a regular boring
existence perhaps.
But you'll always be with me.
When I wanted to die...
you gave me a reason to live.
I'm not gonna give up on life.
From now on...
I'll look after you, Matsuri.
So...
please stay with me.
You idiot.
Matsuri.
I love you.
I shouldn't have gone
to that reunion.
You're warm.
You're cold.
When I was 20
I stared death in the face.
The law now allows
post-brain death transplants.
However, these legal changes...
Tip the glass and pour it slowly.
Then push forward to make froth.
It's like the limits of my future
were being shoved in my face.
If you only had ten more years...
what would you do?
Right this instant,
Matsuri...
Matsuri!
- Matsuri, are you okay?
- Matsuri...
- Honey...
- Honey, get her oxygen.
- Yes.
- Matsuri!
Clock's ticking...
Come on.
What's the point in you crying?
Sorry.
Matsuri, I'll leave
the details to you guys.
OK.
Your writing is as amazing as ever.
We'll definitely publish this.
Thank you.
Matsuri, are things OK?
I guess...
maybe not.
That's why I had to write.
I can't wait for Kazu to read it.
We'll go snowboarding next week.
He's really excited.
He's changed so much.
He's became so much more dependable.
It's all thanks to you.
He thinks there's a cure
for my illness.
Please always stay
within cell phone range.
Familiarize yourself
with the local hospital.
And don't forget your oxygen.
Doc, did you find
the miracle drug yet?
Use me as a guinea pig all you like.
Thank you.
I appreciate the sentiment.
If I can help people like me
avoid this fate...
even if it's just one person...
then I'd feel my life had meaning.
Matsuri...
There's one more thing I have to do.
When that's done, we'll meet again.
You want to try it?
You know I can't. I'm a sick girl.
In that case...
Let's do that.
That's embarrassing.
- Don't worry...
- No, I can't.
We're going so fast!
Oh, no!
- Are you OK, Matsuri?
- I'm fine.
Good.
I was scared.
I was going to choose
a cool moment...
You know...
With you...
I feel I can conquer anything.
So...
please marry me.
No, because it wasn't a cool moment.
No way!
Matsuri!
Wait for me.
What's wrong?
Did I do anything to upset you?
What's going on?
It's no fault of yours.
It's all me.
I've been lying to you.
My illness is terminal.
That's why...
I can't be with you anymore.
I'm sorry.
It can't be cured?
There must be a drug
or some kind of treatment...
It's no use.
No one survives more than ten years.
Goodbye.
Wait, just wait...
Sorry, wait a moment.
I'm not thinking clearly.
Why?
Why you, Matsuri?
That's what I kept asking.
Why me?
Ten years left is like
some kind of joke.
I mean, a decade... is that
a long time or no time at all?
I was so bored I thought I'd go mad.
I just wanted to be left alone
to get it over with.
But then...
I met you, Kazu.
Every day was such fun.
But I guess this is it.
If I stay with you any longer...
I'll be too scared to die.
It's just...
I love you, Matsuri.
Kazu...
Thank you for being my boyfriend.
Don't do this.
You keep on living a good life.
I don't want to.
Please, just say "OK, I get it."
I need to get ready to die.
This is my last wish.
OK...
Thank you.
Welcome back.
I'm home.
Welcome home, Matsuri.
You're back early.
Looks tasty.
It'll be ready soon.
How was your trip?
Matsuri?
Mom...
I...
I want more life.
I want to travel more.
More time with my friends.
To work more.
To know what it's like to be married.
I never had the chance
to do stuff for you guys.
I've just been a burden to you.
Matsuri...
I've always felt so bad.
That day when we got your diagnosis,
your father and I went to pieces.
We couldn't help bursting into tears.
I'm sorry if that made you feel you
always had to put on a brave front.
You know...
it's OK to let go.
To cry, to scream, to yell out.
Your mother has got you.
I don't want to die.
I really don't...
The new imperial era's name
has been officially announced.
It will be called
"Reiwa" (Auspicious Harmony).
This is the dawn of a new era.
I think it's good.
It suits you.
I felt the same.
I'll take it.
Good.
We're nearly there.
As supervising editor,
I'll make sure it's a hit.
Looking forward to it.
OK.
How's Takeru doing?
Well...
We split up.
Why?
How can I put it?
I just love my work so much
and I want to put everything
into your book.
Sanae...
Thank you.
I should thank you.
Yakitori "Gen"
It's a little early but...
here's to you.
Thank you.
Remember the first time
you came here?
Yes, I was on crutches.
You were like a pitiful little puppy.
But you turned out pretty cool, Kazu.
Thanks to those around me.
Have you chosen a name
for the place?
I'm thinking of calling it "Matsuri".
I see.
Make sure you go tell her
about your shop.
Did you finish your novel?
I wrote lots of bad things about you.
Like how you didn't
take me to the SkyTree.
That's not nice.
Doesn't matter.
It's a work of fiction.
You also have a child in the story.
Are you psychic?
No way.
I'm pregnant.
Only two months now
so I'm due next summer.
Wonder if I can hold the baby...
Of course you can.
You can even think of a name.
Sis, I'm so sorry.
I always regretted it
after I said mean things to you.
You've always been by my side.
You've never given up hope.
Thank you.
I'm really glad
to have you as my sister.
Why are you crying?
Shut up.
Thanks.
- Long time, no see.
- Good evening.
"Matsuri"
Wow, it's so busy.
- Good evening.
- Hi, guys!
What a great place.
- Excuse me.
- You can sit over there.
Squeezing through.
Kazu, congratulations.
- Well done.
- Thank you.
Remember that chick
who dumped me?
Don't be mean.
A celebration gift.
Open it after work.
It'll be published in two months.
- Two beers.
- Coming up.
- Excuse me.
- Coming.
He's always got people
looking out for him.
You're right.
I hope the book reaches
a lot of people.
It will. For sure.
You want to try it?
You know I can't. I'm a sick girl.
In that case...
Let's do that.
That's embarrassing.
Delete file?
Yes
Deleting scene
Deleted
So, what's the plan now?
That's unexpected.
I don't really know.
OK then...
I'm going to hang in there.
So no more thoughts of dying.
OK.
Delete file?
(Deleted files cannot be recovered)
It's so nice!
How beautiful.
There's Tokyo Tower!
A good first day.
Tomorrow, you're on your own.
Gen...
Thank you for all you've done for me.
The Last 10 Years
by Takabayashi Matsuri
- Let's get her to the ICU.
- Yes, Doc!
At night, I get scared
to close my eyes.
It always plays back in my mind.
Unforgettably.
Tell me I was not wrong.
That I made the right choice.
I broke up with him
to make my pain bearable.
Hey, Kazu.
My life was full of happiness.
Although it was shorter than most.
To have met you.
To be loved by you.
It made me sure of my existence.
So, I guess...
this was for the best
after all, right?
I miss you and
want to see you, Kazu.
Kazu...
I love you so much.
I'm sorry.
Matsuri?
Listen.
I opened my own restaurant.
I named it...
"Matsuri".
I figured you'd be mad
that I didn't ask you but...
it's the only name I could think of.
Matsuri...
You fought hard.
My dear Matsuri...
You really fought hard.
Dear Matsuri...
You fought really hard.
You really, really did...
The Last 10 Years
by Takabayashi Matsuri
OK, I'll be there in a minute.
See you soon.
Dedicated to the memory of
Kosaka Luka