[light fanfare ♪]
[ethereal, indistinct noises]
[sinister laughter]
[screeching hiss]
[ethereal, indistinct noise]
[rising tone]
Release your presence in the
name of the Lord.
Release your presence
in the name of the Lord.
[cracking]
[prayer in Spanish]
[demonic roar]
[prayer continues]
[violent scream]
[cracking vertebrae]
[ethereal whoosh]
[loud thud]
[girl laughing, maliciously]
Release your presence
in the name of the Lord.
Release your presence in...
[ghostly roar]
[demonic voice]
Shove that cross
up your ass.
[clicking]
[fluttering]
[dripping]
[girl screaming violently]
[demonic voice]
You're going to Hell, priest.
[girl struggling audibly]
Release your presence in the
name of the Lord.
[laughter]
[aggressive groans]
Release your presence in the
name of the Lord.
You're not welcome here.
[laughter]
Release your presence in the
name of the Lord.
[laughter]
You're not welcome here!
[slowing hum]
[muffled laughter]
[slow, soft clattering]
You're not welcome here.
Release your presence
in the name of the Lord.
[malevolent laughter]
You're not welcome here!
Release your presence
in the name of the Lord.
[demonic voice]
She belongs to us, now.
Release your presence in the
name of the Lord!
[girl struggling violently]
[muffled]
Father, she is lost.
[girl screams]
[loud hiss]
[guttural noises]
[wailing]
[inhuman growl]
[sizzling]
[yell of pain]
[muffled thud]
[heavy breathing]
Your God have
no presence here.
[pained grunt]
[laughter]
[wailing]
[prayer in Spanish]
[prayer continues]
[groaning]
[soft vocalization]
[creaking sounds]
[hellish growl]
[otherworldly noise]
[grunt]
[prayer in Spanish]
[groaning]
[creaking]
[choking noises]
[demonic vocalization]
Release your presence
in the name of the Lord.
[cracking]
[yelp of pain]
[malevolent growling]
[ghastly screech]
[hissing]
[cracking]
[electronic whirring]
[crackling]
[whoosh]
[mechanical clicks]
[dissonant chord ♪]
Father Connely?
Father?
[female voice, melodic]
♪ Hallelujah
[ethereal whoosh]
[rock requiem ♪]
[♪]
[ethereal burst]
[electronic music ♪]
[cymbal crash ♪]
[♪]
So I don't see a ring...
...any friends
or girlfriends, so, um...
You wanna get outta here?
Hell yeah.
[electric guitar,
drum, and bass music ♪]
[♪]
[pleased moaning]
[traffic noises]
[car horn honks]
[door opening]
[footsteps]
Go away.
Clean in the morning.
Rise and shine, Jason.
[thwack]
What the...
What do you want, Diekmen?
Thought I'd stop by
and provide you
with a little support.
I figured you'd need it
on a day like today.
You really should
count your blessings,
you know that?
You've been allowed
to see yet another day.
Maybe you didn't
hear me earlier...
What do you want?
We leave in a few hours.
[rustling]
Will your lady friend
be joining us?
That's, uh... Julia.
Nah, I don't think
she will be.
Shall I wake her?
Nah.
[chuckles]
I got an open door policy.
She can let herself out.
Ah, I see.
[clears throat]
Shall we go then?
After you.
[sirens in distance]
[Judge Alberto]
Eddie Bunkley...
Do you understand
why I made the decision
on wether or not
to accept your plea deal,
and why it would
be made public?
Yes, your honor.
Then you also understand
that I cannot ignore
the D.A.'s excursion
of your last stint
as a free man?
The man who
entered prison
ten years ago
was lost
and without faith.
[brakes screech]
[glass shatters]
Now that don't
make what I did right,
but I am a better man, your
honor.
Given the reports
of your good behavior
and taking into consideration
the intel you provided
through your co-operation
on a high profile case,
it is the state
and the court's decision
to grant you your release.
[gavel thwack]
Jason.
Not now, old man.
I've had enough
of your God's justice
for one day.
Without forgiveness,
there can be no love.
Can't you see that?
You should feel proud
we live in a place
where we don't
hold darkness
in our hearts.
What I see, Father,
is that you
and people like you
are no better
than he is.
that just got off
for killing my family,
so don't tell me
how I should feel.
I'm not a little kid anymore,
and Dad's not around
to help force feed me
your religious bullshit.
You must learn
to forgive,
or the darkness
will consume you
from within.
Father Connely is dead.
I need you to come to
the old church
where you grew up.
A lot has changed.
I have something
of your father's,
that he wanted
you to have.
[engine revs]
[tires squeal]
[heavy electric guitar ♪]
I can't breathe when you hold
my head down like that,
Roddy.
Cindy...
...baby...
...I'm just trying
to make sure
you do it right.
That's all.
You're so cute
when you think
I'm mad at you.
[♪]
[dramatic heavy
metal music ♪]
[ethereal whoosh]
[♪]
[music cuts]
[grunt]
[thud]
What the hell, Roddy?!
- Well good grief, baby!
- That kinda hurt.
Well good grief, baby!
There's a dumb son of a bitch
in the middle of the road.
[music on car radio ♪]
[click]
Well, maybe he's sick
or something.
[car horn honk]
Hey, buddy!
Move your ass
outta the road!
Babe...
Just go around.
Nah, I ain't gonna stand
for this shit.
[horn honk]
Hey!
Move your ass
outta the road!
[creaking metal]
Hey... hey!
[creaking continues]
- Babe, what's going on?
- What are you doing?
[crunching metal
and glass]
[panicked screams]
[destructive crunching]
[hellish hiss]
[bell tolling]
[birds chirping]
It's all a bit much,
isn't it?
Most churches have
Bibles and crucifixes,
not swords and...
[footsteps]
...okay.
I see you remembered
how to get here.
It's not Sunday,
so I'm not missing
any games.
Thought I'd come
turn a little water
into wine.
After you.
[somber hymn ♪]
The very basis
of our belief
stems from the arrival
of the Apostles,
from such places
as Jerusalem, Africa,
and even Asia.
With the spread of Christianity
throughout the Roman Empire.
Upon the turn of the second
century, the Papacy,
as you know it today,
was constantly ever-changing.
With one central point
being our Savior, Jesus Christ.
You're killing me, man.
Upon the destruction
of the western Roman Empire,
the church in the West was a
major factor
in preserving
classical civilizations;
establishing monasteries,
and sending missionaries
to the people
of far northern Europe...
...as far as Ireland,
in the North.
So what exactly
is your point?
My point, Jason,
is what isn't written
or taught
is the existence
of an establishment,
Esorcistato,
which was created
during ancient times
to combat the dealings
of Daemon Everto Possessio,
or as you know it,
"demonic possessions."
A rite formed,
to monitor
and perform exorcisms
on the damned...
...known as The Cloth.
"The Cloth."
So what you're telling me
is there's a group of old
people
out there wandering the globe,
aimlessly fighting a war
with the devil?
It's not as simple as that,
but...
Basically,
that's what I'm saying, yes.
Okay, wow.
Diekmen,
I knew you were crazy,
but this?
This is a stretch,
even for you.
Spinning their heads,
spittin' up pea soup...
Ephpeta, quod est, adaperire.
Be open.
[heavy machinery]
[tense chord ♪]
[♪]
[growing dissonance ♪]
Appropinquabit enim
judicium dei.
What is this place?
Appropinquabit...
Jason, be still.
Don't move.
[hiss]
Pax tibi.
It's alright, Jason.
Her name is Nybass.
[Nybass, angrily]
Mind your eyes!
She's an
amphonxious spiritous.
What is it?
Two spirits, one body.
One good...
...and one bad.
Where'd she come from?
Texas.
What you see before you
is someone
who is possessed,
and in a rare case,
found herself battling
within her own body.
She managed to keep
some of her motor functions
and cognitive functions
separate from the demon
within her.
Nybass...
I believe you know
why I'm here.
[growling]
It is time.
You must begin
the sacrament.
The crossover
has already begun.
[hiss]
Beware, Father.
Before the souls
are gathered,
you will breathe
your last breath.
[dissonant rustling]
What the hell was that,
back there?
You guys just keep that thing
locked up underneath the
church?
What's with the whole
dead animal/hand puncture...
I realize you must have
a lot of questions.
Questions are for
history lessons.
All I need to know
is the next flight
back home,
because apparently
there's something
going on here
that I don't want
to be a part of.
Can you think
of someone
other than yourself
for a change?
There is a lot more
going on here
than you can
begin to grasp, Jason.
There is a war coming,
and we don't have
that much time.
What do you mean?
I need to begin
the sacrament.
So for the moment,
try and learn
as much as you can
from Laurel, our gatekeeper.
She's responsible
for recording and organizing
all of our actions,
past and present.
Remain focused.
There is much to do.
The Apostles
were more than philosophers.
The clergy,
during the holy war,
had to be well equipped
in order to deal with
extreme cases
of demonic possession.
[dramatic music ♪]
You have to remember
that back in those days,
any unexplainable event
was met with
a religious explanation.
Are you paying attention,
Mr. Pafford?
Okay, wow.
You used my
government name.
So, yeah...
Clergy, holy war, demons...
So did you know
they have an amphibious
double-inhabited thingy,
girl, underneath
the church?
Is everything
just a game to you?
For the past few days,
we've had over 100 requests
for paranormal assistance,
alone.
Why do you think that is?
Uh, people are all
crazy as hell?
Look, listen...
This is all new to me, okay?
Just a few hours ago,
I was watching the man
I hate most in this world
get off
for killing my family.
Please, just...
[♪]
I'm sorry
about your family.
No, it's fine.
So what do I need to know?
Kasdeya,
the fifth Satan,
according to
the Book of Enoch,
which is found
in the over 14 books
of the Apocrypha,
and omitted from
the final version
you've come to know.
Kasdeya appears
in human form,
as the gateway key
to pave the way
for the arrival
of Beelzebub himself.
[raven caw]
According to the records,
he was once responsible
for tempting men
into turning their backs
against God,
and then bringing them forward
for judgement.
The Cloth's main objective
is to seek and destroy
those that would do harm
to the balance
of good and evil
from within...
...the only place a battle
can truly be waged
amongst men.
Nybass provides us
with the locations
of all paranormal insights
and demon leaders
that may have entered
our realm.
Before her,
we relied upon
word of mouth,
and it limited
our effectiveness.
Her insights guide us
from location to location
as we attempt
to enforce the pact.
Once a person
has become possessed,
their soul no longer exists
in this realm.
[dissonant chord ♪]
Once Kasdeya arrives,
he has seven days
before he must return
to his realm.
It is very important
that he doesn't take
any lost souls with him.
[Diekmen]
Ephpheta, quod est, adaperire.
[monks, together]
Be open.
[Father Tollman]
Credis in jesum christum filium
eju unicum,
dominum nostrum,
natum et pasum?
[monks, together]
I believe.
[Tollman]
Pax tibi.
Where do we stand
on the boy, Father?
Father Tollman,
I have come to ask you
for permission
to begin the sacrament.
The sacrament takes years
of dedication and devotion.
It's not something
to be expedited.
Your concerns are noted.
Father Diekmen,
are you certain
he is the one?
We have other
worthy candidates...
...all of whom
are strong in the faith.
I understand
your reluctance,
but I knew his father,
and he believed in me.
And I see the same devotion,
deep down inside of him.
He's survived this long
without our help.
Imagine if he realizes
his full potential.
Hm.
There have been
an increase in activity
over the past few days.
We have reason to believe
Kasdeya has arrived.
Then we don't
have much time.
Stopping Kasdeya
is our top priority.
You only have seven days.
Pax tibi.
So, basically you're using a
form of prayer
to keep Nybass contained.
Nybass is very imperative
to the operation.
To gain that much insight...
...has enhance our understanding
into the demonic realm.
[♪]
You ever get away
from this place?
[♪]
My beliefs come before
my own personal desires.
In short...
...I'm here for God.
That explains it.
What, exactly?
Why you're so uptight.
[scoffs]
You gotta get out,
live a little.
All this demonic talk
could drive a person crazy,
you know?
Look, I say
we grab a drink later..
Mr. Pafford...
We are all here
on our own
personal journey.
But more importantly,
we are here for something
bigger than our own ideals.
Then you're
more of a prisoner
than Nybass will ever be.
What's the point
in all this
'saving the world' talk
if you can't even
feel alive in it?
Everyone dies, Laurel.
Not everyone lives.
[♪]
Jason.
It is time.
What is it?
This belonged to your father.
[dramatic chord ♪]
It's time you met Helix.
[♪]
[rising musical tension ♪]
[ethereal slice]
Looks like you need
to take those things
back to the drawing board.
The power of God is strong,
my friend.
[metallic clanking]
[fiery burst]
Very strong.
I call this one
"The Judge."
Helix is our
weapons specialist.
And quality control
for the communion wine.
You must be Jason.
Helix, we don't have
much time.
The sacrament
has already begun.
What, this early?
But... he doesn't look
like he could take Laurel
in a fight.
No offense.
Why wasn't I told?
How come I'm always
the last one to know
about anything
that goes on around here?
Nice robe, by the way,
Laurel.
It looks fantastic.
You need to give him
a crash course.
[sighs]
Crash course.
Hm.
Okay.
Somebody slap me
with the devil's nut sack.
You think I can just sum up
everything there is to know
about what we do here
in a couple of hours?
[together]
Yes.
I'll see what I can do.
Your armor...
[metal clangs]
...is said to have been blessed
by the Seven Archangels,
and passed down
to Pope Saint Gregory
the First.
It's essential in dealing
with otherworldly figures.
All the metal we use
in our weaponry and armor
was found inside
the Ark of the Covenant.
You still talking about
this Friar Tuck outfit?
[powerful blast]
The bullets burst
into projectile form.
And the combustion chamber
consists of holy water
and a fusion liquid
that's been manufactured
beneath the church,
which is why
we're located here.
Isn't it, Dieks?
Why else am I never
allowed out of this...
...urban paradise?
Your armor doesn't allow
for friendly fire,
which is lucky,
because
Diekmen's a terrible shot.
[high pitched whirr]
[clink]
It's also why you're not
an ashy pile of goo
and how you'll be able
to defend yourself from...
...any attack
from a demonic creature
that's dwelling
in our realm.
While they might
have certain abilities...
[weapon locking]
...telekinesis,
superior strength...
...there are limits.
It's a consequence
of their human counterparts.
Even Kasdeya
has weaknesses.
Your job is to find them.
[weapon locking]
Exploit them.
[whirring]
[sparking]
Gabriel...
...one of my
personal favorites,
is used on more...
...ethereal creatures.
The Uriel...
...is effective
at close range.
[metallic shing]
[clicks]
[whoosh]
[clangs]
The choice of weapon
will depend upon
the level of demon
that possesses your victim.
[high pitched burst]
Uh..
Your bloodline
will allow you to wield
certain weapons
that we're no longer
able to operate,
due the recent passing
of... your....
Um.
[somber melody ♪]
Yeah, well...
Holy water and crosses
are still the essential tools.
Let's not forget the basics.
Wouldn't dream of it.
But, never forget...
...ye who wields
the mightiest weapon.
[beep]
[weapon humming]
[ethereal burst]
[♪]
Those little babies
are called holy grenades.
Yeah...
Well...
...holy water
explodes on impact, so...
...be careful with those.
Got a lot
of other weapons that...
Well, they're not
what you'd call functional.
But they are street ready.
Unfortunately, Dick-men...
...won't let me
show them to you.
Helix...
...you're meant to
aid our members...
...not injure them.
I'm afraid she's right.
We need to stick
to the basics.
- I'll just take that bad boy
right there...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's not for you.
Then what do I get?
Here you go.
What am I
supposed to do
with this?
You'll figure it out.
If I pull this out
on a demon,
he's gonna think
I'm disrespecting him.
This damn little thing
is gonna break
in my pocket.
[cymbal hit ♪]
[trance music ♪]
[♪]
[Olivia]
Roxy.
Hmm.
[Olivia]
What are you doing
out there by yourself?
I'm waiting for you.
[♪]
[giggles]
Mmm.
You want some goodies?
[♪]
[menacing whoosh]
[minor chord change ♪]
[girls giggling]
[ominous chording ♪]
[♪]
[menacing whoosh]
[otherworldly hiss]
[♪]
Mmm,
it's getting really hot
in here.
[soft moan]
[dramatic crescendo ♪]
[building tension ♪]
[indistinct vocalizations]
[dramatic whoosh]
[girls shriek]
[swish]
[grinding]
[tense arrangement ♪]
Something isn't right here.
[ethereal shattering]
[whoosh]
[♪]
[dramatic hit ♪]
[mechanical clicks]
[intense choral music ♪]
[ethereal burst]
[pained groan]
[grunt]
[click]
[otherworldly shatter]
[♪]
[thuds]
[static burst]
[in demonic voice]
Fear not,
for the wrath of God
is merciful...
Tell me your name.
...but the wrath of sin
is vengeful.
Vengeance is God's.
Kasdeya has come
for your souls.
Exorcizo te,
omnis spiritus immunde,
in nomine dei patris
omnipotentis...
[mechanical thud]
[coughing]
[Jason]
You okay?
[otherworldly whoosh]
Jason, go!
[thwack]
[cracking glass]
[dramatic choral music ♪]
[screech]
[yelling]
[thump]
[mechanical clicking]
Next time, can I have
more than a cross
before you send me
into a gunfight?
Well, you needed
to learn something.
There's gotta be
something missing.
Corinthians...
Letters to Paul...
At the dawn of every era,
man must prove
it is worthy
of God's forgiveness.
Beelzebub will need
a half-breed sacrifice
in order to remain,
permanently.
[shifting rock]
I am the way.
You are the way.
Oh, I didn't mean
to scare you.
That's fine.
I see you're reading
the Book of Sage.
You know, you're as beautiful
as the day
you were brought to us.
If there's ever anything
that I can do for you,
or that we can talk about,
please, please
don't hesitate.
I need to speak
to Father Diekmen,
- so, if you'll excuse me.
- Certainly.
Laurel...
Please do give
the good Father
and his new prodigy
all my best.
Vanity's a sin.
You do know that?
What isn't a sin, Diekmen?
I'm just making sure
I look good.
What's that?
This isn't making any sense.
I've been telling you that
since the beginning, Dieks.
According to the scrolls,
Kasdeya isn't the only
gatekeeper.
What does that mean?
It means that...
There's something else
at play here.
I think we're here.
Hey.
Aren't you forgetting
something?
Come on,
I still don't have a weapon.
Oh...
Right.
[weapon locking]
Here you go.
Hey...
Why is yours bigger?
[car door slams]
[loud pop]
Don't move.
Lewis...
Yeah.
And who the hell are you?
I'm Father Diekmen.
And this is my associate.
I believe you know
why we are here.
You can't have her.
[weapon locking]
Lewis,
I don't have to tell you,
if you don't let us
do our job,
the consequences...
The hell
with your consequences!
That's my daughter.
[loud crash]
[whispering]
Diekmen.
[light crunching sound]
[ominous growl]
[rising musical tension ♪]
[gunshot]
[ethereal screech]
[cymbal hit ♪]
[mechanical clicking]
[loud thunk]
[squishy burst]
[growl]
[gunshot]
[electrical hum]
[tense, dramatic music ♪]
[fiery burst]
[splattering liquid]
[otherworldly roar]
Vade in pace,
et dominus sit tecum.
[roar]
Vade in pace,
et dominus sit tecum.
[demonic groan]
Why are you here?
[speaking demonic language]
Where is Kasdeya?
Speak some more shit!
Exorcizo te,
omnis spiritus immunde...
[demonic growl]
...in nomine dei patris
omnipotentis...
...et in noimine
jesu christi filii ejus...
[yell]
[clang]
I am done.
Well, that must have been
an awkward car ride home.
Don't let it
get to you, Jason.
There's a lot more
we need to accomplish.
[weapon locking]
What's going on?
What's going on is,
I spent the last few days
getting thrown into walls
and spit on
by the devil's minions.
What's going on is,
I don't belong here.
This is what
your father wanted,
I know.
Well, he's not here,
is he?
Did I miss something?
Your father believed
in something a lot bigger
than himself.
He did everything he could
to protect you
and his family.
If we don't stop Kasdeya now,
everything he fought for
will be lost.
And I have found
an interesting wrinkle
in the prophecy.
Good luck with that.
[metallic clink]
Okay, could somebody
tell me what just happened?
Who throws Jesus
on a table like that?
Come on!
[ethereal howl]
Father...
Rosa.
We will pray
for your family,
but our hands are tied
at the moment.
Is there anything
you can do?
You promised
that if I paid,
someone would come.
You gotta understand
how small
your contribution was.
Look, I'll talk
to Father Tollman,
see what...
...if, something
can be done.
- Oh, Father, please.
- I've gotta get
to confession.
I gotta go to confession.
No, Father...
Forgive me, Father...
I have sinned.
Well the Lord
is ready to forgive you,
if you are
seeking forgiveness.
But you must
be willing to change.
[coins clink]
I fear that I can't, Father.
I fear that I won't stop...
...until I have
eliminated The Cloth.
Kasdeya...
This is a violation
of the pact.
[pained breathing]
[coins clink]
They say it's the root
of all evil.
[coins clinking]
I hope he is more merciful...
...than I am.
[coins clinking]
[loud yell]
[wood shattering]
[metallic clinks]
[demonic whoosh]
[light scratching]
Come on, Julia.
Doesn't anyone
take "no" for an answer?
[scratching continues]
Julia, sweetie,
I know I said
to let yourself in, but
this is a bit much.
[ominous ambient dissonance ♪]
You know,
I don't really know
how to say this, but
I don't really see us
working out, you know?
I mean, you're a nice girl
and all, but...
I'm just not looking
for anything serious.
[hiss]
[in demonic voice]
I... will show you...
his true nature.
Do you think
you know what it means
to serve him?
I will show you
the true desires
of a man.
The darkness
will consume you!
[both grunt]
Ephpheta, quod est,
adaperire.
[demonic growl]
[chomp]
[pained yelp]
Mortal, you have nothing
that can harm me.
[demonic chuckle]
Consider it your last.
Prepare
to meet your master.
[spit]
[sizzle]
[sizzling continues]
[coughing]
That's holy water.
Bitch.
[otherworldly whoosh]
[indistinct rumpus]
Laurel.
Hi.
I got your address
from Father Diekmen's log.
In regular clothes, no less.
I mean,
I didn't know you could.
Well, I'm a historian,
not a nun.
I'm free to dress accordingly
to occasion.
Well, you look human,
so that's a good thing.
[light scoff]
Thank you.
What's that smell?
- It smells like sulfur.
- Come on in.
What happened here?
I had an ex-girlfriend drop by,
and we had
a little confrontation.
I wanted drapes,
she wanted blinds,
but I think
she really just wanted
my soul.
Must be some soul.
Trouble's been following me
my whole life,
I don't really
expect relationships
to be any different.
Do you want a drink?
Did your girlfriend
write these?
Ex!
I told you,
I like to
keep my options open
There are more layers
to the context of man...
And so are there
to the context of evil.
I am the way.
You are the way.
I mean, I saw
these same exact markings
from my readings
from earlier.
What do you mean?
It means...
...that Kasdeya
is only one piece...
...of the puzzle.
It means that...
...Beelzebub...
...isn't just trying
to walk amongst us.
He's trying
to bring his hell
with him.
So I just started
doing everything I could
to dispel any rumor
I was my father's son,
you know?
It seems like he wanted
what was best for you.
Yeah, well...
I think he blamed me
for my mother's death
in child birth.
Somehow feeding me
all that religious B.S.
was just a way to atone
for that guilt.
That's what I believe.
Tell me
about the accident.
[dramatic choral music ♪]
I'd just done a stint in juvie
when my old man
picked me up.
It was rainy,
and the roads were slick.
I remember saying so
to my dad,
who was preaching to me
about how God
had provided me
all the tools I needed,
and I needed to stop
wasting my gifts.
Eddie had just lost his job
and then his kids
in a divorce.
He decided
to go out drinking.
One thing
led to another.
He lost control
of his wheel, and...
[mimics crash sound]
People were yelling
at the sight of
all the blood.
I remember looking up,
and seeing everything
burning up around me;
all the chaos.
I looked over
at my dad.
He wasn't afraid at all.
Here it was, you know?
That moment
people talk about.
What would you say
if you had to make amends
for a failed relationship?
What would you say
with your last breath?
Like, this was our moment.
You wanna know
what he said to me?
He looked me
straight in the eye
and said,
"Be open."
That's it.
I can't begin
to understand
your relationship
with your father.
But I do know
that he devoted his life
to our cause.
Lot of good his work did.
World's gonna end, anyway.
Everyone dies, Jason,
but not everyone lives.
Look,
Father Diekmen needs you.
Father Dean was attacked
by Kasdeya
in his church up north.
- How's that possible?
- I don't know.
But I'm not naive enough
to believe that everyone
is playing by the rules.
Father Dean was rumored
to be taking bribes
in exchange for assistance
in dealing with the paranormal.
Corruption in the church?
Go figure.
There's no such thing
as corruption in the church,
Jason.
The only church
that has ever existed
lies within.
Father Dean was found
with over 3,000 coins...
...lodged in his
digestive system
and main arteries.
Sounds like maybe
Kasdeya's not such a bad guy
after all.
Hell is coming to Earth.
And you're too busy
living in your own
to even notice.
I don't even know
why I thought
that coming here
would make a difference.
And you can't forgive Eddie
because deep down,
you were the one
driving that truck.
I thought
you needed my help.
We'll do it without you.
What happened
to being open?
[door slams]
[ominous ethereal chanting]
[siren wailing]
[traffic noises]
[powerful whoosh noise]
232 South Pike Boulevard.
Eddie?
Look, I don't mean to intrude,
the door was open.
Well, I just wanted
to come down here
and tell you
I've been doing
a lot of thinking
about what happened.
And, you know,
I went down
to the courthouse
and got your address,
so I just wanted
to tell you officially that...
[low growl]
Eddie?
Oh, you gotta be shitting me!
How was the house call?
It was hell.
Where do we stand?
We have Kasdeya's location.
He's being held up
in a spot
called Dante's.
And that's not
the best part.
Apparently tonight
is a special night.
And not just because
ladies get in for free,
but because...
it's the last day.
If he's in
a stationary position
like this,
we believe he may have
all the souls he needs
to have Beelzebub pass over.
Which means
it's up to us to stop him.
Gear's on the table.
Your father
had the same look
of determination.
The same fire.
I remember the last time
I saw his face.
He was holding
a possessed girl
in his clutches,
not wanting
to turn her over
to the order.
Why didn't he want
to give her up?
Your father had the ability
to see the good in everyone.
And on that day...
...he saw the good
in Laurel.
Father Tollman had never seen
anyone recover from
such a strong possession,
and he deemed it necessary
to terminate the child.
But your father
felt otherwise.
As I lay there in his arms,
my mind and soul being torn
into two separate identities,
he looked at me and said,
the battle between
good and evil
will be won
in the only place
it has ever been waged...
...from within.
Ephpheta, quod est,
adaperire.
Be open.
As much as I hate
to be the one
to break up this...
...tender moment,
you've got until
the stroke of midnight,
or the crossover begins.
Weapon up, Jason.
Right.
As much as I appreciate
your dedication to
the smaller things...
I believe a little more
of the good Lord's grace
is in order.
Amen, Father.
Amen!
[weapons locking]
Give 'em hell.
[thump]
[whoosh]
[mechanical clicks]
[intense techno music ♪]
[♪]
[footsteps]
[dramatic choral music ♪]
[shattering]
[growl]
[shattering glass]
[loud burst]
[♪]
[rising dissonance ♪]
[gunshot]
[shattering]
[metallic clank]
[gunshots]
[shattering glass]
[♪]
[demonic screech]
[crunching]
[sizzling]
[♪]
[roar]
[thwack]
[grunt]
[gunshot]
[music fades]
It's gonna be alright.
Just keep some pressure on it.
Be open, Jason.
She's more important
than you know.
- No...
- You must protect her.
You are the way.
[light sob]
[sinister laughter]
[slow applause]
Valiant and noble effort,
human.
[weapons locking]
You'd do well
in my legion.
[demonic chuckle]
Exorcizo te,
omnis spiritus immunde,
in nomine dei patris
omnipotentis
et in noimine jesu christi
filii ejus,
domini et judicis nostri,
et in virtute spiritus ut
discedas ab hoc pasmate Dei!
[demonic voice]
It's a little late for that,
don't you think?
Thought I'd give it a shot.
[whoosh]
[shatter]
[grunt]
I really must thank you.
[weapon locking]
Jason.
You had no clue
what this was all about.
And yet, here you are,
providing us
with the very thing
we needed all along.
[demonic whisper]
Be open, Jason.
Eventually we will get to you.
Just like we did Eddie.
Not once, but twice.
And I can't wait to taste
that sweet, sweet Laurel.
[grunt]
[loud thwacks]
[hellish roar]
She...
...is the key.
[roar]
[growl]
You left her
in the hands
of one of us.
How's it feel
knowing that
everyone you love
will soon be serving
my master on Earth?
Or, should I say...
...in Hell?
[laughter]
[whirr]
[gunshot]
[grunt]
Ego te baptizo
in nomine patris
et filii et spiritus sancti.
You...
...will...
...fail!
[shattering]
[demonic shriek]
[fiery poof]
Nybass?
I need to
ask you a question.
[strange squeaking]
[whispers]
Laurel.
How did I break free
from your spell?
You have one of your own
to thank for that.
Tu autem effugare, diabole...
[menacing hiss]
...tu autem...
Save your useless prayer.
[choking sounds]
For years you let me
rot in this prison.
You knew it was you
I wanted all along.
You are the way.
With you, we shall be free
to rule this realm.
[pained hiss]
[demon sounds]
Where's Father Diekmen?
Oh.
[sigh]
I see.
We got there
and they hit us hard.
There should have been
more of us.
Where's Laurel?
Helix?
She's been taken.
By who?
[sigh]
Nybass.
Nybass is planning
on completing the crossover.
And she's gonna use Laurel
as the final gateway.
We killed Kasdeya,
how is that possible?
Kasdeya was just a distraction.
[door thuds]
You gave Laurel up
to be sacrificed.
[whack]
[thud]
God don't like ugly.
Do you wanna tell me
what's going on?
Yeah, Father Tollman
gave Laurel up
for the emergence
of the dark Lord.
Is this thing ready?
It's as ready
as it's gonna get.
I need these.
Okay, I don't think
you're in the right state
of thinking, right now.
You're going up
against Nybass.
Not only that,
you're going
behind enemy lines.
The crossover has begun
as we speak.
Yeah, well, I always wanted
to expand my
spiritual horizons.
But you don't even know
where she is.
- I'll figure it out.
- Wait.
Just a second...
You don't really understand
what you're going up against.
I really think
we need to plan.
Okay.
Okay?
Yeah, okay.
We need a plan.
Good, 'cause,
for a second there,
I thought you were going
to do something really...
[gas release]
Hello, Eddie.
[demonic voice]
Soon Beelzebub
will be upon you.
Maybe.
Not until you tell me
what I want to know.
I'll tell you nothing.
I'm gonna ask this,
one time nice,
and one time naughty.
Where will they
make the sacrifice?
[hissing]
[sizzling]
What do you know?
Somebody put holy water
in my gun.
Where did they take her?
[pained speaking]
They took her back
to where it all began.
But you're too late.
[pained groans]
I got some good news.
I'm not gonna kill ya.
Hold on to this for me,
will ya?
[sizzling]
[ethereal whoosh]
Do you think this is the life
he would have wanted for you?
At some point, Jason,
you are gonna have to
take control of your life.
It's what your father
would have wanted.
[dramatic choral music ♪]
This isn't the lab.
Though not quite as much
as when you dragged me
up to the roof of the church.
I...
Oh, for Heaven's sake.
[growl]
[thud]
[grunts]
[thwacks]
[demonic growl]
[thuds]
[growling]
[fiery poof]
[heavy breathing]
Lord, show me the way.
That didn't work.
There are more layers
to the context of men,
and so must there be
to the context
of good and evil.
I am the way,
you are the way.
[ominous breathing]
[shuffling]
[demon noises]
[demon noise]
[demonic screech]
[pained gasp]
[loud hiss]
[struggling]
Father...
Help me.
[growl]
How'd you get down here?
I serve the church.
It was only a matter of time
before I found out
about this place.
The crossover, it's complete.
Are there any others?
The new trainees
and the recruits
started disappearing
this morning.
So I came down
and investigate,
and I was attacked.
We have to
keep moving forward.
This is where
the pact was formed.
The Cloth's been
working above this
the whole time?
Yes,
this is our beginning.
The first true church
formed underground
during the time of our exile.
It was the only time
where you could
practice your faith.
This is the place
where they planned to
make people believe
in the church again.
Laurel!
Laurel, it's Jason.
Father, I could use
some help in here.
[crack]
[gasp]
Did you miss me,
my love?
Oof!
Soon...
...my master...
...will inhabit this Earth...
...and claim the rest...
...of your weak...
...pathetic souls.
Excorcizo te,
omnis spiritus immunde,
in nomine dei patris
omnipotentis...
[prayer continues]
[demonic noises
from Laurel]
[pained grunt]
[dramatic choral music ♪]
For years, I've waited
for this moment.
I will have my vengeance.
Let Laurel go.
Your pretty little girlfriend...
...is in good hands.
It is time.
[dramatic choral music ♪]
[cracking earth]
[loud pops]
[gunshots]
[thud]
Jason,
we're running out of time!
Come in to me.
In oderem suavitatis,
tu autem effugare,
diabole.
Ephpheta, quod est,
adaperire.
- I am the way,
you are the way.
- [Laurel screaming]
Exorcizo te,
omnis spiritus immunde,
et in noimine jesu christi
filii ejus,
domini et judicis nostri
et in virtute spiritus ut
disedas ab hoc plasmate Dei!
[ethereal whoosh]
[otherworldly hiss]
Your soul...
...shall be mine.
Now you'll serve
the one true master.
[metallic slice]
[squish]
[whoosh]
[clank]
Is the best you can do?
Hey, asshole.
Be open.
[ethereal hum]
Are you okay?
Is it over?
I think so.
[loud burst]
Sorry, this one's...
...not quite...
...street ready.
You know
you missed everything,
right?
We coulda used a plan.
Oh, that's really funny.
Just watch your back,
that's all I'm saying.
Your gauntlets sucked,
by the way.
You just never had
a big boy weapon before,
that's your problem.
Button in the palm.
You gotta make an "X"
Chicks dig the "X", man.
Chicks?
Bro, you gotta get out more.
I don't think it worked
for Laurel.
It's a symbol for The Cloth,
what are you talking about?
[Laurel]
Are you going to do this
all night?
[Jason and Helix]
Yes!
[Helix]
You did, though,
didn't you?
You made the "X"
when you did it, yeah?
[Jason]
Yeah, I made the "X."
[Helix]
That's what I'm
talking about.
[♪]
Good to see you again,
old friend.