Mrinal Sen Production Presents
THE FOOT SOLDIER
Story, script & dialogue Mrinal Sen
Ashis Barman.
Photography: K. K. Mahajan
Editing: Gangadhar Naskar
Make up: Debi Haldar
Arrangement:
Mukul Chowdhury
Still Photo: Provash Nandi
Asst. Director: Amal Sarkar
Bidyut Bhattacharya David Rathod
Cast: Dhritiman Chatterjee, Simi
Provas Sarkar
Bijan Bhattacharya, Jochhan Dastidar
Ashima Singha, Dhruba Mitra
Alpana Gupta, Kamal Kidwai, Farida Kidwai
Avijit Mukherjee, Radha Kisan
Naidu Gayatri Rao, Geeta Mitra
Jaya Lal
Music direction:
Ananda Shankar
Directed and Produced by: Mrinal Sen
Hello
...I'm saying
Yeah, Nikhil...
one of our boys is an important comrade
arrangements are to be made for his stay:
a shelter
I believe staying at your place is best.
Yes.
It is not very safe where he is now...
May I come in?...
Who?...
Come... come
Got slightly delayed with serving your tea...
Your clock isn't working.
Isn't it?
Yes, it's running.
What?
It's running...
Meaning?
It runs while flat and doesn't when it's
standing.
Then how do I see the time?
Like this.
Funny.
For me... it's not working even lying flat
The tea is slightly strong today
isn't it...
No... I prefer strong tea...
Everybody in our house prefers strong tea...
Let me arrange this...
Yeah.
Biman will come tomorrow very early in the
morning
and will take you somewhere else...
Well, don't feel bad...
Today here... tomorrow there... Nothing
fixed...
Your mother doesn't like it at all
I know... surely she asks you to come home
Doesn't she?
Have you a sister or a brother?
You know, something terrible happened
in my school...
Oh I forgot to wash your shirt...
let me wash it now,
it'll be dry by tonight...
Ready.
I'm waiting for you...
Would you go wearing this shirt?
What's wrong?
- Are you going for action?
What do you mean by action?
- I knew... that's why I made arrangements...
What arrangements?
- Just see.
Look.
- What's this?
Shirt.
- What about it?
You'll wear it.
- Why should I wear it?
Do you know where we're going?
Where? Wherever I go?
You'll have to wear this
where you're going.
These are bell bottoms.
- Biman, I've never worn these.
You've never gone to that place either.
You'll make me a Park streeter...
What, you haven't shaved?
Shave.
Whose flat?
- A lady's.
Rich?
- No.
Don't you have any other questions?
Young or old?
Don't know, never seen her, Nikhil's contact...
- Our person?
Allows us to stay... Remember
the name, Shila Mitra.
You will see her after a couple of days.
She is away now... Delhi...
Will she return?...
I'm told... after a couple of days...
You've to stay alone for two days.
Alone?...
The lady lives alone?
This is the key to paradise...
Come.
Wow!
Fantastic...
8th floor means you're 9 storeyed.
Decorated hell...
What do you say?
- Hell.
Any difference between jail
and this place?
Oh! Money plant...
Money on shaking... good luck
Me, you, our landlady...
what do you say?
Didn't you include our group?
The party... let me keep it inside...
Biman... have you been here before?...
Mad or what?
Goddamn what a place... Superb.
You said that there's no telephone...
Hey... don't pick it up...
Let it ring, what's that to you and me?...
Can't say, may even be the C.I.A...
Stop it.
Give a cigarette.
My cigarette stock is almost finished... could
you get me few packs of Charminar?
Relieved.
The lady gets up very early?
- How could you get up?
Or else who could have called so early?
Good... good for the health
The time...
passing the time is very difficult...
I'm thinking... I'll write an adventure story
about these details...
What... Biman...
This is a girl's room...
I mean a lady's
First class, very safe...
nobody will enter...
...it will be trespass on entry...
We'll file a case.
But these materials are Mrs Mitra's.
See what have you done?
Please stop.
You stay here... this is much safer.
Okay.
But the matter is...
Listen, be careful,
till she comes back...
That means I don't have to be careful when
she returns...
Stay as safe as you can.
- I understand.
Now I'm going... I've arranged everything
properly...
There's the toilet... here's the key
- Key?
Key... for the flat?
- Yes
What can I do with the key of the flat?
I'm not going out for a stroll.
Keep it with you...
You'll be coming?
- Yeah... I'll be coming... okay
Biman, listen.
Biman.
Who am I?
Oh! Sorry... forgot to tell you.
You are Mrs Mitra's.
Salaam sir... I'm the cleaner...
I've come to check whether you've arrived
Yeah... he's arrived... taking a bath inside
Madam has asked me
to take care of you.
I'll be downstairs always...
if you need me just call.
Okay...
Who?
- The cleaner...
has come to take care as per madam's
instruction...
You are madam's cousin...
you live in Delhi... you've come here
for a visit...
Come here for a visit.
And Mr. Mitra?
Let him go to hell...
Yesterday in Dum Dum area north Calcutta
3 terrorists escaped from a police van...
Immediately after this an intensive search
was started...
It is reported that
though 2 out of the 3 escaped...
They captured the other one...
Would you get me some tea... strong.
Does Nikhil know?
He must by this time.
The action was not correct.
I took a great risk... it's only luck
that I wasn't caught...
Mass copying has started in
various colleges in Calcutta...
so that the V.C. of Calcutta
University Satyendranath Sen
has met in Darbhanga Hall with the
principals of all colleges...
Apart from other things the disease
of bad habits that...
Escaped, got caught, escaped again...
So what now?
What?
You'll stay absconding...
I'll remain a fugitive... only a fugitive,
nothing else...
...'sports news'
That day I met your father on the streets...
I was returning home from the office
after marketing...
He talked about this and that, talked about
many things but never once asked about you.
Not even once. I think he is very angry
with you.
Very much... Since you're a revolutionary.
But you said once your father was in a
terrorist party...
was in prison during British Rule.
Then he was greatly involved
in the movement of '42...
I don't know how people changed so much.
He would probably say the
nation has become independent
and there are lots of changes.
But what has happened?
Inclub zindabad...
Bobby Bobby...
Come Bobby
I said don't.
You know... always there's fear...
Yeah fear... even in a lift.
How?
Believe me... as many
people are in the house
...the number of dogs are not less
Chased...
Yeah, you smelled of revolution?
Not at all, comrade of bread and curry...
let me put it away...
Hey Biman... this is too much...
there was no need for this.
So... you wouldn't have eaten
anything... fasting?
Take a look.
Wow!
Oh!
With all the food that is here,
I can feed you for 2 days...
and here there's gas, a stove etc... will
you eat?
For now you eat this... I'm going
What's the hurry with you?
Oh! I've brought cigarettes for you
4 packs of Charminar...
Relieved
Here's a match box... okay I'm going
Hey Biman...
you are moving about so much,
be careful...
Karim
Bishey...
Only sleeping... do you know how late it is?
Prepare the tea, get up...
How many spoonfuls?
Eh...
...one & a half
Father you leave... I'll stay here...
What'll you do by being here?
You'll be late for the office...
go for a bath... I'll stay here.
You haven't forgotten that I must go
to the office and arrange for your food...
You still remember it...
You go. There's nothing to be done here
except removing the pulse from the oven...
How are you, mother?
Well.
Who went to bring the ration today?
Who else except for him... why?
No... I found father's mood is a bit off...
that's why.
Look. The milk is here. It's hot...
drink it when it gets cool...
Huh!
Where is Biru? Not in the house.
No.
He went out first thing in the morning.
Oh... he is having his class exams.
We too have worked for the country... have
gone to prison...
our concern for the betterment of the
country is no less than anyone else's...
I find the young boys have
become so irresponsible nowadays.
Listen, father...
I know... I know...
I won't be able to win a verbal battle
with you... you have become learned...
reading a few books of the party
makes you think you've become very wise
you just make a shower of words... we too
knew about the revolutionaries,
talked about revolution... We too
read the works of Lenin.
Where were you then...
your leaders were drowsing in the
dark... used to take opium, I understand
...opium...
Listen father... what you
don't know or don't understand
about those things...
like a fool.
So...
why did you stop?
Say it.
Come eat... you are going to be late for
the office
Stop... no one needs to do
anything for me...
Just see these boys nowadays... they
can say things that they're not supposed to
will say whatever they like... wonderful...
I'll be late for the office.
Nobody will have to remind me about my
responsibility...
Ask you to go... go eat...
What's that to me...
I am male.
I am strong.
I can do everything...
I was in politics once...
but you'll suffer... only you...
The condition of our country
as it's becoming every day...
That's... mine
Hello! My name is Shila...
Oh! Yes hello!...
Er... give those to me...
That's alright.
Biman asked me to stay in this room...
- Who?
Biman who brought me here...
Oh.
This paper is yours?
Yes... I can stay in the living room...
no trouble.
Yes... why are you standing?
Please sit down.
I feel... I'm the guest of the house
Yeah... I've forcefully occupied...
forcefully occupied...
What else... Almost like capturing
Windsor palace.
Without any bloodshed.
Peaceful transition.
Who is our enemy and who is our friend...
this is the most important
question in the case of revolution.
We've seen repeatedly
that to fight the enemy
we've not been able to
join hands with friends
so in the past many of
our wars have failed.
The primary responsibility of a fighting
organization is to inspire the people...
to show the way...
no revolution can be successful if the
fighting organization misleads the people.
If you can develop friendship
with true friends...
only then will the war be successful.
My office? 9:30.
You don't like coffee very much?
Why do you say that?
Isn't that right?
Rightly guessed.
That's what I thought.
How do you know?
I saw a lot of tea leaves
beside the basin...
a lot
I'm very sorry... I didn't know where to
dispose of that many tea leaves...
Where would you dispose of them?
Sugar?
One and a half...
What's up?
As you weren't here I had to make
tea... and so many tea leaves.
Hello... I am Biman...
Hello
Come please
Come... come
Biman... sit
I will have tea.
I was really afraid.
Now you've arrived, please keep the key.
He kept the key...
as it's not very safe for
me to go out... so he kept it.
No... you keep the key...
I've got another one.
Sugar?
- Oh give it to me.
Eat
Oh lovely
It's hot
No really not
Take it
What happened?
Nikhil... I can't understand this.
Which place?
Here... where there is much rewriting.
Oh that place: our educational system.
No... no... that's alright
Then
Here
In our country...
Against our bourgeois education. I'm
putting the word bourgeois down. Listen.
Do it quickly...
I'll write another 2 pages...
you'll finish all the work...
then after printing this...
you will be relieved... understand?
And tomorrow remove this in the early
morning before the work starts.
if you can do it tonight okay...
and look...
Biman
Come
Why are you so late?
There is a total jam in North Calcutta, trams
and buses not moving. I had to walk.
Have puffed rice...
Take this... read...
It will be a very late night today...
you know.
Have you finished?
Wait... it's not a machine like yours...
I will finish, only then can I go home...
and will I get any time off
the next day?
Those are ready?
Yes
Superbly narrated here.
Where?
It's about their meeting in Maidan...
Is it all right or will you say I
have made excesses?
But I was in that meeting...
You? What?
I was in that area on some work...
Had some time in hand... saw a packed
crowd... so listened for some time
It was not proper for you to go there...
the boys of their party could have
identified you... you might be in trouble
No... I didn't enter the crowd... and I
couldn't be seen.
Why the unnecessary risk?...
Nikhil... what does this one do?
Which one?
- This one here
Oh something...
That day in the meeting... there was a big
crowd, a great public gathering...
Must have been over a hundred thousand
So you're quite impressed?
You know Biman... they will go on doing this
forever...
They will arrange and gather people
by train,
by hiring buses, by walking, they will
bring people from various places...
They'll provide food
as they always do...
People will come with their families
to see Calcutta.
This is the last one... do it carefully.
There is some overwriting.
And you know what happens after that...
you saw it today...
meetings... hot speeches...
resolutions, songs and
music... pandemonium...
trams and buses are stopped... revolution...
But they are saying we haven't got public
support...
the public is not with us...
whatever is coming fears
us and our threats...
we have not been able to make
the common people aware.
Don't believe it.
Adulation... Everywhere only
adulation...
the paradise of adulation... within
this pure baby food Henco's Vita tone...
Vita tone in the service of the country
and everyone's children
the baby food Henco's Vita tone...
to bring a smile to a child's face and raise
hopes in a mother's mind...
One and only Henco's Vita tone.
Wonderful, you have made our point very
very well.
Tell her... she has done the job...
Shila has done everything...
Not at all.
I must congratulate you...
Thank you
Well may I see it once again?
Certainly... start it.
When can you deliver it?
It won't take much time.
Still, an approximate time.
Well, within 6 months...
you know the electical conditions...
It's being said conditions
are improving...
Ready
Adulation everywhere...
the paradise of adulation in this
pure baby food Henco's Vita tone...
in the service of the
country and everyone's children...
Henco's baby food Vita tone...
Made with Vita tone and amino
acid: Henco's baby food Vita tone.
I can't understand...
no I can't understand that
so many people...
so many fresh young boys dedicated...
and prepared to do everything...
but what are they doing...
what they are made to
do... what are you doing...
what I'm doing... you've
carried forward the revolution...
you've not surrendered...
Oh no... I haven't surrendered...
Eating and sleeping and in your language
waiting for instructions. Don't you
see we've no programme in front of us?
Well, Biman, don't you see that...
we are floating in air...
darkness... blank...
Sumit, now you're temporarily confined
here... no way to go out...
communications cut off... that's why you're
frustrated
No... you know only cliched words
frustration, cut off, escapism...
Any question which previously I didn't ask,
didn't know how to, now I'm asking...
I've not said it like that...
Yes you said it... cut off...
Okay I'm cut off but
you're not cut off...
You're moving around, working... Yeah with
plenty of risk...
You're coming to me as
many times as necessary...
Tell me... say with
your hand on your heart...
Have you got any aim, any organization,
group from which you could get energy..
Strength...
I am sorry, Biman...
You are probably thinking that I'm injecting
poison into your mind...
You know really...
You, me, nobody can go back...
It's not possible to return...
Sumit I... I'm going...
Hey...
don't break your promise...
...sit dpwn... sit down
I will serve you tea
with a ham sandwich...
Why am I feeling like going to
the toilet so often today?
Because you're drinking more cold water...
Very good.
Mihir, you see, this is too much...
Shila, I know, we know this is over the top...
There is a streak of genius in you.
It's not fair...
Sister you see...
What can the sister see...
Spent her entire life in marketing and
the kitchen...
but it can't be said that
she hasn't dabbled in art...
You see... just draws a bit and see how he's
teasing...
Listen... Shila listen...
Today in the history of our office
it's an event, a remarkable event...
Why?
An event because, yes, it's an event.
A client like this in
the baby food product line...
where everybody in the ad world
knows him to be a tough nut...
you floored him with the depiction
of the story.
I've done as per the brief
given by the client
They give a brief and then change it...
Change it very often...
So I'm saying we, who are admirers of the
lady...
Admirer!
We, who are admirers, are requesting...
requesting earnestly
Shila, I am requesting today you'll have
whisky just to celebrate this occasion...
No... no... no... not me.
I suggest we all invade her flat
one of these days.
Today a few important questions have come
to my mind... that's why my letter...
with whom and for whom is our war... with
the public and for the public...
for farmers, middle class
and working class people...
my question... have all of
them joined as they should have?
Not in fear but at their own urging.
Hello...
You... ringing up once again...
No, I won't listen to anything...
I'm telling you I won't say...
what's the matter with you...
Haven't I told you?
Look, look, why do you keep
disturbing me like this?
Why do you go on disturbing me again and
again...
When you know the relationship has ended.
Then allow
me to live as I wish...
You do as you wish.
Yeah right, I'm responsible.
Your behaviour... you day after day...
You listen to me, yeah...
So what do you want me to do... what?
Money...
You want money...
Again.
Blackmail...
Aren't you ashamed?
No! No... you won't get even a paisa...
Yeah... I am aware of prestige... I've been
able to leave you as I'm aware of it...
Why are you telling about this again...
look, leave me alone... I'm tired...
No more
The child is mine.
...the child is mine...
No more!
Well, in the drawing room...
meaning in that room, I saw a picture
on the wall, a painting... whose?
Oh!
Yeah
Whose picture is that?
That is my son...
Why?
Oh! Just...
An artist, one of our friends painted
it... how is it?
Good... what's his name?
Whose? Of the artist?
No your son's...
Kunal
Kunal?
A very unusual name... how old is he?
Now... 6 years old.
Does he still ride horses? I saw a wooden horse
in that room
No... no not horses... horses
aren't in now... now it's cricket...
Ready... Googly...
Oh my!
Slowly
Out!
My son says he is Gavaskar...
And you? Bedi...
Chandrashekhar?
When my son comes... I am not spared...
Meaning when he comes to Calcutta... he
studies in Darjeeling... on vacation...
You'll excuse me...
Last night when you were talking
on the phone... I heard...
You became very excited...
you weren't talking normally...
Talking loudly... and I
was just in the next room
All my friends... got quite messed up,
you know...
I tried very hard... But we couldn't
live together...
He was creating a lot of trouble...
He is still making trouble.
Tries to...
Oh! I'm going to be late for the office...
I'm leaving, okay?
Won't you eat anything?
I'll have to get my breakfast
somewhere else...
You finish all these.
Okay.
Last night you didn't have dinner...
very bad...
Hello, my name is Shila Mitra.
Me and a few of my office colleagues
have come on a special mission.
To make a survey.
Which you can call... yeah, an attitude
survey...
We've got a question for you... we've
heard of many changes in our country...
social, political and many others.
Our question is, this
change... could it be found
in the relationship
between female and male...
or is it that whatever was there
forever is still going on?
Listen... nowadays going out,
working, earning...
we are doing everything like men...
but still what is needed for total
freedom of women hasn't happened as yet.
Because even now whether we earn or whether
we travel...
whatever... depends on
the consent of men...
we do not do anything
against their will.
On paper female and male
enjoy the same rights...
that's what we've heard...
we can only say more and more
women are getting an education...
and getting the opportunities of an education...
they have gotten a certain amount
of economic freedom.
If you talk about the social
structure of our country...
then it has to be said that the conditions
still prevailing in our country...
have not changed totally...
some changes have come but not completely...
As for the partial changes
that have occurred
there certainly has
been some respectability.
I can't say exactly if the respectability
has increased...
what has increased is the awareness that...
relations between male and
female are under stress and strain.
The more women enter the labour market
and mercantile affairs as a commodity...
their identities are getting changed...
Nora's privileged position
in The Doll's House...
here I use the word
privileged in quotes...
they've definitely come out of there but
haven't gotten the same recognition as men.
A society stands on its wealth... this
society...
...like other countries, ours
too is a democratic country...
here, who's got the wealth
also has the power...
here, those who aren't rich equally have
no pride
I've seen from the experience
of my political career...
that in any movement a young widow
comes with such determination for our work
that those who live under the guardianship
of husband or son... they can't...
she always waits for the agreement
of husband or son.
In any poor family where
the husband is established...
such families are a fine picture...
but where the wife is more
established than the husband...
there arises some complex
question... husbands can't accept it...
quarrels start and the results don't
bode well.
You can see changes everywhere...
about 20 years ago I saw a group of 15
or 16 women going to the Ganges to bathe
taking at least a boy of 10 years old...
now you do not find such things...
but in my own family my mother-in-law
has never gone out anywhere
without a closed horse-driven cart...
but after my marriage
gradually I've seen her
going to her daughter's place
by bus, going to the hospital...
in all places, in meetings
and processions, on roads,
buses and trams, in cinema
halls and playgrounds,
I'm seeing women in large numbers...
but this is not enough of a change...
because the main thing is the
oppressive social conditions...
Here if the social structure is not changed,
the freedom of women is doubtful...
The conditions are so intertwined that
unless the social structure is changed
there can't be any change
in women's conditions.
I'm saying again before
ending my long letter
...India now requires
revolution in all stages.
Darkness, superstition,
poverty and oppression...
against all sorts of attacks...
to create a new society
and new people...
but if we ever make any
mistake in this extreme war...
If we take wrong steps
in blind rage...
if we get sucked into destruction
and blundering mistakes
then history will never forgive us.
I salute the revolutionaries.
Hello what's up? At this time?
What's the time?
An executive director of our company
died... a stroke...
...the office is closed.
Very good... so! Now you can have a good
sleep
I came to the office today...
there was a board meeting...
Anyway... I'd like to have tea
Hello...
This is a wrong number.
Tea or coffee?
Tea
I knew you would have tea...
Why do you read so many books?
Did you say something?
No... I was saying hasn't Biman come today?
No... he hasn't come the last 4 days
What? He isn't in any trouble... is he?
No... problem... I don't think so...
Nothing more to say... don't you see in the
papers how arrests are being made!
Why are you laughing?
There will be none to continue the heritage.
Meaning
because of the arrests being made!
Biman is a very cautious person...
he won't be caught easily...
Probably he is angry at me.
Really?
Yeah that day I had a big argument
with him.
What? You are like us...
if you quarrel you don't see each
other's face...
there must be some cause.
Yeah... there is...
I probably said a little too much
that day...
Maybe... he has reported against me...
I am showing doubts...
criticism, frustration, defeatism.
Take it... the latest... you haven't got it...
How did you get it?
Why? Haven't I got any intelligence?
No... not that...
A bearer of my office supplies brings
these to me...
from somewhere he has heard that my
brother...
you know I'm not Bengali... my native place
is Punjab...
But I have been always here... in
Calcutta... my father had a business here...
The house that you have seen, all the
materials...
Everything is my father's...
my brother... younger brother...
my only brother, very bright like you all...
from childhood he was a bit unusual...
different from this house...
self-willed, obstinate...
a don't care type, independent...
used to quarrel
father didn't like his
friends... was very dogmatic...
It looked like they
were enemies forever.
Then one day 3 years ago... my brother
left the house... forever...
Punjab...
Punjab was very disturbed then as it was in
Calcutta.
Have you heard of Ropar?
Ropar... from there my
brother wrote a letter to me...
Don't think of me. I am not alone.
With me there are hundreds
of thousands of people...
those who are dreaming to build
a new society... fighting...
the hungry people of
our country are fighting.
People who barely have one meal a day.
All of Asia is
fighting, Latin America...
I want to live among all the
freedom loving people of the world.
That is the last letter of my brother.
Sumit
With revolutionary salutation, Sumit.
So nowadays Sumit...
So Sumit nowadays is thinking like this.
Sumit wants to meet you...
Wants to talk with you face to face...
and Nikhil whatever I said
about Sumit and the lady...
I've no concrete proof of that.
You just said you've seen them.
Yeah... just that... I saw just that...
I thought at the time.
Biman, you may go now... we will have to
think about Sumit.
Come back in about 4 days... go.
What do I say to Sumit?
You'll not go there now.
Okay.
Listen...
you are not eating properly...
your health is declining... be careful...
715r
The situation in your area is not good.
I know...
Do you know Amal?
Amal, who?
- Of Belgharia
Amal...? Is he arrested?
We have doubts about him...
we have concrete proof
Nikhil, you are making a mistake.
Go...
Long live... long live...
Unity of labour... war, war...
We want to live making war...
Dearness allowances must
be paid at the enhanced rate...
Retrenchment will not be allowed.
War, war we want to live making war...
Long live... long live...
Are you coming?
Oh no... ok bye... bye bye.
Bye bye thank you for coming
Good night... see you.
Hey... were you asleep?
No.
You had to remain confined for a long time.
So... what can you do?
You know, really I tried very hard to stop
them from coming today.
Why?
I don't like all this.
I've not said anything to you for you
to call them.
I didn't call them.
Your telephone...
your telephone
Hello...
you... how are you?
I'll call him. Hold on...
There's a call for you.
For me?
A call for me?
Yeah... Nikhil...
wants to talk with you...
Hello...
yeah, quite well... as far as possible in this
situation...
Nothing new... going on... yeah
For a few days me too... yeah
Yes I've talked with Biman.
Yes, I wrote those words in a letter.
How strange...
if I've some questions then...
Hey... listen Nikhil,
Nikhil... I am saying that
I don't want to talk about this
on the telephone or by letter...
No listen... strange... you
should at least listen to what I have to say
...yeah... I am saying... these
are certain basic questions...
which are to be discussed. Yeah...
should be discussed
face to face. Yeah...
What
Oh
Well indeed.
So you question my integrity...
after such a long time.
You... no listen Nikhil... for me to discuss
these issues... on the phone
if I could have faced
you then... these words
...no... no Nikhil... the lady...
...what?
Me?
The lady...
Who said this?
Biman...
Biman... has said?
Biman has reported?
Nikhil...
that's my personal matter...
yeah... I'm not bound to give an explanation
for this.
No... no!
What did Nikhil say?
Probably I can't stay in this house
anymore.
Why?
- That only Nikhil knows...
and Biman.
Come in.
Sit.
What's your news? It's been so long.
The key to your flat...
I'll not be needing it anymore
Would you have tea or coffee?
I'm in a hurry.
Wait for 5 minutes...
I've finished my work...
we will go together, yeah.
No... today I'm in a hurry... okay?
There's a saying in Bengali:
a dilemma everywhere...
my condition is more or less like that.
I was saying...
was saying
Here I've no problem...
you can stay here.
No... I can't
Why?
You thought everything is finished...
now only comfort and rest...
But I've not said this to you.
You know...
the time it takes to build a party,
it is the same when leaving.
But the party wants you...
Look...
the party is nobody's personal property.
You've got to fight inside and outside.
You are alone.
At present.
Biman will not come to this house anymore.
I know...
...once I too was like Biman...
didn't know how to question...
cannon fodder without questions, without
thought.
Where is Sumit? I need Sumit very badly...
the condition of Aunty is very bad...
your mother... your brother came to my
house...
Wants to see you at once... do what you think
best... I'm going...
You are alone.
At present.
Biman will not come to this house anymore.
I know...
...once I too was like Biman...
didn't know how to question...
cannon fodder without question, without
thought.
Where is Sumit? I need Sumit very badly...
the condition of Aunty is very bad...
your mother... your brother came to my
house...
Wants to see you once... do what you think
best... I'm going...
Biman!
Now what will you do?
What's the time?
It's about 9
Oh!
I can drop you there?
Okay... stop here... I'll get out...
it won't be prudent to go any further.
You'd better go...
Please ring me and inform me how she is.
- I'll try...
Do you know my number?
- Yes
I will wait...
You should leave. It won't be safe for you
to stay here alone.
Who? Who?
You?
Could have come a bit earlier...
since you finally came...
yeah, she wanted to see you.
Go
Biru
Why didn't come a bit earlier... you could
have seen her alive.
Biru, when did you inform Biman?
You were informed... who gave the message?
Listen.
Me.
I want to talk to you... come.
Hello, how are you dear?
Well
Sit
Please go away. I'll talk for some time.
That you've come is very good...
You are the elder son... you have
responsibilities.
They have come, all these people..
they are all aware.
So I was saying it won't be right for you
to stay here...
so I was saying don't worry about me...
they are here... somehow they'll manage
the necessary work
and Biru will do the last rites.
You'd better go before more people are aware.
Father, please be careful.
I'll be alright...
and Biru's job... I believe
he'll get it... but...
I'm going... I'm going.
Okay.
Well.
Mother talked about me?
Yeah.
I haven't yet said one thing to you.
I didn't tell your mother...
because of what would happen if I told her...
It wouldn't do her any good...
let the rest of her days be peaceful.
7 days ago...
the manager of our office called me
into his room...
only me... called many others...
and gave me a printed paper bond
I won't be able to strike gold with.
but I'm telling you...
I haven't signed that bond.
Go... to war.
FOOT SOLDIER.