Watch out!
No
Oh my God, oh my God
It's nothing
Yes, it's something
It holds
Stop it
Stop it or I leave
Stop it, please
There's a tier below, don't be afraid
Please
That's the point
If I die?
Sorry?
Then I die after you
That's the point, I don't want to die,
so don't die, come
Come!
Come fetch me
You managed to go there, you manage
to come back - No that's not true
Coming
Please, come back, please, I beg of you
Look, I never kneeled
There, I'm out of my home
so come home
At last I get you back
You don't have to be afraid
Yes I have to
For this semester's end:
possible topics for my video reportage
Virginity in Maghreb
Difficulty to be a man
Premarital sexuality
Modern life and respect of the traditions
Possible topics for my video reportage
Virginity in Maghreb
Difficulty to be a man
Premarital sexuality
Modern life and respect of the traditions
And now, our reportage on the forms
of homosexual unions
continues with an exclusive
interview of Abdellah Taïa
writer born in Rabat
who just published his first book.
Abdellah Taïa, do you think
a form of civil union
could be legalised in Maghreb by Muhammad VI
or President Ben Ali?
Civil union...
Well, it's not my...
I don't know what I ought to answer...
and what I would like...
but I don't think this will happen
someday in Morocco
but...
we do have better
rather we had better
It was marriage between nmen
in the oasis of Siwa
which is in Egypt
just near the libyan border
there was, till the middle of XX century
weddings between men
More exactly, it was a specific social class
which was called "Eggallah"
they were workers
for the wealthy in Siwa
and, as they couldn't wed
before they were 40
they had the opportunity
to marry youths
15, 16, 18, something like that
so they proposed to the family
they gave a dowry
they a wedding was celebrated
As there was a lot of palm trees
they devote themselves to some practice
They let their sensuality,
their male sensitivity, express itself
dancing an singing
You have to know that, at night,
the best way to have fun is to dance.
Oh yes, I saw a clip, in Algeria
What's her name, Britters...
Britney Spears
Yes, her
she was dancing with a mini skirt
it's censored, down there
They cut it?
Yeah
I swear
It's a religious country
I don't think so
You go in the bushes
You find Muslim Sisters
and that's what they are doing
Nowadays, for them
twiddling in the bushes
or someplace
it's normal
it's normal, yes
And above all, don't touch...
vagina, or...
So that's hanky-panky
No it isn't, far from it
it's a form of homosexuality
yes, from behind
the boy gets his own pleasure
the girl make do
it's a pity
If you think those people...
they are constrained to do it
so you got many frustrated people
Ethnic an gay tea dance
Every Sunday - Black, White, and Coloured
Why are they late?
Yeah?
Can I speak to you for a moment?
Yeah, go on
It's just to ask you...
I'm doing something about...
I've problems finding guys who'll...
join my reportage
What kind of reportage?
It's...
It's a sociology topic
for my school, I have...
to interview gays from...
Why are you asking me? I'm not gay!
No, no insult intended
No, you come to me...
but it's not because I'm there
on a Sunday that...
No, I don't want to have
anything to do with your trick
No, it's no trick...
No, that' all
Hey... wait!
No, I can't, I told you
To submit your ad, please wait...
Hello
I call for your ad in the papers
I'm much interested,
and I'm OK to be screened
for an interview
You are?
Karim
Hi
I wasn't sure
I almost knocked at the other door
Oh yes?
Make yourself confortable, take a chair
It looks like good equipment
That's my parent's,
for holidays, and everything
So you're Tunisian
You did watch some practices...
homosexual practices down there
What differences have you noticed with here?
What can I say?
Don't you want us to speak more of myself,
my personal experience?
Yeah, go on
Actually, I'm a performer
I work mainly with my body
Artworks take place on my body
Explain
You see, I get naked
and I ask a man to make a drawing
with henna on my skin
on the spot he wants
Afterward, I ask him to take pictures of me
So, I become a living sculpture for the man
who let his mark on my body
a living sculpture, existing till
the henna disappears
But... what's the connection
with you homosexuality?
In fact
it's often Maghrebin people
as yourself
with whom I make love
I want my lovers to make an artwork with me
and it can be heterosexual people, too
You know what?
I've never filmed my performance
Would you like me to become your artwork?
So I'll strip
I'll bring my syringe
and you'll make a drawing on me
Don't worry, it'll be quick
Would you open the door, please?
You'll do your artwork without me
Listen, I'm...
That's not the topic.
Stop laughing
Do you think there is...
a homosexual algerian identity?
I don't know, I'm sorry
I don't know well since
it's been a while since I went in Algeria.
due to the problems.
Last time I went,
I was 17 or 18
From my innocent view, I saw homosexuality
without knowing what it is really.
The thing is, people flirted with me
I thought it was only a contact
a contact between algerians
I know arab contacts are very strong
one holds hands
have some kisses
I think in Maghreb,
a great lot of people are homosexual
But some do it because they like it
others do it short term,
during boyhood
and then, they marry
Was it a burden for you,
when you were young?
I knew it quite lately
lately?
three years ago
and during these three years,
I spend two with somebody
I'm quite faithful, so I stayed with
this person, without questionning
I fell in love with him.
It's over for a year, so now
I enjoy parisian nights
you understand?
Which country do you like most?
Certainly Egypt
Join the club
But you don't know it
Egypt? No.
No, but sensitivity and...
I don't know, but the way
guys sing down there
It's sensitive, it's romantic
Perhaps romantic isn't appropriate word,
but it's sensitive, they aren't afraid to...
they don't fear to express themselves
That's... it a way I appreciate
Oriental music...
it's a sensitive music generally
Very sensitive
And I feel, I'm sure you dance quite well
What makes you say that?
I don't know
We've got time
You could dance for me
you owe me that much
Sure
You could do...
You could show me
how well you dance
I do dance, but...
only for myself
Well Ok
I hope you'll be able to help me because...
till now, the testimonies I got weren't
very deep or interesting
Actually, I don't know
if I can suggest something
really interesting...
What I'll do is...
I'll present you...
a few member's addresses
Say you come from me, it's important
Are they all gay?
Yes, all of them, without exception
as are most members of our association
aside a few heteros
who joined us, funny
Those I selected are serious
no problem
They are willing to be filmed openly
as we agreed on the phone.
Otherwise, I've an interesting contact
an association called ADRIS
who fights for clandestine gays
At the moment, they see to a maghrebin
an algerian who flew his country
who's refugee in France, for the moment.
My name's Mohamed
I'm gay, I'm algerian
I was born in Algiers, I'm 27
Homosexuality is a highbrow term in Algeria
people can't understand
what it means
When you are told "homosexual"
especially people who didn't go to school
they can't understand
people only say
gay,, for them, it's not...
beware, it's an insult
when you say, it's somebody
well,, it means, it's somebody
who's "in his ass"
who gets fucked
but it's not for someone
who fucks, because the one who fucks...
...is a macho, a true man
despite he fucks, he's still seen as a man
I would say, he's accepted
despite he's wicked
he's still respected
that is, his authority is respected
he pass
so society won't reject him
or won't be ostracised
they may wipe it away
but somebody who gets fucked
he got...
not only he gets fucked, but
he gets... all the bad jobs to do.
so it's important
It's passive homosexuality,
I insist, passive...
homosexuality who's condemned.
How are you?
7 floors!
Sorry
Do you like me fat,
ou do you want me to slim?
Thanks
Take a smoke, if you like
Oh, I got some, for once
But they come from America
so they are "deesgusting"
Yes, as at home
See, "deesgusting"
"deesgusting"
How are you going?
Well, I was viewing my film
Hey, I've something for you
Look, your double
It'll look good with your pic, yonder
Michelangeli
Good, my gazelle
As soon as I saw the colors, they seemed...
Funny, the expression is the same
You could believe you did it on purpose
the same position
I think the drawer made it on purpose
He copied me
He copied your facial expression
It's nice, isn't it?
Actually, it makes an axis
symmetry
- Like a couple that...
I cheated on you
There you go! I knew,
going and coming from Algeria...
But she's no algerian
No, we knew her like you before
For the green card, right
But I had her put a veil, otherwise...
True, with a face like that,
it has to be the green card
Well, I saw this pic, it's beautiful
Hi, Karim, I'm in transit in Mykonos
I just visited the island of Delos
I wish you could film me here. I like being
in front of cameras, especially yours. Farid.
Hi, Farid, Karim speaking
I want to thank you for the pics
They're lovely. If you want to
see them, just call me back.
I'm busy just now
I changed at the airport
so you can come right now, if you like
I see you ran
Back from your journey?
Yeah, I arrived just now
How come you're sweating so much?
It's quite hot outside
Yes, but that much, though...
What?
That much?
You're from the countryside, no?
It's so high, you have to
deserve climbing to you
Wanna have a shower,
before I show you the pics?
Just a fresh T-shirt, so...
Ah shit, I suggest a shower,
you ask for a T-shirt
Either one, you don't mind?
Yeah, never mind
Is it OK?
Yeah, fine
Want something to drink?
Whatever, as long as I drink
OK
Since you ran, water will be fine
Where are you changing?
Wow, what a man!
Don't get excited, please
Karim
Tequila, or...
Yeah
Tequila
Alcohol is bad.
I like bad things
I stop, you must be thirsty
Alcohol is bad, but you seem to have a lot
I entertain a lot
You know how to entertain
I have to, people must feel at ease
Thanks
You fell alright by me?
Health
Stop it
Are you uneasy?
Well, I don't know
Don't be afraid, I won't jump on you
So are you showing me these pics?
I look well, don't I?
Yes, you look good on video
Thanks
You too, you look good
Yes, but I don't get filmed.
Your turn will come
Inch'Allah, as one say.
Inch'Allah
Yes, I hear you
Ciao
- Bye
See you
Call me as soon...
- Call me whenever you like
- Fine
Karim, for the interview,
I wish to go to the Calanques
at a naturist spot. Don't be afraid,
nothing's going to happen to you
No trap
but I wish to go there, I like the place.
You introduce yourself ahead of my camera
It will perhaps be showed to students
things like that
Doesn't it bother you?
Of course it does
But I think I'm above that
regarding my ho...
my sexuality, plainly
I'm above that
Yes, I had problems, like
identity problems regarding
my culture and...
my origins, therefore my sexuality too
but it's going on
So long as I assume, myself,
it's going fairly well with others
It would be more difficult
telling my mother I eat pork
than I am gay
- Oh yeah?
- Yes
- Does your mother know?
- Yes, she does
Did she take it well?
No!
But she knows
- She knows
- Yes
Karim, I warn you, I'm going to strip
I hope it won't upset you
Why don't you strip?
Because I'm modest.
Do you want help spreading
lotion on your back
Do you stay there?
Yes
I go strolling
I can't hear you, who's that?
Hello
OK, I hear better, now
OK, now I know who it is
bacause I couldn't hear you,
it went "trbbshhh"
Where are you?
What did you say?
WHere are you?
It's up to you
call me when you come back in Paris
or we arrange a appointment just now
if you like, eh, only if you want to see me
I ask you, if you like,
if you have something to do
perhaps you don't feel like it, you'd like to
stay... I don't know, that's why I ask you
OK, fine, you call me back
So, is you book going fine?
I don't know
Of course, hanging around backrooms...
- I've no means to know, and moreover...
- Why?
Because I've to ask the publisher,
ask the bookshops, and...
On the other side, there's been
no review, nothing
Silence
That's good, but...
But people who know you, who've read
the book, how do they see you?
As a freak, as before
Even you say quite often I'm a freak
Stop thanks
- Go on, help yourself.
- Thanks, I'm not hungry
I actually came to see you
not to eat.
That's soja
Did you ear me?
Go on, eat!
Do you assume your homosexuality,
compared with before?
No, I don't
- Still not.
- No
It hurts me
Every time I ejaculate, I cry
and do you wash afterward, as before?
No, I don't do it anymore
You know, I'm making a reportage...
on homosexuality, right now
Would you like to...
participate.
Do you make movies, now?
I begin to.
You've done everything
At 15, you were in politics
What's the them of your film?
Homosexuality in Maghreb
For me, what's important is...
to drop these questions right now
I mean in my life
and everybody's life.
There're two questions I don't ask myself
but I understand people who...
ask themselves when they are 20...
20, 25 years old
That's homosexuality and origins.
Homosexuality and origins,
it a final question
Yourself, how do you stand
towards sexuality?
Sexuality?
I stand... as an heterosexual
But that's a bit strange
you make a movie on that
when you stand as an hetero
Sociology is studying society
Yes, but one chooses a subjet
chooses a subject in relation
with one's interests
in relation with...
do you feel personally concerned,
in this work...
in this task?
That's a theme that hasn't been covered yet
You mean your film...
you apply sociologic methods
to a documentary?
I don't apply anything. I light up a light.
Light keeps eroticism out, tight?
Does it suits you...
this interview?
Yes, it's fine with me
because it's important
I know another guy who's working
on that subject, too
on Homosexuality in Maghreb
I think it's his film's title
Homosexuality in Maghreb
Funny, I saw you at the same time
I thought you worked together
but you don't know him at all.
What's his name?
Farid?
Yeah, speaking
Yes, I'm fine
What do I mean, could you come, just now?
What's that?
You know quite well, it's my number
Do you know who gave it to me?
Oh yes, I've got an idea
You've got an idea
Yeah
And what were you doing with him?
It's a friend
It's a friend whom you filmed
So what?
So what, you're doing a film about
homosexuality in Maghreb, he told me
Oh, there, cool down, that's it
You don't offer me a drink,
where's hospitality?
Well, I go to see someone,
you go before me, you... tell me!
Think some.
Think what?
You interviewed him the day before me
But, Karim
No, you tell me
if you're doing a movie
You thought the idea is good
You wish to do it in my stead
Do you mean what you say?
No I don't mean it, I'm playing Shakespeare
But I did it only for you
that's it
That's for you
- Is it your interview?
- Yes
But why did you do it?
For you
Why, to help me doing it?
May I have a drink, now?
I don't want it
What do you have?
Tea
I'll heat up some water
But next time, warn me, I don't like...
I didn't want to disturb you,
I meant to surprise you
It's my first present. There will be more.
But it peeves me.
I've difficulties to find people
so if you take them as I find them...
Well, don't speak of it anymore
Your posters are fine
Ah, Farid el Atrache
I'm called Farid after him
Good music, good dance
What question did you ask him?
You'll see
In the new town of Marrakesh
near the great post office
where boys, at night,
dress as women
get feminine forenames
and wait there for a boy
wishing to... fuck them
It's why they are...
Thanks
You're welcome
No, I mean
A bit aggressive, no?
Unbelievable
- I didn't know you that way
- You're not angry?
No, frankly, no
Thanks
As an apology
Hey, I did my best!
I know, I'm patient
Why aren't you in your film?
Because it has no interest,
I'm not a homo...
I don't want to be filmed
just because I'm a beur
Stop it
But it's so small
You want to try?
Karim
Honestly, did you ever sleep
with another man?
No!
Siam and you are going well together
I mean, sexually, for example?
Very well, yes
Will you marry together?
- Do we wish to marry?
- Yes
We're speaking of it but...
I'm quite far from a decision
After marriage, for instance
...if you marry
- Yes
you realised that, all in all,
it doesn't suits you, and...
you fake love
what will you do?
Everything my poor heart wants to say
You are now my master
not knowing what to do with you
if I had bad intentions
because I'm good and kind, as God made me
I dvise love and innocent laughing
But this has no incidence on your life
because it's too locked up, so God made it.
I'll cover you with tender love
I will hurt you only with cuddles
if you were warmer and more relaxed
if you were less cold and distant
we could enjoy good moments
that will stay in our memories.
Hi Karim
I write to you from Amsterdam, where I went
to visit my friend, the photographer
I took the oportunity to search
for a possible gay mosque
I tried to call arab groups,
who could be interested.
I called several times, to no avail.
So I went to the Gay Documentation Center
there, I found documents which
could be of interest for you
I made copies for you
Eventually, I got in touch with one of the
gay group, called Yussef Foundation
That's what they said:
I don't want to establish a gay mosque,
the turkish group had that idea
They wished to benefit from a turkish imam
who came to Netherland,
and get back to his country
The aim of Yussef Foundation isn't radical,
we just try to change mentalities
inside muslim communities, and to create
a research group within Islam
to study an acceptance pattern of homosexuality,
so that Imams learn to confront the idea
We don't seek revolution, only evolution
That's it, I'll try to find a camera
to shoot both groups.
without any guarantee. See you. Mustapha
I hav to go to a photographer.
Do you want to come with me?
What kind of photos?
Photos for a casting
I've a lot of addresses.
Moreover, they are looking for...
young english-speaking arabs
for a feature length
and since you speak english, so...
But I don't want to become an actor.
Why, are you afraid of your body?
I've to shoot closer
like that
yes, very good, don't move
yes, super
you know, the difficulty for the photographer
is to resist being carried away, by himself...
or by his model
He has to resist the desire to shoot
until the craving is so irresitible
he can't do otherwise but shoot
Yes, very good
Yeah
Don't move away
Yeah. I manage quite well
with men, doing nothing
Yes, there, there, don't move
Good! Oh well
Yes, super, super, super, don't move away
Beautiful!
Wow
7 o'clock Place Clichy, did you say?
Half past 7 at La Chapelle, OK
OK?
Is it OK?
It's always happening to me
As soon as somebody is,
even slightly, disturbed
God send him to me. Psychologist on duty
You have the lawyer for the poors,
and I am psychologist on duty
I've something to fulfil
which will certainly go
through music and dance
but I can't explain... the relation with...
if it'll continue, I don't know
I've enough with guys who
don't know what they want,
where they are.
I have to consult a real psychologist
Hi, it's Farid
Listen, I just land
and I'm fine
could we see each other?
I've something to...
- You're OK?
- Jet lag.
Did you film anybody, meantime
What are you reading, Jean Genet?
Yes, Jean Genet's life
Listen, I'm quite tired
I can understand
I'm tired
strip your jacket, why don't you...
I don't dare, I'm so shy
You, shy?
Isn't Siam here?
No, she's out for a stroll
Damn, it's a book
"Do you love me?"
"When I saw this sweet young man
"He was laughing out
"We were both
"alone with God
"However, he put his hand in mine
"and talked a lot
"then he asked me 'Do you love me?'
"Yes, beyond love"
Wow
Arabs are so good
"For you this book
of persian poems
"As for my dedication
"Jean Genet will do it in my stead
"Farid, who cares for you"
- Why a camera here?
Did you interview somebody?
No, I put it there...
to shoot me dancing.
Could you show me some?
May I take a shower?
I go lying down there
Make yourself at home, you didn't forget!
But I feel at home here.
I don't mind, do as you please.
Do you keep your promises?
What?
Do you usually keep your promises?
Sure. What about?
Massage, for instance.
Massage?
You told me you would massage me.
Did I?
I didn't speak of massage.
That's my spare keys,
come whenever you like.
These two dainty little hands!
Oh there you go
It's cute
Ah back off
Stop it
Ah! "Mouk"
"Mouk"!
You wanna play
Stop fooling aroud
Stop it
If you do it again, I overthrow that
You bastard!
OK, let's stop together
I did that when I was 10, are you mad?
I blessed you, you won't be gay anymore
I'll cruise you
You got an rendezvous... love?
Yes. Are you jealous, do you want to go with me
Do you want to see how it is between gays?
- Between men?
- Yes
I'd like to see that, yes
Ah but you have to pay for it. Be laid down.
Are you top or bottom?
- I will top or bottom you!
- Oh I begin to learn
Where did you learn these words? Honestly?
Top bottom?
Do you loiter in the Marais, now?
No, I don't
That makes them believe
it's a cruising trick
But you've got a way to kindle people
I mean, when you look...
you kindle
- Me?
- You know quite well
You're kindling yourselves,
as soon as you see me, you ogle
Star!
Who do you take you for?
You loiter gay places, you look like a gay
you ogle like a gay
and you're dressed as a gay
I'm sorry, I'm not dressed as a gay
You're a faggot... a fag-got
And the faggot sneers at you
Yes you do!
- Are you bottoming, tonight
- Of course...
I'm fed up toping
Oh yes, with Siam
Yes, you must be loose,
now, it doesn't appeal to me
I'm no bottom
You're not a bottom?
No
you'd like me to be, he, bitch
You'd like me to be a bottom
You're a kindler
Shit, that's for me
Hurry up, your lovers're there
Top!
Do you have gel?
- Gel?
- Do you have any gel?
I put some in my hair,
what are you thinking about?
Seriously, ask him if I may come
Oh he's hot, you're
a lucky man to have Farid
he's so hot
Don't listen to him
He's plain silly
I'm not silly, I love sex
At the end you open your ass with...
Are you stuck? It's not entirely inside?
It's too big. That's why. Piss off.
You're a loose hole, that's it
Yes, he only speaks sex. He's crazy
And he claims he's not gay
Stop it with your little shitty taboos
What's the meaning of all that
Of course you get butt-fucked
its looses up, it dilates
- So, we meet at your place, boulevard
Voltaire - Can you turn around, please?
I wanna light up my cigarette
He's jealous. He's jealous, that's why, it's because
he's in love with me, that's why he's like that
Give me a cigarette, Siam
Give me one, go on
Hey, what's your problem?
You wanna say something, what's that
how come you throw me that pack
can't you give it normally,
as normal people do
I have to say I exist
You have to talk, there is something
you have to say, speak up!
You don't do motions like that, if you want
to play such motions, I'll show you how I play
you're gonna regret what you've just done
I'll show you who's the gentle sex
I can't believe it, you ask for a cigarette,
she becomes crazy
WHat's the problem, where's your problem
you haven't spoken for days
Speak up, let's start
the discussion, speak up!
I have problems, too,
I have things going in my head
Don't do it again, never!
Never again. Next time you have something
to say, just speak up
I can't stand moods like that
What will you write down?
What will you write down? Your mood?
What you want to tell me?
Tell it to me, now, in front of me
so you'll see my reactions, live
Now, if it's your way to talk,
write your letter and get lost
Don't talk with me. Damn, women!
You want us to stay like that for years.
Karim
I'm going
I discovered, in one of your books
the charming dedication that the boy
called Farid, wrote to you
I you love him, go with him
I can't live with a man who doesn't love me
who loves somebody else
Of late, you didn't touch me anymore
you didn't want me to touch you
I need love
I can't live without tenderness
If you think you love me, come back
I don't say we won't meet again
I need time to think
Bye for now
Siam
Yes, sure you can come
Siam went back to Algeria
We live like rats, here
It's hard, within this society which
doesn't understand anything
It's really risky, nowadays
to be discovered as a homosexual
and arrested by the state
You can be raped, beaten al night long
you can even die, without your family
knowing anything about you
A whore lived in the neighborhood, once
she got... killed
She got... slayed
Hey, Karim
Karim
So tell me about your problems
Well, I stop the film-making
I don't know, the subject isn't innocent
perhaps I choose it unconsciously to...
I don't know, to expose my desire for men
Don't you have a girlfirend?
It's over
You didn't tell me that
No, because it's over,
and it's between she and me
Anyway, I'm unable to live with somebody
We'll never marry, so?
Do you want to travel with me, see the sun
show you homosexual practices in Maghreb
I will be your guide.
Day after tomorrow
As you see, there's two of them
for both of us
What do you plan to do there?
Assert if you are truly gay, or not.
No, why did you want to bring me there
since you didn't know I took this decision
I wished to be a longer time with you
I, alone
at least a week
to see if we are made for each other
You only have to say yes
Yes to what? The journey, or you and me?
The journey, first
us, later.
No, I left Siam, I'm not oing with a man
I don't know where I stand.
- Karim
what you just said is quite contradictory
anyway, you're gay
Look at me, please
Stop that
What are you doing? Stop it.
You don't know what you miss.
I don't know, I don't want anymore
Finish your project, first
I feel like filming
Be a man, now, OK?
Eh Karim
OK?
How do I do?
I'm sorry, we got a double room,
but I've to smoke
- Oh no, no
- I smoke
You go smoking outside
- No, I smoke
- You're not smoking in the room
That's not your home
Go smoking there
No, I smoke
Go smoking in the hammam
I can't smoke where it stinks
It doesn't stink, it smells
No, smoke outside
Where are you smoking?
Fine, I go outside
I'm outside, but...
Do you fuck?
- What?
- Do you fuck?
Do I fuck?
Yes, it happens, sometimes
Would you like a shower?
As they say in the traveller's guide
what you shouldn't do is
assuming young people walking in the street hand
in hand, or rather finger in hand, are gay
it's a sign of friendship, and not homosexuality.
Wow, top camera
I know
It's ten times better than mine
I know too
Smile to the camera
How are you?
Like that?
Go on, pose
You can also shoot stills with that?
Wow, what a item
Am I the item
Oh yes, excuse me
Are you shooting?
Yeah
First day of filming. It's very hot,
we just arrived in Marrakesh
the town, where, it is said,
homosexuality is quite tolerated
Marrakesh is the Moroccan Marais
Yep
It's the "Funkish" district
There's surely a lot of
gay young Maghrebin here
but I don't know where they hide
Seems gay bars exist, like in the Marais
but here, no bar claims to be openly gay
and anyway, no native
will let himself filmed
Well, that's Marrakesh
the great square I show you before
lot of cruising
Tourists?
yes, tourists.
Prostitution, then?
Yeah
I took a few notes
I'll read them to you
Sexuality can't come true
only in the rightful frame of marriage
with the almost exclusive
goal of reproduction
Islam rejects any whim during
sex, refuses passing unions
and condemn free union
However, age of marriage comes late
so, for lack of performing heterosexual sex
whereas he's in full possession
of his sexual organs
the young finds in homosexuality
a feasible outlet to hetero sex.
So homosexuality is quite
practiced before marriage
and operates like a substitution sexuality
So it's a normal evolution
of young maghrebin sexual life
You know, I've read that, so...
I'm not aware
now you've seen it
but the gesture is...
And all these people, all these boys,
what are they here for?
Amongst these people, almost 80% have
already had a relation with a same sex person
Look, as people pass by, they ogle
- Whether they wear a jellabah or not...
- That's normal
Why is it normal
I've been cruised quite a lot,
since we are here
The guy in the shop, where we were
he told me you're an algerian, i said yes
he told me I can see it, because
it's beautiful people, all that
After that, he asks me which hotel I
stay in, and if he may come tonight
Did you give him the name of our hotel?
Yes, but he didn't know it, and
I didn't took the trouble to explain
I told him if I wished to see
him again, I'd come back
Why did you give him
the name of the hotel
whilst you know he was cruising you,
he told you you were cute
Because when you are in it,
first you are surprised
as long as he hasn't done a true approach
a positive and honest approach
he said he wanted to come
- Somebody tells me algerians like you are cute
- Listen, you have the habit, I don't
I didn't know he...
- if I become jealous... - He says...
he just said which hotel are you in
then he told me...
- Don't forget I speak arab, he wondered if...
- So at that moment, you were being cruised
Some guys made me understand they were
at my service in every sense of the word
and I know it doesn't cause any problem
I know they are quite...
they are quite warmhearted, quite close
Karim
After Wermeer
the male "Venus of Milo"
How's my garb?
What?
Too long?
Too long
Do you know Siwa
Yep
There has been men's weddings till the 40s
and you know, an anthropologist said
there, at the beginning of the century,
homosexuality was thriving
every man had sodomy
they spoke of it openly
and bosses had harems with boys
in Siwa oasis
Egypt was quite open, at that time, no?
What are you ogling like that?
Not much to ogle here.
There's me
Karim, you're a startled virgin, who waits
the wedding to be deflowered. Farid
Farid, if you write instead of talking, I can do
as much: don't be so much of a bully with me
If you want me, learn to be more delicate
Is it OK?
Wait, I pushed some button
Give it to me
Why?
I will do the film
- What's that?
- I will act as the guide
Why, are you aware now?
We won't use many cameras
That's mine
Wait, don't be afraid
Farid, do you want me to be your guide?
Are you really a student in psychology?
Yeah?
Oh well. I've never checked.
I didn't check if you were a real steward
I've never said...
I've never told you to trust me
Go on. Be the guide.
I'm your guide?
Amongst places which allow
closeness of same sex people
there's also the
the coranic school is where the child has
his first contact with sacred texts
the sexual dimension takes its place
it's often with his body's favors
that the boy bypass
his master's aggressivity
When the master doesn't pay attention
the oldest schoolboys take charge of
the initiation of the youngest
indulging in sodomy with them
People overlooked homosexual
practices in these places.
Some even say the master's sperm
includes a measure of intelligence
and divine blessing
A Middle Atlas proverb says:
"He who wants to learn,
should go under the master"
You should sign up your texts, Farid
Don't play with that
How I love you!
Put you hand away
Farid is upset, and doesn't want
to be filmed anymore
Don't look and you won't hear anymore
The road to love
You don't want to take, o my heart
the road that leads to love
Everything is ready for you now,
but you don't want to do anything.
Say yes to me
Take a responsability
at least once in your life
Farid, won't you stop your acting?
Karim
Say yes or no to me
Hey! It's yes or no. Now!
I've other things to do,
I'm not at your disposal
Lovers or nothing
Lovers or nothing, that's it
I don't want to make the movie anymore
I don't know where all that story leads
I don't know where all that story leads, and I ask
myself questions without finding any answers
He told me I want to go
to Jean Genet's grave
before going away
To say the truth, I didn't expect that
but I was happy to go there
"For you this book of persian poems
As for my dedication, Jean Genet will do it in my stead
When I was a child, God was mostly a picture
God didn't count in my kid's little life
At 15, I was seriously ill
every day, in hospital, a nurse
brought me a candy, saying
That's the sick boy next room
who sends it to you
I went better, and after a fortnight,
I wished to see
and thank the boy who sent me
a candy every day
I saw a 16-17 years old guy,
who was so good looking
everything that existed before
didn't count anymore
God didn't exist, he was God
From that guy, a lot of copies were made,
who became all the lovers I had until a decade
but no faded copies, on the contrary copies
sometimes cuter than the original
So God, it's in Greece I knew Him best
Greece, and arab countries
Buy a postcard, it's easier
Romantic pics for a dime, do you
want me running on the shore?
Come along
There is an excerpt on a city in Algeria
where weddings between men took place
as in Siwa
Listen
Practices we call aberrant
are normal in other societies
especially homosexuality which often enjoys
unanimous apporbation from the group
as in the case of Beni Brahim, in Ouargla,
which dispense men's weddings
before the ordinary marriage.
Karim, you talked again of men's weddings
So, meet me in an hour at Foucauld's square
Tomorrow mornig, we take the plane back
If you don't move until
then, it'll be too late.
What is it?
Well,
you'll have to give it to me, now.
Subtitles: coucou21