THE MAN TO KILL
LEGEND OF TSAR
SHCEPAN THE LITTLE
a movie by
VELJKO BULAJIC
screenplay writers:
cast:
Directed by:
Since long time ago Montenegrins have
been talking about a mysterious tsar...
Shcepan the Little, who ruled over
Montenegro since 1767 to 1773.
Even today we do not know his real name
or where he came to Montenegro from.
His unusual personality and destiny
inspired the imagination of the people.
Woe!
Woe to us!
Elfa!
Elfa...
He must have been right about all,
since everyone was against him.
There hasn't been a more modest or
cheap tsar since the beginning of time.
No, really. He helped everyone.
And it eventually killed him.
Ah, Shcepan, Shcepan... My leader...
Our little tsar... Rest in peace.
SHCEPAN THE LITTLE (1768-1773)
The ruler and the lord of Montenegro
ST. PETERSBURG, 2/17/1766
THE COURT OF PETER THE THIRD
Bravo!
Monsieur...
Our father in Heaven,
our Lord Christ...
...bless our emperor
and our tsar...
..our Katarina...
...in the name of the Father,
and the Son,
and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Tsarina Katarina the Second!
Long live the tsarina!
Long live Her Majesty!
Long live!
On the double!
Take your guns!
Move! Move!
Montenegrins!
Captain Tanovic!
Where are you going?
Where are you going, captain?
-Tsar Peter the Third has been killed!
We are going to revenge
our protector.
Don't be silly. You are
in danger too, Tanovic.
This is a coup. Tsar's friends
are going to lose lives, too.
Who knows what happened to the tsar.
Therefore flee to your Montenegro,
if I'm correct, that's the name.
-Who are you?
Whoever he is,
he is right, captain.
Let us get out of here.
Come on.
Follow me!
THE HELL,
THE SAME DAY
Get up!
We've got mail.
Write down,
pal...
Incoming record number:
7643...
Top Secret. To be delivered
to supreme satan personally.
7643...  -An urgent message
from the First Order Agent.
They have killed the tsar... oh...
Peter the Third!
-Peter the Third...
How was he killed?
-There's no how.
It says: the tsarina and the
Church have killed him.
I must deliver this message
myself.
And you better don't fall
asleep again! Understood?
Understood, boss.
Boss! Ask the downstairs to
send us more coal!
I renounce... my husband...
What?  -An urgent message
for the supreme satan.
Go away!
An urgent message from the First Order
Agent, for His Excellency.
Your Excellency!
Your Excellency...
-Speak.
Extremely urgent message
for Your Excellency.
The First Order Agents asks
for your instructions.
Katarina killed Peter the Third and
seized the throne as Katarina the Second!
Summon the Council.
Sudden murder of Peter
the Third...
can disturb the balance
on earth...
which forces us to make
snap decisions.
For...
with Katarina's help, the Church
will strengthen its position...
among the people. It is absolutely
necessary for us to interfere...
in these events and thus
force our enemies...
to respect the share of influence:
a half to us, and a half to them.
Therefore I declare:
there can be no peace between
us and the clergy.
I am going to pay them back
in kind.
And now, gentlemen,
here is the plan:
we will deal with one allegedly
insignificant zone...
and that is...
Montenegro.
Peter the Third helped it and
supported its independence...
in war against the Ottoman Empire
and Venice.
That is why he was so
popular in Montenegro.
We will send to Montenegrins
one Agent of ours...
who resembles Peter the Third
as much as possible.
Such an agent will easily be accepted
in Montenegro as a tsar.
And when the world finds out that the
tsar Peter the Third is still alive...
we will be able to bring him to
Russia as the tsar...
and in that way restore the
balance again.
In order to gain complete trust
of Montegrins in his mission...
he must fight against Turkey
even more fiercely...
and you are to provide him with all
the help necessary for his mission.
All right, yes. Perfect.
It is good for Russia either.
Bravo! Bravo!
But you Russians must not forget...
that Turkey has some old
unsettled issues with Montenegro.
This is the opportunity for us.
We plead to grasp it.
What is good and what is bad for our
politics in the world, Kameleck...
can only be decided by me!
Understood?
That... that Montenegrin
captain Tanovic...
has come back to Montenegro from
St. Petersburg, hasn't he?
He has. The First Order Agent
said so.
Do we have any picture of that...
that Peter the Third?
Yes. Of course we do.
In the archive.
Alexander, Nikola, Stephen...
Shcepan... Shcepan. This will be his
name. That's a Montenegrin name.
Ingenious!
You know, when the leader
starts to accept flattering...
he makes the first step
towards his own destruction.
Is that clear?
Clear.
Just like your
respectful slap.
Tell the First Order Agent to move
to Montenegro at once.
Do your missions!
Merchants... Healers...
Whores... Lieutenant commanders...
Kid! Bring me the
Peter the Third's file!
Your Excellency, I beg your pardon.
The tsars are up there.
In separate archive with their
doubles.
Your Excellency, Peter the Third
and his doubles.
To send to Montenegro the agent who
only resembles Peter the Third...
it is a great risk.  -Yes, a risk, but
happiness makes politics, my dear.
Yes. Satan will help him,
but it won't be easy for him.
Perfect.
Why is the rule of the Church
in the world so unjust?
Who knows?
Come on, who knows?
You tell me.
In order to rule
men and countries,
the Church preaches that
the Judgment of God exists,
as well as the resurrection of the dead,
the transfer of souls to heaven...
Their goal is to usurp our part
of the rule over the people.
However, it's well-known,
the Satan is equal to God...
and they are two equal
rulers of the world.
Very well, sit down.
Who's gonna tell me how the
Church imposes its rule over the world,
and how we?
You tell me.
The same as we do. It decieves,
it takes part in army coups,
uses the military force, spies
and police.
Go! The class is over.
Go!
My goat!
How beautiful you are!
You have a noble face...
You are beautiful like a tsar!
And you shall be a tsar!
Me?
-Peter the Third!
What?
-Yes, my goat!
Tsar! Tsar!
Great is the power of satan.
He's coming! He shall win!
He shall win!
Great is the power of satan.
You've never dreamt about this!
Such an important mission!
And only because you
have a face like that!
Not face like that! But the face of
Peter the Third! Full of self-confidence,
aristocratic, noble!
Put on the clothes, come on!
No. I won't go.
I don't feel like going.
Why don't they send me to England,
France or Venice?
I won't go to that
tiny Montenegro!
But you will be there only a year,
my cursed!
Think of your career a bit,
think of me!
When you come back,
you'll no longer be a teacher,
but a high official!
Finally, it is a perfect
opportunity to make me happy.
Really?
Is this your gratitude?
If I hadn't helped you, you would
have been burnt at stake as a witch!
I, Farfa, saved you, even married
you, although you were a slut!
I didn't mean to offend you,
Farfa...
I've always been happy with you.
You are so good!
And you love me,
I know, Farfa...
Farfa...
I'm going. But...
To work!
Get up!
Come on, filthy priests! To work!
Quickly, quickly,
come on!
For God's sake, don't!
-How dare you call God!
This is your god,
take him! There!
Pull it, God's filth!
Faster! Faster!
Pull it, black priests!
You're not on earth any more!
Pull!
I would be so happy if I were
sent to the sunny Mediterranean!
To feel the sunshine again,
to hear singing...
and debauchery...
Debauchery...
Good.
I envy you, Farfa.
Montenegro is lovely.
Fresh lakes,
mountains, rivers...
And the sea... Ah, the sea...
I really envy you.
Indeed, he hadn't been in any mission
for long, right? -Since the 4th century.
Do you remember, Zephira, how beautiful
were the orgies in the time of Rome?
I still don't feel like going.
A year is a long time.
Farfa! Enough!
Enough!
Third Class Agent, Farfa...
Mission: one year in Montenegro, and
then to the throne of Russia.
Quite a delicate task!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
So...
Absinthe, klamath weed...
Ergot...
Mandrake...
Ament...
Costmary..
Bring the flame thrower!
Why did they choose Montenegro?
A small country with
good strategic position...
credulous people which
have strong connections with Russia.
and always waging war
against someone.
Oh, really?
Flame thrower. Try it,
that's the rule. Blow.
No! There!
You fool.
Stronger!
Justine!
-Don't be afraid, everything's fine.
Four black candles, and the arrow of
Amor which turns to a snake.
Try it too, that's the rule.
-No, you don't need this.
He'll find his way without it.
Good luck!
Come on, lift it!
Pull!
Push, the black priests!
Farfa...
-To work, get up!
Pull, the filth of God! Come on,
faster, faster! Pull!
Good luck!
Be brave!
Push, you filthy scumbags!
Push!
Where are you coming from,
people?
From Jad. We barely
escaped from death.
Where are you coming from, good man?
-Me, 2 children and wife, from Metohija.
Go.  -Thank you.
God bless you.
Thank you.
-Deacon, write down:
Husband, his wife and
two children from Metohija.
I am Stanko Palikarda,
and this is my daughter Elfa.
We are escaping from Greece.
From Morea.
Good bless.
Thank you.
-Father, bless her.
Elfa, God bless you.
Move on, people.
Next!
Don't make crowd.
Move, move.
Is anyone going to Cetinje?
Hey, you?
-Me?  -Yes, you.
Come here.
Where are you going?
-To Montenegro.
I'm sorry, I am coming from afar.
-Come on, you don't need to apologize.
What is your name?
-Farfa... I mean, Shcepan.
I gather herbs
and heal people.
Healer?  -Yes.
-Come over here.
Show me your herbs.
Costmary...
Ament...
Absinthe for the stomachache.
-I see.
Ergot.
And what is this for?
For abortion.  -Do you know that
it is forbidden by Church?
Are you a Christian?
Say "Our Father".
Say.
Say: "Our Father who are in heaven..."
"Who are in heaven."
"Hallowed be thy name..."
-Hallowed be... Hallowed be thy...
Who are...
Guard!
He doesn't know "Our Father".
-I don't know it either, deacon.
Listen.
Come with me.
Climb.
Take off your pants.
-But why?
Show me your manhood,
I want to see if you are a Turk.
Put them on.
It's all right. He's not circumcised!
He's a Christian.
Go!
Go away!
Go away.
I'm on a secret mission.
Go!
All right, you honoured me.
Now go.
Go away.
Go.
This healer...
I have a bad feeling about him.
There, there.
Go now.
Brothers and friends, the death of tsar
Peter the Third, God rest his soul,
brought a great calamity upon
us. Turkey and Venice...
won't spare us.
While Peter the Third was alive...
and helped us, sent us weapons
and protected us,
we could resist them.
It's rumoured that
he wasn't killed.
It's rumoured that he
wanders around the world.
If it could only be true, Markovic!
Montenegrins would be the happiest!
Our ruler and bishop
is good and honest,
but he's old.
He barely speaks.
Don't say that about our ruler
Sava Petrovic.
After all, he's still alive.
I don't mock our old bishop. I only
wonder what will happen tomorrow
with Montenegro, if that slut Katarina
goes to bed of the Turkish sultan.
Let the bishop offer the
treasure hidden in the monastery.
We must buy weapons and
ammunition in Kotor, at once.
He cannot rule like this.
Does he think we can defend the
country with clubs and stones!?
Let me speak,
Your Excellency.
What's the matter?
Captain Tanovic and his men
want to depose you!
And evil as they are,
they are going to kill you!
They will.
They will kill,
and depose me.
They will,
sons of satan.
For a single night they would spent
what we were collecting for years.
Move away, women.
Come on.
Move away.
Chew.
Good.
Get better.
Get better!
Good.
That's it.
You've been healed.
You've been healed!
Healed!
Yes, you are!
You've been healed.
Yes.
Healed.
Thank you...
Thank you.
Let me kiss your hand...
-This is my cousin from Morea.
He's been born mute. Mother takes him
from one saint to another.
Nothing can help him.
I beg you, help
little Phillip.
Say: Shce-pan.
Shcepan.
Shce...  -God Almighty!
-Shce...  -Shcepan!
Shce... pan...
Miracle! This is a miracle!
-Say...
Elfa!
Elfa.
El...fa...
My dear son...
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Here.
My son!
I have never seen
anything like this before.
He opened the child's mouth!
The Lord my God...
Is that him?
Is that tsar Peter the Third?
Might be.
Stranger, who are you?  -I heal sick
people, and it doesn't matter who I am.
Who are you?  -Me? Bishop and
the ruler of Montenegro.
You? Really?
Differently I imagined the bishop
and the ruler of this militant people.
I am disappointed.
People without a ruler is like a flock
without a male goat, without a shepherd
And you are indeed the
ruler of Montenegro?
I anathemize you, you scum!
Disappear, you filthy pagan!
Disappear!
Go away, the son of the devil!
Go away!
The Church always sees devil
where there isn't one!
He said it well.
-Go away!
Welcome.
-You are good, son, very good.
He said it well.  -Welcome.
-Miracle worker!
Sir! Sir, if you would deign to
accept my hospitality...
It would be a great
honour for me.
Especially after such a long trip,
right?
I owe you my respect.
Indeed, a person who...
you resemble... I am happy,
and I offer you my humble abode.
Where is your house?
-Over there.
Great are the works of God, my lord,
my tsar!
I am captain Marko Tanovic.
Don't you remember me?
My dear cap. Tanovic, obvioulsy I can
count on you as you can count on me.
That's enough, my lord.
Don't say anything else, my tsar. Your
presence here speaks for you.
I respect your incognito.
You've always helped Montenegro.
I want to say that I know
why you are here.
Let us go to my home.
This way.
You came at the right moment.  -That's
why I took this long trip.
Prepare a room for our
guest, quickly!
Good evening.
What's the matter?
Why are you calling me?
Everything's fine.
Captain Tanovic believed.
The mission has successfully started.
-Don't work only with capt. Tanovic.
Turn to the people. You must now act
and think like a real politician, clear?
Learn this speech. Immediately start to
perform. This is extremely urgent.
Forgive me.
I thought...
-You thought what?
Call me when you are in trouble. Be
independent. You act like a fool.
I came to you because I see
many conflicts.
I am neither afraid of
the smell of incense...
Two quinces are not ripe yet.
I am following a great wisdom...
Do not try to uncover this
great secret of my identity.
Fresh fish, people!
I don't use incense.
This herb is for the eyes.
I help when neither the Church
nor God can help.
I don't pour out empty words.
Come closer, woman, take this.
Take.
This herb heals the
stomach cramps.
This is for the headache
and the sicknesses of the mind.
And this herb is for girls with
thin blood, without passion!
This is for the gout
and for the toothache.
Come on, people, I give you health for
free. And don't look upwards, but at me
I can see far. I prophesy.
I am hope and salvation for...
You make fools of us! But we won't
allow to be outsmarted by that cheat!
Even if you say that he is tsar Peter
the Third himself! Some believe you.
You will believe too,
sooner than you think...
Markovic.
-I know everything,
but I don't know who bribed you
to cheat all these people.
What did you say?
Take back your words, Markovic!
-I won't take them back, Tanovic.
Come on, Markovic, old mate,
smash him! Smash him!
Smash him!
Come on!
Smash the pagan!
Captain Tanovic,
sheathe your sword!
What are you waiting for, friend?
Sheathe your sword!
Our blood should be shed only against
the Turks, and Turks are many!
Come to peace.
And respect each other.
You, deacon, should be punished for
making them shed their own blood!
Lucifer, go away! May the
soil swallow you!
May you burn in the
eternal fire of hell!
Disappear, the son of the devil,
disappear!  -Go away!
Don't be a fool, deacon!
-Thief!  -Curse on you!
I am afraid neither of the smell of
their incense nor of their anathemas.
But the churches are afraid
of people like me.
I have come to you because
I see many conflicts among you.
My eyes see many diseases
and poverty.
And the Church says
that God has made them.
I follow a great wisdom, and I know
that there's no justice except people's
Two quinces are not ripe yet,
but they will be soon.
Do not try to uncover this
great secret of my identity.
We know who you are! And we know
that you came because of us, our friend
Our dearest Majesty!
-Long live the tsar!
Long live the tsar!!!
Long live tsar Peter the Third!
Long live the tsar!
I came...
I was passing by...
No... No! No!!!
Your Majesty, for God's sake,
why are you forcing me?
God, help me...
-Where I come from...
man and woman, as soon as they meet,
they immediately start doing...
THE thing!
-No!
No! Your Majesty,
you cannot marry me.
You are a tsar!  -Tsar can
do whatever he pleases.
Can marry whomever he wants. Besides,
I am not married, I am free...
I am free like a wild goat. I swear
I will marry you.
You have my word.
You swear by what?
-I don't know, you tell me.
By love and by God.
-By love?
Oh, yes, yes,
by love... And by God.
By Almighty God.
Trust me, I shall marry you.
Your Majesty!
You came to visit us.
To visit me and my daughter.
What an honour!
People say that you are the tsar
of Russia.
They say you are noble,
that you can heal and console.
This people are lucky
to have you here.
Do sit, please.
Your Majesty, never before have we
encountered greater horrors. -The hell.
The hell is the paradise compared
to this hell on the earth.
With my own eyes I watched
my house in flame.
My wife and son were
thrown to the fire by Turks.
I asked God why he was
punishing me.
I asked myself if I ever
did an evil thing to anyone.
I didn't.
You tell me, good man...
will the end to this suffering
ever come?
They accepted us here
as we'd been their own.
And I thank them. But what if the power
of hell interferes here as well one day?
I don't care for myself.
I live for her.
For her happiness...
If it ever comes...
Forgive me, Your Majesty.
I know, it's difficult for all of us.
But I cannot
ease my pain...
Cheers.
-Cheers.
To you, tsar, sent to us
by the Almighty Himself.
To your health,
happiness and joy.
You asked, my lord,
what are the people most afraid of.
I swear, of everything. Of one
another, of great powers...
of Venice and Turkey,
and our land is dry. We must
bow and toil.
And we, instead of a hoe,
always carry only guns!
I must admit, captain, this wine
of yours is excellent!
The wine is from Crnica,
and the bread from the hills.
But it still doesn't suffice.
That's why it is so good.
You are low in number too,
a handful of people,
but it is also good. You really
should, from time to time...
be destroyed a little.
Don't say that, my lord.
-I was just making a joke.
Just to make your manhood and
bravery more firm, as you say...
and to be honest, I don't really
make a difference between these two.
You don't?
Kuchi, those people who came with gifts
to accept you as the tsar...
say this: bravery is when I defend
myself from other's evil doing.
And manhood is when I defend
others from the evil in myself.
You mean: from my own evil doing?
Well, my lord, yes...
Praise the Lord, the Duke Dolgorukov
have just came from St. Petersburg!
He brought the cossacks with him.
This will be the end of Shcepan!
The good-for-nothing is
finished! Finished!
Thank you, Almighty!
-Oh God!
Thank you.
I am sorry to interrupt your dinner,
but I must tell you a piece of news...
that will probably upset
you a little.  -Turks?
No, not Turks.
Russians...
Leaded by Duke Dolgorukov, the
tsarina's favorite himself!
Have a nice meal!
What should we do,
Your Majesty?
I'll have an audience with him.
Did you personally sent the pigeon?
Yes, duke. People believe that
this scum is tsar Peter the Third.
He came even to the monastery!
And the people is always the same...
They want an emperor,
even the false one.
People wants and believe.
Your highness, do something,
as you have a great power.
We want things to be as
they used to be.
I'm powerless 'cause this stupid people
accepted him as a tsar. - Thank you.
Follow me!
By God's grace,
we, Katarina the Second...
the highest and most powerful
empress of Russia...
by this empress's note we announce:
Survival of you Montenegrins
is up to you.
While the doors of our grace
and good will are opened...
we expect that you'll throw into
chains and expel...
usurper, so called tsar Peter
the Third known as Shcepan.
Otherwise, we will be forced to
deprive you of our protection and grace.
If you don't obey, you will be only to
blame for ruining of Montenegrin people.
The sword of Venice and Turkey is above
your heads. Our sword isn't. Yet.
This is the decree from St. Petersburg,
by order of Her emperor
highness, tsarina Katarina the Second.
Thank you, duke. Tsar
Shcepan will be glad to receive you.
Before that you'll have to order your
soldiers to withdraw to the end of the hall.
Don't ask for blood.
Soldiers, step back.
Step back!
My dear, you really think
that I believe you are Peter the Third?
Cowherd! Tramp! I'll stab
your stomach!
You tramp!
You're gonna set countries to war!
I'll burn you!
I'll do anything you want. Anything!
-Here is what you are going to do...
Instead of the tsarina, you'll
sign that you accept me as a tsar.
If you don't do that, you'll be dead.
Your bones will rotten here.  -I will!
Tell them that you are dear
guest of mine tonight.  -Very well.
And let them know that you
are leaving at dawn.
Soldiers! Tonight we drink for tsar
Shcepan. At dawn we are leaving!
Good evening!  -Welcome.
-Good evening.  -Do sit, please.
What is the matter, father?
I've heard the agreement Shcepan
had with the duke.
He will marry a Russian princess.
Higher interests of the country. As if!
We must run from here! Run! And
devil will take him from here... Once.
Bloody imposter!
No! No! No!
Father, I won't live anymore!
I know that you love him, but
the suicide is a great sin.
Don't, Elfa...
Father, help us.
-There is someone higher than the tsar.
And that is church. It would be honored
if she became its nun.
A nun!
Father, you let...
Please!
Let it be...
In the name of bey of Rumelia, Mahmut-pasha,
and in name of sultan, son of the Sun...
I'm telling you that if you don't give us Shcepan
that got you for senseless things 'till tomorrow,
we will burn every
corner of Montenegro!
And you, so called tsar that stir
the people up against mighty kingdoms,
you will be stuck on spit as a ram. If that
doesn't happen, expect our army at dawn!
This time there is no hope for you!
Don't expect help from no one!
Everyone has left you.
Russians and Venice.
There will be a lot of spits
in this wolves nest!
Listen to me! There is no one here
willing to give him to you!
We are waiting for you at down!
And tell to the bey of Rumelia...
...that Shcepan still enjoys the
full confidence of our chiefs.
Don't praise the day before the dawn,
or a sword before the end of the battle!
Or that so called tsar
of yours!
Allah is my witness that the message
is delivered as it was sent!
You really won't give me to them?
No, we won't.
Would you left us?
We are brothers...
Shcepan... Our tsar...
We aren't murderers.
Fen-olah-fen-olah...
Hello, Farfa!
Are you all right?
-Yes, I am. And you?
We mustn't waste a second!
Turks will come at down and then...
Then nothing! Turks will attack and
burn Montenegro.
But you have enough time to come
back down there.  -Where to?
To my home?
No...
Oh! You obviously
do not miss your wife.
If you want to send regards to anyone
before leaving, I'll wait in the road.
But I can't leave just like that.
Not these people that love me so much.
Listen, Farfa, we changed the plan and
made a political turn.
Our cause in Russia is now supported.
We don't need Peter the Third anymore.
I advise you to leave right away.
Politics, you know...
No!
I can't.
Turks are coming tomorrow.
-Don't think about Montenegro.
It won't be the first time for them
to be burned by Turks.
And the people?
They didn't want to give me to Turks.
They are different than I thought.
Farfa, don't get carried away by earthly
things. Be obedient and go down there.
This time, I can't follow the orders.
I am staying here.
Something happened in me.
Something... something...
Farfa, in confidence, if you don't do that
your powers will be taken away from you.
You'll become ordinary, mortal man.
You'll be punished as every outlaw!
No!
Olah... I want help.
I am asking for help!
Turks are coming!
They took away my powers.
I can do without them!
Captain Tanovic!
Sergeant! Captain!
# Traditional song #
Hail tsar!
Hail, my brothers!
You that chose me for your tsar!
Many times I've been told
to go the other path!
I didn't want that! I chose destiny of
an ordinary man and I'm happy for that!
I'm small, smallest among you because we
are great only if we are able to be small.
I have learn't that from the people.
And I'm covered with silk and jewels...
...and most of you don't have
even the basic things.
Take this, Tanovic!
Where does this come from?
Where from?
This is from your suffering
and it belongs to you!
Hail the tsar!
Announce my decree.
We, the people of Montenegro, through
our servant, tsar Shcepan The Little...
announce our free will.
Treasure of church and rich people is
going to be used for building schools...
...roads and everything that
people need.
Is that your will?
- YES, it is!
Come, come...
For killing of our brothers and
spreading discord among people...
we announce death penalty and
destroying of home. Is that your will?
And now, we are telling to everyone!
To mighty Ranier, duke of Venice,
to mighty Katarina,
to sultan Ahmet, son of the Sun and
brother of the Moon,
to wise Louis of France,
to honorable Joseph of Austria
...not to extend their bloody hands
to small, poor Montenegro...
...because I, Shcepan The Little...
am sending a message to forces of
heaven and forces of hell...
that I'll be good with good ones,
and evil with others.
Shcepan, our tsar, we are poor
and thirsty in these rocks.
We and our cattle, too.
You forgot about wells.
-Tanovic, write that down.
We'll make a well in every village
before the winter.
Thank you, our tsar,
and don't be mad at me.
Long live our tsar!
Your highness...
You have to sign orders about
vineyards and roads,
and a letter to the Republic
of Dubrovnik.
Elfa...
It's hard without her...
But Elfa is a nun.
Forget about her.
You are not an ordinary man.
You are a tsar.
Yes, Tanovic, a tsar, but also a man
who is in love.
An ordinary man.
Stop!
What is it?
What do you want?  -They are ready
to forgive you for your disobedience.
But you must come back.
At once.
They forgave me, you say?
They forgave me for what?
For thinking with my own head? For
not wanting to serve to your intentions?
Is that what you say?
You are an outlaw.
It looks like you started
to work somebody else.
Yes. I work, but
I don't work for you any more.
You created Gingis Khan, Nero, Atilla.
You are fed on slavery and hate.
I want to live freely. It's over!
I don't want to have anything with you!
You will regret for this, Farfa.
You will!
You'll pay for this, Farfa!
I don't want to see
you in Montenegro ever again, you spy!
Stop!
I know where are you going to,
and we decided to make you
happy by blessing your love to Elfa.
Who are you?  -Me?
I'm representing all churches.
If you don't want to go along with hell,
bring the people that loves you to us.
And you will be rewarded.
-No, I won't.
I wouldn't be free there either.
-Don't blow in the wind, Shcepan.
You fight with same strength
against hell and against church.
You want something third.
There isn't something like that. You have
to be with someone. Choose your side.
It's a deal and
here are the gold coins.
This is all yours.
-I'll rather stick to the gospel.
Let it be God's what is God's
and Ceasar's what is Ceasar's.
Farfa... Crazy Farfa!
We must brutally punish
that little outlaw!
We must prevent him to disturb
order of things on earth.
For that is the most dangerous and it
can be a bad example to other nations.
Let that be done by Justine.
She has personal reasons for that.
Send that whore Zephira with her.
Elfa!
Why did you run away
from our love?
I became a nun when I heard
about your wedding.
Who said that nonsense?
I'll punish him!
He'll pay for that with his own
head! He will be the first I hanged!
Don't say vengeful words
on a place like this!
We better accept our destiny.
-Now? Now I make my destiny!
Elfa, Elfa...
Farfa! Farfa!
Farfa!
Elfa, did you hear something?
-No.
Heeeey!
Justine!
Guard!  -Here I am!
-I drove two ladies from Venice.
They bring gifts and regards to
His Highness, tsar Shcepan.
Grand duke is sending them.
What the world means to
me now...
it is hard to understand, Elfa.
No-one asks me where I
came from, or of what origin I am.
I know that all powers are against me
except people's.
Because I'm saying what people say:
There can never be too much
of love and freedom.
Look at that scum, Zephira.
What are you doing here?
Who has sent you?  -Good evening.
Come here, deacon...  -I've heard that
you came from Venice...
and that you brought
gifts to that false tsar, that scum!
The church never accepted him!
-This time we have the same interest.
He brings unrest. That Shcepan bothers
everyone!  -Yes, madam. He is Satan.
Lucifer.  -If he were Lucifer
you would easily make a deal with him.
Tell the prior to bring me Palikarda.
The rest is up to me.
Prior, bring Palikarda.
Zephira will explain everything to you.
I'm so glad...
I'll tell you everything...
We must kill Shcepan,
we must kill Shcepan...
Madam, this is Stanko Palikarda.
The deacon is in there.
Bring him.
My intentions are good. My name
is Justine, I am a wife of Shcepan's.
Wife?  -Yes, he tricked
you and your daughter.
My daughter is in the monastery.
- Come. Come and see.
Take a look.
I'll kill him. I'll kill him...
- Kill him!
Kill him. Revenge yourself,
my friend.
We will share your
sin with you.
I won't sin!
I don't want a sin on my soul!
I don't want to sin against God.
I am servant of God, I won't sin!
I am not a killer!
I won't sin! I won't sin!
Only God may take away
one's life! Only God!
Father!
Shcepan, the tsar!
Farfa...
Subbed and translated by:
Crnnica and NinaNish
THE END