(RADIO) "The famous English fashion designer
Mary Quant,
that has popularized the mini-skirt
the miniskirt,
announces its arrival in Madrid
in order to present
its latest collection of models.
No doubt,
tries to help with his presence
to the promotion of this garment
that was so unfavorably received
has had among
Spanish women".
(Music)
Good morning, Nacha.
-Hello, Lupe, how are you?
-Great.
And you, did you rest well?
-Very well.
(Music continues)
Was there a party last night? What kind of party?
-We went to the Royal Bar.
My obligation is to be fashionable,
isn't it?
-Did you go with Keko?
-Please don't ask that question.
You know I'm a faithful girl.
(Music continues)
(Baby crying)
Wait.
Wait...
It's only for a moment.
(Music continues)
Is Mr. Mariano here?
Mother!
Sorry to call you so soon.
Are you awake yet?
What is it, son? What is it?
You don't let her sleep.
Listen, mother,
be attentive
because it is something very important.
God knows what you call important.
important.
It does not arrive tonight
as he had told us.
Arrives now, in a little while,
at 11 o'clock.
I have to go to the airport
to pick him up.
But, Eusebio, who is arriving?
Who will arrive? Your son.
But let's see, Eusebio,
my son is not you
and you're here giving me a hard time?
Yes, your son is me,
but the one arriving today from Buenos
Aires is my brother Jesus.
God save me and all his heavenly court!
and all his heavenly court!
Why the hell
haven't you told me anything?
If we are tired of
of telling you it was coming.
And now I have awakened you
because you have arrived...
There is no one who understands you, Eusebio.
I don't know how you manage
in the restaurant
to explain the menu to
the menu to the customers.
Well, get ready to receive him.
Look very pretty, huh?
It's me, Dad!
You are in no hurry today,
it's your day off.
But I have a favor to ask.
Would you mind not going
to the academy this morning?
This morning? I'm sorry,
but it's impossible for me.
Other times you have been absent.
Yes, but today there is a demonstration
at the university.
Let's all go.
Because of Vietnam?
Be careful, Mer.
We've made a mess of things,
we can not miss us.
It has been to many.
Because you miss one...
But what's wrong, dad?
Your uncle Jesus is coming now.
You have to go right away to look for your sister and her husband.
your sister and her husband.
Well, Dad...
Here is the Moor Mousa
freshly showered.
-Come on, have breakfast at once.
It's getting late.
-Before I have to give
the protocol kiss.
-Let me go, don't be a beast.
-And dress me in distinguished clothes.
(IMITATES ARABIC)
-Do you remember that you met
with Dicasa at 10:30?
-I don't forget, no.
Have you brushed
the elegant corduroy jacket?
-Yes... Hurry up,
it's getting cold.
-The odalisques have to do what the
what the sultan orders,
but the favorite can order
whatever is put in her mouth.
Thank you.
-Surprise, I am no longer a Moor.
I am a dancer.
An elegant dancer from the Roaring '30s.
(SINGS IN ENGLISH)
Let me, I do not find myself today
in the 1930s.
-Any ailments?
Have you stopped taking the pill?
-It's not that way, Anselmo.
What happens has nothing to do
has nothing to do with the pill.
I'm sure it's Mariano.
-And why is Mariano coming
Mariano come here now?
-We are to meet before 10 o'clock.
-What for?
-Anselmo, don't be a pain,
he'll tell you.
If you let me open it,
we tell him to come in.
Hello, Mariano.
-Hello.
-Come in, come in, Mariano.
-The girl is getting fatter every day.
-Yes, everyone says so.
What's up?
-It's freezing cold.
-Yeah, yeah, it looks like it.
-And these covers?
-The ones I'm going to take to Dicasa.
-They are great.
-Chus told me that she was
here with you because...
-Yes, yes, before 10 o'clock.
I have -5.
-The one in the kitchen is -8.
-And you won't mind
if I come too?
-Why should it bother them?
There is trust, isn't there?
-I'm telling you this because of Chus.
Women, you know how we are.
-Well, it's been more than three months....
-Four, almost four.
-Yes, I think so, it was autumn.
-Or late summer?
-Yes, it may have been late summer.
Of course,
it wasn't weather like this.
-Ah, it's you.
-Yes, I agreed to come at this time.
-I've stuck as a chaperone.
-Man, Mariano, what's up?
Do you live here?
-Chus had an appointment here, just as I had an appointment with you.
as I had made an appointment with you.
He will accompany me to Dicasa
to introduce me to the executive.
A chinchón?
-Okay.
-Well, just now,
when you have arrived,
we were about to talk about
private things.
-Well, private...
Well, yes,
they can be considered private,
but I think they can also
you can listen to them
Pepe Landete and Trini Cantalapiedra.
We are all from the same group
and share the same...
(TOSE)
Mariano, watch out, Mariano...
(Music)
Mer! Mer!
Please listen to me,
it's just for a moment.
What are you doing here?
leave me alone for a minute?
Please, I beg you,
I have to tell you something.
So early in the morning?
And in the middle of the street?
We are not going to talk dancing all the time.
Don't be lead.
Can't you see
that I'm in such a hurry?
If you're in a hurry now, when?
Leave me now, I say!
If you really need to talk to me,
call me back.
It's just that I'd rather we talk
before the demonstration,
in case something happens to us.
Man, don't overdo it, Basilio,
that you are not going to war.
It is a peaceful demonstration.
But the grays
are getting more beastly every day.
Well, let's see... What do you want?
Falling worse and worse?
Didn't I tell you to call me back?
I can do no more.
Mother, are you dressed yet?
Is there no way to sleep
in this house?
What do you want now, son?
Come in at once.
But mother,
why didn't you get dressed up?
Don't you remember? Jesus is coming.
You are very small
and do not understand things.
If you had
the experience of the years...
What do I have to understand, mother?
Listen.
It's been a long time
since your brother left.
But now he wants to come back.
And they let him.
But against time
no one can do anything.
Absolutely nothing.
Neither the smartest nor the holiest.
Time knows.
It stretches, it stretches.
It stretches like a rubber band,
but there comes a time,
that from so much stretching and stretching,
it breaks and then
you can no longer walk.
You fall off a cliff.
Well, you get ready
as soon as possible just in case.
Is that you, Eusebio?
What do you want, love?
Has something happened?
No, but dinner at home tonight
at home tonight is no longer valid.
My brother arrives now
and naturally,
it makes sense
is to meet for lunch.
I suppose that at that hour
you won't be able to come.
Impossible. I have a lunch date
with the Frenchman
who brings the models from Biarritz.
And the Marquise.
And I have no way of notifying them,
because I don't know which hotel they've come to.
Veronica, tell Nacha
to take out of the window
Metz foulards,
those sell themselves.
If it weren't for that,
I would go with you.
Urgent news, sister.
Hello, good morning.
(ALL GREETINGS)
What is happening?
Uncle Jesus is arriving now.
I no fancy dinner, but food.
This is the list of
of what you have to do
and this one,
the one about what I have to do.
Dad's orders.
Good thing I had asked permission
at the hotel not to go this morning.
-And what were you going to tell me?
Yes-what about the demonstration?
At least you're going.
-You're right, it's Monday.
The demonstration against the U.S..
-We do plan to go.
-Yes.
-I don't know now.
If Dicasa entertains me...
Well, what about the other thing?
What you had to tell me?
You see we are all in a hurry.
Can't you tell me anything
at long last?
-Can you play a record, please?
-Are you going to say it in song?
-No, man, it's the custom
that there is always music, isn't it?
(Music)
Well, Chus and I
have loved each other for some time
and it is normal for us to tell you
because among friends
you can't do a piggyback.
-You don't make me a pig,
but you give me a hard time,
because I still love Chus.
I think I've got it right, don't you?
-No one is to blame,
neither Mariano nor I are to blame,
You don't have it either.
-There is no such thing as guilt.
-Everything is the fruit of chance,
of chance and necessity.
-I agree.
-I think my behavior is good,
you can't deny it.
-Great, Anselmo.
-You may say that Anselmo Gato is a bad artist.
is a bad draftsman.
-No, not at all.
-But they will not be able to say
that he does not understand, that he does not assume.
Life is an open door,
many open doors.
Anselmo Gato's life is not a series of closing doors.
a series of doors that close,
is a series of doors
that open, open, open,
even if they open themselves to sorrow,
to failure, to contempt,
but they open, they open, they open.
And through them pass Anselmo Gato
with his drawing folders,
with their pencils, with their agenda
of girls' and editors' telephone numbers.
-But how handsome you are, Anselmo.
And how well made your head is.
-But there's one thing I don't understand.
Why did this motherfucker
insist that we get married?
Why?
-What does it matter now, Anselmo?
It's over.
-Overcome...
Cubism has been surpassed!
But what is going to be surpassed?
I think Chus is right about that.
Me too, of course.
-But do you realize
what I look like now
with my family,
with the neighbors, in the neighborhood?
If we hadn't married,
I'd be a tramp
that I had fucked the daughter of a "maître
of a "maître" and that was that.
But what am I now?
-You are a young man
with an impressive talent.
One of the best cartoonists
in the country.
-Yeah, that's for you, but for
for my parents' neighbors...
-You're getting out of control,
Anselmo, calm down.
That's right, take it easy,
it's no big deal.
If I am calm,
if I have assumed everything.
The only thing I want to know
is why is this motherfucker
was determined that we should get married.
-You are deliberately offending me.
-Well, but it's always the same.
-At meetings, I always see someone who deliberately
someone who deliberately offends.
-You offend me by using words
that we do not use.
As if you wanted to tell me
that I am not who I think I am,
that I'm nothing more than a whore
of the old ones.
-I didn't say that!
-You said it about his mother,
which is meaningless.
-What you have to ask yourself
is not why I insisted on getting married,
but why do I insist
now to leave you.
-But why are you getting so upset?
Everything was fine.
-I think for my part, yes.
-You've fit it.
-Mariano is intelligent,
he has literary culture,
is also a man of action
and on top of that he sings and plays the guitar.
How can I be surprised that a girl
that a girl wants to go with him?
And why shouldn't that girl
won't be mine?
But, Chus didn't want to tell me now
why she was going with Mariano,
but why he was leaving me.
-Because you're not funny, Anselmo.
(TITUBEA) -That I don't have...?
-Don't be cruel, Chus.
-Every day...
(IMITATES ARABIC)
With the towel and then,
the dance, Fred and Ginger.
So clumsy... Always the same.
-But in the beginning,
when we first met...
(SINGS IN ENGLISH)
-I didn't expect you to...
-You've gone too far, Chus.
Open doors, Anselmo.
You said it very well,
always open doors.
-Yes, the ones I go through
with my drawing folders,
my pencils...
-Anselmo, what are you saying?
-That's it!
That I will pass through all the doors
with my daughter!
Or do you want me
to give it to Mariano?
I do not believe in the law,
none of us believe in the law,
but now the law suits me
suits me because it supports me.
Or what do you want?
To be left alone altogether?
Without a child, without you, without a home...
Because the house is yours, of course.
-That doesn't matter now,
but yes, it is mine.
-Well, not the girl!
-Anselmo, the children are from the....
-The children are from the bottle!
And cows!
And Dr. Pasteur!
-What are you talking about?
He's gone crazy.
-What do you want?
Do you want me to stay alone forever?
Alone and with nothing?
No home, no memories...
-But this is my desk!
the place where I work!
And these, my drawings, my covers!
Work! These, these are!
-Stay still, Anselmo, please.
- "The Process", "City",
"Counterpoint",
"Heart," "Goodbye, doll."
-Calm down, Anselmo, calm down!
-Chus, you could have been
forever...
-Let me go, Anselmo!
-My wife!
And you won't be anymore! Huh? Not anymore!
-Anselmo!
-What are you doing?
-Watch out!
-He's going to jump!
-Anselmo, don't be crazy!
-No, Anselmo, no!
-Mariano, it helps a little, doesn't it?
It's just that I have to go
to the demonstration, it's time.
(Baby crying)
I want to kill myself!
I want to die! Die...
As I told you in the last letters,
I'm not doing too bad.
And neither did my daughters. The eldest...
Chus?
Yes, she has been made head of
of public relations at the hotel.
Your marriage is going very well.
It's hard enough.
Well, look at it, a thing like that,
sudden, precipitated,
pregnancy, and now it turns out
that everything is going smoothly.
They get along well, they understand each other,
they have the same ideas...
Plus, there's the little girl,
which has brought them very close together.
This highway was inaugurated in 1954.
I'm sure you didn't remember.
No.
But I do.
29 years in America, without returning.
But this one and this one
have not left Madrid.
Hey, what do you think they think here
of what we do abroad?
What about the work of the exiles?
What work?
The government of the Republic in exile
of the Republic in exile.
Because when Franco dies,
and it looks like he's not far off,
something will have to be done
and there we have a government.
Yes, of course.
And what we are most interested in knowing
is what young people think here.
Please think carefully about your answer.
What do young people think here
of the government
of the Republic in exile?
Young people?
Yes, the young people.
Nothing.
I would have liked so much to bring
my wife and my son...
But the kid, with college....
And well, since I can't
introduce you to my family,
at least I will meet yours.
They will all be at home
to welcome you.
The eldest, her husband,
the granddaughter, the little one,
and, of course, the mother.
She hasn't left the house for years.
Yes, I know.
They will all be there.
All of them. Except Marcela.
Yes, except Marcela.
Ma'am, may I make up your room?
Do what you want, but do something.
Who's there?
It's me, Grandma! It's Mer!
How is the soup coming along?
Well, you think I don't know how to skim a stew?
a stew?
And where is your father?
He had to go to the airport.
Well, the other days he leaves later.
Don't start the fuss now, Grandma.
The other days he has nothing to do until
to do until it's time for work.
Until 12 o'clock.
What do you have to do today?
Receive the guy, but he already knows.
What nonsense!
But your uncle drowned!
He drowned in the sea.
It's been so many years since he left.
Why haven't you put on
a dress?
This is what you look like.
This is a dress.
What's your father wearing?
I didn't notice.
It seems to me the same as always.
My son Jesus always dressed
with pants, jacket and tie.
We were poor.
Much poorer than now.
I've heard you tell it.
But Jesus, in spite of that
and his ideas,
which, it must be said, he always wore a tie,
always wore a tie.
Like his father, may he be glorified.
Now these things
are of no importance.
Everyone goes as he/she pleases.
Hey, we would be
whatever we were,
but we were not espadrille people.
Do you know if your father
wore a bow tie today?
He wears it only to work.
He must be very distinguished
with the bow tie, but since
you don't want to take me to see it...
The restaurant where he works is
far away, we have already told you.
Well, he could wear it at home
and serve the table one day
so that I could see him.
And if there were still miracles
and one day my son Jesus would come back...
We should have a dinner party here
in style, don't you think?
And my other son, your father,
would serve her.
Grandma, listen.
Uncle Jesus is coming back today.
What bullshit are you talking about?
Please don't start.
But do you think I'm going to believe
your lies?
Go fuck yourself!
Grandma, I have to ask you something.
Let's see.
Dad wants you to come back
to see your son Jesus
after so many years
don't swear at him.
But how can I swear at him
if he's my son?
Who the fuck is going to come now
to give us a hard time?
Hello.
What, has the traveler arrived yet?
No, not yet.
I come not only for a moment
to meet him and give him a hug.
I do not recognize anything.
When we were kids
we used to come to Barajas
to visit Aunt Encarna.
He would give us slices of bread with honey.
Yes.
The old road runs
on the other side, all this is new.
And why did I come back
if everything is different?
To take a few years off
off, don't you think?
You are right.
I've been here less than an hour
and I already feel younger.
Before heading home
we will stop by the boutique
to meet Lupe.
Just passing by.
I think that the color of your eyes
the one that suits you best is this one, green.
Oh, excuse me, Lali, beautiful.
It's just a moment,
but I warn you that it is
the one that will suit you best
and what we have received from Biarritz,
all in shades of green.
Nacha, monkey, stop that,
you'll make out with anything.
Teaches the lady from Callejanos,
who arrived yesterday from London.
-They're downstairs, do you want to come?
-Yes, let's go.
-Joyful surprise.
Very happy and very surprise.
I thought you were coming here,
but in the afternoon.
We've only been here for a moment
because I wanted to introduce you to...
Just arrived from Argentina, right?
Yes, just arrived.
My brother Jesus,
Lupe, my partner.
Hello, Jesus.
Hello.
Keko, this is Eusebio's brother.
After 1000 years
across the sea
has dared to come and see
how his countrymen are now.
Jesús Muñiz, insurance agent,
businessman,
Spanish, resident in Argentina.
Keko, Marquis of Pradobajo,
and first of all, a good friend.
Tomorrow you will come by here, Jesus,
and we'll talk about your wife,
okay?
Did he show you
those who arrived yesterday?
There are some that are a love.
What was your impression?
Very good impression.
You can see her awake, active...
Hey, what about that spot on the guitar?
What is the marquis doing there?
Ah, it's one of Nacha's flirts,
that employee, she sits and plays.
But Lupe is too young for you,
isn't she? There is a big difference.
Oh, yeah? I hadn't noticed.
(LAUGHS) You're a pion. Always the same.
I put it here
so that you can see it as soon as you enter.
It is what he liked the most,
quince jelly.
Do you also think
your mother is an imbecile?
No, she is an ordinary woman.
My Eusebio thinks
that I don't know anything.
If you want an aniseed, help yourself.
Well, thank you.
Today my son arrives, you know? The eldest.
Now he's just coming to take a look around,
but as soon as he dies
who I know
will return to stay in Spain.
The broth is very good,
but it lacks a little salt, Grandma.
Miracle would be.
Look, this is my Jesus.
Yeah, I've seen it before.
Now it will be older, because
the photo is many years old.
He had to flee
because he lost a war.
He went into the sea...
Chus says to put
these two bottles of y
on the sideboard.
Shut the fuck up!
He went into the sea on one side
And wham, it came out the other!
Where he could no longer be caught.
(SIGHS)
I should comb my hair
a little for when he comes,
But I don't know what to leave you alone.
It's not polite.
Oh, don't do it for me,
besides, I can go to the kitchen
to help her granddaughters and Trini.
Very nice girl that Trini, isn't she?
But what a belly she has,
Is it your husband's?
Yes, of course.
We are now reaching out
to our neighborhoods.
You recognize them, don't you?
This is the traffic circle.
But they removed the statue.
Yes, a few years ago.
She was taken
to the gardens of the Canal.
Where were we going to play?
There.
Do you remember? He was a man in a frock coat
and if you looked at him from the side,
it looked as if he had his gag out.
Of course I remember.
We kids would come to see it.
It was a finger, but it looked like the ginga.
-Yes, he is much better, calmer.
Yes, in one hour we give
the child to the second bottle.
That if you are going to receive your uncle.
-That man is no longer my uncle!
-I hear you, I hear you.
Sorry, Pepe,
but they have just arrived.
Well, here we have...
Let me.
Please let me.
You are Mer, the youngest.
And you are Chus, the eldest.
No, uh...
But I didn't know you were waiting.
And you didn't tell me anything!
No, listen, Jesus.
And you are Anselmo,
Chus' husband
and the father of the child
and come on, of everything that comes.
Listen, Jesus, you're wrong.
This is not my little daughter.
What is she, the maid? You have a maid?
No, we have an assistant,
but it's not this one.
Why do you insist on guessing?
I don't know, it just came out that way,
but I ask for forgiveness, I remain silent.
Look, this is Chus.
Chus, dear niece, forgive me.
It's just that I'm so excited...
Thanks for confusing me with Chus,
I've been with him for a few years.
And Anselmo?
He couldn't come, I'll explain later.
And Mom? I can't wait to see her.
You must be very careful
at this first meeting,
that it does not affect you too much.
Better make it a short interview
and let's all chat.
Trini is a psychiatrist,
she understands these things.
Not a psychiatrist, a psychoanalyst.
-My name is Mariano Andrade,
and here I am just a friend.
I have come to speak to you
not only for me,
but on behalf of a great many
who think like me.
Although we were born many years after the war
after the war,
we are with all
those who were like you,
we understand them
and thank them for what they did.
Even if it later turned out
what it turned out to be.
Thank you, my boy. Thank you very much.
Mother, your son Jesus has arrived.
But you get nervous, huh?
The doctor wants you
you to always be very calm.
Why should I get nervous
if I already knew it was coming today?
Mother, your son Jesus. My brother.
Mom...
Good morning, how are you?
Grandma...
Grandma, it's your son Jesus.
The one who left during the war.
Yeah, you already told me that.
And you greet him like this,
as if he were a stranger?
It seems to me that I have received you
with very good manners.
But you don't have to go overboard.
Aren't you going to at least
give him a hug?
Of course, of course, of course.
How many years I've been
I've been wanting to give it to him!
My son, my son, my son! My Jesus!
Forgive this poor old woman,
forgive me.
Blame it on the damn years,
I don't know what I do to myself.
My head, you know?
It doesn't work well, they must have told you.
That's why I couldn't write to you.
Mom, Mom...
(CRIES) My son, my son of my soul....
Oh, Jesusín!
Sit her down, she'd better sit down.
I couldn't come earlier, Mom.
I know, I know that they were after you
as if you were a criminal.
My Jesusín, a criminal...
But you lifted the skin of the sea
and covered yourself with it
so that the lights wouldn't hit you
and the dogs wouldn't smell you
with those who pursued you.
(CRIES)
Give water.
(Clock)
Hey, Eusebio, it's too much for her.
Jesus should go away for a while.
You'll want to get some rest,
open your bags.
Yes, yes, I have brought
some things I want to show you.
Ven.
It's this way, Uncle Jesus,
the first door.
Wait, I'll bring the suitcase.
Here, Grandma, drink some water.
Thank you, Mer, you're in everything.
The decoration will surprise you a little.
It is Mer's room.
He is very cheerful, very friendly.
But this man
what the hell is my son going to be?
Mom, what do you say?
Do you want to make me take communion
with a millstone?
But...
I have made the pamema
not to disappoint the poor gentleman.
Who is this guy, Eusebio?
Where did you get him from?
He's a comedian,
he sure is a comedian.
How can he be a comedian, mother?
How much did you give him for coming here
to be a jerk?
No, Mother, he's not a comedian. He's a...
You must have met him at the restaurant,
as if he saw it,
and you will have paid him with dinner,
because those bastards
always go to the fourth question.
But you haven't even looked
the box of quince jelly.
And where would my Jesusín's gaze have gone
my Jesusín's gaze?
To the quince jelly, then.
Come here, Mer. Come here.
That you deceive me less
than the others.
What do you want?
Have you seen that you have brought
a sucker home
to make me believe that my Jesus...
No, Grandma, it's him.
Do you also want to entangle me?
This was your friend Trini's doing,
the doctor of the crazies.
Of course, with this fantasy,
he thinks he's going to cure me
of I don't know what.
No, Mrs. Eusebia, it's not that.
But we already told you that.
Look, be careful,
I've had it up to here!
And I don't say up to my balls
so you don't say I'm foul-mouthed!
It's grandma, you know...
She gives it to her from time to time.
It has been many years
and he has suffered so much...
And that little snitch, who has
a faggot face from here to Lima...
Shut up, mother,
I beg you, please!
You tell him that if he dares
to stick his nose in my face again...
He's right next door, he's going to hear you.
That's what I want, for him to hear me!
Hey, how the old woman screams.
Yes, when she gets hit, she screams a lot.
If he sticks his nose in me again, I'll slap him!
I'll slap him!
Don't be bad, grandma, behave yourself.
Don't take me to see him, eh!
I'm telling you I don't want to see
that dumb ass!
That crazy faggot! That clown!
No, I don't want to see him anymore!
Lie down, grandma, lie down and rest.
Don't bring him here, don't bring him here!
(Phone)
Basilio has been arrested.
-No!
-Yes, his mother just called me.
-Why was that?
-Yesterday, at the demonstration.
We will have to call Anselmo,
to talk to his father.
He can give a touch to his friends,
like the other time.
-I am not going to call him,
for he is often with me.
One of you call him.
-I'll call him.
-Have you been beaten?
-I don't know anything.
And neither does his mother, you understand.
(WHISPERING) -But how can you think of calling this house
to call this house for such a thing?
You know how my father is
and now he won't even talk to me.
Well, the best thing you can do
is to call Eusebio.
If you call him as soon as possible,
you might catch him at home.
(Phone)
Chufla, chufla, chufla...
(RADIO) "The national birth
national birth prizes have been awarded.
The first went to a station
to a station attendant
with 1700 Pts. salary,
father of 19 children,
of whom 14 live
and 12 dwell in the father's house".
I told you, they got along very well.
And suddenly, you see,
with the other one, with Mariano.
It's a good thing they're both
are good guys.
You were lucky.
This air, this air of Madrid...
Well, it's not very
weather today.
And that? Doesn't it tell you anything?
Don't you know him?
Chis... Wait.
(Sad music)
The gardens!
They are the gardens
of the Canal de Isabel II!
Of course! Of course it's the gardens
Can't you see, man?
I remembered them differently.
How different!
Hey, there's nothing but old people.
What is memory, eh?
How things change,
who gave birth to it.
Well, the truth is that also
the gardens have changed.
Do you remember, Eusebio?
The rich kids
had a little card
and accompanied by a family member
or by the maid
They would come in through the front door.
And us, the street kids,
we would sneak in from behind.
We would jump the fence,
we would get into the pipes
and a lame guard insulted us.
Romanones!
That's right, Romanones!
He threatened us with his cane,
threw stones at us!
And we him!
(THEY LAUGH)
And sometimes
sometimes we were accompanied by a girl.
Yes, some.
Marcela.
Yes, Marcela.
I was twelve years old
and was already attracting attention.
Well, and there you have
what you wanted to see.
The statue?
Yes, the statue in the gazebo,
that brought her here.
(Music continues)
From that side it was.
You can't even see his guts.
It is necessary to get more here.
But, Eusebio,
you can't see anything from here!
They covered it with the tree.
Yes, it is true.
They must have done it on purpose.
They covered it with the tree.
They change everything!
(Phone)
(Radio)
Mr. Eusebio Muñiz has not yet come
yet, but he should be coming soon.
-He hasn't arrived yet.
Well, I can't stand it here anymore
without doing anything, seeing that Basilio
is in the dungeon.
Where are you going?
That way, to look for friends.
I'm going to go to the tavern,
see if I can find Lucas.
This was not there, did you see?
Over there the places are gray,
unpalatable, you know what I mean?
Yes, I get the idea.
Then it gets really busy.
The food is not bad
and the prices are affordable
affordable for all budgets.
Do you have specialties?
Yes, every day,
hen in pepitoria
and stewed tortilla
and on Thursdays, stew.
Stew!
Do you remember, Eusebio,
the old lady's stew?
How can I remember?
We ate it every day.
(Conversations)
(RADIO) "Several dozen
of students succeeded,
however, to penetrate the...".
As soon as we unpack
and set up the tables for dinner,
I have to go to do some business.
Don't worry about me,
I'm going for a walk.
No, no, if you can come with me.
My daughter's boyfriend has been arrested.
You don't say!
Mariano, the married woman's boyfriend?
No, man, the little girl's boyfriend.
You didn't tell me she had a boyfriend.
Well, boyfriend or whatever.
Hey, but is the management here?
Yes, it is.
I thought it was something
of policemen, lawyers...
Yes, that's right, but it's here.
Veronica, go put
this on that hanger.
We agreed to meet later.
Jesus, the thing with your wife.
Yes, but...
I have made a list of
of potential clients
and Nacha is in charge
to talk to several agencies
if you want local
with street door.
Thank you, Lupe.
Yes, but we
we didn't come to talk to you
about any of that.
Is anybody there?
No one.
Basilio was arrested
at yesterday's demonstration.
What sons of bitches.
-Again? Don't tell me...
Yes, I wanted to ask you...
Veronica, call Leticia.
It is a pity that Yolanda
is in Marbella.
But Leticia will find
Vicky or La Negra.
Of course also Yolanda
from Marbella...
Maybe Nicolás is there.
-Leticia on the phone.
-What's up, Leticia? How's it going with you?
He's a pimp, I warned you.
Well, Leticia, cut the crap.
You have to look for
Vicky or La Negra.
No, I don't need coke.
The one you find, you tell her
to call the sheriff as soon as possible.
Yes, that's right. Have them call me.
Warn them that it is
that Alfonso
owes the magistrate a touch.
It's nothing to do with drugs, dammit!
You, Eusebio, to look for Cuqui,
at this hour, at her house,
or if not, at the Moroco, rehearsing.
Have him call me as soon as possible.
Well, after walking back and forth
back and forth,
now, sit for a while
and wait for news.
For me, these walks
are very good for me.
This is how I get to know
the Madrid of today.
I have little time left, at 8 o'clock I have to be at the restaurant.
I have to be at the restaurant.
I believe that a matter like this
can be resolved in three hours.
There, with Onganía...
Here with Lupe you never know
what can happen.
A cognac?
Good.
It's a jewel, man.
Who is it?
Your mine.
Ah, she's not stupid. And she's related.
I've seen it, I've seen it.
Because of his work, you understand?
And I take charge, you meet people,
suppliers, friendships are made.
He also knows many models.
He organizes fashion shows
in Barcelona, in San Sebastian...
Meet the best women
in Spain.
(LAUGHTER) The flag ones,
as we were saying before.
I imagine.
Some are not models,
are girls who want to earn money
any way they can because they need it.
And Lupe helps them. She also rubs elbows
with the aristocracy,
with executives,
political leaders of the situation,
businessmen
who do not want to travel alone,
about stress
and relaxation, you know?
Yes, yes, I think I understand
what you are saying.
And it puts them in contact
with each other.
Some with others, I mean.
Right, right.
But then, according to
to what you say,
your friend Lupe...
No, my partner.
Sorry, yes,
your partner Lupe, she is a mediator.
How?
It's...
She is a procurer.
Ah, yes, yes! That's it.
And you say so?
You will get to know her.
Don't worry about me, Eusebio.
Not if I don't worry.
Neither for my wife nor for my son.
I educated them in freedom,
in understanding,
and when they come here,
they are going to treat it.
Yes, it can be very useful.
I'm not scared of anything.
Man, I guess.
After the war and exile
and Franco and Perón and Onganía,
these things...
Yes...
(Radio)
If I were to tell you, Eusebio,
how my early days were
in Buenos Aires, when, despite the opposition of the
the opposition of the Argentine government,
we arrived a lot of exiles
of exiles all at once...
They are rehearsing.
It was necessary to defend oneself
in any way.
It was necessary to subsist.
I was a cafisio, that's why I tell you
that for me these things...
Let's see, let's see,
I don't know if I understood you correctly.
What did you say you were? Cafisio?
Cafisio.
You've never heard that word
in the tangos?
It's that I don't like tangos...
Me neither.
Always the same nonsense
with the zeros, the tears...
But what you did when you arrived
to Buenos Aires, the cafisio thing,
What does that mean?
Pimp.
Pimp of whores.
What are you talking about!
That you were a pimp?
But only for a season.
But you were
the shyest guy in the neighborhood.
If women,
especially the pretty ones,
you were more afraid of them
than the fascists.
Yes, life rules, man.
Hunger takes away the fear
even the most chicken.
And then I didn't have a bad plant,
I walked with the tire on the ground.
(LAUGHTER) Jesusín, cafisio
in Buenos Aires.
In La Boca they called me
"el galleguito" (the little Galician).
(LAUGHS) Unbelievable!
Even if it had been me...
Oh! You were so much more daring.
But there was Marcela.
Yes, it changed me a lot.
If it hadn't been for her, maybe
I would have gone into exile like you.
And then, you see.
And why did you split up?
If you don't mind talking about it.
No, no, I don't care.
Well, because of the usual,
we didn't understand each other.
They always say the same thing,
don't give me that.
There are couples who have spent years
without understanding each other,
and they don't even need to.
Well, then she
took to drinking.
When she got drunk
anyone could do with it
whatever he wanted.
I wasn't a saint either.
Eusebio!
The old woman is calling.
Eusebio, for fuck's sake! Do you want to come?
Hey, how it gets.
Yes, when it hits her, she gets angry.
What do you want, mother?
Come closer, son, come closer.
Who the hell is with you that has been
there for half an hour of chitchat?
Is he the clown?
No, it's one of the waiters.
Paco, the eldest.
Do you swear to me?
I swear.
One should not swear in vain,
but to say "yes" or "no".
as Christ teaches us.
Mother...
Did I hurt you?
No, you haven't hurt me.
Why don't you fire him?
I'm sure he's a freeloader.
No, he is not a freeloader, nor a clown.
He is my brother,
your son Jesus, Jesusín.
I'll give you another slap.
Well, I'm going with him, Mother.
I don't like to leave him alone.
Go wherever you want.
You men always do
what comes out of your fly.
What did the old lady want?
Nothing, nothing, it's her time.
In the late afternoon
it almost always starts to rave.
Poor thing...
Oh, Jesusín...
When you were a pimp
in Buenos Aires,
do you know what I lived on?
No, you didn't tell me.
You wrote to me: "I'm doing well,
I'm not doing badly, I'm defending myself"...
Yes, of course, because of censorship.
They opened the letters.
Well, he lived on the black market.
Were you a smuggler, Eusebio?
With the Barajas family.
I did a lot of egg selling,
bread, milk, whatever there was.
Then I got in touch with
with more important people
and I switched to tobacco smuggling.
That's how I defended myself
for two or three years
until I became a waiter.
And then, to take that small
part in the restaurant business,
Do you know who helped me?
No, you didn't write it to me.
Opus Dei.
Opus Dei?
Yes, I've been in the business, little one,
and the head chef,
another, also small,
but we have an equity partner
and that equity partner,
a guy with a lot of money,
he's Opus Dei.
You with Opus Dei?
What are you telling me?
I can't believe it!
Hey, Jesusín!
You were a cafisio in La Boca!
No shit...
It's not the same thing!
It's not the same, man!
You're not going to compare!
(Doorbell)
This is Lupe, for sure.
Great news.
All better than we thought.
Sorry, Jesus,
I've neglected you a little.
Hello.
But because of the child in detention,
I haven't taken care of most of yours.
Here.
This is a list of the premises
that are for sale or for lease.
Red stripe, transfers;
blue, sales.
For starters, better transfers.
I hope you...
Oh, yes.
This is one of the possible clients
I can introduce to your wife.
Rosa. Here you have
some addresses and telephone numbers.
Paris, Biarritz, Milan, London,
very useful.
Amarilla, here are the procedures
to open the premises.
There has been a lot of luck, Eusebio,
Basilio may already be on the street.
Tell me about it tomorrow,
now I have to prepare
Grandma's dinner.
Isn't Mer coming?
He called me to decide that I couldn't,
because I was walking from one place to another
with Basilio.
I am amazed,
what a woman Icasia is, huh?
Active.
And why doesn't she live here with you?
Because of the child.
I don't think it's right, do you understand?
We see each other every day,
but in his apartment.
Does Lupe have a girl?
No, by Mer.
And also for our mother.
But what are you telling me?
Yes, Mer is a very evolved girl
and the old one is always on cloud nine.
Have you taken a look at
at the transfers?
Does any of them suit you?
Very much so.
The only thing I can tell you
is that the prices
are higher
than I thought.
In addition, how is the weight
with the change.
That's right, 350 with the dollar
and 480 with the peseta.
Take your time.
If you need money,
you can ask for a loan.
It's just that I could be inconvenienced,
being a newcomer.
Instead of a bank,
you can ask a private individual.
And you know?
If you leave me a few days
to do the math,
I may be able to lend it to you
lend it to you depending on the amount
and at a lower interest rate
than any loan shark.
As long as you have something under warranty
to respond.
Among friends,
clarity comes first.
Are you a lender?
He helps people.
I knew about the change in the peso.
It is that it plays something in the stock market.
(Doorbell)
Leave it, Eusebio, I'll get it.
Here is the outlaw.
-Thank you, Lupe.
I guess it was you.
-It has been friendships
and chance, as always.
First of all, I wanted to come
to thank you.
It doesn't matter,
as long as you can.
Come in and sit down.
This is my brother, there is trust.
Hello.
The exile? The anarchist?
That was a long time ago.
I was looking forward to meeting him.
A cognac?
Thank you, Eusebio, I don't drink alcohol.
Coca Cola, if possible.
-I'll get it for you.
So I take a peek
at the soup.
There, in Argentina, there is also
a great university agitation.
And all over the world.
I am not a university student.
It doesn't matter, you are young
and it's the young
those who are making
the great world revolution.
No one can stop this.
What we couldn't do,
they are doing it now.
You should have gone earlier
to see your parents.
I'll be right there, but first
I wanted to thank you.
Mer is not here?
No, she is not here.
Me too, as soon as
I'm leaving as soon as I give Grandma her dinner.
I have to stop by Chicote.
Tomorrow comes the party
and they need marijuana.
A real marvel, Mabel.
I feel so sorry for you
that you and the boy didn't come.
Of course,
the streets have changed.
The houses in which we
we used to live in,
the one that I told you was
like a huge tenement
and who called them
The houses of Carlos March,
because all of us who lived there
in it were socialists
or communists or anarchists.
They still exist,
but how businesses have changed,
other.
Eusebio's house,
although it is in the same neighborhood,
was built in the postwar period.
No, not only the street is changed,
the whole city.
Except for the downtown neighborhoods.
But the people, Mabel,
are still the same.
The best you can meet,
I assure you.
Have you been to the Romesa agency?
Yes, they took care of me
wonderfully well.
That friend of yours is charming.
This location was provided to me by him.
As soon as I showed him your little card,
he went out of his way to serve me.
Now, for the good places,
they ask you for a lot of money.
In addition, here in Spain
the taste for dressing was lost.
The fashion for women to dress in dirty rags
with dirty rags, with scraps of cloth,
with old dresses.
Did you see, hey?
Hi, daddy.
Hello.
And Uncle Jesus?
He is not here, he has gone to see
to Vallecas,
I was very interested.
I slipped away.
So, no one is there?
No, of course, just grandma.
Better.
Dad.
I have to ask you a question.
Ah, so ask me.
Do you remember Pita?
Pita? So, for the moment, I don't fall for it.
Who is it?
Well, it's the same.
The fact is that...
Pita, a friend of mine,
has a pretty big problem
and she needs me to help her.
So help her, if you can,
as long as you don't get yourself
in a commitment.
It's not a drug thing?
No, no, no.
I get the impression
that you're beating around the bush.
She needs someone
to accompany her to London,
because he has to go to London,
you know?
No, I didn't.
I find you strange.
You have always spoken to me
clearly.
(Music)
I just don't know how to do this, Dad.
What's that?
Lying to you.
I'm not surprised, you're out of practice.
I feel kind of embarrassed.
That's easy to fix,
don't lie to me.
I am pregnant.
From Mariano?
Yes.
Does he know?
What about your husband?
We haven't told him yet.
What for?
Yes, you're right, what for?
And how did Mariano take it?
Normal.
Are you going to get it?
Mariano says that whatever I say
will be fine with him.
I thought the best thing to do
is to take it off.
For that I need to go to London.
Pita will accompany me
and we thought we'd tell you about it,
but the other way around.
Maybe you don't need
to go that far,
here they do it very well
and you wouldn't be so lonely.
You have Mer,
me and Lupe.
But it's dangerous here,
it is forbidden.
Prohibited.
It is much more expensive.
But is Mariano poor?
Why did you want to deceive me?
Well...
The truth is that only for one thing.
To save you the trouble,
the worry.
I know that's what bothers you the most,
but I didn't know how to do it.
Thank you for trying.
And for knowing me.
(Music)
Where are you going this afternoon?
Out and about, aimlessly.
You agreed that you would come back to see
those from Vallecas.
Yes, I told them I would come back,
but I don't feel like it.
If you want to know the truth,
I haven't seen them for years.
I found them so old,
so different.
Years of waiting to see them and then
we had nothing to say to each other.
The children, the young people,
just like yesterday, another world.
Today, because of Chus
I can't move from here,
I have to keep an eye on the phone.
the phone.
Don't worry about me,
I have a great time
wandering around this Madrid
I don't know.
Want to play some mus?
We are missing the fourth.
Do you still play mus?
Sometimes.
Hey, gentleman,
in case you don't know,
mus is not a fashion,
it's a man's thing.
Did you forget during this time?
You were not bad at it.
Come on, Paco, you accelerate
there are many of them.
I finished it off and took out the card.
Besides, I taught my wife and the kid how to play.
and the kid.
Hala, my brother dares
with us. He is a fool.
I haven't played for years.
In addition, the same thing happened to us
the same as you,
we were almost always missing the fourth.
The two brothers against us
or would you rather we kick out kings?
This does not run in the family,
to kings.
How are things going
in your country?
Yeah, but he's been there so long,
and then the accent.
Can you tell?
It reminds a little bit of Carlos Gardel,
but otherwise nothing.
Come on you and me,
let's get off our asses.
Things are going wrong everywhere.
Today, as soon as I woke up,
I read in the newspaper
that because of that nigger
who was killed the other day...
Luther King.
That the other blacks
have taken to the streets.
They kill, they set on fire, the black hurricane
the newspaper calls it.
And in Vietnam they have cracked.
Come on, the Americans have lost the war
have lost the war
against a bunch of Chinese.
I think they are giving
the gasp.
-Is that because things are going badly?
Maybe they're going great.
-You don't need to be right.
Do you know the address?
For 31, it winks,
the average,
the duplexes...
For you the car.
We'll make do with those.
But I know them all.
Medina showed them to us,
the cleaner of the European Café.
You just follow my lead
and at the slightest doubt you will be consulted.
We've got it licked.
Sucked.
Did you hear, Eusebio,
what my partner said?
We've got it in the bag.
I send, here to the newcomer
I send you.
-You do nothing, Don Jesús, not a peep.
But I...
Quiet, quiet is good.
Envy because it is hand
and is learning
and I'm going to give him a chance to
not to take away the boy's illusion.
You quiet,
up to me, always up to me.
(CRIES)
My partner throws out without thinking
seven more.
A 12.
But why do you throw a girl out?
asshole?
Hey, kid, I'm your boss.
This is what the country of asshole bosses is like.
Like this.
Asshole, he said asshole.
Forgive me, but today
for private matters,
I am distracted.
You can sometimes be distracted at work, but not
at work, but not at play.
My daughter, the oldest, is sick,
just now, it is being
are operating on it.
But in those circumstances,
you don't sit down to play,
that mus is a game of partners.
I have sat down to play the game
because it distracts me.
-Let's go fast,
we'll catch them distracted.
-Everything went very well, Eusebio,
without any complications.
In a little while
we will take her home.
My daughter is doing well,
no problems have been reported.
Problem solved, right?
Let's see if you can concentrate now.
Rabbit.
What?
Conejil, don Jesús,
rabbit.
That you throw two.
You'll see, I'm going blind.
Now, if you carry something,
throw in another bunny.
Because I tell you
with my hand on my heart,
those of Uncle Perete.
Rabbit.
Órdago.
-I can see it.
-But well.
-What's up, dumb ass?
You dumb ass,
he called him a dumb ass.
The girl.
-You, sit down, Chus.
Bonita.
There is a paper written.
(LEE) "There is no such thing as guilt, Chus,
I leave you in the jungle.
I'm going to nowhere,
Anselmo Gato".
What an outrage.
-Has he committed suicide?
-We'll have to call his parents, they may know something.
they may know something.
You are here.
Anselmo.
Don't move, Chus.
If you had told him
to give you back the keys.
-Let me go now.
-This time it was serious.
-Bring a glass of milk,
bring a glass of milk.
better to stick your fingers in your mouth
and make him vomit.
-Bring milk, damn it.
Chus, don't go in there.
Open his mouth, Mariano,
open his mouth.
-If he is not breathing.
Milk.
Anselmo, Anselmo.
It is alive. Chus, he's alive,
it's like the other times.
What we have to do now
is to get him out of bed
and get you on your feet.
-Come, Anselmo.
-It's all very well what Trini says,
but it is impossible.
-Maybe it's better right here.
-On the bed?
-Yes, turn him upside down.
-How?
-Tell it, tell it.
-Didn't you hear me?
I want you to leave me the fuck alone.
Release me or die.
-Take the knife away from him.
-I can't open his fist.
-We'll have to call his parents.
-I don't think so, don't you remember that the other day he tried the same thing at his house?
the other day he tried the same thing at home?
-Better to leave it alone until you see a doctor,
a doctor, call a doctor,
No, that can't be him,
he's a snitch.
Yes, yes, I understood,
Eusebio, love,
but don't be nervous.
I know, I know that you have gone
to your daughter's apartment,
but right now
we send a doctor,
wash it and that's it.
You know that for that
you can't call on the phone,
you have to go.
Point the address.
Doctor Mora,
Villamoral 95, 9, 5.
Yes, call me if there are problems.
Kiss my love.
Well, now you
you must forgive me.
I have to leave.
Is something wrong with your daughter?
No, it is not that.
But what are you saying?
That you can't follow the game?
I'm really sorry,
because I was having a blast,
and with the joy that the girl's
the girl's case had gone well.
But something unforeseen has happened and I have no choice but to leave.
I have no choice but to leave.
And the game?
Well, it's over.
If we are with three to go.
There are more important things in life
than mus.
It turns out that my daughter's husband...
Fuck the family, boss.
It's not like you're a member of the
of good manners.
To have thought about it before
and not married.
The game is the game.
The rest of us are here, damn it.
What do you want?
Do you want to continue the game?
Well, it's a big deal.
What are you saying, man?
Fuck my father.
I...
I can see it,
I think I can see it,
Well, I see it,
I can certainly see it.
The mother who bore me!
-Of a teacher, Don Jesús, of a teacher.
-But what have you done, boss?
Look, Antonio, go to hell.
To hell with it.
He told him to go fuck himself.
Years without hearing it.
I know I will look ridiculous to you,
but when I came here,
I found everything changed.
There was no whorehouse or cafe.
Even the streets
seem different.
But, now, hearing
all those bad words together,
after so many years,
asshole, asshole, asshole,
dumb ass, fuck off,
I felt for the first time
I was back.
(SINGS IN CATALAN)
-What a mess the kids made of it
yesterday at the university.
120 arrested, more than 30 grays
with injuries.
-Better is
the students in France.
-That is already war.
The revolution.
It's only a few days Lupe,
I assure you,
I plan to return soon.
I have to run the store.
-Good morning, I wanted to see...
-Veronica, attend to the young lady.
-Come this way.
All I ask is that you give
lunch and dinner to grandma.
Other times you have.
(TELEVISION) "At the emergency meeting in Moscow
emergency meeting held in Moscow
between components
of the communist countries..."
Who the hell is it?
It's me, your son, Jesusín.
Come in, son, come in.
What's broken?
I wanted to talk to you.
We never do.
I have been here for two months
and we have barely changed
a few words.
So sit down
and talk whatever you want.
To the old people
to give us conversation
and almost nobody wants to.
I do,
but I am about to
to return to Argentina and...
("La la la la")
Do you want me to remove it?
I'll take it off.
Go ahead, talk.
I haven't told you
how I'm doing here,
how I found all this.
I talk to the others,
but you don't ask me anything.
How are you doing here,
my son?
How did you find your land,
your neighborhood, your family?
Everything more changed
than I thought.
They look like others.
You, on the other hand, are the same
as the day you left.
Do you think so, Mom?
I'm much older.
There, sitting in that chair,
I'm not saying no,
but I see you, here, here.
I went to see the people from Vallecas
and I didn't get along with them,
I did not recognize them.
They are bastards.
I want to stay, mom,
to be near you,
but it is not easy.
We have one million
and here a million is nothing.
Also,
I don't do food.
The meat here is good,
but they cut it very badly.
You ate very little meat
when you were little.
Do you think Mabel, my wife,
the same thing will happen with food?
But I don't know your wife
only from a picture you sent
who looked like a marquise
or a mannequin in a shop window.
Here, looking at the photo,
we were laughing for hours and hours.
(Doorbell)
Screw them.
I'm going to see who it is, Mom.
What a bad comedian he is.
Hello, good morning.
Is Mr. Eusebio Muñiz in?
No, it is not.
If I am not mistaken, you must be Eusebio's brother, right?
Eusebio's brother, right?
The exile.
That's right.
I was until recently
nephew of yours.
I am Anselmo Gato,
the ex-husband of Chus, your niece.
Pleased to meet you.
Please come in.
This is Libertad Gato,
her great-niece.
Nice to meet you too.
She's very pretty, huh?
Excuse me, I'm going to sit down.
It doesn't look like it, but it's heavy.
I have come to leave it here.
Can you give me a chinchón?
Certainly.
I thought I would find Eusebio here.
He left for the restaurant.
I've been delayed,
because of the child, you know?
I have to change him,
warm up his bottle.
My intention was to
to leave the child to Eusebio
for him to give it to Chus.
I don't want to see Chus.
Not out of resentment, but because
I am not very well on my nerves
and I don't like
strong emotions.
When we split up,
the fiercest fight we had
was because we both
wanted to keep the child.
(CRIES)
-But I said I cannot.
I'm a cartoonist, you know?
I know, I know.
And since I kept the child,
I haven't picked up a pencil again.
And Anselmo Gato
has to keep drawing,
has to live.
Precisely,
now I have just been commissioned
the covers
of a collection of classics.
I, for the moment, am going to sleep
in the apartment of some friends,
because my parents
have kicked us out of the house.
Why?
To me because of my ideas and to Libertad
because she is not baptized.
Baptize her.
No, I don't want to.
And neither does your mother.
But you are not a believer.
No, I am agnostic.
Well then, what does it matter to her
she cares if she is baptized.
You defend your ideas
in one way,
I defend them from another,
from the one I can.
I understand.
And maybe one of these days
I'll go to Paris,
which is where we have to be now.
What about the covers
you've just been commissioned?
I don't know, I don't know.
If it weren't for the child
and my mother,
who is very sick at heart,
I would have left by now.
If not, I'm going to do something crazy.
I want to ask you a favor. Do you have
something to do this morning?
She told me to bring her.
My daughter, Libe, my pretty one.
Oh, but how thin she has become.
-Don't say, Chus,
it's the same as before.
-Well, then
I should have put on weight.
Look at the way she has her clothes on.
If your father has always
has always been a handyman.
Angelito, but she's soaking wet.
Her whole ass is wet.
Same as the elevator.
Dude, since you're here,
I'll take this opportunity to say goodbye.
Maybe this afternoon
we don't have time to meet,
I leave at five o'clock.
And where are you going?
Look, this is Lucas,
my partner.
Hello, how are you?
Good, and you?
We are leaving this afternoon.
Yes, but where are you going?
To Paris,
with the students.
I guess you'll like it
that we're going there.
You already did your thing
years ago.
Now, it's our turn.
Aren't you too young
to be involved in this?
Come on, man.
It's dangerous.
Well, we already know,
we already know.
Do you want me to say something
to your old man, to your dad?
Because I don't know what he's going to say
when he finds out.
You know, I'm not a girl
who runs away, man.
He signed the papers
just in case.
I understand.
Anyone would say that the one who doesn't like
this trip is you,
to the unbeliever, to the exile.
Let it go.
I thought I was giving him a treat.
You wouldn't want to take
the idea out of your head, would you?
Mer, it's for you, Mer.
Yes?
Hello, Mer.
It's Basil again.
I've been here since early in the morning
here in the cafeteria,
to see you leave.
I went upstairs and knocked,
but no one opened the door.
It would just be my grandmother.
I've been all the time looking out
and I haven't seen you.
I have not slept at home, Basilio.
Don't tell me, don't tell me,
in the pub I found out everything.
I know you're dating Lucas
and I have been told that you are leaving.
Don't talk to me about these things,
Basilio, please.
Tell me it's not true, Mer.
Yes it is true, I'm not going to lie to you.
Does that mean goodbye forever?
Yes, Basilio, it means goodbye.
Goodbye forever?
Yes, forever.
Goodbye.
Forever, Mer.
(CRIES)
-What's wrong with my child?
Shut up.
But mommy
has made you very clean.
-She liked being dirty better.
(SINGS A LULLABY)
My child goes to sleep,
na na na na,
tomorrow what will become of you.
(THEY SING IN CATALAN)
What's the matter, Eusebio?
Don't you know anything about your girl?
Nothing, just the telegram
he sent the next day.
In these student fights,
almost nothing serious ever happens.
But it's not just the students,
they are also on strike
factory workers and farm workers.
and farm workers.
On revolutionary strike.
The boss is right,
this time there's been a good one.
Here they don't tell us half of it.
-So that we don't get nervous,
man,
look out for our health.
-Foreign radio stations report that in all
that in all the cities
Police combat against
against students and workers.
The strikers have locked their
their bosses in their offices.
And Paris airport closed.
-There may be no communications
and that is why you do not have
Hey, kid, plug that thing in.
see if they say anything.
-What are you going to say here?
-You have to put on a good face now.
you have to put on a good face.
Yes, I'm going to do it.
(RADIO) "The streets and the entire city
is pending the Black March.
Terror has gripped
the inhabitants of Washington.
Nobody goes to the restaurants
at night...".
-That is much further away,
you are not affected by it.
Change that, Sagaseta.
I prefer not to hear the news.
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la.
(Music)
Basil.
What are you doing here? Mer's not here.
I know she isn't.
There is no one in the house,
only the old woman.
I'm not here to see anyone,
I'm taking a walk.
This street?
Yes, I like to walk here.
Please leave me alone.
Listen to me, Basilio,
I am much older than you.
You are a man,
but next to me you are a kid.
Leave me alone.
Hear what I say to you.
It is convenient for you to walk
anywhere,
but not on this street.
Leave me alone! Mind your own business!
Listen, Basilio.
I want to be calm.
It's okay.
It's good to see you.
I'm glad you're leaving me!
(Music)
Waiter.
Can I have a coffee, please,
and a glass of Founder's? Girl.
-How?
-Half a glass, no more, I mean.
And the bill.
-Very good, sir.
Another gaucho.
Excuse me, Argentinean.
You can tell.
You too.
More or less, Spanish.
But I've lived there for 30 years.
Please sit down.
Thank you.
A drink?
No, no, thank you.
Antonio, bring me the coffee
to this table, will you?
Have you been in Spain for long?
No, just four days.
I'm passing through, I'm going to Paris.
So what's new over there?
I talk on the phone with my wife.
What can they tell you?
That they are all fine,
that the market is getting
more expensive every day.
Excuse me, but...
You who have been here the longest.
For a tip,
is 20 pesetas okay?
To spare,
this is a luxury place.
Excuse me,
what were you telling me over there?
What can I tell you.
Lavalle, corriente, florida,
is in the same place.
Current, flowery.
Now, if you want to know
something specific,
soccer, you are looking for...
Not soccer.
What happens is that Argentine newspapers
Argentine newspapers are very late.
Last week
I went to the Consulate
and I spent the whole morning
I read "Clarín", "La Nación".
Don Jesús, Don Jesús.
-They call him.
And tell me, are you alone here,
in Madrid?
Yes, I travel alone, I am a widower.
Now that the kids
are grown up, I take advantage of it.
Listen, what do you say
if tomorrow night we get together
and we're going to eat at a place
called Rancho Criollo?
Here, in Madrid?
Yes, yes, here, in Madrid.
We eat a nice barbecue,
listen to some good tangos.
Don't tell me
you like tangos.
Not so much there,
but here they are heard in a different way.
(Music)
(Braking)
Chocolates, how sweet. Would you like one?
Well, thank you very much.
And you, Chus?
-No, not me, thanks, mom.
-I am going to try one.
It's been ages since I've seen you
and you haven't brought her to me.
He must be about to get married by now.
And your sister, Mer?
She's dead, isn't she?
-Oh, Mom, you know
that this month she has her exams.
Well, I have to go now.
-Yes, doctor's visit, right?
-Work, mom, see you soon.
-See you when you can, daughter.
See you later.
Bye.
Have you seen what a pack of lies?
Why do you say that?
You know it like I do.
They won't bring her to me,
because Chus doesn't have her.
His father has it.
No, not anymore.
It will be a few days ago.
Yes.
And Chus is no longer living with Anselmo,
he is living with someone else.
The other one, the little one,
is not coming because she has exams.
If they have closed the faculties.
What is happening is that he has gone to Paris
with a friend to make the revolution.
Unfortunate.
Would you like a drink?
No, thank you very much.
I am going to have a drink.
Are you a teetotaler?
No, but it's not my time yet.
Already.
You were very controlling,
you were quite cold.
Do you think so?
This is how I remember you,
but anyone knows.
Memory is very deceiving.
I remember you always cheerful
and so beautiful.
I remember you playing diabolo,
jumping rope.
But that was kid stuff.
When you grew up,
you became even prettier.
Memories.
Do you remember that
you used to sing at the skipping rope
that was so fashionable?
It's been on my mind
all these years,
but I could never remember
neither the lyrics nor the melody.
It is called "La canastera".
I am the canastera de capuchinos.
Gladden the songs
my land.
I'm watching you,
I'm watching you jump rope.
And there was another one,
another very sad one, of war.
I, who was a kid, was shocked that the girl, in order to play
that the girl, in order to play,
sing such a sad song.
In the mud ravine,
there is a fountain that emanates
blood of the Spaniards
who died for their country.
That one, that one.
Oh, Jesus, you stayed there.
No, don't believe it.
What happens when I see you again
and finding me here.
This is our dining room, right?
My parents' dining room.
Yes.
When Eusebio and I got married,
we bought the four pieces of junk
he had with the ones I had.
Then, when we parted, he
he was very gentle, very gentlemanly.
He gave me the old furniture
and he bought new ones.
I spent entire afternoons here.
In winter, when I couldn't go out
to play in the street...
In that drawer were kept the checkerboard and
checkerboard and Parcheesi.
Now there are only old rags
and a deck of cards.
Sometimes I make solitaires.
You shouldn't drink so much, Marcela.
Eusebio must have already told you
that I'm a drunk.
We don't talk about it.
Ask him who is to blame.
You loved each other very much.
That was before.
You were crazy about Eusebio,
you only had eyes for him.
I used to look at you less, didn't I?
No, I'm not saying that.
But yes, you're right,
to me and to everyone.
You were our mailman.
You don't look the mailman in the face,
you look at the envelope.
(TOSE)
You used to bring us cards and bring us letters.
You lied to cover for us
when we came home late.
He asked me to.
I was the older brother,
but he was the leader of the gang.
(LAUGHTER) The boss.
That was in the good old days,
when Eusebio was another man.
The same as in politics.
We were
against the policy.
Tell it any way you want,
but Eusebio was another man.
He had passion, enthusiasm.
I wanted to do things, to change the world.
He wanted me,
but after the war
became
into the wreck that it is now.
I have found him
as intelligent as ever.
Tolerant,
understanding of others.
Tolerant?
(LAUGHTER)
No, Marcela.
Get the fuck off!
What happens is
that now he doesn't care about anything.
That his mother is backpacking...
He doesn't care.
Don't say that.
It seems to me that...
That a woman crosses his path
that endangers the couple,
he... for her.
That his wife cheats on him?
He doesn't care.
That his mistress is a procurer,
whore, smuggler, usurer...
He doesn't care.
(Music)
(SIGHS)
Look, Jesus...
Look at the difference
there is between these times
and good times.
When Eusebio,
my Eusebio was another man.
And then there's crazy Mer,
the little one.
(CRYING) There, in Paris...
Have you read the newspapers?
Yes, I read something.
Locked in,
mixed up with each other.
And among them, Mer,
the little one.
My daughter...
Eusebio's daughter.
Fucking down the stairs,
down the hallways...
That is the revolution.
I don't know what to tell you, Marcela.
That is where Eusebio
has sent my daughter.
That's what your father wanted
and you two.
That's what that man would have done
that man would have done,
the man who was Eusebio
in the good old days.
Is that tolerance?
What about the other?
What is it?
Don't sneak away, Jesus.
You have said that Eusebio's waste,
Eusebio's dead...,
because he is dead,
was what?
I think I said that I was
sympathetic to everyone.
(LAUGHTER) But with what world?
But he is alone!
He doesn't see anyone!
Nor to those who are close to him,
those who work with him.
Your brother,
the one from now, not the one from before
of how I jumped the skipping rope
and sings the...
The what?
I don't know.
"La canastera".
That.
The Eusebio of today sees no one.
He gets up,
shaves in front of the mirror...
You see him.
There, in the mirror.
And it is as if the mirror in front
the mirror in front of it.
Go away, Jesus.
How?
That you leave.
But why?
Because from now on,
you can no longer be with me.
I can, Marcela.
Only Doña Ambrosia, the neighbor.
But Marcela...
Go away at once!
(Nostalgic music)
Good boy.
Obedient, as always.
Give lots of kisses to the girls
and grandma,
that I love her very much.
You tell her.
Here, I give you kisses for everyone,
the kisses I didn't give you then.
Marcela!
(SIGHS)
Yes, I came with illusions,
but here the haute couture
is in crisis.
I was well informed.
As for me,
I wouldn't know what to do.
Investing is a dream.
What we have are caspas,
Ah, are you happy?
(LAUGHS) If you are happy,
I'm happy too.
Why didn't you tell me
that you were afraid to come?
You were also afraid to
to tell me the other thing. That's silly, Mabel.
And I miss, I miss a lot.
I don't like it,
but it's not what I left.
In addition, I felt like working again.
I felt like working again.
Yes, I know it's weird.
You're right, but they came back to me.
I'm not cold here anymore.
Mer! Mer!
Come into my arms, Mer!
What do you say, mother?
Has Mer arrived?
Where has that tramp been hiding?
What do you want to play?
You know Mer is not here.
She has gone to Alicante
with some friends.
Yes, to Alicante...
To take sea baths!
Mer, I find you.
I find you
and I give you a spanking.
That I heard your voice from the bed,
that I heard your voice...
Mer!
No, no, mother, mother...
Mer has not come.
What has arrived is
a telegram from her.
Then read it to me.
(LEE) "I arrive tomorrow, four late.
Stop. Approximately,
because I travel on the road. Stop.
Hugs to all. Mer".
I knew it, I knew it.
Why did you know?
Fuck! Because I heard it on the radio.
The day before yesterday they said, finally,
that verbena they had set up in Paris
they had set up in Paris.
We have been on the verge of achieving it.
But it is more difficult
than I thought it would be.
I don't know, maybe in another century...
Maybe it will be enough for you.
And the first days
it seemed so fucking easy...
(SIGHS) The youth
of the whole world was with us
or, at least, we believed it.
But the smartest students
smartest
thought Marcuse was right.
The workers are no longer
are no longer for the revolution.
It is that they have left in it
too much blood.
They prefer to submit to the bourgeoisie
as long as they are increased, little by little
little by little,
The Communist Party,
in the end, took flight.
Russia is not in favor of
for the revolution,
We all knew that.
And of course, it's an empire,
like the other.
More or less rich, but like the other.
That, of course.
But what are we going to fool ourselves for?
The truth is that it's all over
when De Gaulle
returned to Paris and made the speech.
The entire right wing
took to the streets.
It was frightening to see them... approaching
from the windows of the Odeon.
Our ringleaders
started to leave.
Then, the police entered the Odeon,
the Beaux-Arts, the Sorbonne...
They were forcibly evicted....
But they had promised
that those who went out calmly
nothing would happen to them, right?
Yes, yes, but...
When we came out,
were the police vans, the police vans
and there they were putting
students.
Some escaped,
I was lucky and I was one of those.
Don Quixote returns home.
(Clock)
And Trini and Pepe?
Trini
is only a few days away.
Please, Mer,
you haven't been gone that long.
He still has two months to go.
And Anselmo? Is he well?
Have you seen him again?
No! We have not seen him again.
But it's good, very good.
We know.
He was about to leave
to Paris, like you!
But, in the end, he didn't leave;
because, as his mother is ill
of the heart...
And for the covers!
Yes, that's why too!
And Basilio's heavy?
Have you heard from him?
Basil...
(Sad music)
What?
Has something happened to you again?
Basilio has committed suicide.
No...
Do you mind if I come in to see you, Mom?
On the contrary, I appreciate it.
Sit down. But first,
please draw the curtain.
The good weather is here
and there is too much light.
For chatting it is better in the twilight.
Well, you tell me.
I'm leaving very soon.
And I wouldn't want to leave
without talking some more.
Because if there...
things are still going well for me,
I may not come back.
And when are you leaving?
Tomorrow.
The plane leaves
at two o'clock in the morning.
But first we will all meet
here, at home, for dinner.
My son told me.
I think it's going to be
a dinner in style.
My son does that very well.
It's his trade.
He, the girls and Lupe have spent hours discussing the menu.
hours discussing the menu.
When I saw you the first time,
I thought you looked like an asshole.
But I have changed my mind.
Have you?
You are very smart.
Do you know why?
That's why he has made
the blanket over his head
and say: "I'm leaving".
Do you think so?
You have
have nothing to do...
Well, what a store of clowns
of clowns and phonies is this one.
That's not why I'm leaving, Mom.
I am leaving because
this Spain is not the one I knew.
Neither Madrid is Madrid anymore.
Here, of course.
Nor are you you.
What I want to say is that...
I didn't mean to upset you, did I?
God forbid.
I know,
because I heard it on the radio,
that Argentine comedians are very good
are very good.
That has nothing to do with...
Shut up!
Argentinean comedians
will be very good, I don't dispute that;
but you, to tell you the truth,
as an actor you're pretty weak.
I'm not an actor, Mom.
I was wondering...
But this guy,
who works so badly,
how can you imitate so well
the Argentine accent so well?
But I got him.
You are Argentine!
Isn't it?
Aren't you Argentinean?
Yes, Mom, yes.
Don't call me mom, milk!
Yes, ma'am.
You see?
You are Argentinean.
From La Pampa...
You are right to go back there,
on the other side of the sea.
Or are you afraid
for political reasons?
Are you a persecuted person?
No, I am not.
Listen to me, I'm talking to you
as your mother would speak to you.
To the politicians
to hell with them!
Whatever color they are.
And if you have to change jackets,
Don't they just backflip when it's
when they feel like it?
Well then...
Do not do as my husband did,
my poor Jesus, may he be in glory.
Who lost half his life
with what if the idea,
with what if the cast...
Or like my Jesusín,
my son, the eldest,
that he had to hide in the sea
and it did him no good.
(SOBS) He drowned,
drowned forever...
You have to live, my friend.
That's the only important thing.
Do you agree?
Yes, yes, ma'am.
Here, in your office,
with that tango accent, he was going to have a hard time
it was going to be hard to find a job.
I would only find scrounging botches,
like this one right now.
Believe me, an old woman is telling you.
Where the work is,
there is one's land.
Unless you are a millionaire,
of course,
that is already international.
(LAUGHTER)
(Door)
No, Florida is a pedestrian street.
Oh, is it?
The movie theaters are in Lavalle, you know?
Lupe much insisting
that we would not be delayed
and it is she who does not arrive.
Ah, there it is.
I thought Florida was like Gran Via.
Sure, that's it, that's it.
These are the candles.
For you, Jesus,
memories of old Spain.
Thank you, Lupe,
why did you bother?
No, don't open those.
They are for Mabel and the boy.
They will be happy to open them.
Ah...
Nothing original. Mantilla of lace
and silver Toledo dagger.
This is yours.
Hey! But what's so big?
It looks like a painting, doesn't it?
How much I appreciate it...
But what does it say here?
(LEE) "Antonio Bienvenida,
Curro Romero and Jesús Muñiz,
that will confirm the alternative".
(LAUGHTER) How much I thank you...
Don't pretend there is trust.
It's clear that you don't appreciate it at all.
I thank you for the detail,
the intention, the memory...
But, to me,
I never liked bullfighting.
Neither me nor my brother.
It seemed like a wild party,
backward...
So...
Are you an Argentinean
who doesn't like tangos
and a Spaniard
who does not like bullfighting?
Don't worry. Just in case,
I made sure the frame was good.
In Buenos Aires, you show the poster
to the compadritos and the family.
Then, you take it off...
and put a mirror.
I don't like bullfighting, but I don't like
I don't like to look at myself in the mirror.
Son, how difficult you are...
(LAUGHTER)
Permission.
The candles are up!
Please,
Who has a lighter?
Thank you very much,
I'll take them both.
Chus, everything is ready!
Lucas, draw the curtains, please.
Mariano, turn off the lights.
You know where they are.
The floor lamp is left alone.
(Campanadas)
But how beautiful you look, Grandma.
For once I leave the house,
I'm not going to be a wreck.
And these flowers? How beautiful...
This gentleman gave them to me,
who is a foreigner.
This is your place, Mrs. Eusebia.
Jesus, there.
Mer, you there and there.
Yeah, I know.
Chus, that's your place.
And Mariano, here, with me.
Well, call the maître d'.
Papa!
No, Chus...
Don't fuck it all up!
Not like this... Clap your hands.
Come on, clap your hands.
(Clapping)
The menu, please.
Oh...
But, my son,
this letter like this, in the half light...
I don't see it.
Do you want to tell me...?
Yes, ma'am.
Today we have Duke of Berry salmon,
filet mignon a la Curnonsky
and strawberries a la Triple Alliance.
Ah, very good, very good...
Thank you, madam.
Lucas, bring the bread and the bottle closer.
How elegant Eusebio is, isn't he?
I think that on such an important night
we could tell the "maître d'"
to stay and eat with us.
Please, Eusebio,
we would like you to sit
sit down to dinner with us.
Here's a place for you.
Thank you, madam.
For me, it is an honor.
What's wrong with you, Mer?
Nothing, nothing.
Tremendous oversight!
Forgetfulness! What a failure!
What's up, Lupe?
The music!
We forgot the music, Mer.
My beloved Buenos Aires....,
when I see you again,
there will be no more sorrow or oblivion.
The streetlight
of the street where I was born
was sentinel
of my promises of love.
Under its quiet little light,
I saw her...
Pass me the salt shaker, Mer.
...to my luminous beetle
like a sun.
(murmur)
Today that luck
wants me to see you again,
porteño city of my only desire.
I hear a bandoneon's complaint
inside my chest
my heart asks for a rein.
My Buenos Aires,
flowery land,
where my life will end.
Under your protection,
today there is no disappointment.
The years fly by,
the pain is forgotten...
(Waves)
(Music credits)