I think I can see it.
See what?
The anchor.
There isn't one silly.
There is too.
No, not really.
What is there then?
Well it's just a border
like anywhere else.
She's always seeing
things that aren't there.
Like that mermaid yesterday.
Well Anne will believe
me when she arrives.
Oh she just humors you.
Checkpoint ahead boys.
Now you take it up there and drop anchor.
Milly, come with me and
help me hide my tins
in the backup from the customs, come on.
Okay.
Don't they have tobacco in Hungary?
Yeah of course there are,
but not my favorite kind.
Why Daddy?
Whatever does your mother do with you
when you're at home all day?
Oh she humors me.
Dad.
Hmm?
Customs are arriving.
Oh.
How lovely to see you.
My goodness you get prettier every year.
Come below gentlemen,
I'll show you the papers.
It's wonderful to see you again.
Thank you.
Hello, how are you?
Very well, thank you.
You have got longer since last year.
Maybe.
He's getting fatter.
Hello Michael.
It's good to see you.
Uh-oh I'm going to tell.
Stop it.
Same old Milly.
First, thank you again
for the lovely time
you gave me when I visited
you in London last year.
Oh, that was my pleasure.
And now to see you all
again, it is smushing.
Smushing.
Did you have a good
trip thus far this year?
Oh pretty straightforward.
We came down the Rhine.
Milly said you could
hear The Lorelei singing.
Then through Austria on the Danube.
Well everything seem to
be in order Mr. Stevenson.
Good.
Now, have you anything to declare?
Oh just a little pipe tobacco.
You?
No, nothing.
There is a man waiting to see you
on the bank Mr. Stevenson.
Oh?
I knew that character was watching us.
You are welcome to go ashore
in our launch if you want.
Oh thank you, I'll just get my coat.
Oh Stevenson, oh my dear fella.
Thank heavens, you're a bit late you know.
I'm Braithwaite from the Legation.
Braithwaite?
Yes, I missed you in Vienna
so we dashed over here with my...
Well the point is, we need
you in Budapest right away.
What?
Yes, Ar-chep's gone sick.
You've got to make the opening speech.
Look I...
Now don't, don't, don't,
don't worry, don't worry.
You can always read his
speech if you get stuck.
But what about my family?
Your fam, oh.
Well that's a bit of a snag isn't it?
Well most certainly,
they've got to come with me.
What in the car?
Well I hate to admit defeat old man, but...
Look Dad, why don't I
take the boat to Budapest
and meet you there?
Well if I must, I suppose I must.
Oh that's my boy.
Now come along, come along now.
Oh but now look here, Milly
will have to come with me.
She's too young to stay here by herself.
No, no, no, I want to go with Anne,
I don't want to go in the rotten old car.
Oh.
Now, stop that Milly.
I'm not gonna have to tell your mother
that you've behaved badly.
Please Mr. Stevenson.
We'll take real good care of her.
Please Daddy.
Oh all right.
All right but now see
that you look after her.
Now come along that's fine old boy.
Now we haven't got a moment
to spare, now come along.
Oh but look here, what about my gear?
I must have a toothbrush.
Oh don't worry, we'll get all that stuff
while you're at the Legation,
now you just hop in there.
Mm-hmm, that's fine now come along.
Come on Dad, in you go.
How do you suggest we do this?
Oh it's very simple, just
forward madame s'il vous plaît.
Eh, there.
There we are.
OH dear.
Very nice.
Well good-bye.
Bye Dad, see you go.
Bye Dad.
Bye.
Come on, let's go.
Nothing to worry about, just
rely on Savoir Faire.
I don't even know if I brought any.
Fortunately I have enough for two.
As you were.
Passports please.
One American and one English huh.
Well we're not married right.
Have you anything to declare?
I'm glad you asked me that.
I want to declare that three
pair of socks was stolen.
No, no, that was in Austria.
He doesn't want to know that.
He wants to know if you have
any valuable merchandise,
gold, or precious stones?
No, not yet.
Shut up.
And you?
I have only to declare my admiration
for the treasures of your country.
I should like to look in the caravan.
All right.
Open this one please.
Well I thought I'd pick up
a few things in Budapest.
Thank you sir.
Please, I hope you will
enjoy your stay in Hungary.
Thank you.
As you were.
If somebody does not watch them,
they will try to steal the Danube.
I don't think you should have said that.
I'm going to pick up a
few things in Budapest.
Well, maybe I shouldn't have said it.
But I think we should.
I mean we should steal something
just to keep in practice.
A few postage stamps or something.
Why do we always have
to steal an art object?
The trouble with you is that
you always think in pennies.
I think in millions.
You got a cigarette?
Wait a minute.
Michael and I are going to the ship stores
to get some supplies.
You Milly go down to the
market and get some bread.
Get cracking.
You men cracking.
Yes, cracking.
Crocking.
Yes.
Smaller, smaller, for four people.
Four people.
Oh.
No, no, no, no.
Four people, 1/4.
But I can't use all that bread.
Can I help you young lady?
Yes please.
How much bread do you want?
I only want a quarter
of that enormous loaf.
Thank you, that was a great help.
Are you on holiday here?
No, we're going to Budapest in a boat.
My father's going there by car,
to a conference or something.
And what have you come to see?
But I can't think of anything special.
But my brother likes to eat special
because of the ice cream.
Anne says there was some
nice things in the cathedral.
Would you like to see
something really special?
One of the most lovely things in Hungary.
And nobody else will be
able to see it today.
Something secret?
Yeah.
Oh yes, please.
You must be one of the youngest visitors
Saint Laszlo ever had.
They clean it like this every year.
And it's a tradition that the cleaning
shall always be done by the same family.
His grandfather's grandfather
did this before him.
It's solid gold, this is
enamel and precious stones.
It's a great treasure.
It's beautiful.
Now I really have got a secret.
Yes, yes. So.
Thanks for letting me see it.
Quite a gem there isn't it?
I know.
What were you looking at there?
Saint Laszlo of course.
Yes, he must be wonderful.
He is, smashing all
that lovely gold hair
and all those rich jewels.
You seem to know quite
a lot about Saint Laszlo.
He's the most beautiful
thing I've ever seen.
When, how could you have seen him?
It was a very special favor.
I'm the only one who
seem him today actually.
Today, no you must be wrong my dear.
He isn't here today.
I know, they're cleaning it.
The same family do it,
they've been doing it for ever and ever.
You think they'd show
it to me if I ask nicely?
They might.
You're sure you're not imagining all this?
I'll jolly well show
you, the house I mean,
not him 'cause that's a secret.
All right, but I still can't believe it.
Come on, I'll show you.
We have to be very quick,
my brother's waiting for me.
All right.
We must hurry, they'll be
waiting for me at the boat.
A boat.
The White Rabbit, we're
on our way to Budapest.
Oh.
It's there, yellow
house with the green door.
I see.
Good-bye, remember it's a secret.
I will, okay, bye.
The men say they
are very sorry Michael,
but we must return to town.
The chief of police wants to ask us
some questions about something.
He especially wants to talk to Milly.
Me, oh dear I bet it's
about daddy's tobacco tins.
Yes, that could be.
This way please.
Yes, that's the little girl.
I'm afraid something rather
serious has happened.
You remember the golden
head, it's been stolen.
Stolen, it can't be,
who'd do such a thing?
Apart from myself,
you are the only one who saw it yesterday.
How dreadful.
Did you tell anybody
about seeing the head?
I started to tell Harold.
I thought she was making it up as usual.
I knew she had a secret,
but I never dreamed it
was anything like this.
You are the oldest one, no?
Yes sir.
Can you explain this?
That's ours.
The White Rabbit is your boat isn't it?
Yes sir.
This tool was used
to break into the house
and then left behind.
But that's incredible.
Perhaps you took it as a joke.
Certainly not.
Our dad's a detective, we
would never be so stupid.
Fancy anybody leaving direct evidence
on the scene of the crime like that.
It's a put up job, but
how did they get our hammer?
My father's at the police
conference in Budapest,
he'll tell you that we don't normally
go around committing burglaries.
You say that somebody
stole this and then the head?
Well it's the only explanation.
Think hard, you must have told
somebody about the head.
No, I would have remembered.
Uh-oh.
Yes.
There was a man in the
cathedral, he was English.
I showed him the house.
Can you describe him?
Could I be of help?
That's him.
Mr. Palmer, the
London antique dealer aren't you?
Yes,
Allow me to introduce
you to the chief of police.
How do you do?
What a tragedy Father, what a tragedy.
It is him, I showed him the house.
Is this young lady in
some sort of trouble?
It's very embarrassing Mr. Palmer,
but she said she showed you where the head
of Saint Laszlo was
being cleaned yesterday.
What nonsense, I've never seen
this little girl before in my life.
You're telling stories my dear.
It's not true, it's
not true, I did show you.
You must believe me,
really I did show him.
Now this is preposterous,
I insist upon my car
and my hotel room being searched.
Thank you Mr. Palmer,
I'm being forced to ask you
to do that after what the child says.
Naturally.
You know if your mommy
and daddy were here,
I'd have something to say
about your upbringing.
You were at one of those
progressive schools no doubt.
Excuse me sir.
Oh Mr. Palmer.
My father's in Budapest,
but perhaps if you care
to leave me your card, if
an apology is called for
you'll certainly get one.
That's fair enough.
Thank you.
Surely you believe me.
My child, I
don't know what to think.
Except that you must be mistaken.
There, there, it'll be all right.
Have they gone?
Yes.
The police, they're
the same the world over.
Mm-mm, now you may assume
that all police are fools, but I don't.
I think I was right to
take the bull by the horns.
To grab the cup.
No, no, that's just an expression,
meaning that it was wise to
go to the police station,
now you've got that?
Yes.
But what did I say?
When?
Look, do you remember
that job that we did
in Bogno in 1950?
Yes.
Hmm, well we're not
gonna do it that way.
Oh.
Now, what is the obvious thing to do?
I just said that, do you know?
Yeah, the obvious
thing to do is something
that's so obvious that
nobody even suspects that.
So we'll get us a jet plane with the...
No.
A truck, a refrigerator
truck with plenty of ice.
No.
No ice.
No truck, no.
Well, what if we got...
No, no, I'll tell you
what we're gonna do.
We'll make it invisible.
What?
The thing.
What thing?
The object.
What object?
Oh you know what.
No, I don't.
The head.
Oh the golden head, yeah!
Now look, I'll explain it to you
in words of one syllable.
Aww there's no need to be insulting.
Now look, what we're going to do,
yes, we're going to pull
the old double bluff.
The old double bluff.
Yeah.
What is the old double
bluff, what's that?
Well you see those kids on the boat
are in so much trouble already,
all we've got to do is to dig
them in a little bit deeper
then the police will never believe
anything they say at anytime.
That's genius, well
you travel with a genius
who just keeps geniusing.
There's a fly in the coffee.
The main questions
that came to our concern
gentlemen are the following.
Firstly to intensify
the service provided by
the Central International Crime Bureau
so that it will be possible,
not only to furnish any
country requesting it,
with visual data and by radio,
such as photographs and
fingerprints of wanted criminals,
but also to follow this up
with a detailed dossier on microfilm.
Secondly to clarify the
extradition procedure
on criminals who abscond from
one country into another.
We will be pooling information on a
- series of armed robberies.
- Don't bother us now,
he's speaking, yes.
- Similar in outline.
- Oh can't it wait?
Which have effected most of us here at
- one time or another.
- Well if it's that urgent.
And which may well...
Sorry young man, it's urgent.
Oh, okay, yes.
Hello, I think he's on the line.
Hello Daddy, is that you?
Milly, you've chosen rather
an awkward moment darling.
Can I ring you back, I'm making a speech.
But this is really
important, you must listen.
It's about a crook.
He's stolen the golden
head, have you got a pencil?
Oh all right, but give me it quick,
then get off the line will you?
Palmer, P-A-L-M-E-R,
antique dealer, 99-99-Saint James.
Yes, all right now,
will you ring off please?
But how will you let us know?
I'll send you a wire to...
Esztergom.
Esztergom, right goodbye.
My apologies gentlemen, a slight crisis.
And now to return to the more serious
business of catching criminals.
I don't think Daddy was very pleased.
Dad will let us know if
Palmer's a crook or not,
we just have to wait and be patient.
These four paintings are very famous.
They are at least four or 500 years old.
The artist is unknown.
In place of his signature he
only used his initials, M.S.
Shall we move on then?
# If I wasn't shy #
# I would look in your eye #
# And I would find the
way to say the things #
# I'd like to say #
# Some things that I feel #
# I can't never reveal #
# I wish I knew the way to say
the things I'd like to say #
# But how can I ask you to be mine #
# I guess I will have to take my time #
# Sweet words in my heart #
# Tell me, where do I start #
# I only hope perhaps one day #
# I'll say the little
things I'd like to say #
That was very nice Michael, I liked it.
It's him Palmer, with another man.
What are they up to?
It's his accomplice, they
always have an accomplice.
I bet that's why they
didn't mind being searched.
What a stroke of luck them stopping him.
Now we can watch them.
Maybe they've got the
golden head in there.
Gosh, do you really think so?
We could catch 'em red handed.
Then Daddy wouldn't disown us.
He may even get promoted because of this.
Now's our chance, let's tell the others.
No, Michael would never agree.
It's up to us, are you with me?
Of course.
We thought we'd
go for a little stroll.
Don't go to far away.
We won't.
Milly?
Yes?
Don't you go
getting into any more scrapes.
All right.
You want to go inside?
Of course.
It's in there, I saw it.
Come on.
Michael!
What?
It's there in Palmer's caravan.
He's got it, he really has.
Not the golden head.
Yes, Milly saw it in the cabin.
You'd better be right this time.
Good evening.
Oh, come in.
In there.
But I saw it, I know it was there.
They must have moved it.
Oh, there's nothing here.
Now if you're quite satisfied,
perhaps you wouldn't
mind leaving us alone.
My friend here is tired.
Pardon.
But it's true, they're so true.
Young man, I hold you
responsible for this.
You realize that if I wanted to get nasty
I could go to the Legation.
I think that an apology
is called for, don't you?
Yes sir, I apologize sir.
Thank you very much.
Nice kid, that kid.
Get it back out again.
Why.
Well we might as well admit it,
they're not crooks and we
made that whole thing up.
On the contrary I'm
convinced they are crooks.
The man with him looked
about as straight as a pretzel.
Yeah.
You know Dad's book on
how to catch a criminal?
Yes.
Well just add a little
deduction as it says.
Now then, why would they
park right beside us?
Because they wanted to be searched.
Why should they want that?
To make us look foolish.
Now our accusations seem worthless.
Why should they want that?
Because they are guilty.
That's it, you were
right Milly old girl,
and I'm proud of you.
You'd better have a look in Dad's books,
see what else it says.
Yes.
Have you ever heard of anyone
needing a life preserver on the Danube?
I never even heard of the Danube.
You know we've been very successful
in our operation so far.
But with every policeman in the country
looking for what we've got.
What do we got?
The thing.
What thing.
The object.
What object?
The you know what?
Oh the, yeah I know that,
I'm not stupid you know.
Well I think we ought
to put it somewhere
where no one will ever
think of looking for it.
Put it right at the bottom of the river.
Mm-hmm, and then we wouldn't
be able to find it ourselves.
That's right.
Now let's put it in
the life preserver locker
on The White Rabbit.
Basil, that's beautiful.
Yeah.
That's why you're a
genius, that's genius.
That's what I thought.
Well see if you could find
an old piece of canvas and wrap it up.
Wrap what up?
Oh the, the...
Mm-hmm, yeah.
I know what.
I hope that boat floats.
I don't feel like going
in that cold water.
I thought you told me
you went to prep school.
Yeah, what's that got to do with it?
Well didn't you take
a cold shower every day?
Every day, twice on the weekends.
Then you should be used to cold water.
Well we didn't take cold
showers to get used to the water,
we took 'em to take our mind off things.
What things?
Well you know, girls.
Well why do you want
to take your mind off girls for?
I didn't.
You know that here in Hungary
they take hot showers together.
Together?
No, nothing.
There should be some word.
She said no.
What now Sherlock Holmes?
Let's telephone Daddy again.
After all we know what a crook
Palmer is and daddy doesn't.
Okay, let's go.
Now this is the
only authentic photograph
we have of the international
art thief, Basil Peale.
He usually passes himself off as a major.
In fact, he never rose
above the rank of last call.
We do have photographs
of a pair of criminals
who's record is similar to Peale's.
My government is seeking
a man who goes by the name
of Sat-yed Palmer.
He stole the Perseid Idol Of Yar-Har
in a daringly executed coup
and he has upset the entire
female population of my country.
This is the photograph.
Until the Perseid Idol is recovered,
no marriages may take place in Yorhar.
So if you gentleman would
please treat this affair
with the utmost urgency.
The gentleman in our picture is...
who attempted to steal
Schubert's unfinished Symphony.
Photo.
Fortunately we foiled
him while he was looking
for the rest of the score.
Hello?
Long distance
call for Mr. Stevenson.
Well if it's a personal
call I can't take it.
The call sir.
No, no, no, I won't accept the call.
Daddy, hello, hello Daddy.
Milly, ring off at once.
I don't want any more calls from you
until you get to Budapest, you hear.
Dad, Mike, look this is an emergency.
Did you send a cable?
What cable?
About Palmer.
What are you talking about?
He hasn't done anything yet.
This is going to be up to us.
Michael, are you, is
everything all right?
Yes, we're fine thanks.
Then don't bother me anymore
Michael please, goodbye.
Is the canvas is stolen
by these two men include a
Dufy, a de Toulouse-Lautrec, a Gauguin,
a van Gogh, a Chagall, and a 90 castles.
What now mastermind?
Perhaps we ought to go to the police?
No.
No, we'll make our own inquiries.
We'll send a cable.
That's a good idea.
Who is the cable to, Scotland Yard?
No, our own investigator.
We'll find out if Palmer really does
have a shop in Saint James.
We'll case the joint.
Who is this super
intelligent investigator?
The Honorable Augustus.
Who?
Why the Honorable
Augustus Pilkington Smythe.
He's got the highest intelligence rating
in the whole of London.
Who says so?
He does.
Come on, let's get to the cable office.
Come in.
Good morning sir.
Good morning Stanley.
A telegram has arrived
for you sir, from Budapest.
You've been reading
my mail again Stanley.
Certainly not sir.
Then how did you know
it came from Budapest?
It smells of paprika sir.
Hmm, you want to have a little joke.
Hmm, get me the Rolls.
I fear his lordship is using it sir.
Then get me the Bentley.
Our ladyship has taken it to town.
May I offer you my Ferrari sir?
Who's driving?
Me naturally.
No thank you, get me a taxi.
Very well sir, right away.
After I finish my breakfast.
You sure you got that number right pal?
I mean we've been up and down this street
three times already, I
can't see no number 99.
I really don't understand it.
There must be a 99 somewhere.
Well there's one next
door to me in Beckham,
but it's a certainty there ain't one here.
Fluid kids.
I'm not fluid kids as
you choose to call it.
My name is Pilkington Smythe.
I'm sure there's a 99 somewhere.
Pilkington Smythe,
ha is it your name huh?
Yes.
Pilkington Smythe, well
that's so cute at that.
Right, your lordship.
You want to settle the fare now
or are we gonna go on missing the bar?
I'm not your lordship
as yet, only an honorable.
Kindly wait me while I ask somebody.
The full leave you are.
Hey, I said,
can you tell me where number 99 is?
Scram kid, I
ain't supposed to talk.
Try a telephone directory.
Excellent idea, thank you.
I shan't be very long, please wait.
All right, all right,
it's mighty times for me,
put your foot on the meter now.
Oh I'll pay.
This is dog waiting mad,
the little monster about.
I'll be broke too.
Kindly embarrassing, I forgot my wallet.
Would you mind lending me a pound please?
I'll pay it back when I get home.
I knew it, I knew it,
he's putting the bite on me.
I have a rather expensive
cable to send, it's most urgent.
The first time I've ever been conned
by a member of the nobility.
It don't make it any better, here.
I'll be eternally grateful old chap.
Get on with it.
Would you read it back to me?
We really don't need
quite so many words do we?
Surely we can allow ourselves
just a little telegraphese.
Certainly not madame, this
telegram is going abroad.
So it would be unpardonable to
butcher the Queen's English.
Very well, as you wish.
I'm sick and tired of that boat,
this is worse than going to a funeral.
You're a sticker bomb,
this is a kind of holiday.
Lovely sunshine, beautiful
country, remember Rio de Janeiro?
Oh yeah, Delores.
Forget Delores.
Oh yeah, Delores, oh I've...
They're still following
us, I wonder why?
They're just curious I guess.
You'd think we got the golden head
the way they are following us.
That's no good, you're too far away.
Uh-huh.
What we need is a close up photograph.
I see, well how do
you suggest we do that?
Well we'll go to an Express
Soup Cafe in the next town.
They'll follow us and it'll be a cinch.
Milly, you know what you are?
You're a mastermind.
Anne is taking a long time.
Well what she's trying to do
is a little difficult to organize.
Here she comes.
Watch out for the
man with the red scarf.
Smashing.
Very good.
Great, just what we needed.
How many please?
About a dozen, and we'll
hang on to the negative.
That's funny.
What's funny?
Oh nothing, I'm probably
imagining things again.
We will send the memo to
Guff, he's got contacts
in Scotland Yard as
well as everywhere else.
Okay, we follow them
into Budapest, then what?
Well we'll check the
boat from time to time
until they leave, then we'll follow them
to Austria and collect our you know what.
Hey, they can't do that,
where are they going?
What a rotten trick.
I thought you said the
road followed the river.
It does, but only on the map.
See they built, I don't know.
Hey, hey, hey.
Oh welcome.
You're in good hands.
Today everybody's our guest.
Come to the wedding.
We're invited to a wedding.
The prettiest girl in
Hungary will be married.
I'm the best man.
She's a ballet dancer.
Did he say a belly dancer?
I think he said a ballet dancer.
She doesn't look like a ballet dancer.
No, she's the bride's mother.
She won a prize in Brussels.
For dancing or for the chicken?
# Hey #
# Hey, oh, hey #
# Hey, oh #
# Hey #
They certainly do some
very lovely candle work here.
Now watch yourself
Lionel, endeavor to temper
with your personality your
body cannot restraint.
Why can't I just sit here?
# Hey #
# Oh #
# Hey oh, ho #
# Oh hey #
# Hey oh #
# Oh, oh #
# Hey #
What is he saying?
They are selling the bride.
He just got her.
If anyone wants
to dance with the bride,
he has to pay.
It's an old British custom.
I'll be a customer.
What, you're the cheapest, meanest man
that ever went to a wedding.
Ooh.
# Hey, oh, hey, oh #
# Hey, hey #
Money please, money, please, please,
more money, more money.
Please more money, more money.
Have you lost your presence of mind?
What's the difference?
We're gonna have plenty of
money once we get to Budapest
and we get the head of Saint Laszlo.
Quiet.
Aww, what you kick me for?
All I said was Saint Laszlo.
Quiet.
That's the house of Parliament there.
Look, Michael, Fisherman's Bastion!
Where, over there?
Yes!
Look, the Chain Bridge, Michael!
What's it say?
Just a minute, it's very long.
Palmer indubitably imposter.
Hurray!
Let's go and tell Dad!
Right!
When this man,
Palmer, came to Italy,
he called himself.
We feared that some of our
priceless antique relics
- would disappear.
- Yes?
Oh, oh, they're here, are they?
Well, tell 'em I'll be right out.
An Etruscan tomb.
The tomb was empty.
And another thing, our fingerprint experts
have reached the point,
- frequently ascertain...
- Here he is.
Dad, you know that
man we told you about?
He really is a fraud.
What man, darling?
The man we phoned about.
We think he stole the golden head.
Well, surely you've heard about that, Dad.
Of course I have, the Hungarian police
are talking about nothing else.
If you're so sure, why didn't
you get in touch with them?
We tried like mad.
They won't believe us.
Milly tried to tell them about
them at Gyor and Esztergom,
but they just won't believe us.
So we sent a cable to London,
and we found out there's no such man.
I mean, no such address,
and so we sent a photo from Visegrad.
Who the devil to?
A friend.
What are you all talking about?
It's true, he gave us a
false address in St. James's.
You mean he's English?
What are you trying to do,
disgrace me with the
British delegation here?
Anna, for heaven's sake,
get them out of here
and show them Budapest, or something.
And Milly, will you
please leave the police
to do their own job?
But I'm positive I
saw it in the caravan,
and now they're following us.
Milly, that room there
is full of police officials
from all over the world.
Are you trying to tell
me that you can do better
than all of them put together?
Dad, take this picture
just in case, huh?
Oh, all right.
Stevenson, be a good
fellow and come and show me
where the notes are on the
forgery case, will you?
We'll need them in a jiffy.
- Hello, you lot.
- Good afternoon.
- Come on, old man!
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Why is Dad so much more helpful
in print than in real life?
There are plenty of things
to see on Saturday afternoon.
Where would you like to go?
The movies.
Football.
All right, football.
Number seven bus will take
you right to the stadium
and you can take a taxi back to the boat.
What are we grown-ups gonna do?
You will see.
Good afternoon,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the Turf Club.
Well, Basil, how we
gonna bet without losing?
Very simple, we won't use our money.
Well, then whose?
His.
Go on, get it.
Lesson number four.
I didn't get it.
I know.
Now, Lionel, pay attention.
This is absolutely the last
time I'm going to show you.
See what I mean?
Oh!
Now, give it back.
Back?
Give it back and look sad.
Don't worry, I will.
You're kidding, huh?
No, no, go on.
But...
And don't forget to look sad.
Don't forget to...
Okay.
Now, look, the big payoff comes
if you can pick number one
and number two.
So we're gonna bet that
on number five and six.
They're longshots.
That' right, big risk, big money.
Now, you take that and
we bet half on number six
to come in first, and the
other half on number five
to come in second, okay, got that?
Yes, six to come in first
and five to come in second.
Right.
Six to come in first,
five to come in second.
And six to come in first,
and five to come in second.
Six to come in first and
five to come in second.
And six to come in, oh!
Five to come in first and
six to come in second.
The horses are
approaching the starting line.
Can't win 'em all, you know?
You were silly, Basil.
You should have bet five
and six, not six and five.
The results of the first race are
number five wins.
Lionel, you made a mistake!
I'm sorry about that, Basil.
Well, this time, I'll forgive you.
Come on, let's collect our money.
I'm sorry, I cannot
pay out on this ticket.
It's a torn ticket.
Oh, come now, I paid for it.
Just a minute.
Hey, what's he sayin'?
He says he can't pay
out on a torn ticket.
Oh!
Would you mind letting us take a picture
for The Evening Gazette?
Sure.
If it's not too much trouble.
Okay.
There you are.
Very good!
There it is.
Can I have both your names
so I have a record of it
in my files?
Yes, what is it?
The Honorable Augustus
Brookington-Smythe
wishes to see you on
an urgent matter, sir.
I don't know any Augustus Thingamabob.
Oh.
Now, wait a minute.
Yes, of course, that'll be Diana's boy.
All right, show him in.
Very well, sir.
Good afternoon, sir.
My mother asked to be remembered to you.
When I mentioned my
particular problem to her,
she said you'd be sure to help
if I reminded you of the evening
of Queen Charlotte's Ball in 1951.
Oh, that's the way it is, eh?
Still, it was a rather wonderful evening.
Right, now, what can I do for you?
Could you tell me if these men
are in your international rogues gallery?
Oh, yes, I think we might manage that.
Anything else?
Well, sir, if the resultant information
were to prove interesting,
I assume you could get
a message to Budapest
quicker than I could.
Well, yes, of course, I
mean, did you say Budapest?
Yes, I did, to the police there.
Now, on second thought, for
the sake of national prestige,
it might be preferable to
get it to old man Stevenson.
Who?
Stevenson, he's at the
International Conference
on Criminal Law.
You know him.
Why, yes, of course.
Now, look here, young man,
there are quite a few
questions I'd like to ask you.
What about the photograph first?
What?
Oh, photograph, yes.
Well, it's still there.
It's Palmer!
It is Palmer.
For once, you're not seeing things.
I wonder what it says.
Gellert Hotel, we can understand that.
Gellert Hotel, that's near us!
There's somebody on our boat!
Hey, what are you doing?
You dirty rotten,
stay away from our boat!
I wonder what they were doing.
Let's take a look.
I wonder what it is.
I don't know.
The golden head!
Those men must have been
in Palmer's gang, but why?
Don't you see, things
got too hot for them,
so they planted it on us.
Police would never fall for that.
Why not?
They didn't believe us before.
Wait till Michael and Anna see this.
You can't show it to Michael and Anna!
What's the matter with you?
Of course we can.
Don't you see?
Anna's Hungarian, and she'd
have to tell the police,
and Daddy told us to lay off Palmer.
Hmm, what can we do then?
Palmer and his gang planted it on us,
so we must go to the Gellert Hotel
and plant it on Palmer
instead, then go to the police.
We better leave a note
for Michael and Anna.
They'll be in a fit
wondering where we've been.
Is this more like it, Michael?
Yes, it is.
I'm sorry your friend
wasn't able to come with us.
Oh, Michael, you're not a good liar.
No, I'm not.
The truth is, I wanted
to be alone with you.
Let's get outta here.
Come on.
Put that note where
they'll be sure to see it.
Right, ready?
There's Dad, what are we gonna do?
Hide it!
- Hello, Dad.
- Where are Michael and Anna?
Oh, they had something special
to see, some kinda museum.
They shouldn't be too long.
Are you up to something?
No, Daddy.
You've stopped all this cops
and robbers nonsense, have you?
Yes, Daddy.
Thank goodness for that.
I say, old man, you are
watching the time, aren't you?
Oh, yes, now, we're
off for a special showing
of the ballet with the other delegates.
Now, we'll take you next
time if you're good, right?
Yes, Daddy.
Right.
Cheerio.
Oh, dear.
Hey, what's this?
Got the golden head.
Planting it on Palmer,
then telling police.
Don't contact police till we're ready.
If you do, it will spoil everything.
Do you really think they have the head?
I don't know.
Crazy kids, they imagine
anything, specially Milly.
Well, we'll just have to wait.
Excuse me, please.
What do you want?
We have something to
leave for Mr. Palmer.
He's a friend of my father's.
Palmer?
Oh, yes, he's in room 244.
He's at dinner now.
If you want to see him,
you'll have to wait a while.
Just a minute.
It's locked, what can we do?
Do you speak English?
A little.
We have a present for Mr. Palmer.
Do you think we could leave it?
Yes.
Thank you.
Keep watch on the door while I try
and find a good hiding place.
Someone's coming!
It's those other two!
But I haven't hidden the head yet!
Under the bed!
Good work, Milly, but Palmer
will only let them out again.
Well, I had to do something.
Either making these key holes
lower or I'm gettin' taller.
Hey!
There's a picture of Palmer here.
Anna, what does this say?
They won a lot of
money at the racetrack.
He's staying at the Gellert Hotel.
Anna, did you buy that paper?
No.
Well, then the kids must have done it,
and they know Palmer's
at the Gellert Hotel.
Come on.
What time should I set it for?
Oh, about 3:30.
AM or PM?
Either one.
Why can't we sleep with our clothes off?
He travels fastest who travels dressed.
That's beautiful.
Did a great man say that?
Yes, I did.
Basil, don't think that I'm not grateful
to learn these beautiful
things and to learn a trade,
but when we come to a
very nice hotel like this,
I don't like to sneak in.
Why can't I be registered?
It's just a simple matter of economics.
Other men my age have
wives and children, a home.
It isn't as though
you're not living anywhere.
You're living with me.
Then why can't I be registered?
It's too expensive.
You always charge me.
I never charge you the full rate.
That's right, you don't ever.
I'm sorry I mentioned it.
Goodnight, Basil.
Goodnight, Lionel.
Hey, hey, hey!
I beg your pardon.
I'm so sorry.
Excuse me.
I beg your pardon.
I'm so sorry.
It's the continental exchange, old man.
They want to know if you'll
accept a call at midnight.
Who from, the Yard?
Yes, old man.
Wonder what it's about.
Something about a photograph
of an Englishman here.
Oh, no!
Why, did we send it?
No, but I have a
pretty good idea who did.
I'll take the call from my hotel.
Are you joking, at midnight?
But I'm taking you out to
the Budapest Bar after this!
- Oh, no, no.
- My dear fellow,
it's the hottest place in town!
- I really can't.
- Of course you can.
It's absolutely jumping!
- Is it?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh.
All right, I'll take the call from there.
Oh, yes, of course, yes, yes.
Hello?
Excuse me, do you have
a Mr. Palmer staying here?
Yes, sir, but at this hour,
I wouldn't like to bother him.
He went up to his room
at least two hours ago.
Have any children been up to see them?
Yes, but that was a long time ago.
They wanted to leave something.
I'm sorry, but this is urgent.
Would you ask Mr. Palmer if he's seen
a couple of children this evening?
He won't like being
disturbed at this hour.
Please.
What the devil do you
mean by disturbing me
at this time of night?
Are there any
children up there with you?
Children?
Don't be absurd, where would I have them,
under the bed or the closet or something?
I shall have a word to say about this
to the manager tomorrow.
- Basil!
- Yeah?
You remember what you were telling me
about here in Hungary,
the people take the hot showers together?
Yes?
Well, can't you arrange one for me
before we get outta here?
Oh, there won't be time, Lionel.
But never mind, you can
have a fine hot bath
when we get to Japan.
In Japan?
Mm-hmm.
Apart from forcing an entry,
I don't know what else we can do.
Where on Earth are they?
Let's find your father.
We can try.
Your London call, Mr. Stevenson.
Hmm?
Hello?
Oh, hello, sir.
Yes, fine, fine.
What?
Oh, yes, I wanted to apologize about that.
What are you talking about?
I should apologize for being so late.
I've been trying to get you all night.
Quite brilliant of you, you know,
to recognize Palmer's technique.
You can bet your bottom dollar
he's got that Hungarian whatsit.
Clever idea, getting that picture.
Bright kids you got there, eh?
Uh, yes.
Yeah, well, you give them
a pat on the head from me.
I hope you get your man.
Bet the Hungarians are
pleased with you, eh?
Well, that's all, I just
wanted to let you know
that we're proud of you.
Goodbye.
Braithwaite, Braithwaite!
Braithwaite!
You know that fellow
the kids were on about?
Well, he's a criminal.
He's probably stolen
that golden head thing.
Impossible, he's English!
Well, let's face it, old man,
if there weren't some English crooks,
I'd be out of business.
Old man.
There's only one thing we must do.
We must nab him ourselves,
then hand him over to
the Hungarians, right?
- Right.
- Let's go.
Oh, just a second, seems
I've forgotten something.
What?
Oh, doesn't matter.
They said he's
he went to the theater,
and up till now, he hasn't come back yet.
He must be working late.
We must go to the police and inform them
that the children are missing.
I'm afraid so.
We'd better get back to the boat
and wait in case they're found.
All right.
Hurry up.
Tell me which room the children were in!
What children?
We've never been out so
early in the morning before.
Ah, he'll tell us how to
get to the police station.
Mister!
We know who's stolen the golden head,
and we want you to arrest him.
I guess he doesn't
understand plain English.
Hi, Dad.
Where are the children?
They're lost.
Not playing detective again!
I'm afraid so.
We've told the police.
Yes, that man Palmer you were on about,
he's a crook, you know?
Scotland Yard's identified his photograph.
That's wonderful, but
what about the children?
Yes, the truth is they've
gone off to Palmer alone.
What?
They left a note.
He's staying at the Gellert.
The Gellert, right, come on, after them.
Oh, dear.
Well, how'd you like that?
After all we've been through,
they go and arrest him by themselves.
Come on, let's get a taxi.
Which room is Mr. Palmer in, please?
244,
- but don't you disturb him!
- Room 244.
Ah, here we are.
Now, both together, Braithwaite.
One, two...
Now, come along, Palmer.
We're handing you over to
the Hungarian authorities.
Have I had the pleasure?
Stevenson of Scotland Yard,
and this is Mr. Braithwaite.
You're under arrest.
And what is the charge?
Stealing the golden head of St. Laszlo,
which appears to be lying on the bed.
Don't try anything, Palmer.
We've both of us played rugby football.
Ah, but have you ever
played it in a snowstorm?
What?
Snowstorm.
You know, as a matter of fact, I have.
It was the winter of '38,
I remember it very well.
It was a grizzly day.
We were playing against Richmond,
I was playing for at the time,
and I came out of the scrimmage...
- 1938, you say?
- Yes, '38.
Anyway, I got on.
Milly!
Oh, you naughty, naughty children!
What have you been doing?
We were so worried about you.
You shouldn't have been
worried, we were all right.
I ought to bang your heads together!
But we planted the head on Palmer.
We just brought the police.
We must find Daddy.
Dad's here, he got here
before the police did.
Well, let's go and help.
Okay, but I still think Dad's
got everything under control.
Palmer!
There he is!
There's the right way
now, come on, let's get out.
Mr. Stevenson!
Looks like you're in a snowstorm.
Oh, thank heaven you're here.
Palmer just got away with the head.
I understand Scotland Yard
recognized the photographs.
Congratulations.
Oh, it's just routine stuff.
There they are, and the children.
After them.
Come on, Milly, come on!
Back to the car.
And for heaven's sake, all
of you, just stay here.
Just stay here till I
come back and get you.
Oh, there's my friend.
Who is he?
Oh, he's all right, come on.
This is beautiful!
When we sell the head, why
don't we get one of these?
Well, I prefer a convertible.
Oh, well...
Come on now, let's get out here.
Oh, no, really!
Come on, come on, get
the train, get the train!
Come on!
There they are!
Come on, after them!
Well, you wanted to see the city.
Now take a good look.
We can catch them on the
side of the river.
Come on, back in the car, come on!
Oh, that's all we need!
Get on with it!
Back in the car.
Shut up!
Gentlemen, I have the most
wonderful news for you.
We have recovered the
golden head of St. Laszlo.
That's him, you might
as well give up now.
Oh, pay no attention, Lionel.
I take it that there is a reward
for the return of this priceless...
You can't do that!
Palmer, you're under arrest.
Oh.
Gentlemen, I think you should know
that without this young girl's help,
we should never have got
our golden head back again.
It was nothing.
Gentlemen, do not allow
yourselves to be swayed
by deceptive appearances.
I can explain everything.
You've got as much chance
talking us out of this
as you got at talking us
into Buckingham Palace.
Her Majesty has graciously
consented to receive you.
If you will come this way.
Daddy, that's Palmer.
Milly!
I, I should know.
Milly, for heaven's sake,
don't start that nonsense again.
Inspector Stevenson and his
daughter, Millicent, ma'am.
Ma'am, that man out there
is a well-known crook,
Basil Palmer.
Milly, for heaven's sake!
Lionel.
Yeah?
Time we started traveling again.
Wonderful, Japan will be
lovely this time of year.