This is the story of a woman after a war...
who lived and hoped...
and struggled trough the anxious years,
and now saw them end...
and another peace begin...
It starts in London on VE Day, 1945.
'This was the day
that it started.
'I wish I'd been with
my wife that day,
'but I was not in London.
'It was a very special day,
meaningful in more
than one respect.
'Later, when Kay had told me
how it all began,
'I felt how strange it was
'that after we'd been together
through so much,
'sharing so many moments
of happiness,
'danger, war and pain,
'she should have been
all alone that day.
'I'd like to tell you something
about her, if I may.
'I say something because
I don't know it all,
'and I'm her husband.
'I've been her husband
for quite a long time.
'But does any man know
any woman completely?
'You meet somebody, you fall
in love with her, you marry her.
'You come to need her
more and more,
'to love her more, too.
'And when you're not with her,
you long for her
with all your heart.
'I hadn't seen my wife
for almost a year,
'but she'd been writing
regularly, so I knew
that she was well.
'This is her story,
Kay's story.
'Oh, and by the way,
our name is Miniver.
'Our family was scattered
around the globe.
'We hadn't seen each other
for years.
'Judy, our daughter,
was in Cairo.
'Our young son Toby
was in America,
'and I was with the Army
in Hamburg.'
This is London.
Please stand by.
The Prime Minister,
the Right Honourable
Winston Churchill.
Yesterday morning,
At 2.41am,
at General Eisenhower's
headquarters,
General Jodl, the representative
of the German high command,
and Grand Admiral Doenitz,
the designated head
of the German state,
signed the act
of unconditional surrender
of all German land, sea,
and air forces in Europe
to the Allied
Expeditionary Force.
The German war is, therefore,
at an end.
Advance, Britannia!
Long live the cause of freedom!
God save the King!
Mrs Miniver.
You don't
remember me?
Yes, I-I do.
Oh, you're Foley's boy!
Tom Foley,
of course!
I'm so sorry, Tom,
but after five years...
Six since I last
delivered
the groceries.
Are you on leave?
Just flew in
from Cairo.
Oh, what a day
to come home!
I'm so happy for you.
Does your family know?
Dad will be
at the station.
Good.
Here, have half
a suitcase.
Thank you.
Well, how are they,
Mum and Dad?
Oh, very good.
How's the shop?
Still there.
You had doodlebugs,
didn't you,
all around
the village?
Uh-huh. But it's
over now.
Yes.
How was Cairo?
Oh, hot as blazes.
My daughter's over there,
Judy, in the ATS.
I don't suppose
you ran into her?
She saw me off.
Tom! Well!
How is she?
Judy's wonderful.
Still a corporal?
She's far too nice
to be a brass hat.
We, um, we saw
quite a lot
of each other.
I'm glad.
It's a bit tricky,
though,
because of my
three pips.
Officers not encouraged
to mingle with
the unwashed.
However...
I haven't heard from her
for ages.
Now I
understand why.
Oh, she...she
sent this.
For me?
Oh! That's a nice change.
Tom, will you forgive
me if I...?
Of course.
Go ahead. I'll smoke.
"Hello, Mother, darling.
"Tom Foley's just leaving
for home,
"so I'm dashing this off in a mad
rush in the middle of the night
"to let you know all's well
on the Nile.
"The lights are out,
and the girls are asleep,
"so I'm writing on my knee
in the bathroom.
"Who do you think I've
been driving around
for the last month?
"Steve Brunswick.
"Wherever he goes, I take him
and bring him back.
"It's wonderful to be
with a man who's really lived
life to the dregs."
All serene?
Yes.
Tom, do you know a man
called Brunswick?
A brigadier?
Brunswick...
Oh, Steve Brunswick.
Commando Johnny?
Good heavens, yes, he's
a marvellous chap. Why?
Oh, Judy mentions him.
He's out there now.
Careless talk.
She ought to be shot.
That's what she says.
Anything like her?
Tom, it's splendid!
Are you always
as good as this?
I happen to know this
particular subject
rather well.
I hope to know her
even better.
I'm so glad you
were at the station,
Mr Foley.
I just couldn't
have walked
another step today.
Takes it out of you,
doesn't it,
all this history?
Thank you so much.
All alone
here tonight?
Oh, no, I have
my boarders,
Mr Farraday
and Richard.
Oh, yes, well,
Mr Miniver will be
home before long
now, I reckon.
I hope so.
I'm delighted
Tom's back.
Tell Mrs Foley,
will you?
I'll tell her.
I like your boy.
Good night.
Good night, Mrs M.
All the best.
Thanks, Tom.
Oh, could I...could I
have Judy back?
Oh...yes.
Good night.
Thank you, Mrs Miniver.
Anybody home?
Spike!
I'll be back
in a minute.
Hi!
I just thought
I'd drop by
and say
congratulations.
Well, thank you.
Have I won anything?
Only a war.
From here in, Kay,
you're a veteran.
You, too, Colonel.
Well, that puts me
in nice company.
Let's shake on it.
We might even have
a cup of tea on it.
Come inside.
I'm due back at the
base right now.
But I was hoping
you might care
to look in at the
George with me later.
I guess most of the
village will be there.
Kind of
a farewell visit.
Farewell?
We're pulling out
Sunday.
Oh, no, Spike.
Oh, I am sorry.
I did want you
and Clem to meet.
I know.
I sort of, er,
wanted to say hello
to that husband
of yours myself.
He must be
quite a guy.
Will you come?
Please.
I'd love to.
Swell. Pick you
up at 8.30.
We're going to
miss you in the village.
We're going to miss
the village.
Somehow, I just can't
believe that it's over.
It isn't.
Sure, some of the
fighting's stopped.
A few generals have
signed some documents
on Lueneburg Heath.
For the rest of us,
you can't just snap
your fingers and say,
"Forget it, brother.
Go on home.
"Take up the old
routine where you
left off."
When a war happens,
a whole new life happens
along with it.
And you're a part
of mine, Kay...
a very important part.
Well, I know we haven't
seen each other
more than...how often?
A dozen times?
Tea in the garden
after a mission,
a couple of movies,
watching a soccer match.
Probably it doesn't mean
very much to you,
but it's helped,
more than you know.
I didn't stop
loving Ellen
when I started
to love you.
Dear Kay, don't look
so worried.
I'm not expecting
you to say anything
except maybe
"Here's a guy I knew
in the war.
"Nice to have met him."
I know it's all
on my side.
You're married.
You too, Spike.
Only I'm here,
and Ellen's there.
Sort of a mess
I'm in, all right.
Oh, you'll snap
out of it.
Very un-British,
shooting my mouth off.
Only, this is
our last evening.
And I just had
to tell you.
You're not mad
at me?
No, Spike, I'm not mad.
It's...it's nice to know
that one's been of use,
if I have.
Let's dance.
My friends!
Tonight, Europe is free!
To the British
I say, "Jolly decent of you!"
To the Americans,
"Nice work, kids!"
To my own country, I say
"God bless you."
Very soon now, I return to
you and to my dear wife
and children.
Don't worry, darling.
Not tonight.
And so to all of you,
to all the people and armies
of liberation,
on behalf of all Europe,
tonight, I say...
Wait a minute!
Won't you say
something, Colonel?
Please?
Well, this isn't
quite my line.
You go ahead.
Oh, no.
Come on, Spike.
Do it. It would be nice.
OK.
Thanks, pal.
American...
here.
I guess some of us
will be leaving soon.
So, maybe I'd better make
this goodbye.
When we first came
to England,
we weren't too keen
about the idea.
"It's murder,"
they told us.
"Rains all day, and the folks
keep themselves to themselves."
Well, it rained.
They were right there.
We've had bad times
and good times.
We've had an awful lot
of war together.
So long, England.
Thanks for everything.
And have yourselves
a good rest.
For he's a jolly good fellow
He's a jolly good fellow
And so say all of us.
'It was a beautiful summer,
'that first summer of peace.
'England had a new kind
of government,
'the world had a new kind
of a bomb,
'and the weather was perfect
day after day.
'It was as if God were saying,
' "This is what life could be like
if only you'd let it."
'It was still a beautiful summer
when I said goodbye to Europe.
'The weather was perfect.
'Two hours later, we were home.
'I was the last of the family
to come home.
'Judy had just returned
from Cairo,
'Toby, from America.
'At long last, the four of us
were home.
'And I was looking forward to
a holiday of rest and happiness
'with Kay and the children.'
How long has this
been going on?
About 12 months.
About 12 months?
There's one up
in Toby's room, too.
Is that so?
And another
in the kitchen,
but that's over the sink,
so that doesn't matter.
Nothing matters.
You're home.
It's about time.
Yes.
Listen to that, Dad!
Mary Lou gave me
a dozen records
the day I left
the States.
Let's get this
coat off.
Who's Mary Lou?
My girl!
She's super!
Super?
Yes! She cuts about
the meanest rug
in Morgan Falls.
Oh, she does?
Yeah, we were going steady
until peace came
and wrecked everything.
Mary Lou's 10.
Oh, she'll be 11
in March.
Well, that's different.
Sorry, Dad.
That's mine.
What is it?
Baseball.
No, no, not like that.
Let me show you.
Batter up!
What?
Home run!
Home run?
Yeah!
All right,
I'll answer it.
It's for me.
Hello, Steve.
I'm sorry.
I can't hear.
Who?
Oh, it's you.
Toby. Teddy Fathergill.
Excuse me, Dad.
She was easier to understand
when she was younger.
< So were you.
Hiya, Teddy.
Yes, we just brought
Dad home.
No, I can't make it
tonight.
I told you.
My father.
Back from the war
and all that.
I have to stand by
and look happy.
OK, bye, Teddy.
Who is, um...
Who's Teddy?
He's a friend of mine.
Teddy Fathergill.
He's English, of course.
Ah, that's too bad.
Say, Dad. You look
kind of lost.
Why don't you give
the body a break
and go dunk yourself
in the drink?
Uh...drink?
I mean, take a nice
plunge in the dipper
and have yourself
a rubdown.
Well, thank you, Toby.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
I say, Dad! Will you get
a load of that horn!
Batter...
Batter up.
Everything all right,
darling?
Fine, fine. I'm about to dunk
myself in the drink,
get a load of a rubdown,
and have myself a fine dip
in the plunger.
I may also cut a few
carpets if I have time.
Oh, and by the way,
I just made a home run.
Dee dee da something
something something something
Goes in there
Then the lights go on
again...
Come in.
Feeling better?
I feel fine, wonderful,
magnificent. Don't I look it?
You look sweet.
Thank you. >
So do you.
Come here
a minute.
Gosh, that's
frightening.
What is?
You...grown up.
And really quite
lovely, if I may
say so.
You may say so.
Oh, it's wonderful to have
you back again!
It's good to be back.
Believe me.
Hand me my socks
there, will you?
Well, young lady,
how's everything?
How many hearts have
you broken already?
I don't know why
it's a shock
to discover you have
a beautiful daughter,
but it is.
You know, when you
were, oh,
six months old,
you were the ugliest
thing I've ever seen
in my life.
Yes, you were.
You took after me
then.
Whereas now you
take after your mother.
Ah, yes, you do.
I can see we're going
to have a lot of trouble
with you.
Father?
Can we talk?
Just for a minute.
Seriously, I mean.
Alone.
Oh, well, I think that
might be arranged.
I'm afraid I'm going
to shock you again,
and this time, I don't
think you'll like it.
I want you to know
right away.
There's no secret
about it.
Mother knows,
but I'd rather you
heard it from me.
Father, you know
Steve Brunswick,
don't you?
Well, I...I don't
know him.
I've heard of him,
of course. Why?
I'm in love
with him.
He's a little old
for you, isn't he, darling?
38, but that
doesn't matter.
I mean, if that
was all...
He understands me,
and I think I
understand him.
Is that so difficult?
Yes, it is, rather.
We met in Cairo
at the end of the war.
He's home now.
We've seen each other
several times.
Is he in love
with you?
I don't know yet.
I think so.
I hope so.
Well, then, everything
seems to be
more or less satisfactory,
as far as it goes.
No, it isn't.
You see, he's married.
He has been for 12 years.
His wife is Pamela Lyndon,
you know, the pianist.
She's awfully nice,
I believe.
They used to have
dreadful rows,
but that was Steve's fault.
At least, he said so.
It's probably true.
And then he met me.
We have rows, too,
but I don't mind it.
He's like that,
you know, temperamental.
I love him so terribly.
I-I thought it was
just the war,
and I'd get over it,
but it wasn't and I...
I haven't.
And now, it's worse
than ever.
And I...
Thanks.
I suppose I should
tell you
all the wise and sensible
things a father's supposed
to have up his sleeve
for these occasions,
but I'm not sure
that I know them.
And I'm not so sure
they'd help very much.
Would they, huh?
I'm awfully sorry.
Food!
Life's quite a business,
isn't it, then?
Uh...all right?
Very nice, darling.
A little tight
around the middle.
I seem
to have grown.
You know this is
the first time
we've all been together
since 1940?
Yes, it is.
Why, it's quite
an occasion, isn't it?
Shall I make a speech?
No? Well, all right,
all right.
All together, huh?
Sorry, darling, what
were you going to say?
Nothing. This soup,
good stuff.
You haven't lost
your touch.
Bits and pieces
from yesterday.
Rather appropriate.
Dad?
Huh?
Have you got
any souvenirs?
What of exactly,
Toby?
You know, Europe.
Scars of battle.
Mary Lou's father
was on Guadalcanal.
Killed four Japs
in 20 minutes.
Brought home a Samurai sword
he stripped off one
of the corpses.
Toby!
That's the kind they use
to commit hara-kiri.
Push the hilt of the sword
in the ground
and jam your belly
hard on the blade.
Works like thunder.
Splits their gizzards
from top to bottom.
Like this.
Oh, Toby, shut up.
We'll all be sick.
Been like this
for days.
America was
a bad mistake.
Will you do me
a favour? Collapse.
Toby, darling,
would you do
something for me?
Of course, Mother.
Anything.
Forget about those
48 states for 24 hours
and try and make do
with your unfortunate family.
I'll go!
You know, Toby,
I'm afraid I'm going
to prove a grave
disappointment to you.
No medals, no trophies,
no scars.
I've still got both arms
and both legs.
My eyes are a bit
groggy,
and I'm afraid I'm
going to need glasses.
But that's the best
I can do for you.
As a homecoming warrior,
I'm a complete washout.
You're OK, Dad.
You went to Dunkirk.
It's Steve!
He's at the Majestic
in Roxbury.
He's asked me over
for dinner.
Darling, would you think
it simply dreadful if...?
Oh, no, Judy.
Not tonight.
I know it's awful,
but I won't be late.
And I haven't seen him
for 10 days.
Oh, it's not that, it's...
As a matter
of fact,
I'd be rather glad
to get rid of the brat.
Then I could have you
to myself.
All right, Judy.
She's all mixed up.
Can't eat, can't sleep,
can't do anything.
I was like that with Mary Lou
the first two weeks,
but we came through OK.
You just have to adjust.
Yeah.
Gosh! If you really mean
that about being alone,
I guess I'll go and see
Teddy Fathergill.
He's all mixed up, too.
Really?
His dad's a socialist.
Gotta straighten him out.
Go right ahead,
Toby, and leave
the old folks at home.
OK.
Goodbye, boy.
Bye!
Bye.
Hello, darling.
'I remember
that evening for lots
of reasons.
'The homecoming, the way
Kay looked, the kids.
'After they'd gone, we cleared
the meal away and went out.
'The rain had stopped,
and there was that strange light
over everything
'that comes so often in England
at the end of summer,
'when it's a little too early
to put on the lamps
'and a little too late to see
everything clearly and true.
'We made a sentimental journey
around the garden.
'It was good to be alone...
and together.
'This is Kay's story, not mine,
'but I have to tell that evening
through my eyes, not hers.
'I don't think there's
very much difference.
'It was full of all kinds
of memories, gay and grim.
'Extraordinary, the wide swing
from the fear and terror
of those nights in the shelter
'to the utter peace of the river
that night I came home.
'It was good to see
the old lady once more.
'She was beyond repair,
and we never used her again.
'We couldn't afford it,
and we hadn't the petrol.
'But she, too, was full of
memories for both of us.'
No petrol.
I wonder if...
I seem to remember
that there was a...
Huh?
Yes.
There might be
a drop in it.
Yeah, good.
Five years old,
that stuff.
Dunkirk spirit.
Still works.
Let's hope so.
Hello, sir.
Hello, Captain.
I heard you were
back, sir,
so I thought I'd just
drop by and say welcome home.
Thank you,
Captain.
Who is it?
Foley's boy.
Thank you, Tom.
Thank you
very much.
Delighted to see you.
We've, er, just been
to Dunkirk.
Come aboard, Tom.
Oh, thank you.
Well, Tom Foley.
When did you get back?
VE Day, sir.
Hm, lucky fellow.
Have a good war?
Oh, fair to middling,
you know, sir.
Am, uh...Europe?
No, sir.
Desert mostly.
Cairo and the Middle East.
Cairo?
Well, our girl,
Judy, was out there
with the ATS.
I don't suppose you
saw anything of her?
Well, funnily enough, sir,
I did bump into her.
Did you hear that,
darling?
Tom Foley here met
Judy out in Cairo.
Well, well! You must
come over and say
hello to her sometime.
She's home now,
you know.
Yes, yes, I know, sir.
I'm afraid she's out
for the evening, Tom.
Oh, really?
Well, goodbye, sir,
and it's really great
having you back.
Thank you, Tom.
Thank you very
much indeed!
I'll tell Judy
I saw you.
Oh, don't bother.
I just dropped by
to say hello to Mr Miniver,
that's all.
Goodbye!
Goodbye, Tom Foley.
You know that I've
hardly said two words
to that boy in my life,
and yet he takes
the trouble
to ride over here
this evening
simply to welcome
me home?
I call that
extraordinarily decent
of him, don't you?
Yes, dear, I do.
There's some days
you don't like to see go.
I'd like to put
the clock back and have
this one all over again.
The rain...
roof leaking...
everything.
Yes, it's been
a lovely day.
Judy's not home yet.
Still striking.
Give Cinderella
till the last chime.
There she is now.
Worried about her?
Yes...aren't you?
Yes.
I could talk to her.
I tried.
I don't think you can
talk someone out of love.
What are we going
to do about it?
Wait, I think.
Of course,
we could ask Toby to
straighten her out.
I wish she'd find
someone like you.
Well, that's
a tall order,
rather like
reaching for the moon.
I'm in.
Good night, darlings!
Judy? Did you have
a good time?
You don't have
a good time with Steve.
He's not like that.
What is he like?
Different.
Good night, Father.
Apparently that's
the technique these days.
In order to be a success
with the modern girl,
you have to be different.
Uh...was I different when
you married me, darling?
You were unique.
Unique?
Unique...
Of course it's nice
to see you again, darling.
But...the real joy
of coming home
is to be able to stand
in your own bathroom once more.
Brush your own teeth
in your own hot water!
Don't know
how lucky you are!
Hot water, soap...
all the delights
of civilization,
right at your fingertips.
If I could have...found
a bathroom like this,
I probably never would have
come home at all.
Ahh, that was wonderful.
It's funny the pleasure
you can get out of a simple...
Kay?
What is it?
Darling, you're...
you're so pale.
Am I?
It's...light...
What's this?
Well, it's...just...
it's something for
when you feel faint.
Feel faint?
Don't look
so worried, darling.
But I am worried.
I'm scared stiff!
It's...it's all right.
I just get a little...
dizzy spell now and then.
When it happens, then I...
take two of these little things,
and...I feel fine.
You mean you've
had this sort
of thing before?
Occasionally,
not for ages.
But why didn't
you tell me?
Darling, it's just
a giddy turn.
Had to happen tonight.
Haven't had one
for months.
It's your fault...
coming home,
getting me all excited.
Now, do you...really
feel all right now?
Of course, darling.
Now don't make a fuss,
there's a dear.
You frightened
the life out of me.
Oh, poor darling.
High time I got
home. You've been
overdoing it.
Oh, don't be
an old woman.
I'm not.
But I'd like you
to be, one day.
Don't rush me.
Anything else
you haven't told me?
Any lovers tucked away
that I don't know about?
Dozens.
Just what I thought.
And you?
Hundreds.
Dotted all over Europe,
from Normandy
to the Rhine.
They're going to be
lonely tonight.
Nice talk,
Mrs Miniver.
Stop a minute,
darlings.
I wonder,
is the doctor in?
Yes, but have you
an appointment?
No, not today, but
I did rather want
to see him for a second
if he could squeeze me in.
Well, I'm not sure.
Is it urgent?
Not urgent, but,
well, important.
I wouldn't be more
than five minutes.
Come in, won't you?
I'm Mrs Kanesley,
and you're...?
Mrs Miniver.
Oh, yes.
Harry's really not
seeing anyone today.
It's my birthday.
Oh. Oh, I am sorry.
Not that it's your birthday,
but for disturbing you.
Doctors' wives see
so little of their
husbands, don't they?
We get used to it.
The children.
A children's party!
Oh, I couldn't spoil that.
Don't bother, I'll go.
I'll get it!
Mrs Miniver, hello!
I'm so sorry about all this.
Come in, won't you?
Thank you.
Let's see...you don't know
my three offspring, do you?
The others
are on loan.
Hello, where
is everybody?
Hello, come here, come on,
come and say hello.
Now, this is Michael.
Hello.
How do you do,
Michael?
That is Susan.
Hello.
How do you do,
Susan?
And that is Joanie.
How do you do,
Joanie?
She only
does that if
she likes you.
All right,
darling,
that'll do.
You run away
and play with yourself.
Fall out, you two.
How about
a cup of tea?
Oh, no, thank you.
I really do feel
horribly guilty
intruding like this
on your one day off.
Nonsense. One of
the few women I'd get up for
in the middle of the night.
I see what
he means.
Why haven't
we met before?
I've never been
ill before.
Oh, are you?
I'm sorry. You
look splendid.
Let's go in here,
shall we?
Just for five minutes.
How lovely the park
looks today, doesn't it?
Yes, autumn.
Strange melancholy
time of year.
Do you think so?
I rather like it.
I've been sitting outside
there under the trees
for the last half hour,
watching the leaves fall
and trying to screw up enough
courage to come in and see you.
Why, was it
so difficult?
You don't smoke,
do you?
No, thank you.
Yes, it was...very.
I had no idea coming
to see the doctor could
be such an adventure.
Oh, it is always...
especially today.
Today?
Oh! Today I'm less
alarming than ever.
Do you like wildflowers?
They're rather a hobby
of mine.
Limonium vulgare,
what we call
sea lavender.
Charming name,
isn't it?
You know, flowers get
called after all sorts
of things,
where they're found,
people who find them.
It's fascinating
sometimes.
Rosa canina,
wild rose.
Rose...
Once a few years ago,
someone...
Oh, nothing...memories.
Tell me, please.
Not just now.
You're going to
tell me something.
Something I want to know.
You are, aren't you?
Well, that rather
depends what it is.
You know what it is.
How long have I got?
Please.
It's all right,
I want to know.
I realise you're not
supposed to tell me.
It's...bad
for the patient.
Professional ethics,
and all sorts
of reasons.
A few months ago, when
you first hinted that
it might be serious,
I...I was glad of them.
I preferred to
clutch at straws,
and pretend to myself.
But I've changed my mind.
It's a woman's
privilege.
Well...I'm right,
aren't I?
Is your husband back?
Yes, two days ago,
and the children.
That's the chief reason
I'm here today, the family.
There's so much to do,
and there's just...
so much time to do it in.
And so I...
I want to know how much.
Please.
You're not afraid,
are you?
I'm not sure.
I mind, of course.
I love my husband
very much.
He's going to miss me
dreadfully.
That sounds vain and conceited,
but it isn't, really.
It's been rather
a perfect marriage.
No, I don't think
I'm afraid.
One's become accustomed to...
to death these last few years.
So many went, the young ones.
It's a tragedy
when the young ones go.
An older person getting
an illness that can't be cured...
well, that's just bad luck.
I say rather
that's it's a pity.
I'm not sorry for myself,
and honestly,
I don't want anyone else
to be sorry for me.
Does your
husband know?
Not yet.
Well, I think
he should.
I'll tell him...
at the right moment.
How will you know
when that is?
I'll know.
Now, be a nice man
and tell me...
how long?
Not less than six months,
not more than a year.
Thank you.
Sorry, that was hard,
wasn't it?
Look. I'm the doctor,
you're the patient,
you remember?
I'll try.
10 out of 10
for you.
What's that?
Full marks.
Hello, darling.
Busy?
No, come in.
I didn't know
you were in town today.
I've been shopping.
Quite suddenly I...
I thought I'd like you
to take me home.
When you're ready, I mean.
There's no hurry.
I shan't be two minutes.
No hurry.
What is it?
You've changed.
Changed?
Yes. Since
this morning.
Something's different. You, er...
Oh, yes...
it's the hat. New, isn't it?
Like it?
Very becoming.
You do look nice.
It's the first new one
I've had for five...no, six years.
Why today suddenly?
I don't know...
just felt like it.
Sometimes a new hat
does something for you.
I know.
Only this morning,
I was saying
to myself,
"Miniver," I said, "Why
don't you buy yourself
a new bowler?
"Might do something
for you."
You had a good day?
Oh, so-so.
Somehow the prospect of
starting in again on my own
isn't wildly exciting.
You might take
an apprentice.
Do you know of any
good young draftsmen
hanging about?
Foley's boy draws very well.
I saw some sketches
he did of Judy,
and they were excellent.
He's a nice boy,
too, Clem.
I rather wish
that Judy would...
Do you like nuts?
Yes...
Yes, I like nuts.
"We in Brazil have
in mind a certain
building project
"along modern
European lines,
"and our minister
of highways and
civil construction,
"Senor Jose
Antonio Campos,
"will be visiting Europe
shortly to discuss
this project.
"Tenders will be invited
from the most vigorous
"and enterprising
architects of the day."
I've just
written to him.
Oh.
Aren't I vigorous
and enterprising?
Yes, darling.
Wouldn't you like to go
and live in Brazil?
What?
Wouldn't you like
to get out and away
from all this,
miles away, where
the sun shines
and there aren't
any ruins on
your doorstep?
Kay...
I can't tell you
what it was like
going across Europe.
Through one country
after another,
the desolation
and the emptiness,
the sense of
utter futility.
It got into me, somehow,
and I just can't seem
to shake it off.
England isn't Europe.
It's too close!
It belongs!
We could take the kids
and clear out.
We still got a good
few years together.
Other people are doing
it. They're making
a fresh start abroad.
What do you say?
It's out of the clear sky.
I...I wasn't expecting it.
You've only
just come home.
I'm thinking
of the future.
That's an old one.
What is it?
Let's dance.
Dance?
Where? When?
Here. Now.
'She meant it.
I didn't know why...
'only that she meant it,
quite seriously.
'As I took her hands,
'I remember thinking
she had changed.
'It wasn't just the hat,
it was Kay.
'There was something...
elusive about her suddenly.
'Something...intangible.
'So, there in the office,
we danced.'
Hell's bells!
Very funny.
Darling, are
you all right?
Maimed for life,
I should think.
There's
a car coming.
Hello.
Breakdown?
Yes, ignition failure.
Coil's gone.
Oh, I'm afraid that's
a garage job. I'll have
a look if you like.
No, it's all right.
I've got help coming.
Tom!
Hello!
Oh, friend of yours?
Yes, sir! Foley,
late captain,
Royal Engineers.
Oh, I'm Brunswick.
Yes, I know, sir. You gave us
a pep talk in Cairo,
before Alamein.
Was I good?
Well, you were
short, sir.
Oh...pleased to
meet you, Foley.
Demobbed?
Yes, sir. I got
out under class C.
Lucky blighter.
Wouldn't have a cigarette
on you, would you?
I think so.
Where are you off to
at this ungodly hour?
Oh, it's market day.
Dad keeps the grocery
shop in Belham.
Belham?
Steve, do get in.
You'll catch cold!
Is your van full up?
How do you mean?
Be a good chap
and give Miss Miniver
a ride home.
Surely.
No, Steve,
I'm staying with you.
You'll do as you're told.
You're with the Army
now...right?
Right!
I've got a pig on board,
but there's room for one more.
Out you come.
Steve, please
let me stay.
I'd much rather.
Shut up.
You'll freeze.
Shut up!
Please, Steve,
please.
Do as you're told
and don't argue.
It's a man's world
and you won't
accept it.
Don't you agree,
Captain?
Oh, yes, sir,
absolutely.
Come on, then.
If she makes any
trouble, wallop her.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Steve, when
will I see you?
Oh, your
cigarettes.
Oh, keep 'em, sir.
Thank you, Captain.
You'd be a major
for this if the war
weren't over.
I'll see what I can do
for you in the next one!
Go away!
Where on earth did
you get that thing?
He's not a thing.
He's a noble beast.
Aren't you, George?
He smells.
Is he yours?
No.
All right,
George. Go on.
No, I'm collecting
him for the Nesbits.
He's a breeder.
Have you
known him long?
Who?
Brigadier Brunswick.
He's a general.
OK, General Brunswick.
Have you?
Yes.
How long?
Ages.
Like him?
He's a wonderful
person.
In war or peace?
Both!
Does he, er,
dance well?
He does
everything well.
That's why I've
seen nothing of you
since Cairo.
You've seen me.
At the shop in the queue
a couple of times.
You can't make love
to a girl in a queue.
Well, don't
look so shocked.
I used to, quite a bit,
in the Middle East.
When you were just
a dumb little corporal
with a couple
of stripes.
Yes, and you didn't
mind it, either.
In fact, you liked it,
didn't you?
Yes, Tom, I did.
I liked it.
Well?
Well, it's
different now.
I'm not.
Well, I'm not
either, really,
only I...
Oh, what's the use?
Ha ha ha! You are
miserable, are you?
No, I'm not.
I'm wildly,
wildly happy,
and I'm going
on being happy
with Steve
and I don't care
what anyone thinks.
No-one thinks
anything, do they?
I don't.
Just wondered why
I hadn't seen you,
that's all.
I like you.
I think you're
a fool, mind,
but I like you.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
Here we are.
Tom...
Yes, Judy?
I...
I just wanted
to say...
..thanks for the lift.
That's all right.
Thanks for coming.
Friends?
Friends.
Other Eden, demi-paradise.
Precious stone
set in a silvery sea.
This blessed plot,
this earth,
this realm,
this England.
What's all that?
Oh, I was just saying
how much I love my country
and the weather.
Winter's all right.
Nice and crisp
and invigorating.
What's wrong
with winter?
Nothing, when
the bath water's hot.
Sorry, darling,
it's only every other
day from now on.
Oh, Clem, these cuffs
will never do.
Shall I turn them?
Come in!
Morning, Mother,
morning, Dad.
Morning, Toby.
Gosh, Dad! That's one
of my handkerchiefs!
That was one of your
handkerchiefs, Toby.
It's now performing
a more important
function.
What's that?
Keeping your father
warm in a vital part
of his anatomy.
What happened,
Dad?
Nothing happened.
If you must know
the sordid details,
my collar was frayed.
Life must go on,
so we operated.
The tail of my shirt
is the tale of England.
Here's the post,
Mother.
There's one for you
from the States.
Can I have the stamp
after you've read it?
Thanks awfully!
You know, darling,
my wardrobe is gradually
becoming nonexistent.
If somebody doesn't
do something about it
pretty soon,
one of these fine days,
well, I'm just going to
disintegrate.
I'm afraid the only
solution is
to enter the black
market in a big way.
Trouble is, I haven't
the faintest idea how
to set about it.
Have you?
Oh, sorry, darling.
Who's it from?
Spike.
Spike?
The American I met
while you were away.
Ah, yes.
I've often wondered
about that.
Have you, dear?
Of course he fell
in love with you.
Of course.
Well,
what's the news
from America?
He sent us a food parcel
about a month ago.
I wonder what's
happened to it.
It takes six weeks.
Oh, oh, oh,
he's accepted.
Senor Jose
Antonio Campos
is coming down
to lunch tomorrow.
Who?
The man from Brazil.
Uh, "Tenders
will be invited from
the most vigorous
"and enterprising
architects of the day."
Don't you remember?
Well, I sent in
a few ideas
and asked him to come
down and feed with us
if he were interested,
and he's coming tomorrow.
You did what?
I asked him
to lunch.
Clem!
Clem, how could you?
You know we haven't
enough of anything.
None of
the plates match,
I have no
cooking fat.
That's just
what he wants.
He asked me to
beg you not to put
on a show for him.
Oh, nonsense.
Listen.
"Please ask your wife
not to make any
specialities for me.
"With the English
today,
"it's an honour to eat
bread and cheese."
We can't possibly have
an important man like that
down to the house
and give him what
we have to eat.
Well, that's
the whole point.
He wants to see
a typical English meal.
Well, he may
want to see it,
he won't want to eat it.
But he does.
Men like that
are used to Brazil,
where they have all
those nuts and things.
He's just being polite.
Clem, really,
it's too bad.
You women are
fantastic.
264, please.
It's the same thing
every time.
A foreigner comes
to England,
having heard tales
of our austerity
and want,
and positively
bursting with sympathy
and understanding,
and the minute he puts
foot in somebody's door,
what happens?
You women start
a conspiracy.
You beg and you borrow,
and you scrape together
a full-size meal!
Don't ask me how
you do it or where
it comes from...
Go away.
All I know is the poor,
unsuspecting visitor
staggers out of
the house,
his stomach bulging
with four people's rations
for a month,
convinced we're
a nation of hypocrites
and not half as
badly off as we
say we are.
I won't sh!
The tale spreads
across the ocean.
Highly delicate
negotiations are
compromised
and the foreign policy
of the country is
seriously undermined
and it's all your fault!
Are you listening to me?
No.
Hello?
Sophie?
Oh, Sophie, I'm awfully
sorry to trouble you,
but Clem has been
perfectly ridiculous
and invited a complete
stranger down for
lunch tomorrow.
So I wondered,
could you possibly...
Er, yes, dear,
some marge and lard,
and er... Oh!
And, er, oh,
yes, yes.
And, er, Sophie...
..the Wedgwood?
Brazil? Do they
play rugger?
We'll ask them
when we get there.
If they don't,
we'll make 'em.
Be swell to get
back to America.
South America.
North, south,
what's
the difference?
The difference
is considerable.
But don't worry
about it
because we shall
probably stay here.
Seems kind of screwy.
I mean, we don't
rate any longer.
We're a vanishing class.
Oh, we are, are we?
Well, who says so?
Teddy Fathergill.
Who?
Oh, oh, yes.
You know,
he's a socialist.
But I thought
you were going to
straighten him out.
Oh, I had
a go at him,
but he
had a go at me, too.
He won.
Bye!
Judy not down yet?
No, she was
rather late in,
so I thought I'd
let her sleep on.
Clem?
Are you serious
about Brazil?
Thinking about it.
Thinking hard.
Be a big chance for you,
wouldn't it?
That's
not the point.
Would you listen
to me for a minute?
I know you can think
of a dozen arguments
for staying put.
So can I,
if I want to.
But there's one
tremendous reason
for clearing out.
You.
Me?
Do you really think
you've been fooling me?
You had quite a war,
Mrs Miniver.
You're having
quite a peace.
Cooking,
washing, scrubbing,
standing in queues,
hunting for rations,
finding the meals,
reading the headlines
and worrying about Judy,
about Toby, about me.
No, Clem...
Will you listen to me
for just a minute?
There are times,
quite a number of times,
when you feel so utterly
and completely tired
that you could sit
down on the stairs
and cry like a child.
It might be quite
an idea to take you out
of the fish queue.
Give you a nice hot
meal cooked by somebody
else for a change.
Sit you out in the sun
for an hour or two.
So it's...it's all
on my account, this idea?
No, it's not.
I told you, I want
to get out of Europe.
And then there's Judy.
Doesn't it occur to you
that to get her away
at this time might
not at all be
a bad notion?
Yes, darling,
I know.
But there's...
I'll go.
Hello?
Uh, yes?
Yes, no, I'm sorry,
I'm afraid
she's not down yet.
Who?
Who is speaking,
please?
Oh, General Brunswick.
Yes, it is.
How do you do?
I've, er, I've heard
a lot about you.
Oh, I'm sorry, that wasn't
meant to sound ominous.
Your coat?
It's quite safe.
Shall I send it to you,
or will you...?
Well, I...I'd like
to meet you.
Uh, well, if you
could wait two days,
I could bring it.
Friday at 12.30?
Well, I'd like that
very much.
All right, I shall
look forward to it.
'A a few days later,
Kay took the 10.40 to London.
'Judy wanted her mother to know
this man who meant so much to her,
'and Kay was
determined to meet him.
'Brunswick lived in Westminster,
only 10 minutes from my office.
'I had offered
to return the coat for her,
'but she was adamant.'
Hell's bells!
Yes?
General Brunswick?
Good grief!
Are you Mrs Miniver?
Kay Miniver, yes.
Good grief.
You're a surprise.
A pleasant one?
Decidedly.
That daughter of
yours never told me.
You're a lot younger
than I thought.
What were you expecting?
Oh, I pictured
something nondescript,
middle-aged.
You're quite a beautiful
woman, in your way.
Not really.
This is one of
my good days.
Here's the coat.
Oh, thanks very much.
I've got foul manners.
What are we standing
here for?
Come in and have
a drink.
Thank you.
I'd like a drink.
Ignore the chaos,
I'm on my way out.
Today?
No, tomorrow.
This is my
wife's flat, really.
She gets back from
Canada Sunday night.
Your wife?
Pamela Lyndon.
Yes, yes, of course.
Do you like good
music or jazz?
Uh, both.
Ever hear her?
I heard your wife
give a Greek concerto
a week before
the war began.
First-class
pianist, Pam.
Magnificent woman
in many ways.
Impossible to live with.
Sherry?
Thank you.
Women are impossible for
the most part, you know?
They get a bee in their
bonnet about something
and they won't
let it drop.
They will go on and on.
I must say,
you don't look as if
you'd go on and on.
But you probably do,
if the truth were known.
I'm worse than most.
Sit down.
Good grief,
you're young to have
a girl like Judy.
I suppose everyone
says that.
Uh, it has been
said before.
But I never tire
of hearing it.
Cheers.
Do you fight a lot
in your family?
Or is
everything placid
and respectable?
Oh, we tear
each other to pieces
all day long
and half the night.
Hasn't Judy told you?
No, she hasn't
said much.
To be honest,
she hasn't had
much chance.
When we're together,
I talk most of the time.
What do you talk about?
Oh, life, love,
the world in general.
The world's in a mess,
did you know that?
I had heard something.
Hmm. You look reasonably
intelligent for a woman.
Why haven't
we met before? >
It wasn't my doing.
You steered clear of us.
Thought it was best,
considering.
You probably hate
my guts, don't you?
I haven't had time
to hate you yet.
You'll get around
to it.
I'm starting
the divorce as soon
as Pam gets back.
Or rather
she's starting it.
She cabled yesterday.
It'll take some time,
of course.
As soon as
it's through,
I'll marry
your daughter.
Probably won't last,
but I'll marry her.
Time.
How much time?
A year, 18 months.
There's a queue
of people waiting
to get separated.
You don't like that,
do you?
You want to see your
chick settled.
Every mother wants that.
But you're in a hurry.
How do you know?
I know women
and I read faces.
It was my job
in the war,
to guess the other
chap's move and beat
him to it.
Why are you in a hurry,
Mrs Miniver? >
You must be a very
difficult man to live with.
Oh, quite impossible.
I warned Judy,
but she just laughed.
She thinks I'm worth it.
Are you?
No.
She's very much
in love with you.
And now that
I've met you,
I'm beginning
to understand why.
Are you?
Well, I can't.
I thank my
stars for it,
but I can't think
what she sees in me.
You're...different.
You're blunt,
almost rude.
You're honest.
That's rare.
And you're rather
dashing and glamorous.
Oh, nonsense.
Oh, yes, that's
your reputation,
you have a name for
bold deeds and wild adventures.
You fire the imagination.
Oh, yes, I can see
what Judy sees in you.
Matter of fact,
if I were her age,
I might...
You might?
That was very good sherry.
May I have some more?
Have the whole
bottle!
Let's get tight.
I never get tight
before lunch.
Let's have lunch
together and get
tight afterwards.
I'm a menace,
Mrs Miniver.
I love Judy,
I love her youth,
her freshness,
her naivete.
Her belief in
all the things that
I no longer believe in.
But I'll probably make
her a shocking husband,
just as I did Pam.
Not that that was
altogether my fault.
We used to throw things
at each other, you know.
What sort of things?
Oh, anything
that was handy.
Ornaments, books,
gramophone records.
You have got a few
of them left.
Are you saving
those for Judy?
Ha! I hope it won't
come to that.
Not yet, anyway.
Peace and quiet
for a time.
Yes, but you're not
a man of peace, are you?
I mean, you've
no peace inside you.
That's why you're always
fighting other people.
< You're really
fighting yourself.
You really are
an unusual woman.
Well, you're right,
of course.
I've no peace inside.
That's why I
make a soldier.
I don't give
two straws if I die.
Oh, death can be easy.
It's living
that's difficult.
That's been said
before, too.
It's still true.
What did you fight about?
You and your wife.
Oh, please don't
think that I'm just
interfering or
digging up the past,
it's only that I'd like
to be able to warn Judy
about the dangerous
topics so that she can
keep off them.
Or perhaps she does keep
off them automatically.
Does she?
As a matter of fact,
she does.
That's because she doesn't
know anything about them.
She's just a baby.
No, Pam and I used to fight
about the maddest things.
Small things blown
up into large ones?
No, large ones.
I thought I knew
all about music.
She thought she was an
expert on world affairs.
Who was right?
Both of us.
Always.
That's what made the whole
thing so impossible.
She has a first-class
brain, Pam.
And a wide
catholic taste.
Her mind's as nimble
as her fingers.
But she's
the most infernally
obstinate woman
I ever met
in my life.
She's quite beautiful,
isn't she?
The loveliest
person.
But of all the
obstinate, idiotic,
pig-headed females!
You talked about
the Greek,
my Harry, the row
we had about that!
You remember
that cadenza in
the first movement. Here.
The one that
goes like this.
Lovely thing, isn't it?
You remember the theme?
That's the way
it should be played.
The way it was written.
But that's not
good enough for Pam.
She has to
play it like this.
Now listen,
listen to this!
See what I mean?
I'm afraid I don't.
They both sound
the same to me.
All right!
You don't have to
know the difference.
You're just a...
But Pam's an artist
and a brilliant one,
and to play the thing
that way!
She adores Scriabine
and Pergolesi.
I loathe Scriabine
And her taste
in painting,
I ask you.
Raoul Mati.
Obscure French painter.
Picasso school.
Trash!
We paid 40 quid
for that.
The second best art
critic in town offered
me 400 for it last week.
I still say it's trash.
These things are important
to you, aren't they?
Music and painting?
Of course
they're important!
There's nothing
else left.
Then they're worth
arguing and fighting about.
I mean, if you're lucky
enough to find somebody
who knows about them,
who feels as strongly
about them as you do,
even if that person doesn't
always agree with you.
Yes, it was exciting
being married to Pam.
Never dull,
I'll say that for it.
Well, I don't think
you'll have any
trouble with Judy.
In fact,
I'm sure you won't.
As you say, she doesn't
know the first thing
about any of these things
you've been talking about.
I don't mean that
she doesn't like
music and painting,
but, well, you know,
we're just an average family.
We like a painting
to tell a good story.
Or music to have
a good tune.
Something nice and simple.
So you see,
I'm afraid you will
have to come down
to her level, won't you?
Because she certainly
won't be able to
climb up to yours.
Well...
goodbye, General.
It's been a fascinating
quarter of an hour.
Shall I give
your love to Judy?
Yes, thank you.
Thank you very,
very much indeed.
Hello, Janet.
Mrs Miniver.
Oh, he's gone
to lunch.
Just this minute,
I'm so sorry.
Perhaps I can
catch him.
Oh, no, don't bother.
He's not expecting me.
It's a surprise visit.
He left early today.
He's taken the
passports, you know,
to the passport
office.
Oh, then we're going?
I envy you.
Janet, tell me truthfully,
is he doing this for me?
Well, he thinks
you need a change.
Most people do,
but they seem to manage
without one.
You don't
want to go?
No, no, I don't.
It's so far away
from home and...
I'd rather...
I'd rather live here.
If you don't want it,
Mrs Miniver,
I think you
should say so.
I mean, tell him
the reason.
Whatever it is.
I can't do that.
That's the one thing
that...
Besides, it isn't
just for me.
He has a kind of
desperate yearning
to get away from this
part of the world.
Oh, that? That's just
the view from that window.
View from the...
Yes, I know
it sounds silly,
a little thing like
that affecting a man,
but it does.
I'm sure it does.
He comes in quite
cheerful and bright
in the morning,
then he sits down
over there,
and within
about 10 minutes,
he sort of glooms over,
if you know what I mean.
Of course we could
look for another office,
I suppose,
but I don't think he'd
fancy the idea of moving.
Why, even when
Mr Blakner retired,
he wouldn't move.
Janet.
Mrs Miniver.
It's all right,
lady, it's a pleasure.
Thank you,
lady, much oblige.
Ten bob each, OK?
All right with me.
How much did
you get for it?
Old Blakie's office.
Well, it was just
an old junk room.
You're not angry,
are you?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
I've hardly
had time to...
Hello. When
did these come?
While you were out.
Are they good?
Are they good, Clem?
Yes. They're
first class.
Somebody trying
to put me out
of business?
No. Somebody wants
to come into the business.
Who did them?
You've been plotting.
The Foley boy, these are
his, aren't they?
But they're good, Clem,
you just said so.
You can't
take that back.
I'm not taking
it back.
No, well, don't try to.
Look, I can't take
on an apprentice just
as we're leaving.
We'll be out
of the country
within a month.
Good heavens, woman,
if you loathe the idea
so much, say so.
You want to get out,
don't you?
Yes, I do, I do. The more
I sit here day after day
looking out at that...
If you want to go,
we'll go, darling.
Hey, come back here.
I want to talk to you.
No, not now.
Tonight at the dance.
Dance?
The sailing club dance.
Don't be late.
Judy?
Darling, turn around.
I have something
to show you.
Judy, it's for you
for tonight.
No, thanks.
I'm not going.
Not going?
Darling, what is it?
Aren't you well?
Please don't touch me.
Judy.
Why? Why did you have
to interfere?
It has nothing
to do with you.
I loved him, he loved me.
We'd have been married
but for you.
But for me?
Oh, don't pretend,
please, don't pretend.
You were there today.
You went to see him.
Yes, of course
I went to see him.
You knew that.
I told you I was going.
I went to take
his coat back.
That was just an excuse.
Yes, just an excuse
to see him, but not
to make you unhappy.
You've hated
the idea of Steve from
the very beginning.
I never hated Steve.
I liked him.
He asked me in
and we talked.
And broke it off.
Darling.
Please, don't
come near me.
I don't know what
you said to him.
I don't care.
I only know
that yesterday
everything was gay
and sweet
and rather lovely.
And now it's over.
Finished.
Oh, how could you?
How could you?
Oh, Judy.
Oh, darling.
I didn't try to talk
Steve out of loving you.
I couldn't have, even
if I'd wanted to.
Darling, he loved you.
He still loves you, my baby.
How could he help it?
But I'm afraid
he loves his wife more.
That wasn't true.
Not till today.
I think it was true
all the time.
He lost sight of her in
the war partly because
he found you in the war.
But the war
is over, Judy.
"The war, the war."
Everybody blames
everything on the war.
That's such a cliche.
A lot of cliches are true.
Well, I don't
believe that one.
I do because I happen
to know that it's true.
A lot of friendships
spring up out of a war.
And they die
when peace comes.
And it's right
that they should.
What do you know
about it?
I'd like
to read you a letter.
It came two days ago.
It's from an American.
We had an awful
lot of war together.
"My dearest Kay, this is
the first time I've ever written
to you with Ellen in the room."
Ellen is his wife.
"Kay, you remember our
last evening together?
"Remember you said, you'll
get the war out of your
system sooner than you think.
"And when it's gone,
I'll be gone, too.
"I didn't believe you then.
"I've been home now several
months and all that time
I haven't believed you.
"Because all that time,
it hasn't been true.
"But now, quite suddenly,
it is true, Kay.
"I'm home again with Ellen.
"Really home.
Home in my heart.
"Dear Kay, I know
you never cared for me
the way I cared for you.
"It was all on my side,
so this won't be a hurt
but a happiness.
"I love Ellen now as much as
I loved her before I met you.
"Maybe a little more
because I did meet you...
"and love you.
"Goodbye, Kay,
my dearest Kay.
"You were there
when I needed you.
"I don't need you any more.
I'll never forget.
"I shan't try to now because
now there's no danger
in remembering.
"God bless you,
always. Spike."
That's why I know.
I know what Steve felt for you,
what he still feels for you.
It could happen and still not
touch his love for his wife.
Spike never knew.
Never. And never will.
No-one will ever except you.
Will they, Judy?
Nobody!
Where is everybody?
What's this, a hen party?
This is just
idle gossip, mother
and daughter stuff.
Well, come on now, jump
to it or we'll be late.
I promised Mrs Foley
the first rhumba.
Second for you, Kay,
and third for Judy.
That in order?
Well, er, Judy's going to bed.
She's got a headache.
I think I'll come after all,
if you don't mind.
Mind?
Well, don't sit
there messing about.
Come on. Somebody's got
to tie my tie for me.
Hurry up, girls.
You know, there's
something about a well-cut
jacket you just can't mistake.
I was afraid the moths
might have got into it.
New dress, isn't
it, darling?
Oh, Clem.
It's six years old.
It can't be. Rationing
hasn't been in that long.
Well, I wasn't entirely
naked when it started.
I'd thought for
a moment you might
have stolen my coupons.
I did. And there's
where they went.
And five of mine
for the shoes.
Evening,
Mrs M. Evening, Mr M.
How about
a sardine sandwich?
Mr And Mrs M, Mother.
Mrs Foley.
Hello, Tom.
What a lovely
dance, Mr Foley.
And the food.
How did you manage it?
I suppose
we'll all suffer for
this next week.
Half a dollop of marge
instead of the usual
two mouthfuls.
Oh, no, nothing like that.
Things are looking up.
Everything will be back
to normal any day now.
He's been
saying that every day
since peace was declared.
Well, there's no harm in
hoping, Mother, is there?
She misses the bombs.
Well, at least they made
you feel you were alive.
Oh, Tom,
I've got something
for you in the car.
Don't let me go off
with it, will you?
Something for
me, sir?
Yes, your sketches.
What did you
think of them, sir?
Well, I think that
probably you'll put me
out of business.
That is, if I don't
take you into it.
How about it? Do you think
you can spare him, Foley?
Aren't you leaving us?
I heard you were bound
for foreign parts.
You mean you want
to take Tom with you?
Yes. I want Tom
to come with me, but
only as far as London.
Do you think you
can manage that?
Trains run every half-hour.
Then Brazil is off?
Hello, darling.
Oh, Clem.
Did you say
something, dear?
Monday morning, 10.30.
9.30, sir.
I'll tell you how
to get to the office.
I'll tell him, Father.
You've only been there
once in your life.
I'll tell him.
Mother.
Don't forget our rhumba.
Happy
about everything?
Completely happy.
Dance with me?
Kay?
Yes?
Where are you?
I'm here.
But you look miles away.
Come back, will you?
I'm here, darling.
I was just thinking.
I have to tell
you something.
Now?
Yes, Clem, now.
It's hot in here.
Let's go outside.
All right, darling.
Our ninth anniversary.
Tenth. '18 to '28,
10 years.
'18 to '46?
28 years.
'46 to '56
to '66 to '76.
We'll be like
old man river.
We'll just keep
rolling along.
Clem, you don't mind
about Brazil?
I belong here.
We both do.
Then you'll stay
here? Always now?
Of course. If
that's what you want.
We might slip away to
the sea for a fortnight
in the summer.
What do you think?
Yes.
As long as
we're home by autumn.
I want to be home
for autumn, Clem.
It's important.
Why is it important
to be home for the
autumn, Mrs Miniver?
Because next to the spring
it's the loveliest time
of the year.
And I...
I won't be here
for the spring.
What does
that mean, exactly?
My darling,
my darling husband.
'She gripped
my hands, gripped them tight
till it hurt.
'And then, she told me,
while the music played
and the moon shone,
'and old man river,
he just went rolling along.
'Kay told me that night
that when the autumn was gone,
she'd be gone, too.
'I heard her voice,
I knew what she was saying.
'But standing there I seemed
more aware of absurd,
irrelevant things -
'an owl hooting on
the other side of the water,
'somewhere inside on the dance
floor, the tinkle of glass,
'one of the little fairy lanterns
overhead flickering on and off.
'She stopped speaking and
looked up at me, waiting.
'I felt a touch on my sleeve
and then her voice.'
The last dance, Clem.
'Somehow, I found my feet
'moving automatically
back onto the floor.
'I remember thinking,
"They're playing that thing
from Annie, Get Your Gun."
'Strange how music
bridges the years.
'Showboat and Annie, Get Your Gun.
'20 years of married life.
'And so we danced.
We didn't speak. Not a word.
'What was there to say?
'We just looked at each other.
'And loved each other.
'And danced.'
Clem.
I won't
let it happen.
It shan't.
We'll find something,
somewhere.
We'll go on
till we do.
There's America,
the whole world.
We'll go all over
the world to the ends
of the earth.
I know there's
something!
I've seen everyone.
The best.
The very best.
But there must be something,
something we can do.
There isn't, my dearest.
There isn't.
I didn't tell you
until I knew.
There's nothing
that anyone...
They say that it was
the war, and then after.
You have to be pretty
tough these days,
and I wasn't quite
tough enough.
You know.
You do know, don't you?
How much I...
I've loved you?
Darling, I know.
We've had one of the rarest
things in the world,
a perfect marriage.
Nothing has touched it
and nothing
can break it, ever.
"Mr And Mrs Clement Miniver
' "request the pleasure
of your company
' "at the marriage
of their daughter,
Judith Diana Elizabeth
' "to Thomas Henry Foley at
St Margaret's Church, Belham." '
Take thee,
Thomas Henry...
to my wedded husband...
to have and to hold
from this day forward...
for better, for worse,
for richer, for poorer...
in sickness
and in health...
to love and to cherish...
to love
and to cherish...
till death us do part...
according
to God's holy law.
And thereto, I give
thee my troth.
Well, Charles.
Thank you once again.
You did us proud.
They're
a charming couple.
They go
well together.
So, by the way,
do you.
The first leaves.
You know, I often think
that England is like
a certain type of woman,
at her loveliest
in the autumn.
Goodbye, Mrs Miniver.
'He was right.
'As I put an arm around her
and we walked back
together into the house,
'I realised Kay had never
looked more beautiful.'
I think it all
went off rather nicely,
don't you, darling?
I'm so glad it was
fine for them.
It's been a beautiful
day, Clem.
Something to remember.
I'll be down in a moment.
'Four years ago.
'Four years ago today.
'The house is still here.
'And we're still here,
the Minivers, if you chance
to be passing this way.
'Tom and Judy in our old room,
Kay's and mine.
'Toby, when he's not
at school, and I.
'Kay isn't here any more.
'I mean, you can't see her.
'But she's here.
'For me, close to me,
she'll always be here,
'in a thousand places,
a thousand ways.
'In the house,
in the garden...
'everywhere.
'It's like that
if you love someone.
'If you love them enough,
nothing can touch your love,
nothing can threaten it.
'You go on together,
for ever.'