Here she comes. Not a second late.
Lead us please.
- Carry on.
Wheel us left.
- Right.
Old Charlie is keeping up his record.
Alright behind.
Going away.
That's new since my day.
The Bristol Mail, sir.
She takes only eleven and
3/4 hours from London.
She's the fastest coach on the road.
Under forty seconds again.
Our stage has never let
Her Majesty's mail down yet.
You have been away long?
Abroad for 40 years.
- Oh.
And I have done pretty well for myself.
I've made a tidy fortune and
no-one to share it with me.
No relatives in England?
Well, that's what I have
come home to find out.
[ Horn ]
I had an elder brother.
He may be dead for all I know.
You have heard nothing of him?
All these years?
- Not a word.
You see, sir. We quarrelled.
We both loved the same woman.
And he won her.
Do you know where to look for him?
I'm to begin my search in London.
He may have children living.
And perhaps there may
be one among them ..
Who is like her.
With her eyes.
And her voice.
When you read to me I think
it is my Erin come back.
You're so like her.
She made you happy.
To remember her is to be happy.
[ Bell ]
Eight o'clock.
He should be here by now.
But he won't fail me.
Has Kit closed the shop?
- No. I'll tell him.
I expect he's still doing the
writing lesson I gave him.
Kit.
- Yes, Miss Nell?
I've written my exercise. Look.
Oh Kit.
I am sorry, Kit.
Now put up the shutters and I'll
get your supper before you go.
Thank you, Miss Nell.
Poor Kit. I'm afraid he'll
never learn to write.
I like to see you smile, my dear.
I'm afraid I'm sad company for you.
- Oh no.
But if only you weren't so worried.
It will only be for a
little while longer, Nell.
Soon, you shall be rich. Very rich.
But it is late.
He doesn't come.
- Who is coming?
Quilp, my dear.
Ain't you pleased to see him?
You're late. You've kept me waiting.
Now come, come.
That's not the way to
treat an old friend.
And such a very obliging friend.
How are you, Nelly?
- Very well, sir.
Upon my soul, she gets
prettier every day.
Nell. Take Kit his supper.
You brought what I asked?
- Yes.
Give it to me! Give it to me.
Give it here.
You got it.
- Oh.
Ah, you old miser.
I swear you'll make that grow
in your hands, won't you.
Yes. It will grow.
How will you do it, eh?
Short loans at high interest?
Speculation?
What's your security?
Tell a friend.
No. You must wait.
You will get it back. A hundredfold.
Never fear.
If I had any fear I wouldn't
have brought that.
Do you know what they call you?
The richest man in London.
Rich?
Yes. I will put her beyond
the reach of want.
She will have no pittance but a fortune.
And a fortune for me too, eh?
Yes. For you too. If you will wait.
Oh, I'll wait. But you are deep.
You keep your secret close.
Yes. Very close.
What do you think I have in my pocket?
Put there quite by mistake I assure you.
A certain mortgage on a certain shop.
A shop ..?
Just between friends, of course.
Now, you won't forget that.
Will you.
It isn't the big words, Miss.
It's the little-uns.
Now what is an 'ee-wee' lamb?
A 'ewe' lamb, Kit.
Why, it's a little girl lamb.
Like you, Nelly!
Sure. Give me a kiss
for Mrs Quilp, Nelly.
You get out or I'll bash your ugly face.
Oh, you will, will you?
Ha-ha-ha.
Be a good girl, Nelly.
And perhaps one day you shall
come to tea with Mrs Quilp.
With Mrs Quilp.
Before Quilp and I were married.
Mother often said he had such a way with
him, he could marry anyone he pleased.
Didn't you, mother?
- Did I?
Anyway, he has no right
to treat you as he does.
Mrs Quilp.
Before I would let a man order me about
as your husband does I'd kill myself.
And write a letter first
to say he had done it.
Quilp is the greatest
tyrant that ever lived.
My poor daughter can't
call her soul her own.
Why don't you stand up to him, my dear?
She hasn't the spirit
to answer him back.
No, not a single word.
What? Not going, ladies?
Not going, surely?
Why not stop to supper?
Why shouldn't they stay to supper
Quilp, if my daughter was to ask them?
To be sure. Why not?
Oh. You look ill, Mrs Jiniwin.
You've been overexciting
yourself with talking.
It is your weakness.
Go to bed.
I shall go to bed when I please.
Then please go now.
Mrs Quilp.
Yes, Quilp?
If ever you ask any of
these women here again.
I will .. bite you.
Fetch my cigars.
Yes, Quilp.
Mrs Quilp.
I have a problem to think out.
I shall smoke all night.
Sit there in case I want you.
Yes, Quilp.
I've got to find out what he does
with that money, the sly old fox.
Hello gentlemen. Are you still game?
Yes, yes. My luck will change.
Of course it will.
- That's the spirit.
I must win.
I must win for her sake.
Don't go to sleep, Mrs Quilp.
Sit up. If you please.
Nell.
Nell. You must go at once
with a message for Mr Quilp.
It is urgent.
My dear me, it is daylight.
Unlock the door, Mrs Quilp.
Good heavens.
You don't mean to say that she was ..?
- Yes, she has been.
Sitting up all night.
Now, who can say that husband
and wife ain't pleasant company?
Oh, you are a brute.
Bless you.
My dear old lady.
Get my breakfast.
You're so fond of me, aren't you?
Oh, you ..
You.
You dear old darling.
Why, it's Nellie.
What is it, sweetness?
A letter from my grandfather, sir.
Oh.
Just a moment, my dear.
I will let you in.
Nelly Trent is here.
Again.
See if you can get anything out
of her about her grandfather ..
And what he does with the money.
I, Quilp?
- Yes, you.
Of course.
You will talk more freely to one
another than you do to us.
Worm your way into her secrets.
Oh Quilp, I don't like to.
I am fond of the child.
Well, so much the better.
Oh.
I will.
Yes.
Now remember. I shall be listening.
If you're not sharp enough
I shall creak the door.
Woe betide you if I
have to creak it often.
What? Gone in four and twenty hours?
What the devil does
he do with the money?
That's the mystery.
Ah.
Come in, my dear.
Come in and see Mrs Quilp.
Pretty little Nelly.
How would you like to be my second?
Be your what, sir?
Mrs Quilp the second.
When Mrs Quilp the first is dead.
Sweet Nelly.
Be a good girl.
In five years you will be just
the proper age for me.
Here is Nelly Trent, my dear.
Give her a nice cup of tea
while I think out a reply.
Surely, you must have
left home very early?
Yes, ma'am. Soon after it was light.
Sugar?
- Thank you, ma'am.
Your grandfather.
Is he well?
I'm unhappy about him.
Unhappy, my dear?
How is that?
He seems to have changed lately.
I'm sorry.
Thank you. You're always kind to me.
How that door creaks.
It's only ..
The wind, my dear.
In what way has your
grandfather changed?
He used to be so cheerful and contented.
But now even the house
seems dark and gloomy.
I know you won't tell anyone.
But every night and all night
long he's away from home.
Indeed, my dear?
And in the early morning he comes
back so sad and wretched ..
What shall I do?
Tell me, what shall I do?
You can go home my dear.
Tell your grandfather I'm afraid
I can't oblige him today.
I was to bring back a note.
I'll see him tomorrow or the next day.
He said it was urgent.
- Hmm. So it is, my dear.
But the note?
- You give him my message.
Goodbye, Nellie.
Goodbye.
Well, Mrs Quilp.
You are a keen questioner.
Ain't you?
I did my best for you.
- Ha.
You may thank your lucky stars ..
That what I have heard has put
me on the object of my strike.
Don't get anything too tasty for dinner.
Because I shan't be home.
If anyone wants me I am at
the counting house at the wharf.
You dog!
If you stand on your head
again I'll cut your feet off.
There's a gent waiting inside for you.
Who is it?
- Mr Swiveller.
Ha.
Well, don't you leave the wharf or
I'll scratch you with a rusty nail.
You dog.
What devil's wind blows you here?
Sir, you must excuse the
iniquities of this attire.
But I had the sun strong
in my eyes last night.
That's evident. What do you want?
Man wants but little here below.
Nor wants that little long.
- Bah.
The fact is my aunt in Dorsetshire
has failed to send me a remittance.
Again?
And so sir, the watchword is .. four.
What?
- Four pounds.
So you want me to advance
you more money?
I'll pay you as soon
as the old lady dies.
And when will that be?
Well, she has been going
to die since I was 8 years old.
She hasn't kept her promise yet.
Well, I'm not lending any more
money on those expectations of yours.
Oh.
But.
I may get you into an office.
With a lawyer friend of mine.
Where you can keep an eye
on me and my expectations.
But aren't you going to fork out now?
There's a little job
I've got for you first.
You know old Trent?
The miser who keeps
the Old Curiosity Shop?
Yes.
He may help you to your fortune.
My fortune?
How?
Follow him and tell me
where he goes at night.
Smart is the word.
- And smart is the deed.
I was thinking of
calling to see old Trent.
But I'll delay my visit until you
find out what I want to know.
Say not another syllable. I know my cue.
Two days.
Two whole days and he doesn't come.
And if he deserts me now.
What can I do?
Grandfather, couldn't
we go away from here?
Let's forget about money and be happy.
We could go away to country places
and sleep in fields and under trees.
And never think of money again.
Or anything that makes you unhappy.
I could beg for us both.
My dear Nell.
My darling.
Who?
How did you get in?
- Ha.
Through the door of course.
I'm not quite small enough
to get through keyholes.
I wish I was.
I want to have a quiet talk with you.
Alone.
Yes, yes.
Leave us, my dear.
Leave us.
You have no secret from me now.
I know where the money
I lent you has gone.
I thought you were
making a fortune for me.
Ann all the time I have been
cheated by a common gambler.
I am no gambler.
I never play for my own gain.
It is all .. for her.
You are mad.
- I have saved so little.
Not enough to keep her when I'm gone.
I couldn't bear to leave her in poverty.
So first you lost your savings.
And then you came to me.
And now .. you're a beggar.
I hold security on all that you have.
The shop and everything in it.
- I can win it all back.
Oh yes?
If a man plays long enough
he's sure to win.
So he is.
So he is. I felt that from the first.
I have dreamt three times ..
Of winning large sums.
My luck is going to change.
I believe it is indeed.
A good friend.
This time.
I must win.
I only want a little help.
Just a few pounds.
So, just a few pounds?
No. I really couldn't.
Two shillings.
Not a penny.
And what's more.
You're going to pay back every
farthing that you've borrowed.
I can't. Not yet. You know I can't.
The sale of your shop will bring
me in something on account.
What? You won't sell me out?
To be sure I will.
I'll ruin you.
I'll have you shut up in a
madhouse you old dotard.
Locked up. Chained up.
Put where you can't cheat
any more honest men.
No, no. No.
They will starve you.
They'll flog you.
And you will never get out.
You will never get out.
You will stay in there until you die.
It's Nell.
Grandfather, it's Nell.
Smoke away, you dog.
Is it good, Brass?
Is it nice? Is it fragrant?
It's famous.
This ought to keep off fever.
How long have we got to
stop here, Mr Quilp?
Until the old gentleman
upstairs is dead Mr Brass.
How kind of you sir, to wait.
Some people would sell off the goods
the very instant the law allowed them.
Some people would have been
all flintiness and granite.
Some people jabber like parrots.
Hee-hee. Such spirit.
Such a genial personality.
Here is my duck of diamonds.
How is he now?
A little better, thank you.
What a pretty Nellie.
Does she want to sit on
Quilp's knee or on Mr Brass's?
Oh no, no.
He is a very clever lawyer.
What a remarkably pleasant
way he has with children.
I only want a few things out of my room.
Then I won't come down here anymore.
Isn't yours a pretty
little room, Nellie.
Quite a bower.
I think I will take it
for my little room.
It was kind of you sir to spend so much
time in helping me in my search.
I wish you had stayed longer in London.
I'm only sorry we had so little success.
Oh, I have not lost hope.
There are plenty of people by
the name of Trent in London.
I shall continue my search.
Take your seats please.
Well. Godspeed and success
in your new work.
A school of my own.
And thirty-five pounds a year.
It is a fortune.
I can hardly believe it.
Come along, please.
We must keep in touch.
Write to me care of my bankers.
Coutts in The Strand.
- Thanks. I will.
The sun is just up.
It's going to be a fine day
for the start of our journey.
We must go at once.
- Are you sure you're strong enough?
I shall be strong when
we get away from here.
Far away.
Where he can't find me.
No-one must know who we are.
He said he would have me shut up.
Then they would take me away from you.
Which way?
I feel as if we have left all
of our troubles behind us.
Yes. We can be free now.
And never go back there again.
Never.
We must keep even our name
secret so that they cannot find us.
You won't leave me, Nell?
If I lost you, who would
save me from him?
You're quite safe now, dear.
Not yet.
We must go on.
Further away.
They've gone, Brass. Gone, I tell you.
They've vanished.
- Impossible.
They think they can give
me the slip, do they?
Well, we will see.
[ Bell ringing ]
That's my sweet wife.
Later.
Does a Mr Trent live there?
Yes, sir.
- Oh.
What the devil are you doing?
Well, I hoped it was somebody else.
Hey, who did that?
He did.
Most un-businesslike.
I wish to see Mr Trent.
Won't you step in, sir?
After you, Mrs Quilp.
At last.
Where is Mr Trent?
That I couldn't tell you sir, offhand.
Why? Doesn't Mr Trent live here?
Isn't this his shop?
- It was.
It's mine now.
Yours? You mean you bought it?
No. Not exactly.
But he owes me so much money.
That I was obliged,
but very reluctantly.
To sell the old man up.
- Sell him up?
Good gracious.
How old is he?
Upwards of seventy, I should say.
I gave them every consideration.
Them? Has he a family?
His grandchild.
A great favourite of mine, sir.
I assure you.
A dear little girl.
Nellie.
- Nell?
Where are they? Where have they gone?
I don't know.
I wish I did.
You don't know?
The fact is they have given me the slip.
Vanished this very morning.
- Then they must be found.
It's for their own advantage.
- Is it indeed?
If you can help me find them ..
You can't be more anxious
to find them than me, sir.
I have been a good friend to them.
If you get news of them perhaps
you'll let me know at once?
Certainly.
What address shall I ..?
- I've no settled address. As yet.
Oh?
If you're looking for
lodgings in London, sir.
I do recommend very
good ones in Bevis Marks.
A lawyer. Name of Brass.
Brass, eh? Thank you.
I'll write that down.
If you can find them for me I
will make it worth your while.
I'll make it worth my while.
- Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
I'll do everything I assure you.
Everything in my power.
To help you to find them.
That is very alike.
I have got to help myself
to find them first.
Don't stare at me.
Get my breakfast, dear Mrs Quilp.
My breakfast.
So my master's a thief, is he?
- Yes, you know he is.
Let me tell you Quilp is the ugliest
dwarf I've seen anywhere for a penny.
Ha. Ugly?
Well, what about Nell?
She is ugly if you like.
Oh, she is, is she?
Right.
You dogs.
Fight, you dogs! Fight.
I will beat you to a pulp.
He said you're the ugliest dwarf
that can be seen for a penny.
Do you mean to say I am not?
- No.
Then what do you want to fight in
front of my shop for, you dogs?
Because he said you were.
Not because you ain't.
And why did he say my master is a thief?
He said that?
He said what he did because he's a fool.
You said what you did ..
Because you are very wise.
Very clever.
Kit.
Always at all times.
Speak the truth.
Yes, of course.
Then tell me.
You have no idea where your
master and Miss Nell have gone?
Gone?
You've not the smallest idea?
No.
Are you quite sure?
I wouldn't tell you if I did know.
What? You wouldn't?
- No I wouldn't.
Very well, Christopher.
Very well.
I hope your honesty will
meet with a suitable reward.
Oh, I do hope it will.
It's all wrong.
Broken here and ..
Broken.
Someone is coming.
- We don't want no crowd in here.
Two ain't a crowd.
- Oh, ain't it?
If you had to stand in front
of a curtain like I do ..
You would know that anything over
one is a crowd in our business.
Good day.
- Good day.
Is this the first time you've
seen a Punch off the stage?
Yes.
Why do you come here to do this?
Well, sir. It don't do for the public to
see the company undergoing repairs.
It would destroy all the delusions.
It is this Judy.
She's all falling to pieces.
You ain't got a needle and
thread on you I suppose?
I have, sir. Will you let me
try and mend it for you?
Why certainly.
Well now. That's really kind, that is.
Where might you be going, sir?
We haven't quite decided.
If you want somewhere to stay I'd advise
you to put up at the same place as us.
The Jolly Sandboys.
- Thank you.
We'll go with you.
Come on then.
Come on, Tommy. Come on.
Alright, Shorty. Alright.
They are strangers, Tommy.
Down for the races?
- Aye.
Doing a bit of practice?
Well, it's better than carrying
them about, isn't it.
Which road are you taking?
- We are taking the longest road.
You see, the more miles we do tonight.
The more we'll save tomorrow.
That's true.
I suppose they're on
the road to the races.
Yes. But that old man
and the little girl ..
Are a queer couple to be
travelling with the Punch.
Well, here's to the landlord.
To the landlord.
The landlord.
A drop of warm ale.
Who are they?
Don't you know?
- No.
They're no good.
- They're no harm.
Here.
I tell you what.
It's plain the old man
ain't in his right mind.
Have you just found that out?
That handsome child
ain't used to the road.
Have you seen how the old man
is always wanting to get ..
Further away?
And what then?
- This.
He has given his friends the slip.
And persuaded that delicate young
creature to come along with him.
All because of her fondness for him.
Now, I ain't going to see
them come to no harm.
I'm going to restore them
to their sorrowing friends.
Shorty, there may be a lot of
good sense in what you say.
Ah, but we mustn't let
them give us the slip.
The more we must.
And remember if there
should be any reward.
We are partners in everything.
You must have a long rest.
We'll go to bed directly after supper.
Do you think it's safe
for us to stay here?
Oughtn't we go on?
Just a little further?
No-one can hurt us here.
Another pint of warm ale.
Oh, what a lovely smell.
What's this?
I'll tell you. It's a stew. Of tripe.
And cow-heel.
Yes. And new potatoes.
And sparrow-grass.
Good evening ladies and gents.
Here we are again.
Come on. You've been
lagging behind all day.
Don't keep nagging at me. Nag, nag, nag.
You're just in time for a
nice drop of hot stew.
Stew? Here, pass it over.
New potatoes and everything.
Another warm ale.
And one for my little boy.
Oh look. Them is Jerry's dogs.
He can't be far behind.
He'll have to be quick
if he wants any stew.
Good evening, all.
- Good evening, Jerry.
Your people don't usually
travel in costume, do they?
No. But we've been playing on the
road to the race-going crowds.
Here. Look at them
there dogs over there.
No, no my dear. No.
Not a morsel out of anyone's
hand but mine if you please.
That dog lost a halfpenny today.
He goes without his supper. Now.
The dogs whose name
is called, eats. Here.
Come on. Towser. Towser.
Come on. Come on.
Good dogs. Good dogs.
Stand up. Stand up. Good. Good.
Good dogs. Again.
How much is it please?
- A florin.
And the lodgings?
- They're included.
Are you ready now?
- Yes.
Towser.
Keep it up. Keep it up.
Stand up. Stand up.
Keep at it. Come on.
Tomorrow, I'm going to gather some
flowers and sell them at the races.
So we shall have to get up early.
- Yes, yes.
In the morning, we must go on further.
Further.
Goodnight.
God bless you.
Shush.
Look.
What is it?
Listen, my dear.
I'm sure you may not know it.
But it's me that's your friend.
Not him.
Not who?
- 'Short', my dear.
I am only an open-hearted man.
I may not look it.
But I am.
You stick close to me.
And always say it was me ..
That was your friend.
You can't think what
an interest I take in you.
Do you think I don't
know your little history?
What history?
About you and the poor old gentleman.
You know about my grandfather?
- Yes.
But you needn't tell Short we've
had this little talk together.
Recollect the friend.
It's Codlin who's the friend.
Not 'Short'.
Are these the only dogs you got, Jerry?
No. I got about a dozen.
A dozen?
And I never lets anybody
feed them but me.
Hey, Tommy.
- Hello.
Have you got the show ready?
- I'm just going to put it up.
Well, we ain't got much time.
As I was saying, I never lets
anybody feed them but me.
Grandfather.
I'm frightened.
Those men. They know about
us and want to send us back.
What? What's that?
- We must get away from here.
Yes.
They say I am mad.
They will chain me up in a stone room.
I shall never see you again.
- They shan't do that. We'll go tonight.
I'll find a time when we can steal away.
Let me think now.
An old gentleman and a little girl?
Yes. I remember the
parties most particular.
They was travelling with
the Punch and Judy.
Oh.
If anybody else comes asking for them.
You haven't seen them.
- Ah, that's as may be.
You don't remember anything about them.
That depends on if I see
the young Queen's picture.
Oh.
Thank you, sir.
Can't we rest here?
We've been walking all day.
We must be safe now.
Are you sure?
Listen. What's that?
Look. There is Quilp.
How did you find the cold pie, George?
It weren't a miss, ma'am.
And the beer, George? Was it passable?
It was flatter than it might have been
but it weren't so bad for all that.
Have you heard who won
the Helter-Skelterman?
No.
Hey, you.
Who won the Helter-Skelter plate?
The what, ma'am?
The Helter-Skelter plate at the races.
Weren't you there?
- No, ma'am.
Come here.
But I saw you on the road in
company with a low, vulgar Punch.
I'm sorry I was.
A nice little girl like you.
Do you know those gentlemen, ma'am?
Know them?
Do I look as if I know them?
I beg your pardon, ma'am.
Granted. Come closer, child.
Are you hungry?
A little. But not very.
Then you had better have some tea.
I suppose you're agreeable
to that, old gentleman?
Take this away George and
bring some cups and saucers.
Take this knuckle of ham.
Now hand me up the teapot for a little
more hot water and a pinch of fresh tea.
No, sir. I ain't seen no couple. Not I.
You're sure they came by on this road?
I traced them on to Watling Street.
An old gentleman and a little girl?
I seen them.
You have? Where?
They was travelling with a Punch
and Judy. You recollect, Jack?
Where did they go?
- To the races, I reckon.
To the races? I'm glad to know that.
Thank you, sir.
- Right.
What did you want to say that for?
I promised the little man I wouldn't
tell anyone which way they'd gone.
How did I know?
Can you read, child?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, what a thing that is. I can't.
Read that.
Oh. 'Jarley's Was Work'.
That's me.
I am Mrs Jarley.
Oh.
Never keep company with
a vulgar Punch after this.
I never saw a wax-work.
Is it funnier than Punch?
Funnier? It's not funny at all.
Oh.
It's calm and classical.
Is it here, ma'am?
- Is what here?
The Wax-Work.
Why bless me, no.
It's gone on in the van.
Oh.
Come inside for a minute.
I want to say something to you.
Sit down, my dear.
You have a way with you that most
people wouldn't find unpleasant.
You could take my place.
And point out the wax
figures to the people.
Do you want employment?
Oh, thank you.
But I couldn't leave my grandfather.
Old gentleman.
Do you want a good situation
for your granddaughter?
What would become of me without her?
I'd have thought you were old enough to
look after yourself if you ever will be.
Don't be unkind to him please.
Well, well.
I might find a little job for him too.
It isn't a common offer.
Remember it's Jarley's Wax-Work.
The duties are very light and genteel
and the company particularly select.
There's nothing of your open-air
vagrancy about Jarley's.
My exhibition takes place in the
assembly rooms or the town hall.
Walk up. Walk up ladies and gents.
And see Jarley's collection
of stupendous waxworks.
Upwards of one hundred figures as shown
before all the crowned heads of Europe.
Don't be shy.
Walk up and see this unique
collection of famous personages.
And finally, he was sent to the
gallows for poisoning 24 families ..
With pickled walnuts.
This, ladies and gentlemen
is Jasper Packlemerton.
A most atrocious memory.
Who courted and married fourteen wives.
And then destroyed them all by tickling
the soles of their feet as they slept.
On being brought to the scaffold he was
asked if he was sorry for what he did.
And he replied: 'Yes, he was sorry'.
'For having let 'em off so easily'.
And he hoped all Christian husbands
would pardon him the offence.
Let this be a warning
to all young ladies ..
To be particular in the character
of the gentleman of their choice.
Observe.
His fingers are curved as
if in the act of tickling.
And his face is represented with a wink.
As he appeared when committing
his barbarous crimes.
Very nice, my dear.
She has such a genteel way with her.
Well, dogs. Here we are back in London.
Yes. Thank goodness.
Luggage, sir?
- Yes.
Take that to a cab.
Where to, sir?
Bevis Marks. Mr Brass's house.
Right.
Who made the fair copy of
this ejectment, Sammy?
Let me see.
Who do you think?
He did.
Did I?
It's disgraceful.
Have it your own way, ma'am.
Why should we keep a clerk
like that just to please Quilp?
Have we another client like Quilp?
I would do anything to oblige him.
Confound Quilp.
There's my Sally.
The virgin of Venice.
The woman I ought to have married.
Very good. Very good indeed.
Really quite eccentric.
There she is.
Hard-hearted as the metal from
from which she takes her name.
I wonder you are not
ashamed of yourself.
Oh, why don't you change it?
Melt down the brass and
take another name.
Hold your nonsense, do.
And how is my pet clerk getting on?
No earthly use to us.
Ah, but he's useful to me.
Because he has got expectations.
So keep an eye on him.
Yes, Mr Swiveller.
You should be proud to have
the friendship of Mr Quilp.
Will you and Sally come across to the
Red Lion with me to talk some business?
If you can spare the time.
Spare the time? You're joking, sir.
It is not everyone who has
the chance of your company.
Young man.
You will mind the office.
If anyone calls.
Take a message.
I shan't be long.
I'll be back in a few minutes.
I am very sorry to hear it.
And if you could manage to be
run over so much the better.
That female dragon.
Just because my aunt stops my
allowance I have to be clerk to you.
Well, what will I be next?
A convict? Or is that
too genteel for me?
Come in.
Please, sir.
Will you come and show the lodgings?
It is 18 shillings a week.
Boots and fires lit.
Why don't you show them yourself?
Miss Sally said I wasn't to.
Because they'd think the attendance was
poor if they saw how small I was first.
They'll see how small you
are afterwards, won't they?
Ah, but then they'd have took the rooms.
Paid in advance.
Do you do all the work of the house?
Do you get plenty to eat?
Yes.
Is anybody there?
I can't wait any longer.
I understand sir, you desire
to look at these apartments.
Very charming apartment, sir.
Commanding an uninterrupted
view of over the way.
And now within one minute's
walk of the corner of the street.
What's the rent?
18 shillings. One pound per week.
Boots and fires is extra.
I'll take them.
There you are.
Thank you kindly, sir.
Here is ten pounds on account.
- Ten pounds?
My name isn't Brass.
- I didn't say it was.
The master of the house is Brass.
- A good name for a lawyer.
And the woman of the house. What is she?
A dragon.
- Huh?
Wife?
- Sister.
Well, tell them I don't want to be
troubled or asked any questions.
I beg your pardon. Your name?
In case of letters.
I never have any.
- Well, if anyone calls.
Nobody will call.
- Don't blame me if mistakes occur.
Blame not the bard.
- I blame nobody.
When he who adores thee
has left but a name ..
Go farther away from the leg of mutton.
Or you will be picking at it I know.
Do you see this?
Yes.
Then don't you ever go and
say you haven't had meat here.
Now, go on. Eat it up.
Do you want any more?
No.
You were helped once to meat.
You were asked if you want
more and you answered no.
You've had as much as you can eat.
My eyes are upon you, madam.
Oh. Please don't tell on me, sir.
She will beat me to death.
I wouldn't take much, sir.
Only enough to squench my hunger.
I understand.
What is your name?
Well, what does she call you?
Little devil.
How old are you?
I don't know, Mr Swiveller.
Well, shut your eyes tight.
And don't open them until I tell you.
Now open them.
Beer.
Have you ever tasted beer?
I had a sip of it once.
Here's a state of things.
It can't be tasted in a sip.
You tuck into that and
wait until I come back.
Hey, boy. Where's my beer?
The governor said I was
to leave you none.
He will have his little jokes.
That's alright.
Tell him I'll call round
and settle tomorrow.
I have heard that tale before.
- Yes.
Here.
Take a pull of this.
But moderate your transports.
Is it good?
Oh, ain't it.
Remember the once popular melody ..
'Begone dull care'.
'Fan the sinking flame of hilarity
with the wing of friendship'.
'And pass the rosy wine'.
Lord.
What's this?
Do you play cribbage?
No, Mr Swiveller.
Then I'll teach you.
And to make it all seem
more real and pleasant ..
I shall call you:
'The Marchioness'.
Now then, Marchioness.
Fire away.
Hey! You men.
I want to talk to you. Come in here.
Do you hear what the
gentleman says, Tommy?
I ain't no talker.
Come on Shorty.
What are you waiting for?
Ain't you got any manners?
Now then, you boys and girls run away.
The performance will positively
commence a little later on.
Go off now. All of you.
Run away.
Come in.
Tommy.
Didn't I tell you there was sure to be
an enquiry after them two travellers?
Didn't I tell you that I
loved that blessed child?
Here, let me speak.
- The pretty creature.
'Codlin is my friend' she said.
With a tear of gratitude
trickling down her little eye.
Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
'Codlin' to my friends. Not 'Short'.
Will you leave off aggravating.
'Short is all very well' she said.
'But Codlin is not after my money'.
But he mightn't look it.
So you can give me no information
that would help me?
Here. Wait a minute.
There's a man of the name of Jerry, sir.
Who keeps a company of dancing dogs.
Shut up about Jerry.
When I think of that
there darling child.
Will you never leave off?
Shut up.
Jerry told me he had seen them
with a travelling waxworker.
Somewhere in the Midlands.
Is this man in London?
- He will be tomorrow.
And he lodges at our house.
- Send him here.
Here is a sovereign each.
- Thanks very much.
And if I find them by your help
there will be twenty more.
'Dear good Codlin', she said.
'He's always devising pleasures for me'.
Once, she called me Father Codlin.
I thought I should have bust.
Queer company for our lodger to keep.
Yesterday it was a Punch and Judy.
Yes. And this morning it
was a man called Jerry.
Now it's the boy who
worked at old Trent's shop.
What does it all mean?
- Something shady.
Can't we find out what it is?
Quilp will want to know.
Shush. Don't make a noise.
I heard you've worked for
Mr Trent, dealer in curiosities.
Yes, sir.
So I sent for you to tell you
I've traced your old master.
And Miss Nell? Where are they, sir?
A man called Jerry tells me they're
somewhere 30 miles north of Coventry.
So I shall go there and make enquiries.
If I take a post-chaise, I shall
reach there tomorrow morning.
Hmm.
Well, you save me the trouble of telling
you I travel to Coventry tonight.
I shall want my bag got
ready for the journey.
Coventry, did he say?
- Yes.
I will go round and tell Quilp myself.
Now listen, Kit.
I want you to come with me.
- Me, sir?
They know you. They don't know me.
You can convince them
I am friendly to them.
I'm afraid that I might do
more harm than good.
The master has been against
me since his illness.
Is there no-one else they will trust?
Well, sir. There's mother.
- Do they know her?
Yes. They were as kind to
her as they were to me.
Then ask her to come.
Bring her to me at the ..
At The Peacock in two hours' time.
I will see that it's worth her while.
Here is mother, sir.
You're just in time, ma'am.
- Oh, I'm all of a flutter.
You will be taken great care of.
But where is ..
Where's my Sunday bonnet?
- Here it is.
Now mind the step, ma'am.
Mind how you go. Be careful Don't slip.
There you are.
Goodbye, Kit.
Be a good boy and look after the baby.
Cheer up, young shaver.
Come and be wafted with me
upon the pinions of concord.
In other words, come and drink.
And may you never want for a
friend or a bottle to give him.
Nell.
We must be moving on, my dear.
Don't forget we open at the
assembly rooms at five.
I'll tell grandfather.
Who is that?
Oh, it's you.
Nell.
If only I had money.
You're sure you have none?
I gave you all I could spare.
I could make your fortune quickly.
I must have money.
The takings are up tonight, George.
Looks like it alright.
I'm going to my room now.
Goodnight my dear and bless you.
Goodnight, Mrs Jarley.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, darling.
Grandfather, where are you going?
What is it?
I have had a dreadful dream.
It was about an old man
in a darkened room.
Who robbed while people slept.
We can't stay here.
This dream is too real.
We must go away.
Tonight?
- Yes.
Tomorrow will be too late.
I know this dream will come true.
And you will be taken away.
If you don't want them to take you,
you must come with me now.
Yes. I will go with you.
You shall never have that dream again.
Nell.
Nell!
Where is that child?
George, have you seen Nell this morning?
- No, ma'am.
Come to that, nor the old man neither.
Whatever is this?
Now, fancy writing me a letter
when she knows I can't read.
Here, George.
You will have to read it for me.
Yes, ma'am.
'Dear Mrs Jarley'.
- Yes, yes.
'Forgive us'.
'For L-e-a-v .. leaving ..'.
Leaving?
'You like this'.
Good gracious.
'Thank you for all your ..'.
'Kind-y-ness. Kindness'.
'Nell'.
Well, I never did.
Good morning.
Mrs Jarley I presume?
- That's me.
You have a gentleman and his
granddaughter with you I believe.
I had.
Had?
They're not dead, are they?
Not as bad as that. But they have gone.
Gone?
Where?
- That's the mystery.
Come inside a moment.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Why, it's Christopher's mother.
Oh look.
Such a dear, worthy woman.
And you wouldn't believe how
fond I am of your honest son.
Let me pass.
I am going to do a lot for him one day.
Will you let me pass?
- In good time.
I can afford to wait.
Oh, sir. It's Mr Quilp.
Only yesterday he was in London.
Are you following us?
I?
You were in London yesterday.
- So were you.
I might say that you were following me.
Why have you come here?
- And why have you come here?
I won't ask why you are going back.
But I wish you a pleasant journey.
Sure.
One minute we are here.
The next we're there in the silent tomb.
Are you sure my husband has drowned?
There seems to be no doubt of it, ma'am.
He was last seen on
the edge of the wharf.
He must have slipped and tumbled in.
I can't believe it.
Ah, what a vale of tears we live in.
To think that I should
be drinking his rum.
It seems like a dream.
Have a drop more. Do.
Yes. It is comforting to a body.
Ah, but what a comfort it
would be to have his body.
A dreary comfort.
Oh, it would.
Then we should be quite sure.
When shall we look upon his like again?
We must send out a description of him.
Now, how would you describe his nose?
Flat.
Aquiline.
Aquiline, you hag.
Do you call this flat?
Do you, eh?
- No, No. I didn't think.
Oh capital. Such an amazing power
of taking people by surprise.
If I could poison that dear
old lady I would have.
Have you been dragging
the river for me all day?
And yesterday too.
- Dear me.
What a deal of trouble.
Pray consider everything yours
that you find upon the body.
Hee-hee.
Such a flow of good humour.
How very whimsical.
So you thought I was drowned, did you?
You thought you were a widow.
I'm very sorry, Quilp.
Oh, I'm sure you're very sorry.
How could you be so cruel?
Disappearing like that without a word.
I like disappearing.
I'm off again.
Now.
I'll be a bachelor.
You can go on thinking you are a widow.
But I'll punch in here occasionally
when you don't expect me.
To see if my dear widow
is behaving herself.
Quilp, you don't mean it?
I do.
I'll be a jolly bachelor.
And live in my counting house.
Ah, it is Kit.
Honest Kit.
How is mother?
Why do you frighten my
mother, you little monster?
Oh. So I am a monster now, eh?
A time ago, you said I was the ugliest
dwarf to be seen anywhere for a penny.
So you are. You are always
frightening people like mother.
It was you that ruined my master.
I, Kit?
Yes, you.
How?
You're a clever boy, Kit.
Too clever to live.
And I dare say you wish that I was dead?
- Yes, I do.
You're not the only one.
But I am sorry.
I shan't oblige you just yet.
Nell.
Speak to me.
What is it?
Nell.
Sit down, boys.
Now we will resume our history lesson.
Where we left off yesterday.
I was telling about
the Kings of England.
[ Door knocks ]
See who that is.
Please, can you help me?
It is my granddaughter.
- Certainly. Where is she?
There she is, sir.
She is exhausted.
Has she walked far?
- Many miles.
Poor child.
I never thought how
weak she was until now.
What shall I do?
Can I take her into my house to rest?
I should be grateful if you would, sir.
You may all go home now, boys.
But go quietly.
In there, sir.
Grandfather.
Here I am, darling.
I can't go on.
No. You mustn't think of it.
Stay here awhile and get strong.
If only we could.
- Why not?
We can talk about the
future when you are better.
Ah.
Listen.
This is business.
- Very good. Very good.
Under what heading?
No, no, no.
Put your book away.
We don't want any documents.
This is very private business.
There's a lad named Kit.
Do you know him?
You mean the boy who
comes to see our lodger?
That's him.
I owe him a grudge.
He is one of your honest people.
He is a prying hound. A sneaking spy.
A yelping young dog.
In short, I hate him.
So do I.
- And so do I.
Then half our work is done already.
Devise your own means, but ..
Put him out of my way.
Shall it be done?
- It shall, sir.
Then give me your hand.
Sally girl? Yours.
This was the old counting house.
It is very beautiful.
I am glad you think it is
beautiful, for it is yours.
Ours?
- Yes.
There's no verger here at present.
So I have spoken to the clergyman.
And he agrees to take you to live here.
And you will also be given a
small allowance of money.
For keeping the keys at the church.
And showing it to visitors.
How can I thank you, sir?
You have made us so happy.
- The happiness is mine.
I shall have you as close neighbours.
Thank you, sir.
Why .. you are trembling.
It's nothing.
My dear child.
Will you wait a moment
while I tell the gentleman?
Thank you, sir.
- Put your hat down there.
As good as done.
But we must keep Mr Swiveller
out of the way until it's over.
Did you send him on that errand?
Yes. A fool's errand.
And he ain't coming back.
He went home with a fever or something.
Excellent.
Poor Mr Swiveller.
Now, do you know what you have to do?
Brass.
Mr Brass.
- Yes, sir?
When that boy Kit arrives,
send him straight up to me.
Very good, sir.
Very good. Such an honest man is Kit.
You may go upstairs now, Kit.
- Yes, sir.
This will help your mother
through the winter.
And I hope to find some steady
employment for you soon.
We owe a great deal to you already, sir.
- Not at all.
If I can't help your old master
at least I can help his friends.
Good day.
- Good day and thank you, sir.
Listen. Here he comes.
You keep out of sight until I tell you.
Just a moment, Christopher.
I'll get your hat.
Thank you.
No. Let him go down the street first.
Now is your time.
Stop thief. Stop thief!
Stop thief.
Thief. Stop thief.
Here, you.
- That's him.
What's the matter?
- He's a thief.
A 5-pound note was
stolen from our office.
How do you know he took it?
- He was there all alone.
I can't believe that lad is
a thief. It's impossible.
If you think I took the money
you had better search me.
What's this?
- The stolen note.
Well, well.
That's proof enough.
Oh for two thousand black slaves
with jars of jewels on their heads.
Mr Swiveller.
[ Door knocks ]
They always clap their hands
instead of ringing the bell.
Oh, Mr Swiveller.
They've took Mr Kit to prison.
The Arabian night. That's what it is.
I am in Cairo and the Marchioness
is the Princess of China.
Mr Swiveller, do listen.
- I am clerk to a female Brass dragon.
That's very genteel.
What about Kit?
I am sure Mr Brass and
Mr Quilp were plotting.
Quilp? Speak not his name.
An orphan's curse on him.
Oh dear.
Why, what is the matter?
Old King Cole was a merry old
soul if you put any faith in history.
Yes.
[ Nell coughing ]
What is it?
You've a bad cough, is it?
Please, sir. Come quickly.
Nell is ill.
- Oh?
Why, Nell.
I am alright now, thank you.
Sit down and rest awhile.
I'd rather get on with my work.
I feel I am a burden to you.
- Don't say that.
Remember that here, we all love you.
You must try to get well.
I will try. You have been so good to us.
I wish I could tell you about the past.
Forget all that has troubled you.
You mustn't dwell upon the past.
You must think only of
the springtime of life.
I've heard them say that you will go
away from us before the spring.
But don't go, Nell.
Stay with us.
I don't want to leave you, dear.
And all because of them,
poor Kit is in prison.
Why didn't you say before?
You was too ill to listen.
- Well, go on.
I heard Mr Quilp saying he
wanted Kit got out of his way.
Marchioness, where are my clothes?
You ain't got none.
- Ma'am?
I had to sell them all to buy the
things the doctor ordered for you.
[ Whistle ]
No clothes.
It would be embarrassing
in case of fire.
Even an umbrella would be useful.
You ain't going out.
You are too weak.
- I am afraid you are right.
Marchioness, you will have to go.
- Go where?
To the gentleman who
lodges with the Brass's.
What, back there? Oh, I durstn't.
Why, I'd run away from there
to come and look after you.
Well, if you don't go I must.
Oh, you can't.
I'll go.
Tell him all you know
about Brass and Quilp.
And if he doesn't go to
the police I'll go myself.
Who is that?
Only me, Quilp.
How dare you come here.
What do you want?
- A note for Miss Sally.
I am so cold.
I'm glad you're cold.
I lost my way in the fog.
Hmm. It does me good to know it.
It has all come out.
Sammy has betrayed me.
'The police are on their way'.
'You'd better disappear. Lose no time'.
If I only had him here I would ..
I would drown him.
Quilt, don't.
They say that drowning men
come to the surface three times.
Oh, to see him those three times.
And mock him as his
face came bobbing up.
[ Dog howling ]
What's that?
So soon?
Such a bloodless cur.
I am afraid I'm going to disappoint you.
He's gone.
- Yes, that way. The wall.
Get after him, quick.
Not that way. That's the river.
He's in the roof so he can't get away.
Come on. Keep close to the stairs.
Look out. See he don't
climb into them rafters.
There he is.
Ladies and gentlemen.
There. Now we've wakened the baby.
We are here on this auspicious occasion.
To congratulate Kit upon his timely
release from the clutches of the law.
For which we're indebted to you, sir.
And to the Marchioness.
But for her evidence ..
Kit might have been sentenced
to 'transportation for life'.
Here is to Kit.
Oh, dear, dear.
To Kit.
- To Kit.
[ Baby crying ]
If it had not been for the
care of the Marchioness.
I might be lying cold on my beer.
I also take this opportunity ..
To tell you my aunt has at last kept her
promise and gone to another world.
So I am now in possession of
a small but welcome annuity.
Which I trust the Marchioness will
honour me by sharing with me.
Oh, Mr Dick.
Ladies and gentlemen, the Marchioness.
The Marchioness.
I was told the gentleman is here.
It is marked: 'Urgent'.
Come inside out of the cold.
Thankee.
It's for you, sir.
- Thank you.
Excuse me.
It's been sent on from the bank, sir.
They were expecting you to call for it.
Thank you.
He needn't wait.
Thank you, ma'am.
Goodnight.
I have unexpected news.
This letter is from a friend of mine.
A schoolmaster.
Some time ago he befriended an
old man and his granddaughter.
He realized they wished to
keep their identity secret.
'The child, worn out by her recent
privations has now become very ill'.
Oh dear.
'And the old man, lonely and worried,
has now told me everything'.
'I beg you to come to them
as speedily as possible'.
I must travel north tonight.
- Tonight?
May I come with you, sir?
- It will help if he can.
Mother?
Of course he can, sir.
- Very well, Kit.
You shall.
I'm glad you're here.
I am rather late I am afraid.
- It's nearly two.
I had been hoping you
would arrive earlier.
It has been a difficult journey.
Where do they live?
He lives over there
where you see the light.
He?
I will get a lantern.
While you're waiting sir, can I go on?
Hush.
Oh, master.
My dear master.
Ghosts.
So many ghosts have been here tonight.
It's Kit. Your servant.
You know me.
Sir, where is Nell?
They all ask that.
They all ..
Ask that.
But where is she?
Tell me.
- Hush.
She's in there.
Asleep.
Thank God.
I ..
Hark.
Didn't she call?
I heard no voice.
Don't tell me you didn't hear that.
Nor that.
Can anyone know that voice ..
So well as I?
She didn't call.
She is still ..
Asleep.
I fear the light might dazzle
her eyes and wake her.
So I brought it here.
She's sleeping soundly.
Oh, master.
Why have they hidden
away her little dress?
She will miss it when she wakes.
I see.
These shoes.
How worn they are.
She kept them to remind her.
Of our journey here.
You can see where her little
feet went bare in the ground.
They told me afterwards.
The stones had cut them.
She never told me that.
But I have remembered since.
She walked behind me.
So that I might not know.
Yes.
She had my hand in hers.
And seems to lead me ..
Still.
Who is that?
Shut the door.
Haven't we enough to do to
drive away that marble cold ..
And keep her warm.
Not in bed?
Won't you try and take some rest?
Sleep has left me.
It is all with her.
And it is a good and happy sleep.
He doesn't know me.
And for days ..
He has hardly recognised me or anyone.
His thoughts are entirely with her.
We must have patience.
Why do you lie so idle there, dear Nell?
When your little friends
come creeping to the door.
Crying:
'Where is Nell'?
'Sweet Nell'.
And weep because they do not see you.
She was always so gentle with children.
What is the earth compared
with that world ..
To which her young spirit
has winged its early flight.
It's not on earth that
Heaven's justice ends.
If one wish could call her back.
Which of us would utter it?
Come.
Come away.
We are not apart.
That will be our comfort
in our great affliction.
You plot among you to
wean my heart from her.
You can never do that.
Never, while I have life.
It is too late to part us now.
In Heaven's good time.
She will wake tomorrow.
Yes.
Her.
She will wake tomorrow.
..r-s..