presents a detective story
THE MURDERER HIDES HIS FACE
STARRING
MUSIC BY
DIRECTED BY
She was lying in the rain the whole night.
- Who found her?
- I did.
Bureš.
Actually, it was Rex that found her.
He dragged me here as if he was mad.
- When was that?
- This morning.
- When exactly?
- After eight.
Fracture of the skull,
cerebral hemorrhage presumably.
Death occured probably yesterday,
around the evening.
- Did you get her identity?
- Marcela Brychová.
She worked as a nurse
at the health centre in town.
- It's a second case already.
- Similar to the one three months ago.
- That Menšíková rape.
- Right, laceration of the head again.
Probably with a stone.
We found one button here
and another one nearby.
- They probably tore off as he dragged her over here.
- She might have just as well crawled here herself.
- Is that all she had with her?
- Yes, Comrade Major.
- Where had you found Menšíková back then?
- Here in these woods as well.
About fifteen minutes from here,
right by the road.
When going home from work, she would always go
through here to the neighboring village.
That trail?
It leads to the gamekeeper's cottage
and to the weekend houses.
Then it goes on to the highway to Prague.
It's a shortcut.
- I don't think so.
- What?
- That this was also sexually motivated.
- And what about the way she was killed?
- With a stone...
- That might have served to deceive us.
- Yes, but...
- Anyone could have used the murder as a cover.
He could have found out about that Menšíková's
regular route and wait for her here.
But what about this one?
- Would she often go through here?
- Hardly.
Yesterday was Sunday,
what was she possibly looking for here?
- A date?
- Well, her husband's serving in the military.
I haven't seen him around in a while.
- She lived with his parents.
- Was she cheating on him?
That's all she had when she married him.
She didn't even have her own sheets.
The furniture is my son's as well.
Does he know already?
My husband is on his way to get him.
When was the last time he was here?
Your son.
It's been almost half a year.
Didn't Marcela tell you where she was
going yesterday?
No...
And didn't you think it was strange
when she didn't return in the evening?
Well, my husband and I were thinking
that perhaps she stayed with a friend over night.
What friend, for instance?
- She had several.
- Since you didn't think it was strange,
you must have been thinking of one specific friend,
haven't you?
Do you really not remember?
Mrs. Brychová,
and what about Tána Válková?
The one who married that engineer from Prague.
Marcela used to hang out with her
around here, didn't she?
- Sometimes.
- They have a weekend house in the woods.
- Others have weekend houses too.
- Who, for example?
Doctor from the health centre.
- The one Marcela worked for?
- Doctor Winter, yes.
His office is in the small castle.
- DISTRICT ARCHIVE; GALLERY
- DISTRICT HEALTH CENTRE
DOCTOR'S OFFICE
WAITING ROOM
Tereza Menšíková,
and now Marcela.
It's like a bad dream.
- Do you think that the same person did it?
- We don't know yet.
But perhaps you could tell us what was she
doing in the woods yesterday. Where was she going?
I'm sorry, I don't know. Please.
- Is that her desk?
- Yes.
Since when did
Mrs. Brychová work for you?
Since the beginning of the year.
I knew her more or less only from the office.
And did you know her more or less?
I knew her normally.
Is it true that you have a weekend house
by those woods?
- Yes.
- Did you happen to be there yesterday afternoon?
- I did.
- By yourself?
Mr. Král was with me.
He's our repairman.
He's been repairing my roof, so I went
to take a look in the afternoon.
Did you go together?
No. He had been working since morning.
- He wasn't finished yet, so...
- You went back by yourself.
- Yes, but...
- What time approximately?
Around five.
But I'm not sure.
- And didn't you see anyone on your way back?
- No.
- Does that repairman live in this building?
- Yes. On the second floor.
- Do you think he's home now?
- I'll go take a look.
What is it, Radka?
Is your Daddy home? Wait.
What was it?
Didn't Mrs. Brychová confide in you
something we should know about?
Well...
She was a bit testy lately.
Probably because of her husband's long absence.
- He's...
- Yes, I know.
- Was anyone interested in her?
- I don't know.
- Are you married?
- Divorced.
Is that important?
Repairman?
I'm more of a housekeeper here.
- When did you leave the Doctor's house yesterday?
- Yesterday?
'Round the evening. It started raining,
so I went to the state farm.
My brother's in charge there.
- Was there anyone else around the weekend houses?
- No.
Wait a second...
Michal was there.
A boy from the farm. He's a little...
- He always tends horses by the woods.
- And when did Doctor leave?
Doctor... doctor...
I don't know the exact time.
It was before the sunset.
But he's got nothing to do with this.
- Did you see Brychová?
- Or the gamekeeper? - No.
- Radka, what is it?
- Lunch.
OK.
- We don't want to hold you. Enjoy your meal.
- Enjoy your meal.
Hm.
- How old is that girl?
- Radka? Sixteen.
- Sixteen... she looks older.
- She does.
She's not his daughter. He married her mom
when the girl was two years old.
But they say he's a good dad.
And what about Válková?
Well, they've known each other since they
were little.
When they would come from Prague, Marcela would
be at her weekend house all the time.
Would anyone else come visit Brychová here?
There was also...
Wait a second, what was her name?
- Kveta Kramárová.
- Who is she?
She's an accountant at the state farm.
STATE FARM POLNÁ
Jerk!
Let's see.
Can you hit that bottle?
Huh?
Nice.
You're Michal, aren't you?
You were tending horses
by the woods yesterday, weren't you?
I don't know anything.
What's wrong?
Michal!
Oh no, you're not going to get anything
out of him.
He's kind of nuts,
but otherwise harmless.
We're only keeping him here
because of that granny of his.
This is Major Kalaš.
My name is Král.
We were asking the comrade when was
his brother here yesterday.
Why, he was here. He came around seven.
Did you come here just to ask that?
- Would you call your accountant over here?
- Kramárová?
She's away on a leave,
left about ten days ago.
- Her mom in Prague is sick.
- When is she coming back?
In time for paychecks, for sure.
- Can I be of any help in the meantime?
- I doubt that.
- I don't suppose you were friends with Brychová.
- No.
- Have you found out anything yet?
- No. Do you know anything?
Well...
Don't you have anything to do?
- You see...
- Thank you.
- I saw her yesterday.
- Brychová? - Yeah.
I was driving on the highway when I saw her.
She was just coming out of the woods.
- By herself?
- No. - With whom?
- With a man.
- Did you recognize him?
It was already getting dark, but I could
swear that he was wearing a uniform.
The autopsy findings, Comrade Major.
DISTRICT POLICE STATION
Please, Comrade Major,
consider yourself at home.
Coffee?
Brychová's autopsy findings.
No signs of sexual violence.
Interesting.
I think this is something different
than the Menšíková case.
Wait a second.
She was three months pregnant?
Exactly.
I see.
It's starting to become more clear.
Husband is in the military for a year,
she is pregnant...
If that guy who was walking with her...
Down.
- Good evening.
Oh God, as if what's already
happened wasn't enough.
We don't want to make things
more difficult for you.
We just need to talk with your son.
Please.
Look, Mr. Brych,
we know how you must feel,
but you'll have to tell us
when was the last time you saw your wife.
About half a year ago.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Where were you last Sunday?
In the barracks, as usual.
Where else would I be?
You see, we've just called your unit.
So what really happened?
- My mother had written to me.
- What did she write?
She wrote that...
She wrote that Marcela was seeing someone.
And you secretly came on Sunday
to see for yourself.
- Yes, but everything cleared up in the end.
- How? In the woods?
No, before that. Then she just saw me off
to the highway. She hitched a car for me.
- What time it was?
- Around five.
Do you remember what car it was?
Blue Octavia, Prague license plate. AC.
Two sevens in the license number, I think.
The driver works in Glass-export, I think.
Did your wife tell you that
she was pregnant?
No, after all I wasn't here for five months.
What did your mother write to you?
Mr. Brych.
She wrote that Marcela might be seeing
that doctor.
But she was going to the weekend houses
only to see her friend.
She gave me her word.
To see that Válková?
Yes.
Hey, Michal!
Who let you cut the small trees?
Just you wait, we will settle this!
If I see you doing that again,
I'll break your arms!
- Look at that fool.
- Let him be,
people are stealing away your wood anyway,
and you don't even know.
- Early morning and you are already so cross.
- Can you blame me? That rascal...
- His head is empty, but he's bright enough to make trouble.
- I heard he tended horses here on Sunday.
That's possible.
You mean because of that Brychová?
Oh no, it wasn't Michal.
He might just look at women, he would barely touch them.
He wouldn't dare to do more than that.
After twenty years here, I already know
a good deal about people.
- How old are you anyway, Mr. Bureš?
- Years, you mean? I'll be 50 soon.
- Why?
- Really? You look more like 40.
- I mean, looking at your hair.
- What did you want with me anyway?
Is that Válek's weekend house?
Yeah, but they're probably not there now.
And where does that doctor from the health
centre has his house?
Nearby, behind the trees.
But you can't see it from here.
Has he ever brought a girl with him?
- Well, you know, he's alone...
- Or someone's wife.
- Brychová, for instance.
- I'm not a voyeur.
Tell us the truth, you know what's going on
around here, don't you?
I don't want to do damage to anyone, but...
She mostly came here,
to the Váleks.
To see Mrs. Válková, huh?
Just about a month ago I saw Marcela here
with some hunk a few times.
- Always around the evening.
- Wasn't that engineer Válek?
He doesn't come here, the old fart.
People were wondering why Tána married him.
- And what about that hunk, do you know him?
- No, he's definitely not from Drahovice.
What does he look like?
He's big,
looks kind of like a boxer.
I had caught a glimpse of him earlier
in the spring. He was cutting roots in the bushes.
- Roots? What for?
- Decoration?
- And wasn't he here last Sunday?
- I don't know.
- I'm sorry, I wasn't expecting a visit this early in the morning.
- I'm not going to hold you for long, Mrs. Válková.
- I only need to know a few things.
- Something uncomfortable?
- Shall we sit?
- Please.
Isn't your husband home?
- No, he went to Brno on official duty.
- When?
On Friday.
Hm.
- You have a weekend house somewhere, correct?
- Yes, in Drahovice. Why?
- Do you and your husband go there often?
- I do, by myself mostly, my husband is usually too busy.
Were you there last Sunday?
Last Sunday? No.
And didn't you lend anyone the keys from the house?
A family member or someone.
- No.
- No?
In that case everything's alright.
I'm sorry for troubling you.
Don't worry about it.
And that is all?
For now.
Is that your husband?
Yes.
That's nice. May I?
I collect these as well.
Well...
Do you know Mrs. Marcela Brychová?
Of course, we went to school in Drahovice
together. What about her?
On Sunday we found her near
your weekend house... murdered.
Waiter! Two coffees.
Make it three.
May I?
I have time, Mr. Kyncl.
But if you want, we can call in witnesses.
So?
Well, if you have witnesses.
- I was there a couple of times with Marcela.
- There you go.
And did Mrs. Válková give the keys
from the house to you?
- No, to Marcela.
- Well.
And for how long did you and Brychová
have an affair?
- An affair?
- Or did you go there to pick mushrooms?
Wood decorations.
And there was no affair.
What, then?
- I assume that you two are men as well.
- We hope we are. So what?
Well, there are times when a man
is in love,
and then there are times when he just
needs an outlet.
And when he meets a woman of the same mind,
they don't have to make up names for it.
It simply goes on until it's over.
- Ours was over a month ago.
- When did it start?
About three months ago in Prague.
- How?
- In the Chamber Theatre.
- She was there with Mrs. Válková, I was...
- Of course.
After that, Mrs. Válková gives you her
weekend house at your disposal,
and for two months you and Brychová are
secretly looking for outlets there,
and all of a sudden we find her murdered
near that house. Isn't that interesting?
And based on that you think
that I killed her.
When was the last time you saw her?
A month ago,
when we broke up.
And where were you last Sunday?
- At home.
- Do you have any witnesses?
I was home by myself,
I was working,
so you'll first have to prove that I killed her,
gentlemen.
Well, that goes without saying.
After you.
Would you tell me what's all this about?
I thought I told you just about everything.
Just about?
So who was here on Sunday?
Here's a Saturday evening newspaper.
Marcela probably.
- She must have been here.
- By herself?
Men's swimsuit.
And it's still a little wet.
Who was the weatherproof man?
Mr. Kyncl?
How should I know?
Mrs. Válková,
you didn't know anything before either.
That was about Marcela.
- Because of her husband I didn't want to...
- Yes. But now it's about Mr. Kyncl.
Why should it be about him?
This wasn't the first murder here.
- That Menšíková...
- That was murder out of lust.
As for your friend, it looks like someone
wanted to get rid of her.
- You don't think that Kyncl...
- Kyncl?
Mr. Kyncl doesn't have an alibi. He claims
he was home by himself on Sunday.
He has an alibi.
He was here with me on Sunday.
Was he seeing both Brychová and you?
No.
He started seeing me only after he broke up with her.
The two of you didn't see her on Sunday?
- No.
- Are you sure?
We didn't.
I don't know what else do you want.
Please.
Mrs. Válková.
Kyncl Jirí, advertising arranger,
no permanent employment. Correct?
- Yes.
- Do you know Mrs. Válková well?
Yes.
Have the two of you established mutual trust?
- Sure.
- Do you agree Mrs. Válková?
Or are there any questions that you would
prefer not to answer in front of Mrs. Válková?
- No.
- Excellent.
When was the last time you saw Brychová?
I've told you already, a month ago.
Are you sure that's correct?
- Yes.
- Where does your wife live?
- My ex-wife? In Brno.
- What do you mean, ex-wife?
As far as we know you haven't been divorced yet.
Divorce... that's just a question of time.
I think that divorce is divorce, right?
And to get ahead of yourself like this is a fraud.
You're already paying alimony to
two women, correct?
Excuse me, but...
isn't this inappropriate?
I had asked your permission earlier.
You also have debts,
of pretty high value too.
And now more trouble.
You're seeing Brychová,
and all of a sudden, she's pregnant.
- I'm hearing about this for the first time.
- Jirí! Tell them already.
What are you talking about?
What should I tell them?
- Did you drag me here all the way from Prague
for this gossip? - Don't talk anymore please.
Go have a smoke.
Tána, I'll explain everything.
Please.
He must have known.
What do you mean?
She came to see him on Sunday,
while we were at the weekend house,
- that she must speak with him.
- And Kyncl?
He went with her in the woods.
Marcela wanted to see him face to face.
He came back upset,
so we immediately returned to Prague.
Did he explain?
He said she flipped out
because of me.
That's so horrible.
Thank you.
Come on, let's go.
Send everyhting he was wearing on Sunday
to forensics.
Some deep trouble he's in, huh?
Sure, but what about Brych?
He's all clear.
They found the driver who had given him
the ride to Prague.
He saw him with Brychová,
he identified her from a picture.
- He's lucky.
- Well, he's got good memory.
- The only number I remember is 097.
- What is it for?
Oh, I forgot that already.
Hello.
Speaking.
What accountant?
Kramárová?
OK, we're on our way.
- You said she went to her mother's.
- She said that,
but a telegram has just arrived,
asking where she is.
Here.
She took her keys with her.
Is that her?
Yeah.
There has to be an explanation, right?
- What? - Maybe she made an excuse
that she was going to see her mom,
when in fact she went to see a boyfriend.
- When did she leave?
- On Saturday, it's been ten days.
- What time exactly?
- I don't know, around the evening.
- There's no bus from Drahovice on Saturday evening.
- She went hitchhiking on the highway.
She always travels like that.
What was she wearing?
Gray dress, white purse...
- And a light-colored suitcase.
- Is anything missing from here?
- Hmm, I don't know.
- Did she take any money with her?
- Yeah.
- Do you know how much?
She asked me for an advance payment
of 1000 crowns, but I don't know.
- Is anyone else living here?
- Me.
There's an arched room behind that door.
Kitchen and bedroom are in the back.
What next?
What if she doesn't come back?
Should I keep waiting?
- Keep waiting for now. - Easy for you to say,
but who's going to take care of the paychecks?
Someone is watching us
with binoculars from that barn.
That's Michal, our nutcase. He's got himself
a telescope and now he's always watching others.
Hey, tell that rascal of yours that
if he keeps watching people from up there in the barn
I'll push him off.
That's his grandma.
Do you think I should get a substitute
for the time being?
She may come back,
but the paychecks, you know...
You might. Did she have to go
through the woods to get to the highway?
Yeah.
Thank you. Go.
Through Christ, our Lord.
Amen.
Give her eternal rest, oh Lord.
And let an eternal light shine for her.
May she rest in peace.
Amen.
Nothing, Comrade Major.
She would have come to the surface already.
Should we keep looking?
Yeah, down through Duby
all the way to the highway.
Duby? Is that the trail
where Brychová was attacked?
Yes. In the woods.
That Kramárová must have passed
Válek's weekend house, right?
If she really went to the highway,
then yes.
Wait a second... that hunk from Prague
must have seen her then.
He was definitely here on Saturday
two weeks ago.
I was there, but I didn't see her.
Where do you know Kramárová from anyway?
She went to see Marcela a few times,
that's all I know.
She must have passed Válek's weekend house
on Saturday two weeks ago.
You were there then.
You were even sitting outside
between four and six.
Look, I could have told you
that I was asleep or something.
But I was outside and she didn't
pass the house.
Do you want me to plead guilty
just because of your beautiful eyes?
After all, you had
also tried to deny Brychová.
If you weren't a fuzz you would
have done the same thing in my spot.
If they found a woman dead in the woods
half an hour after you talked...
...after you talked with her, you would
try anything to avoid them pinning it on you.
She was pregnant with your child.
- She hadn't told me that until that talk in the woods.
- And how did you react?
I've already told you for Christ's sake!
I promised her that I would take care of it in Prague.
And where did you accompany her afterwards?
Nowhere!
We joined hands and then she went off.
For how long have you been coming here?
Since spring, right?
I see, you'll pin that Menšíková
on me as well.
- Now you'll pin everything on me, won't you?
- Watch your mouth!
What about that teen with binoculars
who's pretending to tend horses while eyeing every woman?
Or that gamekeeper whose wife is one
foot in grave, but he keeps dying his hair?
- He does it for the squirrels, I suppose?
- Watch it.
You wish.
While some hooligan is out there killing women,
you'd have me quietly wait here
until you're finished sewing a rope for me.
You can go now, Mr. Kyncl.
Go ahead.
What is it?
The analysis of Kyncl's clothes.
No traces of blood.
That might be just luck, right?
Brychová didn't bleed much.
I know, you would love to pin
it on Kyncl and go home, huh?
But why Kyncl of all people?
With Brychová he kind of had
a reason to do it.
Think about it please.
Brychová comes to see him at the weekend house on Sunday.
She leaves with him in front of Válková to the woods
and he comes back by himself.
Would you murder so stupidly?
Thank you.
And what about the other two women?
Why would he attack them?
He can have all the women he wants.
Unlike us.
I suggest that you speak for yourselves
gentlemen.
Hello.
Yes.
Yes?
Comrade Major.
It was buried in a haystack.
It's hers.
But... she also had a suitcase.
We'll have to comb it through here again.
Did you find anything else in the haystack?
What about that convertor?
Have them try to break it open.
He could have buried her in the ground.
He would have needed more time for that.
And tools.
Menšíková had been found lying in the ditch under
the bridge. He had simply dragged her there.
- Who knew about the advance payment?
- She came to see me
- one time when I was in the barn.
- Who was there at the time?
Wait a second, there were Ferdyš, Bauerová,
Mlejnková and... Michal.
Hey! Comrade Major!
Come here!
DISSECTING ROOM
- So what do you make out of it?
- It's perfectly clear, young men.
Death occured about 11 days ago,
and it's virtually same as with Menšíková.
Clear signs of sexual assault,
deadly blow to a temple,
from behind,
with a stone or something of that kind.
Interesting.
Are you surprised?
It's starting to look like it was the same guy.
Only based on the way they were killed,
other than that it doesn't really fit.
For example, Menšíková was raped,
Kramárová as well,
- but Brychová wasn't.
- Wait a second.
You said something about a storm with the last one.
Perhaps it distracted him.
Storm?
I doubt that.
Also, Kramárová was robbed.
- That doesn't rule out...
- But it muddles it.
After all, Menšíková had more than 200 crowns with her.
He could have taken Brychová's golden watch and ring,
but he didn't. Why?
I wouldn't want your job.
Likewise, Doctor, likewise.
Drive to the farm.
What there?
The boy with binoculars.
Where did he get them?
He could have bought them.
Does he make that much money?
If so, I'm going to tend horses from now on.
You're going to look around
here again?
You've been here for almost a week,
and it doesn't seem to do any good.
You can join us,
we need capable people.
Seriously, it's been too much already.
Ever since that thing with the accountant happened,
I have my female workers running away from their jobs.
One of them is down with fever.
The doctor from the health centre is with her just now.
Did you want anything?
Is that boy here now?
Michal?
He's just got back, why?
Can we see his grandmother?
But no fuss,
we don't want to scare anyone.
- I'll be on my way.
- Yep.
Good afternoon.
The binoculars? He hasn't had them
for more than 3 days, not before Monday.
- Do you know where he bought them?
- Bought them? His grandma takes
the few crowns he makes right away.
Do you think it was him
who killed Kramárová?
You were there when we found her -
she didn't have the money on her.
Oh my god.
We're no thieves.
What do you think?
I've never taken anything.
And neither has Míša.
We're not suspecting you,
Mrs. Horáková.
- But you might know where did Michal get
the binoculars from. - How should I know.
He said he'd found them.
- Found them? Where?
- He didn't say.
I don't know what's so strange
about that.
- Is Michal here?
- No.
Sometimes he sleeps here.
- Is this your boy's?
- Yeah.
What are you looking for anyway?
Money, matron.
Maybe he's hiding it somewhere,
and you don't even know.
He doesn't have any. I put away what he
earns on to his deposit book.
Get that boy.
- What is it? Do you want anything?
- Me? No.
- Do you know where did Michal get the binoculars from?
- I don't know.
If I were in charge I would have
thrown him out long ago, the fucker.
I knew it was going to end
like that one day.
Hey!
When I came here,
he was already lying here.
Maybe he can still come around.
Should I go get the doctor?
That can't be.
His hands are still warm.
How could this happen?
- I told him not to climb up there.
- You promised him you'd push him off.
Me? God, I would...
- Damn.
- Is anything up there?
Nothing.
- May I...
- Go ahead.
And not a word to anyone yet.
You can see inside the barn from
up there.
He probably realized he was in trouble,
so he wanted to get away quickly,
and fell down.
Damn, I think I should ask for a transfer.
Three murders,
and now the mess with Michal.
What are we going to say to those people?
That it was him who'd done
those women in?
We'll wait for the old-timer.
Good morning.
I almost overslept.
It's been a while since
I laid on a bed this lousy.
What's going on?
Nothing, Comrade Major.
We interrogated people from the farm
almost until the morning, and...
no one knows anything.
Nothing about the binoculars either.
And we haven't found
anything in the barn.
- It looks like he really did fall by himself.
- Are those the autopsy findings?
Yeah. Broken spine and spinal cord...
Death by a fall from a great height.
- Did you find Kramárová's suitcase?
- No.
But I have people still working there.
Could you get us coffee?
I didn't take the boy into account.
We should have been interested in him sooner.
It's always better to convict
a murderer alive.
He would've confessed only after
we found that money anyway.
- Where could have he hidden that suitcase?
- Where?
Shouldn't we ask 'why' instead?
Why did he clear away Kramárová's things
so meticulously
and left Brychová with her
purse spilled?
- You can't expect a nutter to have a system.
- He had one.
He was killing in the same way.
It's strange.
Everyone at the farm was suspicious of the boy.
Why didn't Král throw him out long ago?
You're right.
The supervisor is a great man.
If it wasn't for him
Míša and I wouldn't be here long ago.
He would always stand up for us.
Now that Míša's dead,
it doesn't matter anymore.
Have you known Král for long, Mrs. Horáková?
Ever since he's become the supervisor here.
It's been almost 8 years.
- Sometimes I wash his clothes and cook for him...
- Why would Král stand up for you?
What?
For Míša,
when they called him names.
Did he like him that much?
I... don't know, but he couldn't stand
the others blaming Míša.
Like what?
Why, he never hurt anyone.
Not even that Radka.
Radka?
The one from the castle?
Someone punched her in the head in the woods,
and he thought it was Míša who did it.
When did that happen?
- Last year, but no one knows.
- And how do you know?
From the supervisor.
He came to me then and said
that it must have been Míša.
And how did it end?
I was afraid, that he was
really going to do something to him.
Was Míša home when that happened?
He came later, but he swore
that he didn't even see the girl.
Call Král.
The old woman probably doesn't have a clue.
That boy must have started this
last year already.
And Král kept quiet.
Here. Just behind the little cross.
- What happened?
- Well... I've told you.
She came by in the evening,
I gave her a bag of eggs, and she left.
I was on the yard getting my motorbike
into the outhouse,
when I heard screaming. I ran here,
and she was lying there on the ground.
I heard someone running towards
the quarry.
Did you recognize him?
I was only concerned about her at that moment.
- Was she unconscious?
- She couldn't speak.
She was just shaking and crying from shock.
She had only a scratch.
And you're telling us now?
- Why didn't you report it right away?
- You'd say that it's rubbish, I know how it works.
- How can you know?
- How? Imagine what would happen.
Radka was already so agitated,
and with all the protocols...
You know how people are, everyone would make up
this and that, and the girl could never even marry.
Yes. Someone kills three women with a stone
and you don't even think of bringing
Michal forward.
I thought about it only after Kramárová was found.
It had not occured to me with Brychová.
And then I was afraid that you would
go after me for reporting it late.
- But...
- Wait a second. Did Radka identify Michal?
He jumped on her from behind, rascal.
It couldn't have been anyone else anyway.
Thank you.
He must like that Radka.
Why isn't he married?
Did he have an affair with Kramárová?
He was always around her at first,
but I don't if there was anything more.
I asked the people at the farm,
but can you expect them to tell you anything?
They're all scared shitless.
Are you here to see me?
We're always troubling you, aren't we?
You're here because of Radka, I know.
- My brother has already called me.
- Really?
Who could have known back then?
It didn't seem like a big deal.
You don't rush to a police station
with that sort of thing.
It would have only made my brother trouble
for keeping a delinquent.
- Could we speak with her?
- She wouldn't tell you anything.
Is she sitting outside all the time?
Won't she catch a cold?
We've been telling her to go out for a walk,
but she likes to sit next to her room the best.
- That's my wife.
- Good afternoon.
- Králová.
These are the gentlemen from Prague
who are investigating here.
They came here because of Radka, they want
to talk with her. About that thing...
What do you want with her?
- We would only ask her a few questions,
if we may. - I've told them
that they're not going to get anything
from her.
We could try, couldn't we?
Go ahead.
- Doctor.
- Yes?
Could you please tell me
what time it is?
- Half past five.
- Half past?
Yes.
Thank you. Good night.
Radka?
Radka, open the door.
Can you hear me?
Come on and open the door, Radka.
Radka!
Open the door.
She locks her room all the time.
Would you leave us with her
for a moment?
Can't we stay?
We're not going to hurt her.
- But...
- Please.
- Why should you be afraid, Radka?
- Go away.
Look,
we came here to ask for your help.
Will you?
Can you remember what happened
that time
when you went home from your
uncle's by yourself?
You know what I'm talking about.
He doesn't remember exactly,
but perhaps you could? Huh?
Someone wanted to hurt you.
Correct?
Are you sure they didn't?
Come on, who was it?
Did you see him?
Was it Michal from the farm?
Well?
Look if it wasn't him,
then this is the last thing
you can do for him.
Was it him?
There's something wrong with that girl.
Why is she glued to that balcony
like that?
- The boy passed away, so...
- Exactly.
What is she afraid of?
- Where did they find it?
- It was buried in a pile of stones.
Thousand crowns.
- The advance payment for the road.
- How can that be?
- Why, it was Michal...
- He had nothing to do with Kramárová.
He'd gotten the money from somewhere else.
But then, maybe he didn't
fall from the ladder...
And what if it wasn't him who attacked Radka?
Wait a second, the girl knows who's the killer.
Comrade Major.
Is Radka home?
- I'm just on my way to go shopping.
- Answer the question, is she home?
- Yes, she's in her room, but...
- Is she alone?
Yeah, my husband went out.
Did something happen?
No, but it might.
Did anyone ask to see Radka?
- Did anyone ask to talk with her?
- Not that I know of.
- Radka!
- Don't call her!
Anyone could have got inside.
The door on the first floor can't be locked.
We've never locked our doors.
This is crazy.
- Have someone keep a guard on Radka.
No one is to go in. - Sure.
Who came here today?
Here? Just the gamekeeper
before you came here.
- He brought my wife a hare.
- And after us?
Just the doctor from the health centre.
He forgot his keys in the office.
And wasn't your brother here as well?
Yeah, I forgot about that.
So what happened?
Two days ago, just as we start looking
for Michal at the farm,
he falls off a ladder.
Yesterday we first started to be concerned
with Radka,
and it has nearly cost her her life.
Perhaps someone really did
push Michal off?
Wait a second.
Suppose that he didn't take
the money from Kramárová,
- but that someone had given it to him.
- For what?
For what?
Perhaps for keeping quiet.
And what about the murders?
That's exactly it.
It confused us that there were three similar murders
and three different motives.
First, a sexual one, then a robbery,...
and finally, both.
That's true.
Kramárová wasn't robbed, which leaves
just a rape, as with Menšíková.
And what about Brychová?
Doctor from the dissecting room said that
the perpetrator might have been distracted by a storm.
But what if it was something else
that distracted him?
The boy from the farm.
- Damn.
- He was always around,
so suppose that he saw what happened.
What could the killer do?
He leaves Brychová lying on the ground
and runs after the boy.
Brychová crawls in the bushes
where she succumbs to her injuries,
the killer returns, but he can't
find her in the rain and the dark.
And would he have let the boy go?
There's killing and then there's killing.
He could have killed the women
in a state of trance,
but he'd had to kill Michal
with a clear head.
One doesn't easily find courage
to do that.
Wait a second.
That murder happened on Sunday.
On Monday, Michal gets the binoculars
and perhaps even the money.
That could've worked.
But those things could have kept him
quiet only for so long.
Then he saw us coming in the barn,
so he made sure that Michal would be quiet for good.
Who knew that you were looking for Michal?
- The Král brothers, the gamekeeper...
- The doctor from the health centre?
It could have been anyone.
He could have hidden there and hear us.
Do you think it was the same person
the whole time?
Looks like it.
- And what about Radka?
- I consider her case separately.
It might be where everything had started.
The attack on the girl might have been
his first attempt.
Of course, I'm only a psychiatrist.
That's why we came for your advice.
The following cases show
that the killer's sexual drive was stronger
than the fear from being exposed.
Perhaps he hadn't had sufficient
opportunities for an intercourse.
And the stereotypical way of killing
suggests that he is a habitual offender.
Such cases are, unfortunately, not that rare.
And could you conjure up an
image of the perpetrator?
Perhaps a mental one, but I doubt
that would be of much use to you.
Why? On the contrary.
Well.
Based on the way he killed,
I would guess that he's a man with no imagination.
A primitive.
And based on who he killed,
I would say that he's an older person,
a person of a flawed character.
He may be aware that his victims
would reject him under normal circumstances.
He might be in his fifties,
a widower,
a husband of a woman who had aged prematurely...
That's probably all I can tell you.
Thank you, doctor.
I think it's starting to look more clear.
And as for the girl...
If she was the first victim, she's the only one
who survived the killer's attack.
Why doesn't she talk, then?
That's hard to say.
It's mutism as a result of a great shock.
Fear of men.
It's a trauma, perhaps for life.
Is there any way to get her out of it?
If it was that easy, I would have already
suggested a way.
But it's too risky.
Doctor, there have been four murders already
and others may follow.
Isn't that risky?
Make the people go about their own business,
we don't want any drama here.
The snow is just what we needed.
- Listen...
- What is it?
Could you tell me what good will this do?
Do you want that girl to become
even more insane?
Leave that up to us, Mr. Král.
Excuse me, but why have you dragged me here?
Because of some fallen balcony?
Look, doctor, sometimes we do things
that are beyond all understanding,
forgive us for that.
That's all, comrade major, I'm taking
three of my people with me, is that enough?
That depends on them.
- What is this all about anyway?
- I don't know, they want you here.
Come this way please.
Don't be afraid of anything, Radka,
we're going to do what we talked about.
You'll be walking like a year ago, okay?
You were returning from your uncle's,
you're holding a bag...
Is that how it was?
And now go.
Walk just as you did that time.
And you'll show us where it happened, okay?
Nothing can happen to you,
look how many of us are here.
Relax, Radka. Walk slowly...
Don't turn around, we're here.
No, Dad, I don't want to!
I don't want to...
I don't want to. I don't want to...
Stop!
Stop! Hold it!
You can't get away!
Jirka!
Stop it!
Watch it!
You knew.
Yes.
I know.
THE END