AN ACTOR PREPARES
- Is it an accident?
- What happened?
- I'll go and see.
- Let's take a look.
- Is everything all right?
- He fainted.
- Hurry.
- That's not good.
- Sir, where are you hurting?
- It hurts.
- Where?
- I don't know. Everywhere.
- Let me help you get up.
- I can't move. It's too painful.
- He is here.
- Is it there?
Is this a scam? Is it real?
- Hello, is this emergency service?
- It must be fake.
- I'm here at Dapeng.
- Is it a scam?
Is it real?
Sir.
I'm also an actor.
Your acting is not good.
The key to a scam is the feeling of pain.
You're not showing enough emotion.
It's not convincing enough.
- Gosh.
- Look at you.
Even your moan is so frivolous.
You were hit by a car.
You can't just moan like that.
Of course, you can't succeed.
Otherwise, the audiences
won't sympathize with you.
Gosh. It really hurts.
No, sir. Your acting is terrible.
Let me show you.
Gosh.
It hurts...
Sir, you're doing it too fast.
Fainting is fine, but it has a process.
For example, hold onto your head...
The blood looks real.
Too bad your acting was bad
in the beginning.
You've already lost your credibility.
I'm just sharing some tips with you.
Don't take it personally, sir.
The ambulance is here.
- Make way.
Mild fracture in the left chest,
third rib bone, not life-threatening.
Come on.
That's so serious.
Hurry.
- Ready, up.
- Up.
- Be careful.
- Okay.
I'm so sorry, sir.
Is the lady his family member?
She is a lunatic. Ignore her.
What happened?
- Help.
- Help!
- My leg!
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
Don't you know how to act?
You're in pain. Why aren't you screaming?
Do you know how to act?
Well, in my own experience,
when people are in pain,
they don't always scream out loud.
What the hell are you talking about?
Sir, please come over.
Could you act out a painful reaction?
This is fake.
Do me a favor.
This is real. There is no sound, right?
Please talk to the director.
Director, what do you think?
- I...
- Director?
You...
- Three.
Get the hell out.
What happened?
- She was thrown out.
- Thrown out?
- What happened to her?
- Who knows.
- I don't know.
- What's happening?
- Hey!
- He is here.
I need an extra to play as a corpse.
You must keep the makeup on for two days.
- Who wants to go?
- How much?
It's 400 dollars for two days.
- Add more.
- That's too little. Add some more.
I'll go.
Can I play a role that can show my face?
Are you bargaining with me?
You don't have to pay me. A meal is fine.
- Okay. Let's go.
- Is she doing it for free?
She is crazy.
- Yes.
- There's something wrong with her.
Come on, let's eat.
The food is getting cold.
Gosh. It's your birthday today.
If you don't start eating,
no one else will.
Dad.
Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday.
Dreamy, your makeup is very unique today.
It's quite terrifying.
Is filming fun?
I get to play a corpse this time.
There's a close-up,
so I can show my acting skills.
How could you even show
your acting skills by playing a corpse?
Dad, death makes
an interesting context for actors.
Imagine.
If you were to die now
and your whole body turns stiff...
What did you say?
I dare you to say it again.
Birthdays should be a happy occasion.
Dreamy, stop the nonsense.
Go and remove your makeup.
But I still have a shoot tomorrow.
Do you really think
you're a famous movie star?
You guys grew up together, right?
Look at Bobby.
He is now a big-time lawyer.
It's nothing much. Nothing to brag about.
And look at Peggy.
She lives a happy life now.
She married a good husband.
Look at you.
We'd hoped you would become a lawyer.
Not a corpse.
Everyone has their own specialty.
A lawyer and a corpse make no distinction.
I can support myself even if I'm an extra.
I have my own dreams too.
You're already 30 years old.
You've been an extra for over a decade.
Have you ever played the lead?
I believe that with my talents,
if I work hard,
I can definitely be the lead actress.
Sorry.
- Mom, do you believe in me?
- Yes, you can do it.
That's bullshit!
It's all your fault. You've spoiled her!
I'm giving you one last chance.
Take that thing off your head!
I can't.
Then, I'll add one more for you.
Here. You asked for it.
Wait a second.
Never mind.
Your emotions are so inspiring.
Dad, hold the cleaver and hop again.
I want to record this.
Ready, jump.
- You've gone too far.
- Gosh.
Look at her.
- What are you doing?
- Aunt, we'll leave now.
- I'm sorry.
- Get out.
I've never given birth to you!
Take your trash with you.
But Dad, those are all your trash.
I don't give a damn.
You total bum.
Get the hell out of here.
Enough.
Stop it.
It's all your fault.
Enough!
Hey!
Can anyone act here?
- Yes.
- I can.
Hey, you. Show me.
Do a happy reaction.
A sad reaction.
All right, come with me.
Hey, who can do an angry look?
- Me.
You.
No way. Get lost.
You try.
Okay, come along.
Anyone, act like you've got hit
by the ultimate power.
- Me.
- You try.
Director, can you specify
the type of the move?
What's with all the questions?
Get lost if you can't do it.
- How about Icy Palm Attack?
- Okay, Icy Palm Attack.
It's so cold.
It's freezing.
Go see a doctor if you're sick.
I don't want to get infected.
You. Try.
Why are you dragging me here?
I'm not going.
I just want to bring her some soup.
You made soup for her?
Are you on her side?
You can just pretend
we're passing by to see her.
If I see her, I'm going to hit her.
Don't stop me.
- Or else, I'll hit you too.
- Idiot.
You're asking for it.
What's wrong with you?
Just do the acting.
Why do you need to know everything?
It's you every time.
I just want to build up my character.
Build my ass.
No one will even notice you.
Do you think you are the lead?
Even if I give you the context,
would you even get it?
If you could get it,
you won't be just an extra here.
Go, come with me!
- That was intense.
- Yes, indeed.
- Hello.
- What is it?
- Could you speak nicely?
- What?
The actor was just asking you a question,
why would you get mad at her?
What does that have to do with you?
She is so serious about acting.
Can't you see that?
- Who's that?
- You know who I'm talking about!
God is watching what you're doing.
Be careful of the karma.
You have some nerves.
Production assistant!
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
- Do you know who I am?
- No.
That's good.
What a lunatic.
Hello.
Your acting for Icy Palm Attack
was intensely sensational.
It hit the mark.
It was passable.
The key is imagination.
Immerse yourself into the scene.
That's amazing.
I'm Young.
I'm Dreamy.
- You're reading this book too?
- Yes.
Do you like "King of Comedy" too?
Of course. I love it so much.
Do you want to try acting?
- Right here?
- Sure.
Hey.
What is it?
Are you leaving?
Yes.
- Where are you going?
- Home.
- And then?
- Off to work.
Can you not go to work?
Are you going to feed me if I don't work?
Hey.
What now?
I'll feed you.
My boyfriend is here.
Hey, that's the wrong line.
No, my boyfriend is really here.
See you.
Who's that guy?
- A colleague.
- Really?
Yes. Let's go.
You can have my sausage.
Let's share it.
I've earned 4,000 dollars this month.
Let's deposit it into our wedding fund.
You only make 5,000 dollars
at most a month.
How would you survive
if you give me 4,000 dollars?
One thousand dollars is enough for me.
I have free catered meals for casts.
Let me contribute 4,500 dollars.
You can take 500 dollars.
Take it easy. We agreed to half each.
I thought my love for you was deeper.
But it turns out,
your love for me is just as deep.
Are you really giving him your money?
Yes.
Then, why don't you give it to me?
I'm not getting married to you.
You might as well be with me then.
- Lend me your soap.
- Okay.
Why do you keep staring at Mimi?
Do you like her?
It pisses me off when you say that.
Looking at her doesn't mean I like her.
I despise her from the bottom of my heart.
She is so cheap.
Don't you think Mimi's pretty?
Beauty means nothing.
She is just an eye candy.
- Do you know why I love you?
- Why?
Because you have good taste.
Of course.
Dear.
I want to introduce you to my parents.
They'll be so relieved
to know we are together.
That's for sure.
Actually, I've been busy
with a big project lately.
When I accomplish this,
your parents will definitely
be so proud of me.
Not to brag,
but I, Charlie, will be
the next Bill Gates.
You want to be number one
when you just started?
How about you be more realistic and go
for number two or three first?
I am very humble and realistic.
- How many eyes does Bill Gates have?
- Two.
- Then, how many eyes do I have?
He doesn't have more
and I don't have any less.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
Whatever he can do, I'm capable of it too.
Absolutely right.
Listen to me.
You must believe you're the best.
You're not in the second or third place.
You are the number one.
Stop thinking about the web series.
You should go for
the international blockbuster movies.
Actually, an international production
is looking for Chinese actors.
That's your chance.
But they're looking for Snow White.
- You're Snow White.
- Me?
- How many eyes does Snow White have?
- Two.
- How many eyes do you have?
So, why can't you be Snow White?
Tell me. Why not?
Tell me!
Don't just keep staring at me.
Say it!
Does it make sense at all?
You are Snow White!
Hey, do you really want
to get beauty injections?
Yes, Snow White is a Western classic.
I wish to westernize my face.
You've even thought of that.
Those famous actors do it all the time.
Marlon Brando went all out
to get the role in The Godfather.
He took great pains with his face.
Bullshit. It's just an excuse
to get cosmetic surgery.
You guys just don't get it.
Getting prettier is surely a good thing.
I found an amazing beauty application.
SoYoung Medical Aesthetic App.
SOYOUNG MEDICAL AESTHETIC APP
It stores wholesome information
and various cases.
I actually know a well-known
80-year-old brand.
- Where is it?
Pig liver, pig brain and pig intestine.
- Have a look.
Here we are.
- Five hundred dollars.
- Have a look.
Doctor, I bring a new customer to you.
Fresh shrimp, come and have a look.
- It's fresh.
- Have a look.
Please come again.
What would you like to do?
I want to look like her.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
But it's my first time,
so I'm a bit nervous.
It's also my first time doing this style.
I'm a bit nervous too.
You do Chinese faces more often, right?
Honestly, I usually do
human looks more often.
Do you want the hair too?
What hair?
The whole body is hairy.
Right. They're hairier than we are.
But usually, most people won't notice.
It's hard not to notice.
You're so professional.
But I'll just skip the hair.
What a shame.
The effect will only last for two days.
It's simple. It can be done quickly.
Doctor, I want a tall, upward nose.
Any more upwards and your nostrils
will be as big as a yin-yang hotpot.
Yin-yang hotpot?
Whatever, as long as you like it.
Doctor.
Why do you keep looking at that gorilla?
I need to look at it,
so that I'll know what to do.
Why?
You wanted this gorilla look, right?
No, it's not that. I wanted this.
Why didn't you say that earlier?
- I want a mirror.
- Hey.
Don't look. You won't be able to take it.
Relax, let me fix it. Just lie down.
All right, it's done.
How is it? Let me take a look...
What should I do now?
- It's gorgeous.
- How gorgeous?
Too gorgeous to look at.
It's much better now.
AUDITION ROOM ONE
Number 16.
SNOW WHITE AUDITION
LINE UP HERE
Wait there.
What do you want?
I'm here for the audition.
Which role?
Snow White.
Why?
Because I want to audition
for the role of Snow White.
Could you please repeat that?
Why should I repeat it so many times?
I'm not sure if I heard you right.
I'm here to audition for Snow White.
Come again.
Never mind, excuse me.
Stay there.
Stop that woman.
Don't let her go.
Stop her.
- Don't run.
- Stop her. Catch her.
- Stop!
- Catch her!
- Don't run.
- Chase her!
- Don't run!
- Stop!
- Catch her!
- Are you still running?
- Still running?
Where are you running off to?
I'm so sorry. It's my fault.
I shouldn't have come.
Boss, take a look.
What do you think?
That's the one.
No.
I won't do it again.
- Neck, 33 inches.
- Dismiss.
- Get to work.
Sleeve, 60 inches.
Loosen the clothes here.
What's going on?
Don't move.
Please tell me what's going on.
You got the role.
What?
Director.
- We're almost ready.
- I got the role?
We're ready, Director.
- If the actor is ready, come to the scene.
- Okay.
The actors, go to the scene.
May I know what this scene is about?
Stay calm. We'll tell you after we shoot.
What's the character's emotional state?
Don't worry about it.
You'll find out after this. Actor, on set.
- Hurry.
Okay. Stay here.
Next one.
Over there.
- Hurry.
- This one.
Don't move. Wait.
- Ready.
- Come here.
- Camera.
- That way.
Okay. Switch to the actor.
Lose the double.
Actor, ready for your lines.
Take her away. Hurry up.
Move aside.
I'm not afraid.
Beat me to death!
Okay. Keep going.
Actor, take a break. Double, take over.
Sir, you've worked hard.
Turn around.
- Tilt your head. Stay sharp.
- Come on. Hold up your finger.
Lift up your finger. Get ready to shoot.
Okay, face the camera.
Switch.
Action!
I can't believe you really killed me.
Wonderful.
The seven dwarves have finally
avenged Snow White.
This is so touching.
Director, aren't I supposed
to be Snow White?
- What the hell are you doing?
- Get lost.
- Sorry, Director.
- Sorry.
Director.
Director, sorry.
- Ready for Snow White's scene.
- Yes.
Mr. Marco.
Tell that washed-up actor to hurry up.
We're waiting for him.
Who's the washed-up actor?
Me.
Watch your mouth.
SNOW WHITE, BLOODBATH IN CHINATOWN
Make way. Mr. Marco is coming.
Director, please pick
the female version of Snow White.
Any pretty face will do.
There's only one shot.
Attention. Mr. Marco is here.
Mr. Marco is here. Make way.
Attention. Mr. Marco is here. Make way.
Get out of the way.
Mr. Marco is here.
Mr. Marco, in this scene,
you will be playing Snow White.
You were set up by the evil witch.
You ate a poisonous banana
and then, you became a man.
The prince was too drunk to notice
and he slept with you.
- Did I do him? Or did he do me?
- Both ways.
When the prince woke up,
he found out you were a man.
He couldn't accept it,
so he tried to kill you.
But it ended up that you killed him.
The prince's men tracked you down
all the way.
You ran to Chinatown
and was attacked by them.
You were badly hurt.
Your guts came spilling out.
Isn't that too cruel?
Actually, I want to pay homage
to Zhang Che's aesthetic of violence.
Zhang Che, aesthetic of violence.
- Do you get it?
- Fine.
It's not that. Did you get it or not?
- What do you think?
- It's hard to say.
Of course, I get it. It's violent, right?
This is perfect.
Let's do the scene when you get stabbed
and you're angry. Okay?
Okay, let's begin.
Okay.
Mr. Marco, let me set up the props.
Camera!
Take one.
I...
I am so angry.
Mr. Marco, can you try
to look really angry?
I've already said I'm angry.
- You all heard it, right?
- Yes.
Director, only you
didn't hear what I said.
Do you think I'm lying?
It's hard to say.
Then, don't say anything.
No one is forcing you.
Can you be more girly?
I thought so too.
I'm a princess after all.
I was waiting for you to say it.
I am so angry.
I am really...
Damn it.
What the hell is this?
Cut. Wrong lines.
Director, what kind of line is this?
How did my guts become hot dogs?
Mr. Marco, listen to me.
A New Year film can't be too violent.
- What about all that violence aesthetic?
- The aesthetic of violence.
Attention, everyone.
Mr. Marco is pissed off.
Something big happens.
- My acting was so good.
- Mr. Marco is pissed off.
Why can't you just cooperate?
Our target audience includes children.
The aesthetic of violence can also
bring out the innocence.
Seeing my guts as hotdogs,
I almost burst out laughing.
How can I get into character?
It's all about commercial consideration.
It's complicated.
You're an amazing actor.
The hotdogs won't be a problem for you.
Of course, it won't.
But you're insulting
the audience's intelligence.
New Year movie, my ass.
You might as well add a cute kidney.
- Props. Get me a kidney.
- Copy that.
Okay. Right away.
Director, would this work?
Dip it into the ketchup and let's see.
Hold this higher later.
- This is the one.
- Ready. Actors in position.
Why hasn't it cut yet?
I'm worn out.
Attention everyone.
Mr. Marco is here. Make way.
Attention. Mr. Marco is here.
Stupid director, making a stupid movie.
The old me would have slapped him.
Why don't you do it now?
I'm a classy gentleman now.
What are you laughing at?
- There's nothing here.
- Okay.
- Enough.
- Move there.
What's your problem?
Are you mocking me?
How dare you mock me?
What's so funny?
Attention, everybody. Mr. Marco is angry.
Something big is happening.
He is so scary.
Mr. Marco is angry.
Dreamy.
Is it really you?
- Young?
- Yes.
Is this special makeup?
Yes.
What happened just now?
Nothing.
You can have my meal.
It's okay.
Excuse me, sir.
Can I have an extra one, please?
One for each person.
You are just an extra.
Don't be so greedy all the time.
Get lost.
If you dare to come back,
I'll call the cops.
I've told you guys earlier.
God is watching everything you do.
Why are you always so mean?
What?
Aren't those lunch boxes for eating?
What the hell?
Tell me.
Answer me.
What is it? What answer do you want?
Aren't those lunch boxes for eating?
Yes, so what?
- Why didn't she get one?
- Who?
That girl with special effect makeup.
- Answer me.
- Okay.
- Okay. Don't be like this.
- Why didn't she get one?
- Calm down.
- Okay.
Gosh. Why did you hit yourself
with a bottle?
I couldn't hit him, could I?
Didn't you see how big he was?
You are indeed...
Did you see our daughter?
No.
And we're just leaving?
Go.
Well...
Do you know?
I saw Marco on set the other day.
- Who's Marco?
- It's Marco.
- Who?
- Never mind.
He was in a bad mood.
He kicked away my lunch box.
So, I asked for another lunchbox,
but they refused.
But suddenly, when I was leaving,
he gave me one.
Does this mean good luck
is coming on my way?
You're just an extra,
don't think too much.
Have some respect for extras.
Many stars started as extras.
Sun Li, Carina Lau, Zhao Liying.
Are you as talented as they are?
We're all special in our own ways.
I work harder than they do.
I don't know what to say.
Anyway, opportunities are reserved
for the hardworking people.
It's impossible that I would be discovered
just by standing on the streets, right?
Excuse me, miss.
Would you like to be in a movie?
Who are you?
She is a famous producer.
Hi, I'm Dreamy. I'm an actor.
Hi, we're looking for actors in our movie.
Are you interested?
Yes, I want to try.
Sorry, it's not you.
It's you.
- Me?
- Yes.
Give it a try?
Our company is just over there.
No worries.
At least, you tried.
Don't be sad.
They picked me as the female lead.
Really?
I don't know how to act.
Why would they pick me?
I went in and they removed my makeup.
I only said two lines.
Then, I am chosen. What should I do now?
What do you mean?
It's a great opportunity.
If it were me, I would trade
50 years of my life for this chance.
But I don't want it.
I'm so scared.
I don't want to be an actor.
It's okay.
Don't cry.
I'm so innocent.
I can't let
the entertainment industry ruin me.
I don't mind to be ruined.
Perhaps you can recommend me to them.
I've already told them.
I asked them to let you in,
but they said they would rather die.
They would rather die?
Yes, they said they would rather die.
- They would rather die.
- What should I do?
- Mr. Huang from Hong Kong was here today.
- The car is over there.
Okay. Is everything fine?
- Don't worry. Everything is ready.
- Hi.
- You're still here?
- Thank you for giving me the chance.
- Do your best.
- Sure.
Do you want a ride?
Sure, I live nearby.
Take the back seat.
Mimi move out so soon?
She has moved everything.
She even took my soap and sanitary pads.
I've told you.
She is cheap.
I shouldn't have asked Mimi
to eat with me.
If I had gone there myself,
they would have picked me.
Even without Mimi,
they might not have picked you.
Aren't opportunities reserved
for the hardworking people?
It means that the opportunity
wasn't meant for you, but for Mimi.
But if she doesn't try her best,
she will eventually screw up.
Hang in there. You'll get the chance.
You're right. I'll try even harder.
I'll send out my CV all over China.
I want everyone to know
what acting actually means.
Well said.
Be positive.
I'm short on cash for my start-up,
but I still have hope.
- How much do you need?
- Twenty thousand dollars.
- How about you use the wedding fund?
- No.
If so, we would never get married.
Maybe I can work overtime
or get a part-time job.
Don't worry. Just do your part well.
Otherwise, I will feel bad.
- Get to work.
- Lighting department, hurry.
Help me to deliver that.
Sir.
- I have one here.
- Okay.
- Excuse me.
- Add three more.
Sir, I need money.
Do you have any work that pays more?
Pay more? Who do you think you are?
I can do anything.
I'm not picky about jobs.
- What is this?
- Help me. Please.
Thank you.
Are you kidding me?
Go away. I don't know what you're saying.
Who hired the double?
I beg you, miss. Please put on clothes.
- Get out.
- She is scary.
Sorry, Director. I didn't know
she'd look so bad without clothes.
Are you kidding?
Where do you find this kind of people?
Bad figure and saggy skin.
- She even has black stains on her ass.
- Sorry, Director.
You might as well ask me to do it.
- Go get me another one.
- Dreamy.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
The director said I have
a bad figure and saggy skin.
They begged me to put my clothes on.
I am really fine.
HIRING STUNT DOUBLE
HIRING EXTRAS FOR DROWNING SCENE
Come, hurry up.
Don't touch her.
Everyone, do it again
in the same angle. Okay!
Ready!
Start!
- Are you ready?
- In a minute.
- Director.
- Let me do this.
Do I need to move later?
Damn it. Have you ever seen
a moving statue?
- No.
- Why don't you use real statues?
Because they're too expensive. Get lost.
- Here.
- He is here.
Dreamy, are there any acting tips
to be a statue?
I see. Meditating to appear lifeless.
I'll try this.
- Everyone, stand by.
- Hurry. Let's begin.
This scene is about the prince waking up
and realizes that Snow White is a man.
Rolling.
Shot Four. Take One.
Who are you?
I'm Snow White.
Did I sleep with you?
What are you doing?
It's only lust for you, but love for me.
Why are you so upset?
Director, get someone
to explain the scene to him.
Come on. Let's do the close-up
of me killing him first.
- Mr. Marco, do you know your lines?
- Stop the nonsense. It's late!
Okay, ready.
What's the line?
"It's all the fault of my body.
You heartless man."
Okay, again.
It's all the fault of...
Whose fault is it?
- "It's all the fault of my body.
- You heartless man."
I got it. Okay.
It's all the fault...
of my boobs.
Sorry, Mr. Marco. It should be "body."
It's the same.
It's just a bit off.
The audience will understand.
We have a lot of underage audiences,
it'd better be pronounced accurately.
Kids don't care about pronunciation.
Why don't you say one, two, three?
We can dub the lines later.
You're letting me count the numbers?
Are you insulting me?
No, this is easier.
Easier? Why didn't you say this earlier?
You wasted my time, you damn fool.
Come on, shoot.
Ready.
One, two, three...
- One, two, three, four, five, six...
Got it. Roll.
One, two, three, four, five, six...
Eight...
- One, two, three, four, five, six...
Who wrote these lines?
It doesn't make any sense.
How can I memorize this?
My Chinese is not good.
Let's do it in English.
Okay. Ready.
What is he doing?
Mr. Marco, what's wrong with you?
Can't you understand simple English?
No, I don't.
And the way you were doing it...
Of course, you won't understand.
But if you insist, I'll tell you.
Attention, everyone.
Mr. Marco is giving acting lessons.
Something amazing is happening.
I killed my beloved by myself.
My emotions are extremely complicated.
Sad, fear, selfish, vanity, arrogant,
excited, shy and so on.
Those emotions...
The emotions intertwined.
Then, they leave.
Do you get it? You even cut me off.
I'm sorry. I thought
you were having a seizure.
Seizure?
My acting was amazing,
but you thought I was sick.
Didn't you guys see it?
Didn't you guys see my amazing acting?
Hey!
What are you doing?
I'm giving acting lessons
and yet you are sleep?
Sorry, Mr. Marco.
It's you again.
Here. Come here.
This statue is too clean. The texture is
not good. How can you film this?
None of your business. Go away.
I didn't sleep well last night.
I didn't intend to yawn.
Here. Get down on the ground.
Quickly.
You keep moving.
The texture is not good. You're way
too clean. How can they film this?
This won't look good.
Where's the dirt? Where's the texture?
It's no use. It's not dirty enough.
Fine. Don't use this statue anymore.
Don't look. Let's go.
- Hurry.
- Go.
Get to work. Stop looking.
Give this to him.
And this one.
That one.
Hello.
How are you recently? Is everything okay?
I'm pretty good, Mom.
Everything is fine.
That's good.
Remember to be humble
and learn from others.
You have said it so many times.
I remember.
Your dad and I are worried
that you will be bullied.
I won't.
Everyone likes me here. Really.
That's good to know.
By the way, Mom.
Is Dad still mad at me?
He is not.
Your dad is having a headache
and is resting now.
Please tell Dad that...
I love you both.
What did you say?
Say that again loudly.
Damn you. Get lost.
You should remove your makeup outside.
Are you touched?
Damn you.
What is it?
Are you touched?
Dreamy, are you okay?
Young.
Please stop asking me if I'm okay.
Your face...
They've gone too far.
What are you doing?
Don't make things more difficult for me.
I'm short of money. I need this job.
Why didn't you say it earlier?
Money is all I have.
How much do you need? I'll give it to you.
Stop joking around with me.
Who do you think you are?
- Can't you see I've reached rock bottom?
- I just want to help out.
If you really want to help,
just leave me alone.
I am sorry.
Wish I could fly a rocket
And fly you to the skies
Live together in outer space
Live for a thousand years
And be blissful every day
Having you by my side is endless fun
Being together with you
Is my pride and joy
Fear not the end of the world
When the storm comes
As long as I see you
It is like a thousand miles of sunshine
Having you around is joyful
And makes everything marvelous
Even plain water tastes sweet
Longing to be with you forever
I need you every minute
You are my sunlight
You are my breath
Dressing up for you
Feeling crazy for you
Being a fool for you
Screaming like a crazy person
Is joyful too
Having you by my side is endless fun
If I lose you one day
Blossoms would feel sad
I would desert the world
To live on an island
Carve a figure of the wood
In the memory of you
Live alone with the figure of you
-Having you around is joyful
-And makes everything marvelous
-Even plain water tastes sweet
-Longing to be with you forever
-I need you every minute
-You are my sunlight
-You are my breath
Mr. Marco, this is the first shot
of the entire movie.
You ate a poisonous banana
and you realized you've turned into a man.
I want you to show a deeper inner fear,
or this movie is doomed.
It's not like this...
I want true fear.
Show it to me then.
Try expressing it with your eyes.
What are you doing?
Do it again.
It truly feels...
If you keep doing this,
the movie will be doomed.
Do it again.
For example, it's...
Forget it. Take a break.
Well...
Get lost.
Hey.
How did it feel?
Are you unhappy?
It's hard to say.
We're all just trying to make
a living here. It's never easy.
Let's not give each other a hard time.
Why so serious?
Production assistant.
Give him some water to freshen up.
Director Su.
Mr. Marco.
Have you seen the news?
I'm busy with filming.
How would I have time?
Do you remember the female extra
you were yelling at?
Yes. What is it?
She is dead.
- How did she die?
- She hanged herself.
She wore a red dress
to show her deep grievance.
What is she doing there?
I don't see anyone.
That person in red
who is standing by the wall.
Can't you see her?
Mr. Marco, stop joking.
Hey.
Get a close-up of him looking scared.
Director, why am I looking at the wall?
It's not a wall. It's an ocean.
You're watching the ocean at an ice rink.
You see your crush, Mr. Marco.
You dare not look at him,
so you steal a glance at him.
Then, hide behind the wall
and steal a glance again. Got it?
Got it.
Now, have courage.
Give your love token,
the necklace to him happily.
This is for you.
Great. Cut!
This is perfect.
Director, he...
- He peed his pants. What should I do?
- Never mind, hold on.
Sorry, Mr. Marco. Don't be angry.
That was the expression I needed.
You can do it. Let's continue.
- Let's get ready...
- No.
- He gets angry.
- He peed his pants.
I need to go to the hospital.
Well...
You'd better think of a good way
to compensate me for this.
Sorry, Mr. Marco.
I just wanted a better effect.
You could've just told me how.
I'm an experienced actor.
It's not that I can't do it.
I kept asking and you kept failing.
So you came up with this terrible plan
to deal with me?
Attention, everyone.
Mr. Marco pissed his pants.
What did you just say?
Attention, everyone.
Mr. Marco did not piss his pants.
They're just wet.
I've had enough of you.
I've been in the movie business
for decades.
I've never been so humiliated in my life.
How is it possible for an extra
to humiliate a world-renowned star?
What the hell?
Where's the justice?
- How dare you still stand there?
- I am sorry.
No, you stay.
You go.
Yes. You should go.
I meant you, Marco.
You should leave.
You, young people these days...
You're so inexperienced
and come up with this method.
I can totally...
I totally understand.
I had to do this
because your acting is too bad.
Then, why did you hire me
in the first place?
Because your rate is cheap
and everyone else was busy.
You've been a total washed-up actor
for years.
I thought you would cherish this chance.
But it turned out like this.
You're a failure because you don't have
what it takes to be an actor.
We're running out of time. It's late.
Everyone, get ready. Let's roll again.
Don't worry about it. We're replacing you.
Don't go too far.
I have made a concession.
Aren't you good at that?
We should talk.
Get back to work. Come on.
Director.
I do appreciate you giving me this role.
I think about repaying you
even in my dreams.
Can you return the script to me?
Please don't do this.
I haven't worked for seven or eight years.
Do me a favor. I can't lose this job.
I'll give you half my commission.
Deal?
- Do me a favor.
- I can't.
Please?
Take back the script from him.
Mr. Marco.
- Please don't.
- Let go.
- Do it for my sake, please.
- Let go!
Mr. Marco. I'm so sorry.
- I didn't mean to scare you.
- Don't say a word.
- I didn't know it would turn out that way.
- I don't need anyone's sympathy.
Coming here makes me feel like fighting.
You weren't fighting,
you were just beating yourself up.
Marco.
I haven't seen you for a while.
So you're still acting.
Hey, I'm taller than you.
You've got saggy skin.
Dad, Mom.
She is my daughter.
- What are you doing here?
- Let's take a selfie.
- Please stop.
Come on, let's pose together.
Darling.
- What pose?
- Show me the heart pose.
Come on, be a good boy.
Smile.
One, two, three. Yes.
It's done.
Sorry to bother you, Mr. Marco.
Mr. Marco.
Let me tell you,
when my daughter was a kid,
she watched your movie, Orphan Adventure
and fell in love with acting.
You're her inspiration.
Mom, please stop.
Mr. Marco, please forgive us.
My whole family is your fans.
Mr. Marco.
My daughter won't listen to me.
But she is just not cut out for this.
Can you help me talk her out of it?
She works very hard.
She'll make it.
Thank you, Mr. Marco.
Young.
Your suit looks so nice.
Which role are you playing?
- Do I look all right?
- Whose fancy car is this?
Dreamy, is 200,000 dollars enough?
I can give you more if you need it.
Stop messing around.
- Using prop money will get you arrested.
- Boss.
Time's up. We have to go.
Wait a minute. I'm almost done.
Dreamy, just take it.
No need.
I found a part-time job.
I have enough money.
That's good then.
So, you're actually rich.
It's all from my family business.
- Why did you even become an extra?
- I'm interested in it.
But I need to go abroad
for my family business soon.
I can't fool around anymore.
That's so amazing.
- I've got to go.
- Okay.
Dreamy.
Actually, I like you so much.
Well, I like you too.
No, I mean in a romantic way.
I thought of you as a friend.
- But you wanted to sleep with me?
- Yes.
What do you like about me?
You've got a beautiful soul.
This kind of saying again.
- Are you saying I'm ugly on the outside?
- No.
You look beautiful too.
That's so fake. Have some imagination.
Try again with more feeling.
You're really good-looking.
Just forget it.
I don't blame you.
The lines are a bit of a stretch.
That's true.
How dare you.
I've got a boyfriend already.
I know that.
But thank you anyway.
I'll be going then.
- Come and visit me sometimes.
- I'll be in America.
I won't be able to come back for a while.
You're a big shot now. I'm so envious.
I should be the one who is envious.
You get to do what you love.
- I'll be rooting for you.
- Sure.
Hello.
Your food's here.
It's hard to say.
Please give me
a five-star rating. Thank you.
- This is mine.
- Thank you.
- This is yours.
- Okay.
Mimi!
Try it on.
It's been a while. How are you?
- Do you know her?
- Yes.
Director Chen.
My goodness. It's really you.
What an honor to meet you.
I'm a big fan of your movies.
I love your work.
Thanks.
- Try this one.
- Okay.
Actually, I'm an actor. My name is Dreamy.
If possible, could you give me a chance?
- I'm willing to play any roles.
- Sure.
Really?
That's wonderful.
If you give me a chance,
I won't let you down.
That's good.
Thank you.
Then, I won't bother you.
- Excuse me.
- Director Chen, please have a look.
Director Chen, may I ask you something?
Which role will I play?
I want to be prepared.
- Do you know her well?
- Not really.
We'll call you.
You can go now, thank you.
I'm sorry.
May I have your WeChat ID?
I can come anytime to audition.
We don't use WeChat.
Why are you still here?
It's okay.
Can I borrow a pen?
I'll just leave my number.
- So, he can reach me anytime.
- Just go.
Okay.
- Enough.
- Thank you so much.
We won't be calling you.
- Just go.
- Didn't you say you'll call me?
Hold on.
I was only being polite.
I didn't want to hurt your feelings.
Have you never looked into the mirror?
I look at it every day.
Do you actually think you have a chance?
- I do.
- No, you don't.
I know the chances are slim,
but I'm willing to wait.
You don't need to wait.
You'll never get a chance ever.
How long would "ever" be?
It's from now
until the end of the universe.
Do you understand now?
Well, what about after the universe ends?
People like this
is the biggest disaster to humanity.
She'll never make it,
but yet she is in denial.
She is not giving up
and keep causing trouble.
We just want your food.
Aren't you here for the delivery?
Sorry, Director Chen.
Sorry for the troubles.
I'll lead her out.
Let's go.
What kind of person is that?
What are you doing?
You're making a fool of yourself.
I just wanted to fight for a chance.
Forget about it. It's fate.
Do you know what fate is?
What is it?
I never wanted to be a star,
but here I am.
You've always wanted to be a star,
but you're only an extra.
This is fate.
Don't fight against fate, okay?
Charlie, where are you?
I'm with a client.
I want to see you.
I still have a meeting later.
I'm really busy.
I'll call you later.
Wait, don't hang up.
What's wrong?
What are you wearing today?
I wear the same clothes every day.
White shirt and black pants.
Why are you asking?
All right. I'm just curious.
I'll talk to you soon. Bye.
Okay.
- Let's take a taxi.
- Okay.
Where can we find a taxi?
Right over there.
It's raining hard.
Hi, Dreamy. What a coincidence.
Darling, she is my cousin.
Wait for me for a while.
Who is she?
A client.
Why did you call me your cousin?
Whatever. Don't worry about it.
- Let me ask her.
- Hey.
She is really my client
and you're my client too.
I provide services, do you get it?
What kind of services?
Well...
Boyfriend for hire.
Are you an escort?
Whatever, it's the same thing.
Why me?
Is this my fate?
Is it because I'm stupid?
Don't be so hard on yourself.
Ignorance is bliss. It makes you happier.
All right.
Give me back my wedding fund.
As for the money,
I'll take good care of it.
Don't worry about it.
The money you need.
I've got all you need.
If you want to lie to me,
I'll just let it be.
I'm not scamming you.
I'm just collecting my service fees.
You can't just dine and dash, right?
You never thought
I would make it as an actress, right?
You'll make it.
You're the very best.
As long as you pay me, I'll keep saying it
as often as you wish.
Don't cry. She'll get suspicious.
Stop it.
Don't give me any trouble.
Why did you...
Don't screw it up for me.
Hey, I've asked you
to stop being a junkie.
It'll kill you.
Don't ask me for money anymore.
It's never too late
to turn it around, Dreamy.
You're right.
Don't lend her any money.
Lending money to her is harming her.
Are you okay?
Did you fall asleep? Were you drunk?
Are you trying to kill yourself?
Of course, not.
Could it be you are filming?
Are you an actor?
No.
I'm not an actor.
I'm awake now.
You fell asleep.
It is very dangerous.
Don't do that again.
- Take care of the actors.
- Hurry up. Next scene.
- Get up.
- The next scene is here.
- Step back.
- Hurry.
Good day, Assistant Director.
Mr. Marco. I haven't seen you in a while.
What's your role?
- A courageous dying soldier.
- Just lie down over there.
Quickly.
Costumes and makeup, get ready.
Over here, right?
Stick your heads closer together.
- Here, don't move. I'll help you.
- Has it started?
- Hurry.
- Don't move.
Should I open my eyes?
- Or keep them closed?
- It doesn't matter.
Then, I'll die with open eyes.
After all, we die in a war.
We want to avenge the nation and family.
- Dying with regret, I should...
- Don't move.
Okay. Come on.
Ready.
- Protect the general.
- Be careful.
Quickly.
- Quick, get cover.
- Get down.
Look at this. What the hell?
- Where did you get that?
- Tencent WeSee.
Check this out.
Yes.
He was so scared that he peed his pants.
Look at him. He is ridiculous.
- Do you know Marco?
- No, I don't.
No.
He did wet his pants.
- Let's watch the other clips.
- I can't get enough of this clip.
It's crazy. It's so funny.
I can't stop laughing.
What a funny guy.
Marco.
- Marco?
- Yes.
- Is it really Mr. Marco?
Is it really Marco?
It does look like him.
Yes, it's him.
- Yes, it's Marco.
- It's really Marco.
- It's Marco.
- Marco!
- Mr. Marco.
- I'm seeing him in person.
- Marco.
- Let's take a selfie.
- Take a selfie.
- Come take a picture.
- Look at here.
- Mr. Marco.
- Let's take a picture together.
- I want to take a picture with you.
- Mr. Marco, that clip was so funny.
- I love it so much.
RECORD-BREAKING VIEWS: MARCO IS BACK
WASHED-UP CHILD ACTOR
BECAME POPULAR WITH HIS PEEING VIDEO
PEEING HIS PANTS TO SUCCESS
MARCO IS SHOCKED OVER UNEXPECTED FAME
BRANDS FIGHTING OVER NEW STAR,
MARCO ENDORSES BABY NAPPIES
MARCO IS MAD AT PEE MEME.
I'M NOT THE GOD OF PEE.
Mr. Marco, we're so glad
to have you today.
Can you tell about
how you made your comeback?
What "comeback"?
You're popular once again.
No, I was asking you
what do you mean by "comeback"?
I...
- Was I dead or disappear?
- I didn't mean...
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it that way.
No, what did you mean by "comeback"?
Are you trying to insult me?
- Your acting was really good.
- Of course.
Mr. Marco is absolutely brilliant.
Your emotions can appear anytime.
Sure, when my emotions overflow,
it is unstoppable.
Can you show us
the "peeing-the-pants" look again?
I think that many children will be
watching this program.
Let's not do that.
You're right. Do you have
any upcoming plans?
I've got many invitations
to take part in the international films.
- I've met Mr. Marco.
- Like thriller...
This is the video of me
scaring him to pee his pants.
You're an actor too?
Yes, I used to be an actor.
Have you met Bruce Lee?
- I've met...
- Hey.
Stop chatting and get back to work.
There were so many ups and downs
in your life.
Tell us how you feel.
I feel so blessed.
Not everyone has this kind of experience.
I am grateful to the person
who scared me in the video.
I wouldn't be here today without her.
Who is she?
I don't know her name, but...
She is an actor.
Dreamy.
Look who's here.
- You are so handsome today.
- Yes.
- Mr. Marco.
- Yes, Mr. Marco.
Dreamy, I've finally found you.
I come all the way to thank you.
Actually, she didn't do much.
All she did was scared you.
My hair turned white
from the shock she brought me.
I wouldn't thank her for that.
- Have a seat, please.
- It smells delicious.
Mr. Marco, you're so popular now.
It's all thanks to your scary face.
You have an amazing daughter.
- You're way too kind.
- She looks like her dad.
- No, like her mom.
- Looks like her dad.
- Looks like her mom.
- She looks like both of you.
Also, I want to congratulate you.
You're on the list
for Stephen Chow's new movie.
What?
You didn't know?
They're recruiting new actors
with real talent.
I saw your name on the list.
Where did you see it?
I found it online.
It's held in Beijing tomorrow.
See, right here.
- What happened to the Internet?
- Sorry.
It's fine, I'm not going.
Why not?
I have a new job now.
I am not an actor anymore.
- Why not?
- I'm a waitress now.
Plus, I'm operating an online shop
and making a decent living.
Dad and Mom are satisfied.
Yes. Dreamy is living
a happy and stable life.
- This is good for her.
- Yes, it is.
- Here, Mr. Marco.
- Yes.
It's a good thing.
It's good.
What's the matter?
- I'm just not feeling well.
- Is it menopause?
Nonsense. He is way too young.
Is it a heart attack?
- Quick, call the ambulance.
- No need. I'm okay.
- It could be serious.
- I'm fine.
Seeing Dreamy living a good life,
I'm feeling quite sad.
Don't get me wrong.
What I meant was
it's like an undefeatable boxer
giving up before the match even starts.
I didn't give up,
but I just came to my senses.
I don't fantasize
about being a star anymore.
You're giving up.
Mr. Marco.
It has been more than a decade.
I was ridiculed and rejected every day.
Nobody wanted to see me acting.
I've never gotten
a single moment of respect.
I've had enough.
Why?
What do you mean by that?
Why did you give up?
This is not giving up.
It's just...
It's just that I'm not cut out for it.
Hard work doesn't always pay off.
I told you so, but you insisted.
Let her be. She was bullied all the time.
I know, I get it.
I totally understand.
I came here just to show my gratitude.
I have something to do. I've got to go.
Let's finish the meal first.
Mr. Marco, have dinner before you leave.
Yes, Mr. Marco.
I think that success
is all about not giving up.
You taught me that.
- Maybe I should give it a try...
- I knew you will be like this.
You useless bum.
Go.
- Book her a ticket.
- Hey.
Train or plane?
- Plane.
- Got it.
- First class.
- Yes.
Get out of here.
I don't need that much, Dad.
Take it. You're just a bum.
- Let me tell you...
- I've got the tickets.
- Go now.
- Is it first class?
- Thank you, Mom.
- Okay.
Dad, you're the best.
- Silly girl, don't ever come back.
- All right.
- Did you take the house keys?
- I got it.
BODY MOVEMENT
I'm a robot.
Thank you, next.
Good day, judges.
I'm a growing mushroom.
- It has...
- Okay, next.
Hurry up. Next.
EMOTIONAL CONTROL
Mom!
Grandpa! Grandma!
Uncle! Cousin!
Brother-in-law.
Aunt!
Why does this happen to me?
My whole family is dead.
Fantastic. Next.
Good day, judges.
Okay, next.
Sorry, please let me indulge myself.
- I just need five minutes.
- Hey!
Five minutes?
There are over a hundred people waiting.
TALENT SHOWCASE
Thank you.
That's very good. Next.
Good day, judges.
I can make sounds by my hands.
Next.
I'm sorry.
This is a talent showcase.
Idiot.
ROLE PLAY
Good day, judges. I will play a hero.
All right. Start.
I, Chen Zhen, will take revenge today.
Who killed my master?
Good day, judges.
I will play a spy.
All right. Get started.
Boss, what are you doing?
Aren't we supposed to be playing mahjong?
Don't.
Hey. Boss, it hurts.
Please don't use your belt.
- Good day, judges.
- Hurry up.
I play a con man.
Go ahead.
- Hurry. There are over a hundred people.
- Darling.
Hey.
Darling, she is my cousin.
Wait for me for a while.
Who is she?
A client.
Why did you call me your cousin?
Whatever. Don't worry about it.
- Let me ask her.
- Don't.
She is really my client
and you're my client too.
I provide services, do you get it?
What kind of services?
Well...
Boyfriend for hire.
Are you an escort?
Whatever, it's the same thing.
Why me?
Is it because I'm stupid?
Don't be so hard on yourself.
Ignorance is bliss. It makes you happier.
The money you need. I've got all you need.
If you want to lie to me,
I'll just let it be.
I'm not scamming you.
I'm just collecting my service fees.
You can't just dine and dash, right?
You never thought
I would make it as an actress, right?
You'll make it.
You're the very best.
As long as you pay me, I'll keep saying it
as often as you wish.
Don't cry. She'll get suspicious.
Don't screw it up for me.
Hey, I've asked you
to stop being a junkie.
It'll kill you.
It's never too late to turn it around.
Thank you.
Why did you hit me?
I'm not the cousin.
Sorry, I didn't mean that.
Can you switch the role
and be the victim now?
Sure.
Are you an escort?
Whatever, it's the same thing.
How could you do this?
Don't cry. She'll get suspicious.
You look like a retard.
How could you be an escort?
You can say anything about me,
but don't say I'm a retard.
That's not true.
I've touched your nerve, haven't I?
You must have been seen
as a retarded since young.
So now, you scam people
to boost your self-esteem.
That's bullshit.
Everyone loved me since I was a kid.
They didn't love you.
They just pitied you.
- Shut up.
- You shut up.
Someone like you
doesn't deserve to be loved.
I...
You lowlife.
Everyone loves you?
How could you be an escort with this face?
I'm going to kill you.
- Why did you do this again?
- My goodness. I'm so sorry.
I really didn't mean to hurt you.
All right. Enough. Next.
So sorry.
Hey.
That way. You're shortlisted.
ONE YEAR LATER
- Hey, what are you doing?
- We're here looking for our daughter.
Look for her at the police station.
There's an event tonight.
- Please go upstairs.
- Thank you.
I have all sorts of feelings
after hearing this song.
I wonder if everyone here
feels the same way.
- Over there.
- Okay, let's continue with the awards.
The competition for the best actress award
this year is intense.
The nominees are from all generations
in the Chinese movie industry.
Who'll win the crown
of today's best actress award?
Prior to that, let's enjoy the footages
before they became famous.
Lin Yun was quite pretty before.
Yes.
Who's that?
That's Dreamy.
You're right.
Please welcome
our award presenters on stage.
It's an honor tonight
to give out this award.
The best actress award goes to...
This actress was really
one-of-a-kind from the beginning
- to the end of the universe.
- Just cut the crap.
Life is but a dream.
Dreamy.
You did it.
Congratulations.
Dreamy.
- Dreamy!
- Dreamy.
- It's all right.
It's all right.
Hello, Dreamy. I'm a fan of yours.
I love all your movies.
Thank you.
I am an actor too.
Do you think I have the chance to succeed?
Do you really love acting?
I was born to act. Will I make it?
No, you won't.
From now until the end of the universe,
you have no chance.
Do you understand?
I get it.
So, what are you going to do?
I'll go back to being a farmer.
No, you can't.
Don't let people tell you what to do.
Keep it up.
You can make it.
I get it. Thank you.
Thousand.
Thousand wrongs.
Ten thousand.
Thousand...
You.
What is it? Did I ask you to do that?
Your turn.
Come here.
A sad reaction.
Give me a sad reaction.
Put in more emotions.
You. Do a sad reaction.
Sad.
Okay. You can come.
This is good.
This is okay.
Like this.
Okay.
Hit her.
The first move.
Do it harder for the first move.
Scream louder.
- Louder?
- Of course.
Maybe she will scream louder
when you hit her later.
Subtitle translation by
Ng Khoon Chuan, Lan Hee Hong