I can take 150 shares.
50 are for me, I know
where I can place the other 100.
Write it down,
Professor Filippo Morisoni...
150.
And I'll take 25.
Don Gesualdo Malena...
..25.
What about you, Don Giacomo?
For me,
you can leave a hundred or so.
Don Giacomo Sordi...
100.
That makes...
..275.
Maybe I can place another hundred.
Now we need to try and get some
of them into the countryside.
You'll have to deal with that.
It's not easy. They're not very
trusting in the countryside.
How can you speak
about the Freedom Bond
to people
who're suspicious of everything?
It doesn't matter, you try. And
I don't think they're mistrustful.
It's something else.
They're disheartened.
You're right, that's true.
The failure of the last uprising...
What do you mean, failure?
Remember the Master's words...
"ln revolutions, every mistake
is a step on the way to the truth."
The secret of power lies in faith,
true virtue in sacrifice.
Eleven were arrested
and four of them
climbed the scaffold.
You can't say they were lacking
in the spirit of sacrifice.
And that's exactly why we shouldn't
consider January 7th 1834
as the date of a defeat,
but rather as a date of glory.
Turn to the young,
speak to the impatient youth
in whom we place our greatest hopes.
What does it matter
if one uprising failed?
Nothing is lost
so long as you still have courage.
The police! Gather everything up!
Hurry up!
I didn't do anything!
Am I not allowed to sing?
We'll really make you sing now!
Take him away!
Get away!
You lot, come with me!
On you go.
On you go!
Hurry!
We'll take the shares to my house.
I'm still not under suspicion.
Take him away!
- Why? What have I done?
What have I done?
Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
Leave me alone! What have I done?
Knock it down!
That way, quickly!
Who's there?
Beatrice?
Beatrice!
Mom...
Did you hear that? Was it you?
No, Mom...
Maria?
Maria!
Basile...
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
Mommy...
You...
What are you doing here at this time?
I came to look for you.
Didn't you say you had work to do?
I do.
Where were you? Playing cards?
No.
So why did you go out, then?
I've got things to deal with.
I need to sort them out.
And did you sort them out?
Maybe.
Leave me alone now.
I'll tell you about it tomorrow.
Well?
I don't understand you any more.
What is it?
You've never treated me like this
before.
What do you want?
Leave me alone.
I have to finish this deed.
Tell the truth...
Did you lose again?
No, Anna, I swear.
Look at me.
I'd tell you...
honestly.
Who's that?
It's your husband, go now.
I'll go down and let him in.
Remember,..
I didn't leave the office this evening.
If it was one of the tenants
from upstairs who barred the door,
tell them not to do it again.
I go out in the evening.
All right.
How did you get on?
All that's missing
is the copy of the will from 1782
and the date it was recorded
at the registry office.
You need to look in the archive.
Volume 270, compartment 25.
Remember it has to be ready
for tomorrow morning.
I'll go right away.
Don Giacomo!
Don Giacomo...!
Who's there?
- Go right away
to the house
of the Marquis of Rionero!
Something terrible has happened!
- What's happened?
The marquise has been killed!
- When?
This evening, not long ago.
The marquis has just got back in.
Come!
He's waiting for you.
- I'm coming.
Where are you going?
- The Marquise of Rionero, murdered!
Was it you...?
- Shut up!
Was it you? You murderer!
Murderer!
- No!
And this?
It's one of the marquise's rings!
I've seen her wearing it
a thousand times!
And it just fell out of your pocket!
How could you have?
How could you have...?
I don't know... I don't know...
Save me!
Do you want to hand me in?
Go away!
Anna!
It's the evidence, you can see it.
Ferdinando Maria Baldieri.
It's your scarf.
- I've never denied that.
So why not confess everything?
I can't confess to a crime
I didn't commit.
And yet the scarf was found beneath
the window the murderer escaped from.
You won't deny, I hope,
that you passed by there?
I don't know anything.
Not even that the Marquis of Rionero
wasn't in his villa that evening,
that the notary Giacomo Sordi
had delivered
a substantial sum of money to him
the previous day?
I've already said
I don't know the Marquis of Rionero!
The crime took place
shortly before midnight.
Now, it has been demonstrated
that you weren't at home at midnight.
No, I wasn't.
Where were you?
I won't answer.
You're politically suspect.
Had you taken part in some meeting?
- Who were you with?
The dilemma is clear.
Either you're the murderer
of the Marquise of Rionero
or you're keeping silent
so as not to compromise someone.
In either case...it's the gallows!
Unless you decide to take advantage
of the only way out
that's left to you.
Try to understand me.
Who were you with?
I have nothing to reveal.
You said there was a witness
to the crime.
Show me to him.
Think about it...
that witness isn't able to face up
to a confrontation at the moment.
Her pulse is good as well.
But is it not strange
that she's sleeping so much?
It's a good thing.
This means the delirium has finished.
Apart from anything else,
it's the first time she's rested
since she had the brain fever.
Mommy?
Beatrice!
Is that you, Dad?
Yes, dear, it's me, yes.
I can't see you. Everything is dark.
But...
this...
..can you see it?
No... I can't see anything.
Doctor!
Blind?
Isn't it wrong what we're doing?
How can we keep silent?
We have to. Ferdinando Maria Baldieri
is our leader,
and we don't have the right
to go against his plans.
And will we save him by revealing
what we were doing that night?
So we just have to watch him die,
stained by an unjust accusation?
I can't keep quiet,
my conscience won't allow it.
You have to keep quiet!
If my father isn't speaking,
then we shouldn't either.
But it's the scaffold.
It's the scaffold!
In the name of his Apostolic Majesty
Ferdinand ll,
King of the Two Sicilies,
Cyprus and Jerusalem,
the Criminal High Court of Naples
following the trial
of Ferdinando Maria Baldieri
finds him guilty
of robbery and murder
and condemns him to be hanged
in the public square.
My fate doesn't frighten me.
I know I did my duty.
The truth is born out of sacrifice.
I have one worry only...
To leave you alone...
But you'll feel me in your heart.
I'll just be...a bit further away.
Father!
Be strong.
Farewell!
In the name of his Apostolic Majesty
Ferdinand ll,
King of the Two Sicilies,
Cyprus and Jerusalem,
the Criminal High Court of Naples
following the trial
of Ferdinando Maria Baldieri
guilty of robbery and murder
condemns him to be hanged
in the public square.
An innocent man is dying!
Be brave!
The world is an unjust place.
But in London
you'll rebuild your life,
you'll complete your studies,
and maybe one day...
And write to us.
Any time you need us...
Thank you.
He has to be tall, thin, fair...
Why fair?
Because all the English are fair.
Naturally, he'll have glasses...
Glasses?
Of course! For a doctor, glasses are
like a thermometer, indispensable!
We should go, I wouldn't want him
to arrive without us.
I have to do the honors
of the house.
Let's go, then. But how will you
do him the honors of the house?
You don't speak English!
Look!
Oh, sorry...
I copied it out of a grammar book.
The problem will be when he speaks
but I'll just keep saying all right!
It's a shame he's a doctor.
But it's still better
than a notary!
Welcome back! You know
I nearly didn't recognize you?
You're a man now!
I'd hoped to return to my country
under my own name and head held high,
yet here I am, Doctor Oliviero Simon!
The famous Doctor Oliviero Simon,
you should say.
Poor Sordi said, didn't he,
that you'd go far.
Poor Sordi, of course.
He ended up that way too, in jail.
And you've settled in Sorrento?
Yes, since I left teaching.
I live here with Maria Luisa
and a nephew of mine.
Your daughter will be a woman now!
And how, what a woman!
You'll meet her.
Furthermore,
there's something of our past here.
You see that villa?
It belongs to the Marquis of Rionero.
He's lived here for years,
doing nothing
but look after his daughter...
..who never got better.
The only person who saw the killer
and could have recognized him.
If I could restore her sight,
who knows...? - Exactly!
Or I wouldn't have insisted so much
on you coming back to ltaly!
You're forgetting
whom I have to operate on.
Will I keep my self confidence?
Come, we'll talk about it later.
I'd recommend selling it, sir.
It's unproductive land.
We could use the proceeds
more profitably.
I've received a few offers.
Study them. You're my notary.
I trust you implicitly.
Thank you.
I know you are very fond of that land
and I didn't want...
Yes, but my concern now
is to ensure Beatrice's future.
That's my concern too.
- I know...
I know,
and I'm grateful to you for this.
Well, then, if you'd like to sign...
Well, how did it go?
Wonderfully, Dad!
Miss.
- Mr. Basileo, how are you?
I need to go.
Be careful, don't get too worked up
over Doctor...
Simon.
If your cousin notices!
- That idiot?
Goodbye!
Sir....
- Miss?
Did you remember my message?
Of course. I've got the samples.
Wait till you feel
how soft the material is.
Come.
Here they are.
I hope you like them.
I'm sorry to be a pest all the time.
Why do you say that?
It was a pleasure for me.
I'd like to help you all the time...
..do something for you every day.
You're too good.
I don't deserve this.
Good?
No, don't go. I love you, you know...
and there's nothing in my love
that could offend you.
Because it's respect,
tenderness, devotion...
And pity.
Say it, I won't be offended.
Only one person would deserve pity...
me...
if this were just a dream.
Do you think
you can love a blind person?
No creature on Earth
can be loved more than you can!
Shall we go?
Yes.
Let's go.
I've told you a thousand times...
spero, promitto and iuro
take the verb
in the future infinitive!
Take care of yourself.
But when I'm trying
to teach you something,
who knows what you're thinking?
You...you know less than your cousin,
and that tells you everything!
Because she knows nothing!
On you go.
Translate this sentence for me.
Caesar's legionnaires hoped
to be able to break through...
..the enemy wall.
Milites...
Caesaris...
Good.
..sperabant...
Sperabant...
sperabant...
On you go.
Ingressuros esse...
..Valle d'Aosta...
Ignoramus, ignoramus
and thrice ignoramus!
There's something else to consider.
The marquis might find out who I am.
And how? It's a secret known
only to the two of us. Therefore...
I'll do as you ask.
What, he doesn't speak English?
He doesn't even have glasses!
Here's the masterpiece
I told you about.
Doctor Simon.
At last!
- You're starting up again?
Every time you go to Sorrento, you
never find the road back to Naples!
I have my reasons, good ones.
You know that.
Oh, yes! If the marquis asks
to see the accounts,
you'd end up in jail, I know!
And that's why you have to keep
in his good books...
.. but especially in his daughter's!
- Stop it!
No!
- Beware!
That's what I'm telling you, beware!
I know what you're aiming at,
but if you think
you can get rid of me, you're wrong!
You still don't know me!
Come on! Do you think I could...?
- You could do anything!
Unfortunately!
Even love you!
Go back to your own house now.
I'll come over later.
The sacred armies
and the godly knight...
All you did was look at him
at the table!
..That the great sepulcher of Christ
did free, I sing...
You smiled at him three times.
- Six.
Much wrought his valor
and foresight...
You poured his drink for him too.
- And I drank from his glass!
Ah, listen, this is cynicism!
And in that glorious war
much suffered he...
I said, cynicism!
- I heard!
In vain 'gainst him
did Hell oppose her might.
I'm going
so as not to be compromised.
Shall I keep you company?
Maria Luisa?
She's upstairs, shall I call her?
No, thank you, I'll go.
Miss di Rionero?
- Yes.
I'm Doctor Simon.
Ah! Maria Luisa has spoken to me
a lot about you.
Sit down.
I wouldn't want to disturb you.
Not at all! Professor Morisoni
will have told you...?
Yes.
You know we have to become friends.
And you think he could do it?
I trust him completely.
His first attempts, I'll say,
left me a little skeptical,
but then I had to acknowledge
the evidence.
Today,
the eye can be operated on too.
We've been left behind now.
Excuse me if I insist, but don't you
remember what you felt then?
Nothing, I don't remember anything.
I was scared senseless.
My mother,
thrown against the pillows...
the killer's hands
squeezing her throat...
And could you see the killer?
No...
the room was dark...
All I could see was a shadow.
Try to remember!
- It's useless.
The only two things I'll never forget...
..are my mother's lifeless face...
..and the killer's eyes!
- His eyes? - Yes...
He had the eyes of a wild animal,
horrible!
And nothing else,
only his eyes?
That's all.
- Try! Concentrate!
It's useless!
- It's essential! You must!
Doctor!
Excuse me...
I didn't want to frighten you.
Come.
Let me look at you.
Raise your head.
Try to keep them open.
Do you feel them burning?
A little.
Two drops
and that'll be it for today.
Keep still.
No, don't be afraid.
There, that's it done.
Remember, don't go out right away.
Shall we stay shut in here for long?
You can go to your lessons,
if you like.
Do you care?
- Not for me...
.. but for your cousin.
He's down, huh?
Till later.
Don't be late, I'll be waiting for you.
- You can rely on me.
He's so good.
Especially with you.
Do you think so?
- Absolutely!
Dr Simon seems to me
to be something of a charlatan!
Don't you think your judgment
might not be entirely disinterested?
What do you mean?
You understood me.
No, sir.
Illustrious clinicians
who cure a case of blindness
with sailing trips and romantic walks
don't convince me.
MUSlC: "Dorme Surriento"
by Carlo Buti
Are you tired?
- No...
I was listening.
- You like these songs of ours?
Very much.
That's unusual for an Englishman.
Why don't you come nearer?
This sea must be so beautiful.
It's magnificent.
You love it too?
Very much.
If only I could see it again...
You will.
Do you think so?
- I'm sure of it.
We need to head back to land.
It's late.
It's indispensable, believe me.
I need to bring the operation
forward, I have to go back to London.
But why?
I feel that for Beatrice
I'm not simply her doctor any more.
And this frightens me...
I'm frightened of myself.
I'm condemned now
to being Oliviero Simon for ever.
The murderer had a formidable ally,
time...and Beatrice.
Is that you, Oliviero?
It's me, Miss.
And I hope my company
won't make you pine for the doctor.
Of course not!
Why have you changed so much with me?
I haven't changed at all!
Excuse me.
Today is the last medication.
Then two days' rest and then...
So you've decided to operate?
Yes.
Is the young lady there?
Let's go, then.
I don't understand you.
You shouldn't behave like that.
Sir, don't misunderstand me.
Have you thought of the consequences
of an operation like this?
What if, instead of curing her,
he disfigures her?
No, no,
this is an obsession of yours!
Dear Anna,
the situation is becoming dangerous.
Beatrice
is going to have the operation.
It's necessary that I stay on
in Sorrento. I have to try something.
I'll keep you informed about
what's happening. A big hug, Ernesto.
What's going on?
Someone missed their target.
Or someone wants to do away with you.
Maria Luisa!
- Here I am!
Professor!
Don't worry.
Madam Anna is here to see you.
In the other room?
I'm very grateful to you,
but how did you find out?
The notary told me.
Can I see the young lady?
Has she had the operation?
They're operating on her now.
Well done! You really were brave.
I was right to tell you
there was no need to be so alarmed.
And now a few more days in the dark
and then...
the miracle!
Beatrice!
Dad!
Was it painful?
- No.
Can I say hello as well, Miss?
Who is it?
- Mrs. Anna.
You came too? Thank you.
It's nothing, dear.
The notary has been kind enough
to keep me up to date about you.
I wish you all the best.
How do you feel?
I'm still a bit befuddled.
That'll pass in a few hours.
Try to relax.
I'm going to prepare you a tonic.
Leave her in peace, let her breathe!
Maria Luisa, give me a hand.
You go as well.
I didn't disfigure her!
Let's sort her out a bit better.
There...
That's the way.
And now puff up the pillows...
and Lady Beatrice is served!
There!
Who's that?
It's that idiot Giovannino!
I have to go down. He's capable
of whistling all night long.
Quiet, now.
As soon as you like to stop, feel free!
- You'll be served.
I don't know how I'm holding back...!
What do you want?
I wanted to see you.
I couldn't sleep.
If you can't sleep, take some opium,
and remember...
You'll leave tomorrow!
That would suit you, but I'm staying.
You have to go!
- No!
Don't you see you'll ruin me?
- I don't care! And it's not true!
How isn't it true?
- That's not what's worrying you!
It's something else,
but you won't make it, I promise you!
I've understood
and you won't make it!
You've understood?
All the better!
It's Beatrice I'm interested in.
I won't give her up.
Beware!
- What will you do?
Listen...
I didn't report you
when I should have...
I stood beside you
in all your sordid dealings.
Stop it!
- I was your accomplice!
I let someone else go to the scaffold
instead of you!
Stop it!
- But not this time, no!
Not Beatrice,
or I'll send you to jail!
Don't you feel the horror
of what you're thinking of doing?
I'll tell her what you are...!
Just try!
You scoundrel!
Scoundrel!
And then?
- And then,..
he grabbed her
and told her again to go away.
Yes, but Anna kept saying no. So
he left without even turning round.
But...children...
are you sure you heard properly?
Well,
ask her.
Yes.
And you haven't told anybody?
- Nobody!
I mean it...
don't say anything to anyone!
Come in.
Shall we go?
Listen, Professor, I'd like you
to remove the bandages from Beatrice.
What?
- I'm leaving.
You're leaving?
- It's best she doesn't see me.
But...
if you were still needed here?
Listen...
if you want, I'll go alone now...
.. but you have to stay here.
Look at me carefully.
You must!
- Why?
Don't ask me anything...
wait,
who knows what we're dealing with?
You have the duty to speak, Madam.
I don't condemn your feelings,
I might even understand them,
but if there's a secret
behind your passion,
if you've sealed it up all this time
and someone suffers because of this,
then you have to speak!
I have no secret to reveal.
Why do you want me to remind you
of what I heard last night?
And if you heard it,
why are you asking me?
What kind of woman are you?
You've been covering
this man's wickedness for ten years!
It's not true!
- You're his accomplice!
No!
- Even now as he slips away from you!
He won't slip away from me
- And if I could assure you of that?
Answer me!
Well?
I'd have lost everything.
All right, remember...
no fuss, no fainting...
and no tears!
Do they hurt?
No!
Open the shutters...
..slowly.
Try to open your eyes.
Don't be scared.
I can see!
I can see...!
- Oh, my girl!
Dad!
I can see!
Professor, thank you!
Doctor Simon?
But what did I do to him, what?
Why don't you ask him?
- Me...?
You're right, I can ask him.
- Maria Luisa, no!
Yes, don't worry.
Come in.
Am I interrupting anything?
- Not at all.
I'm always delighted to see you.
So, you're leaving?
- Yes.
Great!
Well, I just have time to tell you that
your English ways are quite unseemly.
My English ways?
- Yes, you understood me.
And don't tell me you didn't notice
because I won't believe you!
What are you talking about?
- Beatrice.
If you'd tried it with me,
it would've been fine, I know men!
But taking advantage of that poor thing!
Taking advantage?
There must be some misunderstanding!
A misunderstanding? Making a girl
fall for you, then leaving her?
But l...
- Never mind! I could see, you know!
Would you have the courage to tell
Beatrice it was a misunderstanding?
Answer me!
If it were necessary.
- Let's go then!
You can start by taking this off.
You can put it back on later...
if you need to.
Here he is! You deal with her now.
Why didn't you want to take my
bandages off? What did I do to you?
Nothing. My presence was no longer
indispensable. My job was done.
Done?
Yes, in fact I wanted to leave.
- Leave?
Without even letting me thank you?
Without saying goodbye to me?
Forgetting that...
- Forgetting what?
I needed your trust,
and I needed to inspire trust in you.
So, even that kiss
is part of your professional expertise?
Excuse me...
I'm really grateful anyway...
and... I'll see you again
before you leave...won't l?
Goodbye, then, and thank you.
Mr. Basileo...
- Miss?
Come, I have some very exciting news
for you, you'll be very pleased.
Come.
I wanted to ask you a favor, sir...
I absolutely have to get back
to Naples this evening.
Could I use your coach?
Of course. I'm only sorry...
So am l, but it's unavoidable.
At what time?
I'm not sure... At eight?
All right.
Aren't you happy?
I'll get out of your way.
You've achieved your aim.
You'll marry Beatrice...
I could have betrayed you or myself
if I'd stayed here.
I'll go.
- What do you plan to do?
You're not laying a trap for me?
- A trap? No... I'm moving aside!
Anna, you know me.
Oh, don't worry.
The last thing I want
is to be shot at too!
I don't understand this sudden
and unexplained departure of Anna.
I do!
- You do?
I mean, no...
I don't understand it either.
But lots of strange things
happen here.
Doctor Simon
isn't leaving now either.
Will your fiancé be long in Naples?
No...
I don't think so.
Here, this is it, isn't it, Anna?
It's ideal for an engagement.
That would be my choice too.
For the payment...
- Oh, please, sir!
And my very best wishes.
- Thank you.
I'll see you out.
You'll see,
we'll be happy all the same.
Don't you think it's a bit late?
You have to set off.
I understand. You want to go?
- No, it's not that.
Farewell.
- Farewell?
See you again!
Maybe.
Like this?
- No, they're better like this.
You're so beautiful!
That dear Doctor Simon!
He has to die of jealousy!
Simon?
What does he care about me?
You should have let me leave,
Professor!
No...
No!
All the best!
I hope to be as happy as you one day.
Thank you, my dears, thank you.
Sir!
- Aren't you dancing?
May I have the pleasure
of this dance?
"Sir"? Aren't you able to call me
by any other name?
Perhaps this is something
I will manage with time.
I must manage it.
Are you tired?
No.
May l?
- Thank you.
Who gave you this ring?
Why?
This ring belonged to my wife!
It was stolen along with some
other jewelry that tragic night.
How did it end up in your hands?
Who gave it to you?
Answer me!
I... I don't know...
I don't know,
I've never seen this ring before...
I never had it...
A short while ago,
there was a different one in the box.
I looked at it...
there, in my room...
Someone has replaced it ...
Who could it have been?
Who?
Me!
You...?
You?
His eyes!
The murderer!
The murderer...!
In the name of his Apostolic Majesty
Ferdinand ll,
King of the Two Sicilies,
Cyprus and Jerusalem,
the Criminal High Court of Naples
following the trial
of Ernesto Basileo
finds him guilty
of robbery and murder
and condemns him to be hanged
in the public square.
There's one thing
I can't forgive you for,..
not telling me Ferdinando Maria
Baldieri was innocent.
I didn't have the right to do so.
In any case, Ferdinando Maria Baldieri
himself chose sacrifice..
over betraying our cause
and his companions.
We had faith that time
would have done him justice.
And, indeed...
everything comes out in the end.
lndeed!
- What?
Look!
What a rascal!
No, leave them be!
Anyway, they're being set
a bad example by them down there.