There are a lot of handsome boys today
This one is really handsome
Come on
Are you blind? Should be more careful
There are many devil women on the beach
Come here
Give you a penny if you can catch me
Give me back my uniform
Come on
Don't
God damn you!
'Crazy woman chasing after the cop'
What an incident!
That police woman looks pretty nice
It's a pity that she wears glasses
You again!
Don't you think I'll not recongnize you
if you don't wear glasses
Good-day, Lady!
I beg you, please don't come
for further questioning
Every time you finish your questioning
we have to do first-aid for the criminals
I am just being loyal to the police force
Fine, I go to tell the doctor
Sex Maniac!
You go to hell
Son of bitch
That's not true, I have not even tried
Give it back to me
Let me try
Not bad!
You're not gonna get it back
if you don't say 'YEs'
I am not in mood, you'd better admit
Admit what?
Have roses got stings or not?
Yes, it has stings
Why all these laughs?
Too bad, it's you. Who is 'Seducer Wong'
Is it so funny to trap the'madam'?
Playing the role of a fool? Still again?
Jesus, I'm dying of laughing
What are you doing?
Injection
You are a nurse?
No
Doctor, she abuses me, I gonna sue her
Sue me? Have you got witnesses?
There are only two of us here. Are there
anybody else to witness against me?
You are murdering patient, are't you?
No, he laughed himself to death
I didn't even touch him
He laughed himself to death?
You saw it, tell him
Right, there are only two of us here
I said it's you who murder him
You are the murderer
Jesus! Got 'returns' now
Madam, this money note is mine
What evidence have you got that this is yours?
Did you see what kind of note it is?
Indian money note
This Indian money note is yours?
If you don't believe, you can smell it
Just the same smell as my pile of notes here
Just now when I went to
the toilet, I counted it
Beauty, want any? Give you two pieces
Fake
Rings are real. I want to make love with you
You go to hell
I love money but I never
make love with a watchman
Boss, your brief case
Going to cricket today?
Ya
Play hard! Let's get to the car
You said to give me rings
Now, no ring
You are too greedy
You are degrading the integrity
of our race, get moving
6080, come over here, got a seat here
I reserved a seat specially for you
Thanks
Our Father, who art in Heaven
hallowed be thy name
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done
On earth as it is in Heaven
Give us this day, our dialy bread
Forgive us our trepasses: As we gorgive them
Who trepasses against us
Lord, lead us not into temptation.
But save us from devil. Amen
The killer comes here for dinner?
GOOD AFTERNOON SIR
I beg you. Don't do that again
The Lord will punish you
Our Father who are in heaven. Hallowed be thy name
Thy Kingkom come, thy will be done
On earth as it is in heaven
Give us this day, our daily bread
Forgive us our trepasses as we forgive them
Who trepass against us
forgive us our trepasses Lord, lead us not into temptation...
What do you want?
Oh nothing, I just cover up your dish
so that they won't eat it
Pretending to be good
Someone's beating the cop
cop fighting against cop!
Help
More sideways! Please!
I'm sorry, I didn't mean it
No, Superintendent
No, killer sir
No Superintendent Wong
Although my hand has been hurt
I'm still working hard
Duty on street, dull as a cloud
You have to remain extremely alert
Trying to fool me by pretending to be as leep
Stand up for those who have fooled me
Stand up for those who have not fooled me
PC5198,PC5198
Now I am looking at you, I'm Mr Lau
Mr Lau
He I looked at me right in front of me. He
would have noticed if I opened my eyes wide
Can you see me?
Yes, I can. I'm looking at you too
PC5198, wipe the blackboard immediately
YES, SIR
Hurry up
There is no brush
The brush is in my hand
Thank you
Why doesn't this brush work?
Sorry
How come you are pinched all over by the crab pincers
Yes, here, and there too
Everybody has been pinched by him
But nobody dares make a noise
I made a complaintjust when he is at around
Come in
I have not complained you
Sir Cho
Take a seat please
Want some walnuts
Thank you
Do you know your nickname?
Crab-pincers
Somebody complaint that they are pinched
by you. Is that really true?
I hate one who treats others badly
Are you going to witness against her, PC6393
She alreadygestured 'No'
Do you like very much to pinch others?
Sometimes I do like to, butjust
pinched very gently
Full of love and care, incidental contact only
It should be described as gentle
touch rather than pinch
Good. I figure that you have
worked for me so many years
Forget it, 6393 doesn't rally sue you
Sir Cho, you are really a nice guy
O.K. Thank you
Darling, what brings you here?
Mrs Cho
Yes
Your son? So lovery
You...
So funny
Crab-pincers, you are really something
ATTENTION
GOOD MORNING, SIR
The result of the appeal are all here
And so are the seven of you
1,2,3,4,5,6. Only six?
Only six? Where is the other one?
I am sorry. My car broke down
I'm sorry
Get back to your seat gently
YES, SIR
Really smart
Good, got results. You wait to accept
the cruelty of fate
Everybody gets his share. This is yours
That is yours
Fired, too bad
Fired!
Ho Pik Sai, PC6017
It's lucky that it's not me
who is 6017?
Me
You're not lucky enough got fired, take it
Fatty, don't get happy too soon.
All seven letters are the same
Be calm
I think something uncommon will happen
Everybody knows, get out
ATTENTION
I think you all know me
Yes, we do
You are Inspector Tam. Who wouldn't know you
Chief Superintendent Tam
He is the typical gambling addict
throughout the police station
Sit down, please
The incident of all of you being fired
today is an arrangment of mine
Four bar-girls are separately murdered last month
The cause of death and places of
the four cases are different
Superficially, there seems no
connection among the cases
But personally, I feel they are
all done by the same person
The common factor for the 4 bar-girl is that
they all look cheap and wear very little
The commander orders to keep it confidential
and find out the murderer as soon as possible
I have even no time to play Mah-jon
If the murderer kills more club girls, then
it would make the case open to the public
The bar-girls wouldn't get
back to work, What then?
The wives wouldn't be afraid of husbands
fouling around in the night-clubs
Certainly they can turn to the call-girls.
No, to call the prostitutes
That is even worse
The night-life business will be affected
if the bar-girls wouldn't get to work
Then how can be still have
horse races and dances?
And how to maintain the stability
and prosperity of Hong Kong
The problem is really serious
I have already got an idea
for unweaving the case
I have made arrangements that
you are going to be a spy bar-girl
You are going to the most luxurious Crime
City Night Club to be a team of bar-girls
And your team number is 169
raise your hand one by one
Shut up! If you have any opinion,
Although everybody agrees that
I still have a good look
However, to be a bar-girl at my age...
Right, You are not going to be a bar-girl.
You're the mom of this team of girls. Next
Would it be possible if I don't do it?
I'm a Catholic. I'm afraid that
the lord would not forgive me
Is the Lord your boy-friend?
Call him to come to see me, sit down. Next
Why wouldn't you give us a little guidance on
how to be a bar-girl?
Don't worry, I prepared to teach you tonight
Who is it? Darling?
Soup again? I can't come home for dinner
I have some important thing to do
Three short of one, original cast
I'll come back immediately
This time, I must win back all my money
About your mission, talk less
and act smartly, that's all
Sir Tam, I don't know what a bar-girl is like
Sergeant, go back and read some further
reference, then teach them
OK, SIR
Yes, Sir Tam, we are all so beautiful
others would doubt
You average out with 6 ft3, then
nobody's gonna suspect anymore
Sir Tam, can we go to bed with customers?
Of course not
How about make love?
What's the difference?
To make love doesn't necessarily
have to be in bed
If there is no need to go
to bed, or to make love
But then the customer voluntarily
gives us money, can we accept it?
If you have this client, introduce me, please
Thank you sir. Thank you for picking me
Let me tell you the way I chose you
The night I chose you is just as tonight
I'm hurrying up to play Mah-jon
What has it got to do with out selection
Then what has Catholicism got to
do with being a bar-girl
You just treat what I said was crap
just that I have said nothing
Sir...
The case tonight is straightly confidential
Only eight of us in the world know this case
Absolutely no other people
should know, got it?
UNDERSTAND?
YES, SIR
Tonight, I must launch my revenge
I suppose we as the police force should catch
call-girl who knows we are becoming one now
What can i do?
Mum, it's all dynamite
You know, I'm treating you well
Get up, fattie
What's the matter, mum?
Are these magazines yours?
Those obsence magazines?
Gosh, you read these obsence magazines
What do you say?
You seemed like a law enforcer
while not being a chick
Not being a chick. It is stealing a chick
It's so simple: How come you don't know
What do you learn in school?
You are a good for nothing, Fattie
Bye, mum
Now we start our weekly self-study schedule
After my kid has gone to school
and before he is back
We must speak carefully. Let's use symbols
The project we received today
is 'Action of Hell'
We are 'Angels'. The killer's
named 'Melon Peeler'
We have to work hard to accomplish our task
OK, follow me to cry out a logan
ATTENTION
'Hell and Angels will win
Melon Peeler will finish'
'Hell and Angels are the best
Melon Peeler will cry to death'
Now we start the first part of our training
Which is the information that I found out.
These are jargon og the club girl
Every night they speak to their clients
They always ask them like this
Listen, Mr. What is your names?
What is your name?
You've been here long?
What's yourjob?
Where do you go for leisure?
Don't talk in such a fierce manner be softer
Do you want to smoke? No?
I want a pack of Marlbore
I want a pack of Marlboro. OK?
Now it's time for practice
You want some honey melon? No?
Why haven't you shown up for such a long time?
Why not stick with other bitch?
Now I give each of you a background
I trust you've all learnt it by heart
PC3341, recite your part
YES, MADAM
I am'Chie Yin', no 8 group 169
of Crime City Club
I live in Lamma Island
My dad is a gambler and
my mother seduce another man
My elder brother has absconded
and my sister-in-law is pregnanted
We need money badly for theirs books
What aslo can I do other
than club girl? That's it
However, you speak in a policewoman's way.
It's a complete failure
I know you are being loyal
to the police force
Now is only the training, you
should dress like a club girl
YES, MADAM
You only care for sleeping. Go and
recite it for a thousand times
YES, MADAM
I'm a club girl named 'Chie Kuan'.
No 7 group 169 of 'Crime City Club'
She is my mother
Speak up
YES, MADAM
I'm a bar girl named 'Chie Kuan'.
No7 group 169 of 'Crime City Club'
You are my mother, and I'm
your girl. I'm a club girl
I know you are a club girl
You fool, why don't you go on TV
You are quite without shame
Part four is dancing
6'3" come out and domostrate
It's OK. Go on with your dinner
I don't know the pattern of this dance
Tood bad, earthquake
God, what shall I do?
Believe in Jesus can get a bull?
Believe in fish can get a bull
My god. Believe in bull?
Sis, go get the BB glue fast
Stick it
What? You know nothing about dancing?
Who said it? There is a certain dance...
That I have won a prize for
Really?
Show us
Come worship our God
Our mighty God. Holy Mother, your voice
of saint will always...
Take care of one
Lord, forgive me, hatred has
completely occupied my mind
Clergyman, those words are stuck
well. They'll never fall
Thanks
Believe in bull can get Jesus
The last lesson today is...
To practice wine drinking
You find yourself in a very disadvantageous
position if you get drunk very easily
So be ready to drink when I count 1,2,3
The devils come again
God, your kindness
You are too noisy upstairs
Jesus would be angry too
You got Jesus annoyed
Sorry: I think Jesus will gorgive me
If you don't go, you'll see Jesus very soon
Are you ready?
You all must not laugh if the truth pops out
I'm your protective angel. What do you wish?
Miracle! Lord, I have sinned
I gonna be a club girl after I have got drunk
Please help me be the hottest
and most beloved bar girl
And don't help those women cops in my team
Help them serve nobody
Fly, I goona fly to heaven
You're so insidious. Throw her stones
Hypocrite
Open the door
I come to warn you
I want to warn you
What are we accused of?
No. I mean I beg you
Do you wear underwear?
Why don't Clergy Ho come back yet?
Miracle, Jesus
No, I'm Clergy Ho
Clergy Ho
Don't worry. God will be with you
Why is he tied up?
God bless one who is tied up
You don't go to hell, who goes?
I don't go to hell
Forced to be a prostitute
What's your name, sir?
I'm from the Saint Church
What do you do?
I preach
Where can you find more fun?
We can't foul around everywhere
We usually foul around with ourselves
Just playing with oneself
Do you mind if I watch you with this stuff
No, that's OK
You watch carefully, I have
already phoned the police
We are not afraid of cops. We are cops
No, we are with the 169th team
of the Crime City Club
We are club girls
Oh, My God! It's crazy
Come follow me
This place is really big.
There is even a canteen
And even boutiques
Don't touch
Jesus, what if some of them recognize us
Calm down
Disgusting
Talk, say something
Dear Sisters
We are the newcomers, team no 169.
I'm their mamashan
Wendy Cheung also named as W.C.
Itjust doesn't seem alright.
Your name sounds so smelly
Miss WC, since you first come here.
I'll remind you of one thing
According to our rules here
all newcomers must...
Worship 'Kwan Gong'
'Kwan Gong', I know that god well
We worship together in the
police station very often
I mean when we are arrested
to the police station
I can read from your face
Let's worship
I'm Catholice, and I don't worship Chinese Gods
What are you afraid of?
Your God will condemn you?
Pray to him when you get back home, OK
You must stretch it over your head
to show your sincerety
Right?
Make wishes
'Kwan Gong', help our names sweep through
the whole of Tsim Sha Tsui East
Customers pour in well before seven
Customers bring us out even
before we get changed
Money, money and money each round the circle
Notjust supper but also money from the bed
And plenty of private pocket money
All things done and it's only 3 a.m.
Wish we could have comfortable bath
better than hearing your murmur
Bathe, and comfortably
Hurray
Look, this one's trembling as in a cold
Maybe the omuth is blocked
and water flows over here
That's impossible. It that's true
water would have jetted down
It stuffed
Am I right?
Why isn't there anything jets out?
Waterfall
Why it takes so long for mamashan
to send for the client
We are the only two remains here
All other girls are out
Duck-beak-tart, a regular client has come.
Your wishes come true
Who?
There are altogether two only
'Crook-backed 7' & 'Lame-ming'
Don't stick around
I got to go to work. Can't be
as comfortable as others
God damn it. Even the leavings
are so arrogant
Though we are leavings, it's still better
than those good-for-nothing beast
Don't stir up troupble, get out
Mr, do me favour, calll my girls
Sir...
A real good-for-nothing beast
Nobody here doesn't know that I, Ko Tin Wai
like tall and musclar girls
All these girls don't suit me
Mamashans here are getting incapable.
Go get her fast
Hurry up
I'm sorry, Mr Ko
Sisters, everyone gets a table
Hurray Mamashan. Angel win all the way
Who got the nerve to swallow my table?
You are the Mamashan of team 169?
Calm down
You already know she is
I asked on purpose. Otherwise
where could I start from scolding her
You know who I am?
You are the most popular
Mamashan Queen Elizabeth?
Q. E
It's not I who want to take your tables
that short client requested
He asked you to swallow my tables
No, he asked for a very tall girl
and we've got one in our team
Which one is the tallest, let me have a look
She is really tall, my god! My hands shake
Don't get impetuous, sit down
THIS AN ORDER
King of groovy ha! So obedient
Stop laughing
THIS IS AN ORDER
Order!
What are you laughing at? Stop it
Everybody has limit for patience
Got any nerve to play with me
Villainous
Really something
Nothing here, better get to the tables
Go out
She asked for it
It wouldn't work if you don't play tough
Hurray! Mamashan
Just now, I'm so awe-inspiring
Just now you asked me to concede the tables.
Then you'll compensate for the hour
Since I don't know you will.
Better pay me now
Don't try to pretend. Pay it fast
What is even stronger than money
Pay her
Don't be so tough, we are sisters anyway
What? Don't keep your promise?
Take out the money or you'll try my fist
Bitch. You know who she is
She can arrest you
Accuse you of being prostitute
I'll pay
I'll pay. Lhave a card here.
I suppose that's alright
This is Miss Chi Ying
Not bad, the girl look nice
What's your name, honey?
I'm Mr Kim, Just come back from San Francisco
What do you do?
I mine gold
That's why your hands looks attractive
I suppose your hands worth
several 10 thousand back
That doesn't worth a mention
What are you doing?
I'm very nervous
Do chat with your man
What's your name, honey?
I'm Mr Cheung
Have you been around for long?
Yes
Smile
You've hang around for long?
What's your name, Mr Cheung?
Didn't mention it? I am Mr Cheung
Cheung. Your name is terrific
You are a new comer, aren't you?
That's right, I justjoined in
How do you become a club-girl?
Mr dad died very early and mom
ran away with another man
My little brother got cancer
And my little sister got
her legs broken by a car
And I support the whole family myself
How in human of you to laugh
at those sad stories
I noticed that you have not made
a sound for the whole night
Have you been observing are?
I have special talents with my eyes
and they can see in all dircetions
Now I'm watching your eyes
and I know all your secrets
Really? I don't believe you
You can try
Stare at my eyes
Is that guy watching me?
Miss, are you wearing a red
underwear with laces tonight
And there is a hole on the left
This is really terrible. I ran into a demon
Miss, easy. There is a cockroach
just about to attack you
I don't think so
No. That can't be true. It's on my shoe
Cockroach
Mamashan, come over here, fast
A suspected client wants to take me out
You have to go and induce him to kill you
Then you know if he is Melon Peeler
That's a good idea
However, can you do that for me?
I am too old to be killed
He's only interested in
young beauties like you
That sounds reasonable
Don't worry. If he killed you, I'd ask
Sir Tam to increase your salary
Who got the serve to play TV games
at this time of the night?
It's me
He comes for you
We'll talk in my room
Mamashan...
Any progress?
We did more outdoor service recently
but still no table service yet
I'm not refering to that.
Forget your table services
I suppose you forget what you are here for
don't you know that three hours earlier
There was a club-girl killed
in a night in Mongkok
What do you think?
I suppose the murderer hasn't got much money
left. That is why he moves to a low class bar
I think you know what is shame
Let me tell you two things
Firstly, the murderer my have
all his front teeth missing
It is told from the teeth mark
on the club-girl last killed
Besides, probably he has lost an ear
Because we found the remains of an ear
inside the club-girl's stomach
It is almost digested
Anyway, we cannot be certain it
a pig's ear or an human ear
Then, it is very easy to identify someone
without front teeth and an ear
Now, you know what to do. I give you
two weeks' time to get the case done
Or else, I make you a club-girl
for the rest of your life
Sir, we have our promotion campaign next week
And we will elect the hottest one
I think the murderer will come to have fun
It will be great if he is coming
Well, I am not seeing you off: Goodbye
Just now I said you would be a club-girl
forever. I don't think it will be true
For your age, you will be a hawk
in Temple street soon
Got damn you. Dare you insult me
Meat ball, what makes you cry?
Has your client gone?
He has gone: Why?
Have you switch to work in a club?
How do you know?
Cause you have phone calls frome your clients
other clubs and your woman
How can I do not know
You know how heart breaking it was when
you were with the man inside the room
It's lucky that it's easily done
Meat ball, you misunderstood me
Mum, I won't look down upon you
I think you are great
I swear I'll turn over a new leaf
I'll never read obsene books
play girls, bunk, smoke
Never steal your money
You got many bad habits
From now no, I'll work hard
If I had known, I would have make it
straight that I'm a club-girl
I'll wok hard
Your client played TV games with me
He lost twenty-eight dollars without paying
Don't let him owe you money
I know how to do
Mother
Meat ball
Team 9, telephone
Cameraman, someone asks us to make a poster
We ignored them
You are too kind to us
Do you guarantee to put us on the front page
Of course
We have our principles, we won't make any nude photos
No. We never ask people to put off
everything to shoot photos
At least put on a pair of stockings
or a watch
It's better
Let us think of that first
You are in a club deceiving girls again
Sister, I'll be fired without
photos to produce
I understand now, mum said you made
her drunk last time
What did you take last time
If i am not that bad, I won't ask
that worst girls to make photos
You insult us, We don't let you take photos
Go back to take your mum's photos: Bastard
It's really hard to make a living
in the cultural field
That's why I lost four teeth
What is this?
He is Ah Kai. The only model with our magazine
Please introduce a beauty
to take a photo with Ah Kai
You only come to me when you have problems
You figure which one of these club-girl
would not get along well with you?
How about team 169
In the Hottest Team Contest Night
I already said there must be one
Sister got a lot of enemies outside: Besides, she is insidious
What did you say?
Nothing
I'm talky, I deserve a slap
Mamashan Q.E., telephone
Stick up your forehead
and let me see you brows
Your brows are sharp and slender, just like
the new moon hanging up on the trees
You just whisper to Uncle Ho's hearing aid
We can't hear
That's the way I like it
Your brows are sharp and slender, just like
the new moon hanging up on the trees
Your eyes are clear and bright
just like waves in the sea
Lovely songs
Chi Ling, you are so cute
You are lovely too
Uncle Ho, our company is launching
a promotion next Sunday
We need your support
Sure
Uncle Ho, would you like some bean curds.
Be sure not to choke yourself
You're left-handed?
Mamashan, you know I am materialistic
You grabbed Uncle Ho from the hands of
Big Sister. You're really something
It also means saving our teams' face
But you must not forget that we are angels
Q.E., they have supper with Uncle Ho in there
Uncle Ho, we do need your support from now on
You bitch. You grabbed my customers
What do you want?
How about taking all out for supper?
It would be even better with more beauties
It's almost twelve. Tomorrow
is my 80 in birthday
Uncle Ho, are you eighty? You don't
look like. You look so healthy
80 Years old. The makes 83
on the lantern after death
What are you saying?
I'm just proposing a toast. I wish
you good luck and good health
We wish you old as pine
all the fortune and health
Fine
I wish you more future, longer life
and the older, the stronger
Peace for young and old and happy birthy
This day gonna last forever
Every luck for fortune
I wish you peace for young and old
and prosperity in business
Asorted Sushi, barbacue fish
Pepper and salted prawn, coffee or tea
All these dishes. You still want more?
No, I just want to congratulate
you on your birthday
And wish you live as long as a tortoise
or crane. Cute and fortunetoo
Coffins open their lid when they see you
What did you say?
Uncle Ho, she said you are close to death
I didn't. She lied
No, I didn't
She did say so
No
TESTING, TESTING
1, 2, 3, Uncle Ho, Can you hear?
It's all your fault, isn't it?
It's all yours
Snaky woman
You bitch
Bitch
Snaky woman
You bitch
What did you say? I can't hear
It make me angry when I can't hear
what others say in front of me
She is a bitch
Snaky woman
Shut up, one by one, you first
She is a snaky woman
What? I didn't hear
She is...
A snaky...
A dish
Snaky
Woman?
Woman, snaky woman
Fine
Your turn
Mine?
She...
Nice smell
Nose
Smell
Sniff
I don't know how you make it. Stupid fool
Me foolish, I have shown all
on my facial expression
You bastard. You can't get it
You better go to hell
What? You call me bastard and curse me!
I'll beat you up
Go
Be careful, you 'silly bitch'
I'll beat you up
Beat her up
Uncle Ho...
The Hottest Team Contest Night starts now
Our friends, welcome to the 'Crime City Club'
As you all know, the three
hottest groups of ladies
Will be elected by the tickets you buy
Prizes of the winner is gorgeous
A return ticket to Ethiopia with meals
and hotel inclusive
Mamashan, I have a feeling that
we will be the worse one
What should we afraid of. The worst is
the worst still, we are the angels
I have a feeling that Melon Peeler
will show up tonight
Listen, we have to be very alert
Melon Peeler is characterised by having
four front teeth and an ear missing
Let's go
Yes
Why did you take pictures?
My sister Q.E. Ask me to take photos here
You drink both red and white wine. No wonder
your have one ear red and one ear white
You face is red and white too.
Just like a monkeys bum
You two drink white wine and have red shit
Ladies and gentlemen, I just got
the preliminary result at hand
Up till now, the leading team is team1
Why don't we have a few words from
the Mamashan of team 1, Q.E.
Q.E. Please
Thank you for your support
I'm to glad that our team is leading
Don't you mistake it as
the Miss Hong Kong Pageant?
I want to cry
My heart is broken
As there are 238 teams of
Ladies in our company
But one of the teams is really discouraging
They are the no. 169
That's us
And it is no.169
That is the mamashan of the team.
They only got 82
470 polls behind the second last
What a pity
As Shakespeare said 'being a
woman is a dull business'
Awoman with out a man is
no better than garbage
Come out, better come out quick. You bitches
Listen girls of 169
The mission tonight is to pull polls
Just now, you said the contest
is rubbish, is nothing
Maybe it is. But one's face is more important
But Melon Peeler would be here any minute
He can't get out of our hands anyway. But
in two hours, all the polls would have gone
Get going
Go to get polls
Could I speak to Uncle Ho, please?
He isn't in?
What? Gone to Lye-yuen Villa?
No, the Kowloon Hospital. Thanks
You have a lot of restaurants?
Come to my restaurant after we fininhed
Do you know I love you so?
Don't you know our relationship?
Boss, I'll go over at onece. Please sit
Suit yourself, want a drink?
Beer?
Beer...
It must be XO
OK? OK
It's fortunate that I'm smart
It's always you get in my way
Don't I ever see you again
Why did you take my picture?
You look sexy
I lose control and the button clicked
Really?
I've made a lot of exciting photos
OK
Finish
Everybody, I got a good news!
In response to the stimulation of mamahan from team 1
After working hard
Team 169 has gained 246 more polls
The rate of increase is incompatible
It's getting closer and closer to second last
Only a different of 362 polls
Mamashan. We gonna lose
Why don't we sneak out before
they announce the results?
Sneak out? That's what a coward would do
Hurry
You gonna try my fist before you get through
Q.E. Knows you will run away
That's right
We come to get you on to the stage
Ya
Let's break through
Run
No. None's gonna get free.
How dare you beat me
Uncle Ho
You are so kind
Gentlemen, it's only half
a minute to the deadline
Hope you take your time for the last attack
However, personally, I advise mamashan of
team 1 be ready to come on to the stage
Because up till now, she leads
all the way by 3, 100 polls
Mamashan Q.E., please
Mamashan Q.E. Must win
QE, QE, QE...
Now, what about on 15 seconds countdown?
Ready, 15, 14, 13, 12, 11, 10...
Wait a minute
Hurry
Uncle Ho, have you get money for our polls?
What did you say? I can't hear
Now I demand complete silence
THIS IS AN ORDER
Uncle Ho, have you got money for our polls?
Ya, but not much
I'm sorry, I have to resume the count down
9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3...
Wait!
Probably enough for 3000 polls
Uncle Ho, fixed 3000 for us
Congratulations. Shall we have a few words
from mamashan of team 169
Thank you
THANK YOU VERY MUCH
I'm so glad tonight. I feel a little
uneasy for mamashan from team 1
Shakespeare has written 'lt is honourable
for the last one to get to top'
He also said 'lt's hard to go off
the stage with a dummy prize'
Thank you
Shup up! Stop barking
Be good! Don't be impolite
Let me introduce to you
Miss Chi Mei of the 'Crime City' Is she pretty?
You must be hungry. Let me
treat you a big dinner
Take the bag, please
Easy. We are going
Your places is really queer
This is my studio too
I did my photos here and my dissection too
Would they let you do that?
It's not up to them, anyway
These girls looks familliar
I remember, they are the victims
of a certain murder
What a concidence. You've made
photos for them before
Good. You got photos of them
at the time of murder
How can you get it, honey?
Right, the murderer has one hand
4 teeth lacking
Listen, I tell you now why I want to kill you
Because you look just like my wife
Rotten and degrading
That guy of bitch of hers knocked my teeth out
Doesn't they worth the killing?
Yes, it does
Isn't thta rotten?
I'm rottenl. From this moment, I will change
I can be a fair lady
Can you? Then show me
Go
Sit
Stand up
So like
Sleep
I will never let a man watch me sleep. Never
Don't touch me
Do I look like a lady?
Yes, you do, very much like my wife.
Like a lady outside, but you are rotten inside
You'd better get start. Don't waste time
After you died, I still
have a lot to finish up
After the photographs, I gonna kill you
Then I'll clean up and dump your corpse
I am afraid I won't have much sleep tonight
Tomorrow at seven, I have an appointment
with Margaret Cheung
I beg you
We now shoot the bustful scenes, wilder
Got to be real
CAMERA
She's changed. Don't waste your effort
It won't be help even you get in
It's all over
Drink
Come on. Drink
Please do me a favour pursuade Chi Mei
I do love her
I am afraid she's deceived by that reporter
I followed them to the house.
They made love in there
God damn you. Still thinking of girls
even when you don't have a penny
I'm glad for Chi Mei
She finally realize the importance of money
That's right
Bloody hell, drink it, want me to shit you
Alright, I'll drink it
Look at Chi Yin, she's all red
Just opposite for 'Fattie Pig'
always been white
That camera man is even stranger.
One ear red and one white when drunken
Isn't it?
Maybe one of the ears is fake
'Melon Peeler'
Bring us there now
Wait
More food?
Pick it up, please
Let me go
Your legs are nice
Really?
Don't
Winter is coming
I'll eat your legs
It is time to kill you
I blow you with an axe
You must bear the pain
Don't make here dirty
Thanks
CAMERA
Siu Wan, Siu Kit, what are you doing?
Somebody is coming
Catch him, he is in his spur of emotion
Get lost, I want to kill you bastards
Help
Bloody hell, what are you barking at!
Let me kill you
Chi Ling, what do you throw at it?
My goldin bracket
I fained
Why don't you just calm down?
PC5198, how come you bring along so much food?
Of course madam, you know
I like eating very much
Take her share otherwise
it will finish very soon
It's all finished
'Melon Peeler' has come
What's that?
It's pertrol, he wants to burn us to death
Oh God, I'm a little bit sinful though
it is not necessary to burn us to death
First part take one 'Chick Fillet Cubac'
Lit the fire. No lighter
Lit up the fire. No lighter
W.C., where are you? Come out if
you have guts. I'll beat you up
Q.E. Come on if you have guts
What? I dare not come in to beat you up?
I tell you something, sister
You must not go into spoil the whole thing
But why? You bastard, you are
always on the others side
Sister, it is not the case
What? Ambulance chasing. You will
only shoot a film for the winner
I'm very angry
No smoking, miss
None of your business
No smoking
Do you have a lit?
Sister, no smoking here
Government warning:
Smoking is hazardous to health
What are you doing?
Q: E:, you have no guts to come in?
No guts? You silly bitch
Uncle dog, Aunt dog, watch out
somebody is attacking you
Help
Siu Wan, Siu Kit, don't do this to me
Siu Wan, Siu Kit, no, I'm your sister
Beat her up
Silly bitch. You want to run away.
Help me chop her into pleces
Ah Shing, go away, it's not your business
He is hired. Move
Chi Mei. Pincers
Elbow
Knee
Damn. Pincers
Elbow
Knee
Step...
Pincers
Elbow
Knee
I pinch...
Help
we are friends. Don't beat
Damn
Are you crazy?
Don't come over. I don't want a fight
I like it
The first blood. Father, the son
and the holy gods, and go
The first blood of girls are dear
I have to avenge
God says 'Love your enemy'
I love my enemy is dead
I killed her
Why does the hole disappear?
Where is the hole?
Gold chain. I'll be rich
Gold, gonna beat you up
pass out the gold chain
You trapped me. You made me
Go, move it
Help
Sister, are you OK?
Ya, I'm fine
Sister, what's wrong?
Get lost, bitch
Don't get my closer or I'll chop him up
Go to hell
Miraculous strength
Master spirit came
Anything can't go through
All passed
The axe is real
I'm painful
We got a way out
We can saw the rods part and jump
Open the door
You can't go away
Just like in a sauna, bitch
Cheers
Guess whether Sir Tam has heard about it?
He would have learnt from
the news early this morning
This looks like mom's client
Mom, you got a client on TV
Do I? Let me see
Deputy Police Commissioner Mr Tam Tai Tok
Last night in his friend's home
He lost much in Mah-jon game
Thus, heart attach immediately
Died on the way to hospital
Age 46
Mah-jon Trade Union shall hold
the funeral ceremony tomorrow
Each and every of you looks
Upon this whole world only 8
of us know all about the plan
Nobody would know if he died?
Don't press me.
I have studied what you said
There seems so evidence of you being a
'Cover Up as a Club-girl'
What the hell is all about?
SIR
They found this order in the
files of Superintendent Tam
It has your names written
You are too lucky
This seems the ony evidence supporting you
It's alright then
Shut up
What are you doing?
What's the meaning?
What do you want?
Now then, there wouldn't be any evidence
Don't worry, it can't be
I know he's kidding.
He already got a photocopy
No. I'm sorry
You...
Look for yourselves
What is this?
You were elected 'The hottest girls'
It's all published on news. How can
we have you in our force again?
I'm just protecting the name of
the Rayol Hongkong Police Force
What can we do then?
Get back to where you belong
Great
Objection
No, I can't, what would my son say?
Why are you so sad?
You can all make bucks, poor me. I only got a
thousand or two. How can I survive on that