- Hello there, boys and girls.
Recently you may have noticed
some changes in your bodies.
But don't worry, these
changes are perfectly normal.
What's happening to
you is called puberty.
It's the process of changing
from a child into an adult.
- Deaths have been reported
in cities around the world.
Back to you-
- This ain't from
nature, people.
This is a man-made
biological weapon.
- The scale of which
we have never seen
and every adult is at risk.
- It appears the
disease has no effect
on prepubescent children.
However, when infected
children reach puberty,
the effects of the
disease will be fatal.
- It may seem strange,
uncomfortable,
even unpleasant at times,
but it happens to each
and every one of us.
- Let us pray for our children,
for soon we will be gone
and they will have to
suffer this plague alone.
- We're not gonna make it!
Yes we are! Hooah!
- Cute backpack.
Bring it here.
- Come and get it.
- Ah, ah. I got this.
Look, buddy, there's two
ways this can go down.
The easy way, or...
What am I saying?
Nothing is world
is fucking easy!
- He cut you?
- I'm solid.
- Tell me he's got water.
I'd kill for something
with bubbles.
Shit, man.
What's with you?
Think it's funny?
Starving to death in
the fucking woods?
- Shh!
Listen.
You hear that?
- Where are we?
This place ain't on the map.
We should skip it. We
gotta find that genius.
- Wait.
They've got water.
But they're packing heat.
Heavy.
- Water?
They got a whole ocean!
♪ You never want to hurt
the one who loves you ♪
So.
What's our move here?
- It's my move.
You're staying on recon.
- Boring!
- Lay low and suss out the area.
This is just a pit stop.
- Wait. You're leaving me here?
Alone?
In Blue Meanie territory?
I heard they found
geezers around here.
Wrapped in blue plastic.
Throats cut open.
Like pigs.
- Don't be a pussy.
I'll back with a tasty
treat just for you.
Don't lose that.
Scared of a ghost story.
- I ain't scared!
It ain't no story.
- Mm-hmm.
- Halt!
Who's there?
- Water!
Please.
Meet me in three. By
the jazz swingers.
- Jazz swingers?
Thank you.
It's been rough out there.
I'm headed north.
Town called Derby.
Heard of it?
They say there's
like some kid genius
who made a vaccine or something.
It's probably just a rumor,
but I'm still gonna go look...
- Are you alone?
You sure?
I hate surprises.
- Yes.
- I'm just playing.
I love surprises. You're
coming from the city, right?
I heard kids over there
be going, like, crazy,
like full-on Mad
Max and whatnot.
My mom was from there.
Where are you from?
- I'm from- - Oh!
Guess what I'm working on?
Bet you money you can't guess.
Not that money matters anymore.
I'm sorry, I just get really
excited when I meet new people.
Oh, speaking of surprises, I
need to show you something.
My project, Al-Shifa.
You're gonna bug out. It's
literally gonna change the world.
Can you walk on that?
- Sorta.
- Great. Here, let
me get that for you.
- Hands up and don't move.
All of your shit? It's mine now.
So be a doll and
gather it up for me
and I'll be on my merry way.
- Whose blood is that?
- The last fucker who
didn't do as they were told.
Hold still!
One more step and I toast you.
I'm for real, this aint a game.
- Sure it is.
- Kids these days.
- Wow!
You were really gonna
ice me just like that.
You cold-blooded.
Tell you what.
Apologize and maybe I'll
still show you my project.
- Back the fuck off!
Hey, Bui!
- Okay, you know what?
Now you're starting
to piss me off.
- Ow!
Ow! Ow!
Ow!
Please.
No. No more shots.
No!
Stop!
Don't! I'm not sick anymore!
Get off of me!
Stop! Stop!
Stop! Ow!
- Idiot!
Hold still!
- Kid.
Kid!
- My name is Kuan.
And I bet we're,
like, the same age.
Okay.
This is going to hurt,
but you're a dingus.
And you sorta deserve it.
- Ow!
- I ain't scared.
♪ Oh, I wish I had
someone to love me ♪
♪ Someone to call me their own ♪
♪ Oh, I wish I had
someone to live with ♪
- What is this?
- Dinner.
- This smells like
actual garbage.
Wait! Sorry.
♪ Oh, please meet me
tonight in the moonlight ♪
♪ Please meet me
tonight all alone ♪
- Aw, jackpot.
These are mine, girl.
- Ines.
- What?
- Ines. That's my
name, it's French.
It's clear tonight.
- Dormir a la belle etoile.
That's French for
"to sleep under-"
- Je sais. Tu parles francais?
- Oh. Uh, no.
Not really. My mom taught me.
She knew, like, 20 languages.
Wanted to learn 'em all.
Even at the very end.
You should've seen her
in her hospital bed
with like all of her phrasebooks
stacked up around her.
Counting to 10 in Indonesian.
Satu.
Dua.
Tiga.
- Kuan, why are you helping me?
- The way I see it is that
we're helping each other.
My project, it's...
It's like a football game.
I need a team. I
can't do it alone.
Unless I threw the ball
really high to myself.
Or made little cardboard
team cutout people and-
- What project?
- You ever heard of Al-Shifa?
It's this ancient Persian
book. It means "The Healing."
Now, I'm not religious, really,
but they say that
if you can recite
all of Al-Shifa to a sick man,
he will be cured like that.
So that's what I'm building.
That's my project. Hold this.
- You're making a cure?
- Yep.
- I knew it!
You're the kid genius! You're
the one I've been looking for!
- You can't cure the virus.
That's literally impossible.
My cure is for something else.
- Wait, then you're
not- - Watch this.
I am a golden god...
Or not.
Dang it.
- Wait, so what are
you curing then?
- Well, it's like...
Did you believe in Santa
Claus when you were younger?
- Of course.
- Right, so when you're a kid,
you believe in the impossible.
But then you grow up
and the world teaches
you that it's not true.
You stop believing.
But what if the world is wrong?
- The fuck are
you talking about?
Have you see the world today?
The twisted shit these kids
are doing to each other?
It's a sickness! We're
all sick, inside and out.
I'm sorry, but you're
weird and I'm confused
and this all just seems
like a huge waste of time!
Which, if you hadn't noticed,
that is in short
supply these days!
And I want...
I, I...
- What do you want?
- I...
I...
Bui, don't!
- Big mistake!
You guys are dead!
- She hurt you?
- We gotta take her out.
What the fuck?
Bui!
Shit!
- Faster.
You know, I had a,
like, perfect plan
before you and your
butthole friend came
and mucked everything up.
Now I'm not so sure.
I mean, maybe you're right.
Maybe I got this
world all wrong.
I mean, shit, we're
gonna die anyway, right?
Why waste time?
Why not kill each other?
Move.
What do you see?
- A moldy old slide.
Wrong.
You're only what's
right in front of you.
You have an imagination,
don't you, dummy?
So use it.
See what this place could be.
What we could share with
everyone that's left.
Look.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
No!
Can we do that again?
- Yeah!
- As we go through puberty,
we start to notice
changes in our bodies.
Our voices start
to sound different.
See, there's an
organ in your throat
called the larynx, or voice box.
During puberty your larynx
grows thicker and larger.
Boys will notice their
voice becoming deeper.
Girls will too,
but only a little.
So buckle up because
puberty is taking you
on the bumpy road to adulthood.
- Relax, Scarface.
The first kill is
always the hardest.
It'll get much easier with
a little more practice.
And cheer up. You're
this week's champion!
You just made my new squad.
Here's your uniform.
Scarface, don't go
crybaby on me now.
You wanna be part of my
squad, you better man up.
- Hey! Get over here!
Hurry up! Faster!
- Fucking bitch.
- Where did you
learn to do that?
You're a freaking fish ninja.
- YouTube.
- You see what
I'm seeing, right?
- Hell yes.
A little salt, some chili
oil, and we got us a tasty...
- Hands off Carpe Diem!
Have a little vision. This
is only the beginning.
We get your gigantic
friend to help us,
we stock this place
full of specimens,
make sure the rides and slides
are spic and span and up
and running, and boom!
We are the proud owners
of the best theme park slash
aquatic entertainment center
in the world.
- Best and only.
Huh! Fuck me.
So why carry a fake gun
when you got the real thing?
- Never let the enemy know
the true power of your forces.
Art of War.
Sunny Zoo wrote that.
- It's Sun Tzu, not Sunny Zoo.
And he never said that.
- It was Tom Cruise then.
Say, what do you think
happened to the zoos?
Do you think all the
animals ate each other?
Or did some of them escape
and start toasting people?
What would you rather fight?
A lion or a Blue Meanie?
- A Blue Meanie. 'Cause
they aren't real.
- They are too real.
We're on the same
team now, right?
And you're going to put
your genius hunt on hold
and help me with Al-Shifa.
Don't lie!
I can see if you're lying.
- Bullshit you can.
- Wait!
Wow.
You just, like, saved my life.
- This guy's not poisonous.
- Are too real!
- Dude!
The Blue Meanies were
made up by some kingpin
to freak his squad out
and keep 'em in line.
Trust me, it's what I do.
Only I'd come up
with a better name.
- You ain't got no squad.
- I used to.
- What happened to 'em?
- What do you think? They
were two grades ahead.
They went geezer a while back.
Bui and I are all that's left.
- Oh. I'm sorry.
- Don't be. No one's
gonna miss those pricks.
- I wish I had a squad.
All I got is stupid Luka.
- Who?
- Luka, my brother.
He's a real pain in my ass.
I mean, he was supposed to
re-up on water from the river.
I'm sure he's out there
somewhere just, like,
playing with little
cars or something.
I mean, this kid...
Earth to Ines!
- Sorry. What was...
- I said did you happen to
see Luka on your way in?
- Sorry.
- What a little fuckin' pussy.
- Easy, tiger.
- Took you long enough.
- If you played nice with
her for like two seconds,
she'd let you go.
- When do we play nice?
Don't get it, man.
Shit here's all backwards.
Shit!
- Chill!
She won't see us.
- Ugh.
She's crazy and tone-deaf.
Yo, we're wasting time here.
We gotta get moving and
find that genius already.
You wanna go full geezer
in this shithole or what?
- So just lie to her.
Say you're sorry.
- I ain't like you.
I ain't a liar.
- You're a pain in my
ass is what you are.
- Wait.
- I got the wrong key.
- Since day one I've done
like you've always said.
I might not be clever like you,
but I can see what's
in front of my face.
And I'm telling you, that girl,
she ain't us.
- Bui.
Let me go!
- She fucking stabbed me!
What are you all standing
around for? Do something!
One of you get her!
I'm your goddamn leader!
Oh shit.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit!
- The king is dead. Long
live the motherfucking queen!
From now on you do what
I say, when I say it,
or you get toasted.
We crystal on that?
Lovely.
First things first:
no more of this.
We shouldn't be
fighting each other.
This aint' fuckin'
"Hunger Games."
We stick together and we keep
the system nice and binary.
There are two kinds of people.
There's us and there's them.
And if you ain't us,
well, then tough titty.
What do you say?
Bui?
Us?
Or them?
Wait! I...
I give up!
You win! Stop, please!
This is your last chance.
Concentrate.
Make it count.
Ho-ho-ho!
C'est dommage.
So close.
Hey! You only get three tries!
You know, cheaters
only cheat themselves.
Silly girl.
Aw, snap. It's chow time.
- We are not eating that
garbage-ass stew ever again.
- Wow. Harsh. ♪ Two
lovers quarrel ♪
♪ And then they break up ♪
♪ Time goes by ♪
♪ They kiss and make up ♪
♪ And before they mend
their broken hearts ♪
♪ Before they've gone too far ♪
What's another word for sacred?
- Um...
Holy?
Hallowed?
Divine.
- Hallowed. That's perfect.
Hey, wanna know what
I'm writing about?
- Not really.
- Ah!
Oh, dios mio!
This is the tastiest
thing that I've ever ate
in my entire life.
This is magic. This...
This is...
This is Carpe Diem.
I loved that fish.
- And it's not your fish.
It's Severus Snake.
- Not cool!
What the heck kind of name
is Severus Snake anyway?
That's like not even...
Oh, wait.
No, I get it.
That's actually pretty
funny. That's pretty funny.
♪ Stop and think
before you act ♪
♪ In everything you do ♪
♪ Broken hearts can be mended ♪
♪ But when they've
gone too far ♪
♪ Mended hearts
always leave a scar ♪
Ines, how come you
know so many words?
- I read a lot. Like your mom.
- You were sick too?
- Mm-hmm.
- So tell me about it.
- Uh, I don't now.
I spent a lot of
time in the hospital.
There was no one to talk
to. I was bored as shit.
- Where were your parents?
- I never met them.
So I read.
A lot.
My favorites were the stories
with disasters and monsters
where everyone dies at the end.
I started imagining what I'd
do if that ever happened to me.
And then I started, like,
researching what to do.
And the more I read,
the more I started to
believe it was all real.
And it sounds nuts,
but it was almost
like I was waiting
for the end of the world.
So that when it finally
came, I was ready.
Although I was hoping there
would be some zombies.
- There's Blue Meanies.
- Shut up and pull it.
- Aw, man, that's it?
It looks terrible!
I spend like so
long working on...
You did it!
Magnifique!
Ah!
♪ Mended hearts
always leave a scar ♪
You hear that?
- It's Bui.
♪ In everything you do ♪
♪ Broken hearts can be mended ♪
♪ But when they've gone to far ♪
♪ Mended hearts always ♪
- Wowzas.
- You should hear
him on the guitar
♪ Leave a scar ♪
- Time to signal Luka,
make sure he's okay.
Be right back.
- So. What do you think?
Is Luka gonna be okay?
- What are you talking about?
- Don't play stupid with me.
- Just keeping it on your level.
- Why you always
ragging on me? Huh?
Like, why you gotta
be so nice to her
and such a dickhole to me?
Is it 'cause I know the real you
and not this fake-ass
character you're playing?
Is that it?
It's like, what if she knew
you toasted her little friend?
Would you still be
all BFF then? Huh?
- For two years I've kept your
dead-weight bitch-ass alive!
Remind me why I bother.
- I wasn't gonna tell
her nothing! I swear!
Ines! Ines, wait!
Shit!
- He's gone. Isn't he?
- Kuan, I gotta
tell you something-
- You know, every time
this happens, it gets...
Easier to say goodbye and...
Just like that, you
start to forget.
I don't want to be forgotten.
I don't want this place
to just disappear.
I want us, all of us,
to build it, together.
To remind everyone that's
left what this world could be.
What it should be.
And I believe in that.
In this place. It can save us.
I'm not crazy for
thinking that, am I?
- Oh, you're definitely crazy.
But you're right
about this place.
It's...
It's really special.
What?
- You have, like, some
paint on your face.
- Ow! Be gentle.
- Ines!
It's time for us
to go. Right now.
- Bui- - Me or her!
Who's it gonna be?
- Big guy, you need
to take a chill pill.
- Move.
- Bui, no!
- Oh, you're dead!
- Guys! Stop!
Ow!
- You okay?
- Ow!
- This was Luka's.
You!
No.
It was you.
Yeah. Of course it was.
- Kuan, please. I didn't know.
- Should've seen it right away.
But I saw something in you.
You were different.
You were good!
I'm so fucking stupid!
Now you have 10 seconds
to get out of here
before I'm back with a
bullet for each of you.
You killers.
You fucks!
You don't belong here!
You'll never be cured.
And you'll die.
And you'll rot.
And you'll be forgotten.
- Kuan!
Kuan!
No, Kuan!
Please!
- Shit!
Shit.
Come on, we gotta go! Come on!
We gotta get those gats.
Where's that cabinet? Come on!
- But the Blue Meanies,
they're not real!
Bui!
Bui.
Stop.
- Gotta keep...
- Dammit, let me down!
- Ines, we gotta...
We gotta keep going.
- There's no we.
And there never was.
There's you and there's me.
So go. Keep off the trails
and you can make it.
- Ines.
Fuck you.
They're close.
Shit.
Come on, you gotta
eat something.
Shit.
- Put me down.
- Ines- - I need to see this!
- Okay!
Chill.
- His throat.
Looks like it's smiling.
- Come on.
Creep.
Good news. 10 miles.
Derby's up the road.
If we hustle tomorrow
we can find your genius.
- There's no genius.
No cure.
She was the only one
who understood that.
And even still, she
built all of that...
Al-Shifa.
What a useless thing to do.
I never got to say goodbye.
- Leave it.
We need to keep on.
You want it? You want it?
I'm sick and tired of
this crybaby routine.
It ain't you.
Snap out of it!
Ines!
Ines, for real!
You can barely swim!
- You can't swim at all!
You wanted me to choose!
I would've taken Kuan!
Not you!
- Think you're so
fucking smart...
But you don't know
dick about shit!
Family ain't
something you choose.
- Family?
- You can't stop me!
You and me? We're family!
You can't...
And you can't change
that, you stupid...
Stupid asshole!
- Bui!
Bui! Shit!
No!
Wake up!
- What a little fuckin' pussy.
- Hey, kid.
Word of advice? Never
let them see you cry.
See you around, kid.
No! No!
Fuck this!
Get up!
There's work to do and
you're not finished yet!
I need you, Bui!
So if you know
what's good for you,
you better take
a fucking breath!
Right fucking now!
Please!
Oh my god!
- Did you try to kiss me?
Ow.
- Don't ever do that again.
- This is all I could find.
What's your move here?
- Our move.
We're done running.
It's time to hunt.
You'll be the bait.
- Wait. Wait, what?
- Trust me.
This is gonna work.
♪ But when ye come ♪
♪ And all the
flowers are dying ♪
♪ If I am dead, as
dead I well may be ♪
♪ Oh, Danny boy ♪
♪ The pipes, the
pipes are calling ♪
♪ From glen to glen ♪
♪ And down the mountainside ♪
♪ The summer's gone ♪
♪ And all the roses ♪
- Man, this plan sucks!
- Checkmate, dickhead.
Well, fuck me.
Hey, freak!
Drop it or I open her up like
a fucking Christmas present.
Let my friend go.
You okay?
- Solid.
- Blue Meanies my ass.
Look at you losers. You
ain't nothin' scary.
You're just a
couple of stupid...
Stupid kids.
- The hell are you doing?
- Let 'em go.
Trust me.
- We can't just leave them.
- Sure we can. They're smart.
They know what happens
if they come at us again.
Come on.
Bitch, are you deaf and dumb?
- Hehp ooh. Hehp ooh.
Hehp ooh.
- I don't speak fuckin' Meanie.
- Hehp ooh.
- Hehp ooh?
You've gotta be kidding.
All this time...
You...
All this time, y'all were...
Y'all were, uh...
- Ines? Ines, Ines, Ines!
Ines!
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
- The more you know,
the less you now.
Or is it the other way around?
The less you know,
more- - Am I...
I mean, like...
Are we...
Are we dead?
- I don't feel dead.
But I have been here
for, like, an eternity,
which is a lot of time
to think about things.
- What kind of things?
- Ines things. Your whole deal.
Your purpose, why
you exist, you know.
All the basic stuff.
- I've done terrible things.
Made so many mistakes.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Or if I ever did.
- What you should do is
throw the friggin' plane.
You may not see it yet,
but you're on a path.
A road you've been walking
down your whole life.
And it's bumpy and it's rough
and sometimes you get a
little rock in your shoe
and then you get a blister
and then the blister just
keeps bursting, it's the worst,
then you wonder, "Is this
the wrong shoe for this?"
But you gotta keep
walking the path
and leading the others
down it with you.
'Cause that's what
girls like you do.
Everything we do in this life,
the good, the bad,
the help and the hurt,
it all gets added up.
And in the end,
I'll bet top dollar
that you'll have
a big ol', giant, 10-story
stack of good in your hands.
You just gotta keep on.
- Kuan?
I...
I'm...
- I know, girl.
Me too.
- Hey!
The bag.
Toss it over here.
You got a death wish, bitch?
Yeah.
That's what I thought.
Aw, fuck!
Let me go!
Oh shit, you're one of
them! Please don't kill me!
I have money!