Seek those things that are above...
not those things
that are upon the Earth.
Brothers and sisters...
every day I hear
a grumbling against God.
Times are hard.
The times are bad.
Grievous times.
And that they are.
But let us not forget...
the words of the Apostle
in his letter to the Romans.
"The sufferings of this present time
"are not to be compared
with the future glory,
"the glory that shall
be revealed in us."
Indeed, brothers and sisters,
I would go further.
I would go further and say
that this life simply has to be harsh...
to stop Earthly happiness
being loved.
It is essential that this life
be troubled so that the other life...
Right now it is still dark.
You cannot see God yet...
or hold in your hands...
all that he has promised you.
But do not despair. Trust in him.
Hope.
Hope in him.
You will not be disappointed.
Tribulation produces patience.
Patience passes the test.
Passing the test gives us hope.
While hope...
Hope does not disappoint.
So the other life may be light.
Seek those things that are above...
not those things
that are upon the Earth.
Straw, Springer...
look away.
Look away.
I just like to announce the moment.
- OK, OK.
- It's all right.
All right, Brendan, God be with you.
Hey!
What's that?
Robber scum skulking
in the bushes, eh?
- Where are the others? Up ahead?
- I'm alone!
- Yes!
Stephen!
In these times, what kind of fool
travels the road alone?
I'm a laborer out of bond. I left
my master's land without a license.
He's lying.
Oh, God, please.
- Speak up.
- Please don't.
Or shall we loosen
your tongue with a knife?
Listen, let me go.
I promise I won't say what I saw.
What? What did you see?
I saw a merchant
dragged from his cart.
Aye, now we are the brigands.
Your clothes.
Our costumes, worn against the cold.
- Costumes?
- We're actors.
Traveling actors.
And here's our badge of livery.
We're Lord Robert Sanville's company.
- Martin?
- He's no brigand.
I saw you kill a man.
Brendan was my father,
our father and our leader.
He's been ill for many months.
A canker of the belly.
He begged us to end his pain.
The hands of a laborer?
I don't think so.
Come on. This bloody axle!
It's getting worse.
We'll find a cartwright
in the next town.
What do we pay him with?
We've not even got enough
to bury Brendan.
Then we'll perform.
Where are you headed?
North to Durham,
to perform for our lord's cousin.
That's all we are, a Christmas gift
from one noble family to another.
Come on!
- Can I come with you?
- No!
Hello!
I want to join your troupe.
You know you're short an actor.
I could learn.
No one could ever
replace Brendan. No one.
Well, I wouldn't try and replace him,
just plug the hole he left behind.
Whoa.
Plug the hole he left behind?
All right, let's see what you can do.
I know, be a bird.
- Be a what?
- A bird. Be a bird.
How about if we try a heron?
A big gangling lad like you.
Aye, that's it.
But now on one leg.
Hop. Move, move.
Not around in circles. Go that way.
Godspeed, stranger.
He's right. With Brendan gone,
our parts will have to change.
We need someone
to play the minor roles.
Attendant Angel, Devil's Fool.
You're the fool, Marty.
We don't even know who he is.
Halt.
- We'll vote on it.
- What?
As our leader, I'm calling a vote.
Springer?
Oh, well, there's a surprise.
I'm against it.
Need you ask?
Straw?
Well, I've never seen a heron like it.
I'm with you.
Welcome.
I know what you're doing.
Come on.
Where to now?
We head west.
And why not east?
Fenland's impassible.
And towards the west?
I don't know, Tobias,
I've never been there.
Hey, hey, whoa.
Whoa. Whoa!
So where is everyone?
Hello?
- There's no one here.
- We'll head up this way.
Get. Get.
Get, get, get, get, get.
Hey, hey, hey, come on! Come on.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Come on.
Come here. Come here, you.
You're useless!
Whoa.
How many can say
they've walked their roads
and wet their fields without fear?
Sleep safe in their beds at night,
their bellies full?
If we can, it is because
each man plays his part in it.
There can be no exceptions.
For his vigilance in this affair,
the court is beholden
to Brother Simon Damian,
confessor to our noble lord,
Robert de Guise...
from whom this court
draws the power to dispense justice
according to the laws of the land.
After due deliberation of the facts
and circumstances of this case,
it is our finding that the accused
is guilty as charged.
It is the sentence of this court
that you be hanged by the neck
and your body drawn
until you are dead.
And may God have mercy on your soul.
- What was her crime?
- Murder.
Young Thomas Wells.
Sixpence for this?
For the use of the yard, twopence
on every shilling taken at the gate.
Twopence?
It's the Feast of Saint Lazarus
tomorrow.
There'll be plenty other minstrels
happy to pay the price.
We're not some band
of minstrels. We're actors.
Actors, minstrels or scoundrels,
it's a share of the purse.
We'll take it.
When I think of the respect
our profession used to command...
One, two, three. Pull!
- Sorry, Martin.
- Straw.
- Come on, Straw.
- Get the head.
- Get it in front, Straw.
- Get it.
- Get the head.
- I'm trying.
- Keep him covered. Quickly.
- Hold him up, Straw.
- To the barn.
- Hold him up.
- That's right, hold him up.
- Which way, Martin?
- To the right.
He's not stiff anymore.
That's what happens after a day
and a night have passed.
Cover him up, Stephen.
Stephen, cover him up.
You know a lot about death.
- So does Stephen.
- Stephen was a soldier.
This one doesn't strike me
as a veteran of any war.
The first plague hit my village hard.
Those of us who were spared
saw to those of us who weren't.
He's a liar.
That fucking lad is a liar.
Again.
That's it.
Tobias is right, we need a cartwright.
Good people, we give you our play
of Adam and Eve.
We pray you, give your ears and eyes.
See Eden lost by Satan's lies.
How woman led her man to fall
from holy grace and with him, all.
I, God, great in majesty,
in whom no first or last can be.
Heaven and Earth are made through me.
And at my bidding now be light.
With breath and body...
him to bless,
above all creatures...
both great and less.
The serpent came with song...
and smile, but Adam slept,
free from his wiles.
And while he slumbered, thus alone,
I drew from him a single bone...
and fashioned forth a human mate...
that mankind might itself cre...
Create.
Ghostly paradise I was in.
But thence I fell,
and through my sin,
Earthly Paradise, my God's gift,
men and women dwell within.
I have tried my all, but in vain,
by my wiles to bring them pain.
By my wiles to bring them pain.
By my wiles to bring them pain!
Or must I say that line again?
If the world belong to thee,
lord of all things thou wouldst be.
If the world belonged to me,
women all would ready be
to harken to the devil!
I'm... I'm sorry.
Two measly shillings.
We used to make ten.
Not exactly a fortune, is it?
Well, it is enough to bury Brendan
and be on our way.
Oh, Brendan, Brendan.
Who would have thought
he would end up in this hellhole?
Father?
We'd like to have a word with you.
There's a friend of ours
we'd like to have buried.
Dead, I trust?
As you can see,
we're a little busy here.
A child's grave.
Thomas Wells.
- Come now.
- The boy murdered by the woman?
Aye. She strangled him.
Yeah.
- Six shillings.
- Six?
Six.
Six shillings.
Are you, by any chance,
related to the innkeeper?
I am not some tinker
to be bartered with.
We'll bury him in a wood out of town.
I promised him hallowed ground.
We have no choice, Martin.
- You understand?
- What kind of God
inflicts such suffering
on his loyal servant?
Or, indeed, his own son?
- Amen.
Goodbye, old friend.
- Nicholas, thank you.
- Thank you.
Thank you, Father.
- It's just you, a priest.
- Martin, please.
What did you do?
A priest on the road,
traveling incognito.
- A man's secrets are his own, Tobias.
- No, no, no, it's fine.
I should tell.
I lay with a woman from my village...
another man's wife.
I thought that went with the job.
- Enough said, I think.
- No, no, no, no, no.
I want to know every
sordid little detail.
Get off. Get off of me.
- It's been so long.
- You're the devil, my guest.
Stay.
What are you really running from?
I see it in you.
Not the woman.
Some darker secret.
As long as you're with us...
you force us to carry it too.
Where will you go?
- The traveler's friend.
- Saint Christopher.
It was my mother's,
and her mother's before her.
Where is she now?
Plague.
- Who did you lose?
- A sister.
I begged to be taken with her.
And God had another purpose for you?
I think he's given up
hope on me by now.
Without you, a good man would not
have received the burial he deserved.
You've earned our thanks, I daresay.
Our friendship will follow.
It may not be much...
but it's more than lies out there.
Nicholas, would you have paid
good money to have seen
our play last night?
You're not alone.
No one comes to see us anymore.
Our purse is always empty, our stomachs rarely full.
In Wakefield and York
the guilds put on cycles
of all of the mysteries in a week,
everything from the fall of Lucifer
to the Day of Judgment.
In Coventry, I saw Christ
resurrected from the tomb,
hoisted up to the heavens
on a cord not visible to the eye.
- How can we match them?
- You can't.
Not unless we change our stories.
You can't change stories,
they're written in the Bible.
I'm talking about new stories.
Ask yourself:
What matters more
to the people of this town,
Eve's temptation of Adam,
or the murder of a young boy
who's lived among them for years?
- Feast of Saint Lazarus.
- Bad day for pigs.
- I'll settle up with the cartwright.
- Martin?
It's a gift.
That ass-faced innkeeper
and his poisonous ale,
I'll be glad to see
the back of both of them.
Bad news.
The axle can't be repaired.
It has to be replaced.
- How much?
- We must perform again.
I can barely stand upright,
let alone prance about a yard on stilts.
You may not have to.
I have a proposal.
We change our play.
Oh, please, please, not the Crucifixion.
All that hollering.
A new play.
A play about greed,
temptation and mortal sin.
A tale in which virtue and vice contend
for the soul of a young woman,
and justice prevails as she must.
- Thomas Wells?
- Thomas who?
He's the young lad
who sleeps beneath Brendan.
- I knew it.
- The one that girl murdered.
Who dares play things
that happen in this world?
It was just a question of time.
I believe this is the way plays
will be made in times to come.
So you've been saying for years.
But what did your father
think of your ideas?
By naming me as his successor,
I believe he was condoning them.
- Lies! Lies, Martin.
- Even at the last.
Lies, and you know it.
Your father'd turn in his grave
if he could hear you now.
I don't know about that.
It's a tight fit in there.
Martin, it's just a killing.
So was Cain and Abel,
and we've played it often.
Cain and Abel is in the Bible.
God has not revealed to us
the meaning of this story.
So much of God's meaning
remains hidden to us.
Why does he visit blights upon
our crops, plagues upon our people?
The priests spout empty words
from the pulpit,
but we can show the people
God's hand at work
with real stories,
in events that touch us directly.
- Why did she kill him?
- You've no voice in this.
But I have.
Greed. The boy was carrying
his father's purse at the time.
She lured him off the road,
then strangled him.
Then the road is the way of life.
- The path of righteousness.
- Yes.
And by turning aside for temptation,
the boy found death lurking for him.
Don't you see?
It's a morality play.
Only the figures are different.
So where are the words for this play?
We can do it in mime,
speak words as we think them.
Tobias?
The minds of men may change...
but we have no authority
from God on this.
- I'm still against it.
- So am I.
Well, why not?
We are stuck here till tomorrow,
like it or not.
Springer?
Three for, two against.
The deciding vote is yours.
An equal split
goes against the proposal.
Remember, you're a priest.
God hasn't given us this story to use.
No.
But he is everywhere,
even in this story.
Martin's right, it's for us to find him.
Just as I thought.
An ally to swing the vote your way.
We'll perform this afternoon...
and use the morning to find out
more of what happened.
- Jack Flint?
- Yeah?
You're the man who found
the body of Thomas Wells.
Are you from the castle?
Because I've already...
No, I'm a player. We plan to
tell the story of the killing.
Worse than I feared.
De Rougement.
Ampleforth, even Vilius.
Martin!
Martin?
- Where are you going?
- What did you find out?
Nothing. He wouldn't speak to me.
No one would.
It's a feast day.
They've got other things
to think about.
Come on.
- Half a shilling?
- See into her heart.
The heart of our play.
In.
- Did you hear?
- Who are these people?
Guests of Lord de Guise.
There's one who left his lands
to work for another.
Another who preached dissent!
It was he that gave me the money.
You can stay here and watch.
Hey.
Beware her touch.
They say she has the power.
- What power?
- Well,
you've paid dear for the pleasure
of hearing your own crowing.
She's deaf and dumb!
My name is Martin.
That's Nicholas.
We're players.
What am I doing?
She can't hear.
Look.
You can see my words?
We're to tell your story on our stage.
Why did you do it?
What possessed you?
A young boy, a child.
The monk saw you
near the woods at dusk.
He's lying. Why?
But the sheriff and his men
found the boy's purse in your house.
The monk. The one at the trial?
That... That monk?
Purse.
The monk's purse.
The boy's purse.
The monk...
grabbed the boy's purse...
and hid it under your bed.
You saw him do this?
You weren't there?
So the...
The monk was with them...
when they searched your house?
And they arrested you
when you returned.
Silence in there!
You didn't do it.
Got it.
She didn't do it.
She wasn't even there.
So she says. So would you.
- She wasn't there.
- What would you have us do?
Declare her innocent based on
a few snatches of mime?
You're a player, a master player.
You know how to read people.
Tell me she was lying.
Look at me.
For heaven sakes, man,
we're actors, not judges.
Well, that's exactly
what we have become.
Just tell me she was lying.
Look at me.
I'll hear no more of this.
&
Right.
The lad went with his family
to a village just near here
to sell his horse.
- It was a cow.
- A horse, a cow, it doesn't matter.
The point is, his father
went straight to the nearest alehouse
with the money, to drink it all away.
- And he would have done so...
- If his wife
hadn't slipped it to Thomas,
sending him home with it.
Which is why he was on the road.
It's why he got strangled.
Yes, all right, we
know the rest of it.
Good work, Springer.
We'll open with the alehouse.
Tobias, set up the table here.
Stephen, you play the drunken father.
Straw, you'll have to double.
You'll play both
the mother and the woman.
Her name is Martha.
And you, Nicholas,
shall be Good Counsel,
urging Thomas to stay on the path,
the way of life.
Right. Right, where should we
start from?
From over there.
&
What troubles you?
Ask your brother.
You're free to leave.
If I do, does my precious vote
go with me?
I will put on this play
with or without you.
The first are arriving.
Sarah.
- Well, take your place.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Hey.
Tobias.
Good masters!
- We beg your patience.
- Yes, sir.
And also to give
good audience to our play,
which is also yours.
It's a new thing to make a play
that belongs to a town,
and this play does honor
to your town, for it shows
that wrongdoers are punished here
with great speed of justice.
Gentle people, we give you our play
of Thomas Wells.
The family have just sold their cow.
Their purse is full.
They pass an alehouse.
He tries in vain for half a day,
to drink that precious purse away.
Are you ready?
- As daylight fades, so does he.
- Straw, take the purse.
For his wife, an opportunity.
Each and every man
to keep well upon...
Take it now, Straw.
The purse recovered, she must stay,
and so dispatches Thomas on his way.
Of Christ, Good Counsel is my name.
The shadows lengthen,
night draws ever near,
- he's tired and cold,
- Martin.
His young heart gripped by fear.
He quickens his pace,
still clutching his precious load,
- recalling the words of...
- Straw needs more time.
Pas de deux as best you can.
Use your Latin.
You never know.
- Go on.
- Good Counsel is my name,
and some call me Conscience.
- My task it is...
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Head.
- Come on.
To urge each and every man
to keep well upon the way of life.
Which path was opened to us
by the sufferings of Christ.
&
Come on, come on, come on.
Heed well my words, Thomas,
for as everyone here is aware,
it's in the contrary nature
of the young
to be drawn to the very thing
from which they are warned,
- convinced that their elders conspire
- It's a disaster.
To keep some...
hidden fruit that must be tasted.
Sin, in the beginning,
may seem full sweet,
but the reckoning comes,
be you never so fleet.
The die is cast,
- his fate now sealed,
- It wasn't like that!
- As Thomas to temptation yields.
- No. No.
- What did you say?
- My Thomas was a good boy.
Too young to know who holds his hand,
- I know my son, I know him.
- And draws him to the shady land.
He wouldn't have gone with her,
I tell you.
- I'm sorry.
- He wouldn't have gone with her.
He wouldn't have gone with her,
I tell you.
- I'm sorry.
- His mother should know.
- The Reaper,
- Martin.
- In a guise so sweet.
- But he must have gone with her.
His body was found in the woods.
She wasn't strong enough to carry him.
No, not strong enough
to wring his neck, neither.
- Well, now, he was just a boy.
- Big beyond his years, he was.
And strong as an ox.
Get me the sheriff! Now!
Get off the stage.
Get off. That's it.
Please! Quiet!
Quiet! Maybe she hit him
before strangling him!
No! There were no marks
on the body! Just his neck!
- Yes.
- That's what I heard from Jack Flint.
The man who found the body?
He's the only one
to have seen the boy dead.
Even his own mother
weren't allowed to see him!
Is this true?
A mother has a right
to see her own son.
Is this how you repay
the charity of your lord?
The man who gave your son
a proper burial?
Clear the yard!
Come on! Clear the yard!
Let's go.
Clear the yard.
- Get word to the Lord de Guise.
- Show us a play about the other boys.
- What other boys?
- Get a move on!
- Out of this square.
- There were other boys?
Four in a year.
Disappeared without trace.
Come on, come on!
- Never seen anything like it.
- Neither have I.
You wanted meaning...
you got chaos.
- He got truth.
- Gossip.
Sunrise finds you
on the road or in my jail.
The axle's broke.
It won't be ready in time.
Your axle, boy, was ready this morning
at first light, as well you know.
It's only by the grace of Lord de Guise
that you lot still have your freedom.
Sunrise.
You lied to us.
A broken axle,
just to put on your play.
Master player?
You're not worthy
of your father's title.
&
Forgive me.
Grave robbery.
That's a capital offense.
Help him dig.
That's not a boy.
It's a man, my lord.
It's a friend of ours that we
buried here just to save expense.
And who performed the service?
I did.
Priest...
turned player.
Take him out.
Well, uncover him.
That's why you came here,
to examine him,
see what his parents
were prevented from seeing, yes?
Do as the king's justice says.
The king's justice?
Uncover him.
Remove his robe.
Nothing.
Except the bruising at the neck.
Bite marks.
Yes.
Oh, God.
- Oh, Christ!
- What? What is it?
A swelling, in the pit of his arm.
If he hadn't been killed,
the plague would have taken him.
It's all right, there's no danger.
He's three days dead.
There's no danger. Help me.
Help me.
You'd be wise to move on
with your friends.
Are they gonna hang her?
She's innocent.
No woman could have done this.
Are they gonna hang her?
And you, too, if you reveal
what you've done here tonight.
What does the king's justice
want with a dead peasant boy?
I'm sorry.
The sun isn't up.
They waited as long as the dead,
then they left by the north gate.
You might just make it.
Jesus!
- You mean you dug Brendan up?
- I had to, to get to the boy.
He'd been violated.
She didn't do it. She couldn't have.
We have to help.
- How?
- And why?
You said yourself the king's justice
has shown some interest.
Martin, you gave her hope.
You gave her hope!
- You can't walk away.
- Why are you doing this?
I got no choice!
I have nothing else to lose.
Except your life.
It's just a matter of time
before they find me and hang me.
What, for bedding another man's wife?
Martin?
Come back with me.
Oh, Christ, Martin. Come back.
Please.
How much were you paid?
- What?
- How much were you paid?
I don't know what
you're talking about!
How much?
I found the boy and I brought
him back, that's all.
He'd been missing for two days!
Found him in the clearing,
by the big oak!
I thought he was asleep, resting,
and then I saw the marks on his neck!
- What were you doing there?
- I was collecting firewood.
I'm a potter, you can ask anyone!
And then I loaded him onto the horse,
and that wasn't easy
- because he was stiff as a board!
- He was what?
He was stiff!
But he'd been dead two days.
Well, so what?
Rigor mortis?
Come on.
Whoa, boy. Whoa, boy.
Whoa.
I wish I were half the man
my father was...
and half the father you deserve.
I shall see you all in Durham!
I went to the jail to see your daughter.
I have no daughter.
You don't care
that she's to hang tonight?
It is God's will.
But she's innocent.
No one is innocent.
Then what's her sin?
For it wasn't murder.
Blasphemy.
She lays on hands and claims
that God himself speaks through them.
She's a healer?
God is the only healer.
Man's nature is corrupt.
It has been since the fall of Eden.
We can be redeemed,
but God is to be found nowhere
in ourselves
as she and her followers claim.
What followers?
Who are you that brings a message
from my daughter...
yet knows nothing of her repute
in these parts?
She's scared.
I warned her.
Warned her they would find a way
to bring her before the judges.
- They always do.
- Who?
The monk? The Benedictine?
A minister of hell, Simon Damian.
The lord he serves, the judge.
They are as one.
And as one,
they will face the flames...
with their hounds, their horses,
and their whores...
that they feed and clothe
from the blood we sweat.
You talk of divine justice.
What of human justice?
You're not from these parts, are you?
Else you would know,
those who seek justice...
fall prey to it.
&
Father?
There is a brother of yours
who wishes to speak with you.
Well, have him come in.
I know that the woman
didn't kill Thomas Wells.
She wasn't even there
the night he died.
What is that to me?
I've seen the body.
Wounds no woman could have inflicted.
No, the body is buried.
Was...
and is once more.
So this is your proof?
Evidence you dare not reveal.
I don't have to.
The king's justice was with me
when I dug him up.
It's only a matter of time
before you're taken.
Why tell me this?
Because I'm giving you your life.
Your freedom.
But in return, I want hers.
A written confession,
to be found after you're gone.
I will not confess to a crime
I didn't commit.
Brother Paul is leaving.
Have they caught him yet?
Is it not enough that
an innocent woman should die?
Must I die too?
There is more at stake here
than you will ever know.
How do you sleep?
You!
Daniel! Leave him!
Leave him! Leave him!
The monk's dead,
found hanging in his chamber.
Dead by his own hand.
Out! Out!
I'll have no gropers here! Out!
Gentlemen excepted, of course.
You went to see him. Why?
To ask for his confession,
and if you'd just...
- In return for his freedom?
- He wouldn't have got far.
His confession, if there was one,
will never be found.
This is his confession.
Why else take his own life?
He didn't. When a man is hanged,
the rope rides up
behind the jaw, the ears.
The weight of the body drags it up.
He was throttled.
Because of you, all is lost.
It's over.
Leave.
Before they hang you too.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no. No.
No, no.
Our horses, fetch. Saddle them.
How long have you known?
How long?
There was talk of other boys
in France
while Lord de Guise was
on campaign with King Richard.
We needed him then.
At what price?
The greater good of the nation
is a strict mistress to serve.
Oh, I'm sure she is.
And does she now demand
that de Guise is brought down?
Yes, if many more are not to die.
He's planning a rebellion
against the king.
They're gathered in the castle
as we speak.
So, to you, the children
were just a detail?
They were a reason to arrest him.
Our only hope
was to get the monk to turn
king's evidence against de Guise.
You see now what
your interfering has done?
You should have told me.
A player?
Affairs of state?
You soothe your conscience
with grand phrases.
But it's a weak, contemptible man
who trades in the lies of others.
De Guise is beyond my reach,
and certainly beyond yours.
Tell the people the truth.
They have a right to know the truth.
You think they don't know?
Thanks to him,
they have food enough and shelter.
In these times,
how many can say the same?
Theirs is the silence of consent.
I'm not sure I can do this.
We are come here
to execute the sentence
passed down by our lord's court
upon this woman,
found guilty of the murder
of Thomas Wells.
She is to be raised from the ground
by her neck,
and her body drawn until she be dead.
Let her death be a lesson to all
who would stray from the paths
of righteousness.
She is so brave.
&
God bless you!
Stop this!
Stop!
Arrest them!
We came here
in ignorance and poverty!
Poverty drove us to claim
your story as our own!
And ignorance blinded us
to its truthful telling.
For both, we beg your forgiveness
and in return we offer you...
the true story of Thomas Wells.
- Yeah, tell us!
- Get word to the castle!
Let us begin.
It was dark, someone was watching.
But it wasn't this woman
stood here before you.
It was the monk,
Brother Simon Damian.
Think of it.
Imagine it!
Thomas...
Thomas would have gone willing,
trusting that a man of God
could not possibly
have designs upon the money
he was carrying.
But a night, a day,
and another night passed...
and Thomas was dead,
with his life wrung from him.
He had already been missing
for two days...
when he was found at daybreak
by Jack Flint.
Flint had difficulty,
and this is important.
He had difficulty loading the body
onto his horse
because it was stiff with rigor mortis.
Now, he took that poor dead boy
back here to the town.
And bad news travels quickly.
Thomas Wells is dead.
- Thomas Wells is dead.
- You people...
- You became angry.
- Thomas Wells is dead.
- And the monk...
The monk was frightened.
So he lied.
He said that he had seen
this woman, Martha Lambert,
near the woods
the night Thomas disappeared.
And his word was enough...
because he was a man of God.
Now, he acted swiftly,
and he, the sheriff and his men
went to Martha's house to arrest her.
But Martha wasn't there, and she
hadn't been the previous day, either.
Where was she?
She was away.
She was away healing the poor.
Giving her time to people like you.
They broke down her door.
They searched
and they ransacked her house.
There, down!
And remember,
the monk still had the purse.
And when he was alone, in her room,
he hid it under her bed,
where it was then discovered.
Lies!
He took this evidence
that would hang a woman with him,
and he placed it there, a man of God!
Lies, I say!
She killed the boy!
- How?
- With her bare hands!
- She choked the life from him!
- Why?
- The money he was carrying.
- When?
The night he disappeared.
Then why was the body still stiff when
Jack Flint found him two days later?
The rigor mortis
would have gone by then.
Speak up, then!
You have an innocent woman
standing on your scaffold.
My Lord de Guise?
Now, you all know Martha!
You know her!
She doesn't have much,
but what she has, she gave freely!
Do not let her pay for it with her life!
You can stop this!
You can stop this
because you have the truth.
And the truth has power in it.
Thomas was not killed
that first night.
No, he was taken away
and he was held hostage
till the following day...
during which time he was subjected
to the most brutal, unspeakable acts.
Unspeakable acts.
But it was not the monk
that violated and killed Thomas.
Nor did he kill himself.
He was murdered by the very man
whose hunger he only served.
The man for whom
he procured the boys.
Lord Robert de Guise!
Lord de Guise!
De Guise!
He killed Thomas!
And he killed your other boys!
De Guise!
Stephen!
You dare to accuse Lord de Guise?
I dare to tell the truth!
Just the truth!
You ask yourself who had Thomas
buried so quickly
not even his mother
could see the body!
Get Nicholas! Out! Get out!
Go!
They're coming!
Martha, quickly!
Quickly!
- Point the way!
- Go, go!
Come on!
- Quickly!
- To the church!
Quickly!
Quick!
May I ask who you are?
May I see the face of the man
who wishes to know?
I'm Nicholas de Vilance.
Of Norman blood, like myself.
Well, houses become
somewhat diluted over the years.
And why have you come here,
Nicholas de Vilance?
No reason.
No, fate.
Do you believe in fate?
I believe in a fallen bridge
that drove us westward.
But that's not fate,
but poor workmanship.
We create our destiny.
Fate is the religion of the weak.
And you don't strike me as weak.
Foolish, maybe...
and headstrong, yes...
but not weak.
So it seems I'm accused by you
of unnatural acts and murder.
- Do you deny it?
- Not only deny it,
but defy you or any other man
to prove otherwise.
Well, you know I cannot.
And therein lies your foolishness
and your ruin.
No.
No, don't threaten me.
We're protected by
the holy sanctuary of God's house.
Your threats mean nothing here.
Do you really believe that your God
has the power to protect you?
No, nor the inclination.
Well, what kind of God is that?
The kind who allows
his innocent children to be murdered.
&
Well, since the beginning of time,
your God has had us
killing each other
under his various banners.
So I'll ask you again,
what kind of God is that?
I don't claim to understand.
But I do believe.
The triumph of blind faith
over reason, huh?
But what you fail to understand...
is that between faith and reason
lies the only true god:
Power.
You mean the power of evil?
To murder without conscience?
We are taught that God
bears no responsibility for evil.
That evil springs not from him,
but from the freedom of choice
he has granted to us.
Well, then, that freedom
is a thankless gift
if all the suffering in the world
is the price we must pay for it.
Sacrilege to the ears of a priest.
Sacrilege from the mouth of a priest.
No.
And what crime drove you into
the arms of traveling actors, Father?
Adultery.
How disappointing.
And murder.
And you dare lecture me?
You and your companions
are free to leave.
You have my word
you will not be harmed.
And if we refuse?
Are you prepared to die?
Are you?
Thomas Wells
was taken with the plague.
It is the one consolation in all this.
He was dead before
you so much as touched him.
What did Brother Damian tell you?
Not the truth.
He dared not tell you the truth.
That he brought you a boy
touched with the plague.
You want to know why
I did what I did?
Well...
because I wanted to.
And...
because I...
could.
&
Arrest them all.
Wait.
Hold me.
Godspeed, my friend.
His death was not in vain.
King Richard shall know
of the great service he rendered.
He didn't do it for you... or your king.
Stephen? Straw?
Load up the cart.
We have to be off... to Durham.
To perform our new play.
Let's go!