What are we waiting for?
Get him now!
Come on!
Come on, move!
That 'hurts!
- Pull it.
- Come on!
Go!
Stop! Stop!
- What has this man done?
- He pinched a horse.
He stole a horse.
- No offence, pastor.
- You can't do that! There's no charge.
Ain't necessary! We busted him.
You can't hang him for stealing horses.
See, desperado.
The preacher is defending you.
Who knew that a man of God
defend see someone like you.
Let the preacher pray for this bastard.
But we'll hang him first!
Go with God, my son.
You'll soon be face to face with him.
Pray for His forgiveness!
For your self!
- And for them.
- Get out of here, Preacher.
I don't want to pray.
He'll be fine in hell when I get through.
It can't be a bit worse than here.
Go on, get it over with.
Thou shalt not steal,
isn't that what the Bible says?
Preacher?
One minute, preacher.
- Give me the Bible.
- Thanks to the God!
- At the right time.
- On time!
It's no use all going through this.
It's just a waste of time!
All right, make it quick, preacher.
Gotta hang him anyhow, bastard start praying.
Hallelujah!
Praise the Lord showing you
the path of salvation.
The Almighty will hear
your prayers and be with you
in your hours of needs.
The string is going tighter,
so repent, my son.
Repent and God will save you!
Yes, repent!
That you may be forgiven for your sins.
In a moment you will be in peace.
And know the joys of everlasting life.
Proceed...
THE DIRTY OUTLAWS
Do you have a smoke Jonathan?
What have you done these past two years?
Where've you been?
- Here and there...
- Something interesting?
I just lived.
Where're you going now?
Away from here.
- Always alone, he?
- Sure, I always go alone!
That's only Confederates retreating.
Why not come with me to Calin?
Certain churches there are filled
with gold waiting for us to take.
No.
Here.
Think it over.
You won't live long if you go
risking a life for a horse.
I might die, but I do it alone.
Reverend, with all due respect, the
Major would be obliged if you come with us.
- Some of our boys are wounded badly.
- Sure...
- I don't have the Good book with me.
- A little comfort is what they need.
Good journey, preacher!
Give me... your horse.
Bury me.
Don't leave me to the buzzards.
Please, mister.
I have no time.
You will not have to wait long.
Take my gun.
If you ever get to a place called Overton,
give it to my father.
He is blind...
but he sees with his hands.
Sam Flannigan... is my father.
Overton is...
...about 75 miles north away.
It is a ghost town now.
Only my father lives there.
We were going... to buy
a ranch with that money.
You said Overton?
Father! Leave Overton!
Buy the rancho!
Use the money I sent you.
That's what's it for.
The ranch.
Buy the rancho.
I want you to...
do well... won't you for me...
There is not soul inside.
Sure, they sent us to a ghost town.
They sent us because nobody is in and
you're surprised by no one around here?
Well, let's have a look.
This place is the western gold rush towns
they wrote about in the papers back home.
Come on, you let me know how to read now?
Well, maybe somebody read me the stories.
Over there!
You hear that?
Two soldiers of the cavalry.
Why don't you call them?
Might want to talk with us!
But they didn't stop, they went on by.
And besides they were both so ugly,
neither of them could've been Bill.
Maybe I exaggerated.
You're tired of me hearing
talking about him, aren't you?
No, I think it's wonderful to hear
someone talk about the person he loves.
I always reckon...
if one our soldiers have news of Bill.
Tell me the truth, Katy.
Is it true that the South was defeated
and they want to stop the fighting?
Now tell me everything.
In Tolville Sam, when I delivered the two
revolvers, they said they were worthless.
And that now you'd better off
making safe and hedges.
Certainly
So they can get those guns at $10 a piece.
If we had Bill,
they'd respect us more.
You had to pick the most bad house to stay in?
It's no worse than the others.
But if the cholera epidemic was over,
why there ain't anybody here now?
Because the Yankees will get here soon,
and that scares more than cholera.
You start the fire.
I'll get the rifles.
It sucks.
This is no town, it's a swamp.
Sam!  Sam!
Sam Flannigan!
Sam!
It's me! Bill!
Hey, Bill?
Is that you, Bill?
Bill!
- Why don't you answer?
- Yes. It's me here.
My son.
Welcome back, son.
Come inside your house.
You're home again!
Everything is just as it was.
Please, Katy.
Tell me, why you're so different?
I want to hear about everything that
happened to you all these years.
I hardly know you.
Here. I still have this you gave me.
Yes.
You know Bill, three years is a long time.
Thanks.
I am Katy.
I often wrote to you about her, Bill.
I haven't received any letters
from home for a long time.
Katy is my right hand.
She does everything for me.
Takes my work and travels around making sales.
Her folks all died from the cholera.
- You're not wounded, are you Bill?
- No.
Tell me the truth, Katy.
The truth.
No, he's not injured.
You see I was right not to leave
Overton with the other folks.
I knew I should've waited for you.
If I had not as expected,
I'd rather die here in our house.
What is this what I'm eating?
You'd better off not looking at it.
How much gold'll there be on that wagon?
I do not know. Heard that it was
salary of two months of the division.
Figure it out. I can't.
Two rebel rats like us.
And all that gold.
- Is the war going bad for us, son?
- Yes.
It is not. It's going very bad.
As soon as it's over we buy the ranch.
- You remember that.
- Yes, the ranch.
You haven't spend it, have you?
What?
The money.
How could you even say such
a thing to your father, son?
It's all there!
I even added a bit to of myself.
Is it in a safe place?
The very place you chose.
That flour mill in Russels.
But one place is as good as another.
Who would look for that many on Overton nowadays?
But enough of that.
Tell me about yourself, son.
I wanna hear all that's happened.
Not just now. It brings bad memories.
And now... now I'm tired.
We'll be talking more about it, tomorrow.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, son.
- Goodnight.
Maybe I'm unfair to him.
I don't know.
- He has mighty changed.
- It's the war.
It is the war that makes it like that.
When it's all over, he'll be
just the way it was before.
Are you still awake?
When I'm really tired,
I can't sleep. And you?
- I saw the light...
- I wanted to make sure that father's money...
was still where I'd hidden it.
I know. I've been guarding the money.
Am I like you'd have imagined me?
Tell me the truth.
I understand.
I'm different.
But...
Better or worse?
I don't know.
Let's go.
Remember, no killing.
Right, they are more useful alive.
Tie them up.
So you're... the ones sent to
receive the gold here?
Are you the one?
Are there more soldiers in town?
All right.
The horses!
Confederates.
I guess we're not the only people in town.
I saw two soldiers going through today.
But I didn't expect them to stop.
Listen.
Get my father's money.
You gonna take it away?
It will be safer with me.
Come out of there!
Throw down your gun and come out.
You and the girl, out.
You stay out of sight.
Throw us your gun and come out of there!
The desperado...
Steve Belasco. The Terror of Texas.
It's all right, he's a friend.
Hey, you had so many amigos, Lucy
how you can remember them all?
I know him well.
Very well. He's a skunk.
We teamed up for a while.
I was teamed up with him.
So I know him very well.
So then, he's no a real soldier.
Steve, a soldier?
So you're the famous desperado.
You're not alone.
Who's in there with you?
The girl in there! Who is she?
What do you care?
Pick up his gun, Togo.
Search there.
Togo!
Nothing. The girl ain't there.
No one.
I judge by this masquerade that
you wait for the that military wagon, too.
Right, Steve?
What else?
We are all in the same boat.
A pity I have to split with you.
Take the soldiers inside.
There should be a blind man in town.
That's right. Over there.
You better leave the blind man alone.
And why?
If the soldiers arrive and know about him,
they'll wonder where he is.
Steve always has the last word.
You better all get used to it.
If you wanna go in there you
will have to kill me first.
She lives with the blind man.
She'll stay with us now.
So that's what you were doing in the mill.
You always want to mix business with pleasure.
What is wrong with you?
Why don't you speak to me?
Say something sweet to me, girl.
Come on, let me hear your little voice.
Even if you manage to get the gold,
they'll catch you afterwards.
You wanna hang?
You're all be hanged by that time.
Where did you find him?
What difference does it make?
I needed someone.
Why did you disappear that way, Steve?
And without a word!
You can't always choose the way
you have to do something.
I missed you.
James! Jake! One of you head to the north of
the town, the other head to the south. Go.
It won't be long now.
Stay wake.
And watch for that wagon.
Katy!
Get him out of the way.
And no tricks here.
- Katy?
- Yes, it's me.
I've been listening to them.
Who are they're there about?
Troublemakers? I wonder what they're about?
You think we should wake up Bill?
No, we better let Bill sleep.
Let's go home, Sam.
They're musicians who will
spend the night at the saloon.
Strange. It's been months since
we seen a stray animal here.
- And now, all of a sudden...
- Sam, try to get some rest.
I'm going back to the saloon and
make the visitors comfortable.
You bought me this comb, remember?
- No.
- You don't remember?
Did I age too much?
Tell me the truth. Say the truth.
No!
You'd not have to bother,
I would kill him with this.
Calm down, Togo. Just wait.
At Redrock there'll be plenty of ladies for you.
That wagon is heading this way, Asher.
Quick, untie them.
Give them a hand.
- There'll be a storm in here.
- That explains your temper.
The day is getting hotter.
But it is the best climate for a long time.
Last year, well this time and well
also that time of day,
took me a damn Yankee this arm with one shot.
You think they've a Christian burial
for my arm?
That must be the town there.
They won't last long if they try anything.
Good morning, sir.
We weren't expecting no officers, sir.
The area is full of deserters.
They don't want to lose this wagon.
I was sent to command this escort.
That's you business, sir, but
I'm afraid we can't stay.
We've got to head straight back
to camp at Black River.
We're also be needing your
horses for the ride back.
Those were the Colonel's orders, sir.
Right. Take the horses.
There were no incidents?
That road liked to bounce our brains loose.
I hope nothing else bounced out of place.
There was a change, the charging
is in bags and not in the coffin.
Good luck, sir.
Good luck!
Unload it.
That 's your job.
Get to work soldiers.
Well done, Steve.
There, you see how easy it was?
The soldiers were smart.
Who would go look inside?
- Asher, I'll get rid of the wagon.
- Right.
No tricks in the mean time.
Open the other!
Hurry up!
It's got to be here!
I can't understand!
Where is that pay roll?
That gold has got to be here!
Maybe these two know something.
Where is that gold?
Well, where is that gold?
In the green sack for the horses.
Damn it!
Where's your friend?
Where did he go?
I said: where is he!
Let's go!
Don't shoot yet.
Look at the bags.
The gold is here, dollars!
You thought of everything.
You're real clever...
But you didn't figure...
how well I know this part of the country.
A lot better than you.
Please let me go back to the old man.
- Is he your father?
- No, but he needs me.
And Steve?
I saw how you looked at him.
Forget him. It's all over for him now.
You can join the old coyote
just a soon as we leave.
Your friend isn't a man of his word.
He's ready to take your share as well.
Get off.
I'll teach you...
Now try to get up, desperado.
What we do with these two reds?
Untie them.
Let them go.
Make tracks!
Bunch of dirty dogs...
- Bill, anything wrong? Where are you?
- Return at home.
Sam...
Go back...
What they've done to you, Bill?
Where are you, Bill?
Answer me! What's going on?
What did you do to my son?
I'll kill you if you touch him!
What son?
No! No!
- Where are you?
- Come on! Shoot!
I'm here, Grandpa! Shoot!
- Where are you?
- Come on!
- Shoot, old man, shoot!
- Murderers!
- Come on, old man. Shoot!
- No, let me go!
Cowards!
- Shoot!
- No, Sam! No!
Katy?
- Katy, get away!
- Here we are!
I hear you.
Let me go!
Where are you?
Sam!
Bill.
- Bill.
- Sam!
Sam...
They will pay for this.
Sam!
I want to kill him.
I can't forget what he's done to me.
To the horses.
You can join your friend. She must love you
very much if she has the courage for that scene.
She did a very good job.
I thought she'd killed you too.
Leave that gun. It belonged to Sam!
I bring it back.
Afterwards.
He tried to defend you
and they killed him!
The ones who killed him
are going to pay for it.
You'll never find them again!
Or is it only for the money?
Is that why you're after them?
If you go north they'll capture
you in that uniform.
But I've grown fond of it.
Steve... they'll kill you.
This time it's my turn to kill, Katy.
Whiskey.
Friends! A Confederate soldier.
You'd applaud this hero officer.
I'm proud you got away.
What you have against the cavalry?
Nothing. They're fast when
it comes to retreating!
They flee to the Yankees directly to our homes.
Don't worry. A swine like you'd be
doing business with them in no time.
War is an ugly affair.
Soldiers die young.
But cowards keep right on going!
Glad to find you girl.
We'll have much time together tonight.
Hey you! Wake up! Come on, wake up!
What's the matter with you?
Looks like he's dead.
He's dead as a door-nail. Let's get him
out of here, gives the place a bad name.
Now believe me friends, in times like these
you shouldn't invest your money in banks.
Should invest your money. Invest!
It's just $0.02 a share.
- How about you? Just two cents.
- Excuse me.
- What's that, ma'am?
- Can you explain how much in a year?
It's all down here in black and white.
The Western Union railroad
doubles your money.
- I reckon I'll take $10.
- Now that's 500 shares.
Congratulations, ma'am!
You are now part of the railroad.
Dollars Union, not Confederate money.
That would take $10,000 Confederates.
Who else wants to ride the rails
progress with Western Union?
- Thousand dollars.
- Money-Union?
- Confederates.
- 50 Quotas.
- I also want quotas.
- Here, ma'am.
Talk loud, folks. Do not miss the chance to
participate in the Western Union railroad.
Only $2 for 100 shares for the railroad.
Remember, the future of this country
lies in the railroads.
- So, I'll be back in a few days.
- I'll send you those warrants as soon as they'll get here.
Excuse me, sir.
Hello, I'll be right with you.
- Anything else I can do for you, Judge?
- No, Sheriff. Thanks.
- Have a good day.
- Thanks, bye.
Let's talk inside.
Wait for me downstairs.
I just heard Jim was killed
in a fight at the saloon.
No one knows who did it.
Don't tell me that you
are all torn up by their deaths.
No, I just hope nobody has
found out about that gold.
I don't like this place at all.
I've already told you that.
Why did you wanna stop here?
We got to get out of here quick.
- The dead of Jim... I don't like it.
- That's too bad.
Don't think you make me get back on that
horse and ride hundreds just to please you.
No. This time we go by stage.
No, thanks! I'm staying here.
- You can't make me go with you.
- Don't say that, Lucy! Don't talk that way!
I've told I don't want to go, I...
You will come! Wether you want to or not!
Well, judge?
There's s a little confusion in
justice today, my friend.
But I think the military must
even more confused, right?
- It would take too long to explain.
- I understand... Sit down.
You smell the perfume around here too?
This place smells like gold.
A few minutes ago
a man left here.
Oh yes!
He wanted seats on my stage.
For him, and his lady,
and two friends of him.
What did you tell him?
I said all right.
I don't think he's traveling
with empty pockets.
- Want to do the job together?
- No.
No, the gold doesn't interest me anymore...
Listen.
- It's so hot here!
- The lady is not comfortable?
Why don't you come and sit over here?
In a little while, I wanna make
a business stop.
We'd rather not stop, judge.
I'm sorry, but it is important.
Because I must wait...
for an official who brings the warrants
for the arrest of the Asher gang.
My friends here might be of help to you.
They ride on later, if horses
can be found for them.
Where we're stopping there'll be a farmer.
- You haven't seen the judge at all?
- No.
Two of these gentlemen
will wait for him here.
I need to get going. They can fetch
the documents if it's there.
Everything's settled?
Sure. When do we get our share?
When you finish your job here.
Then we will divide everything up.
- Well, I just want my horse back.
- Naturally
In three days I'll meet you at Fort Worth.
- Thank you for collaborating with the law.
- So long, sir.
This kind gentleman will deliver the horses.
I'm sorry ma'am, but
there aren't any refreshments here.
Never mind, it's not important.
I wanna thank you too,
for your cooperation.
So long.
No!
No! No!... No!
Desperado... but you were dead!
Pray.
Forgive me, Lord.
Lord, forgive me my many sins.
I am a miserable sinner.
I stole and killed, but never I
killed... unarmed men, unarmed men!
Forgive me!
Forgive me, Lord!
Why? We're turning around.
Maybe the driver took the wrong turn.
You haven't done anything but looking
out of that window since we left.
Hold it!
If you are a judge,
I'm the president of the Confederation.
Out to rob me, he?
First you got rid of my men.
You're only waiting for the right moment.
That's it, isn't it?
- Why did they stop?
- I think we arrived.
You are wrong!
We're not across the Texas border.
Asher!
Hey, come back!
Come back here, bastard!
Asher!
That gun won't help you.
That was your last bullet, Asher.
I wouldn't want it so easy for you.
You still have time to die like a man.
Because you're looking death in the face.
Are you ready?
You really shouldn't have done that.
Call yourself a man?
You still have bullets, Asher.
Try again. Go on.
See better with mud in your eyes?
The gun is right there. Shoot!
Now, shoot it!
I am here.
Here!
The old man couldn't see either.
Remember?
Good day, sir.
He was making off with our gold.
We chased him for ten days.
I'm afraid you made a mistake.
This man is a judge, Captain.
He was helping me, he was guarding the gold.
There's the thief you're looking for.
- He's a murderer as well.
- You mean...
So he was telling the truth.
He is really a judge!
Untie him. Hurry!
Your Honor, please hold out your hands.
It seems that my destiny is
to be judge. Goodbye, Steve.
Aren't we going together, Steve?
No, Lucy.
I hate you, Steve.
That's not true.
You're right.
Steve... good luck.
- Captain would you escort them to Delmar?
- Yes, it will be a pleasure.
Good luck, sir.
Good luck to you.
Come on! Forward!
Take the money that belonged to Sam.
Buy a ranch of your own.
I wish you think it over.
There, beyond the mountain.
It is good land.
It's what old Sam would have wanted.
Why don't you stay?
I can't now.
I still have to come to terms with myself.
Will we see each other again?
Sure, we will.
I will wait for you, Steve!