(Dramatic music)
**
(Orchestral music)
(Ship's horn blowing)
(Seagulls squawking)
Uh, excuse me, sir.
What?
Oh, I... I beg
your pardon.
What have I here, dear?
Uh, "what have I
here, dear?"
(Ship's horn blowing)
Come on, big brain,
let's hear from you.
Excuse me, sailor.
"What have I here,
dear" means...
A cigarette case.
Wrong again, professor.
I suppose you know
We're starting this act
tomorrow night.
I hope, sweet angel, it
means a cigarette case.
It means a fountain pen,
nitwit.
Darling, you're a liar.
Thank you, professor.
Well, you gave me
the wrong cue.
That's right...
Put me in the wrong.
I never argue
with a lady.
I'm not a lady...
I'm your wife.
Yep.
"What have I here,
dear" means, uh...
Oh, a fountain pen.
Oh, yes.
Well, let's try again,
professor.
What am I holding?
Uh...
Uh-uh, that's cheating.
Well, if you don't
trust me,
I should get a divorce.
"Judge, my wife
didn't trust me."
One of these days, I
shall have you destroyed.
Oh, that'd be nice.
So now what?
So now,
what am I holding?
Uh, uh... darling,
Do you by any chance
happen to remember,
The exact day when
we were married?
Don't change the subject.
Well, you see, uh,
what I wanted to say was,
Since next April
is going to be
One of our anniversaries,
that I might go out
And buy you a nice
big Christmas tree.
What am I holding?
You're holding a box
of chocolates.
Wrong.
Right.
Right, Miss Know-It-All.
Wrong.
Prove it with the book.
Go on, prove it.
Oh, well...
What were you saying
about our anniversary?
What am I holding?
What am I holding,
you darling, you?
You darling.
I say, where's Mother?
Mother!
Dear, don't we
have a porter?
What for?
Remember, a fool and his
money are soon parted.
Yes, and you remember...
(Muffled)
Oh!
There they are!
(Overlapping chatter)
Could I help?
Put it on there.
Well, Simon, I see
you've got everything.
I have everything in
the world, I should think.
Let's go.
Come on,
you're wasting time.
Come on.
(Overlapping chatter)
Now, madam, have you anything
to declare?
I have not.
No.
Cigarettes?
Cigars?
No.
Cameras?
Perfumes?
No, no, no.
Open this bag, please.
Have you anything
to declare, sir?
Uh, oh, no,
thank you, no.
Here's a pretty thing.
What is it?
Pretty thing.
That's, um,
a powder compact.
Right, darling.
Will you open this
suitcase, please, sir?
No cigars, cigarettes,
cameras, or perfumes?
No perfumes.
Now, what have we
got here?
"What have we
got here?"
That's, uh...
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
A bottle of whiskey.
Eh? Where?
Oh, I beg your pardon,
I didn't mean that.
There isn't one.
You said there was.
Yes, well, you see,
You said to me,
"What have we got here?"
And the answer to that
is "a bottle of whiskey."
You see?
Yes.
(Laughs)
No, I'm afraid I don't.
Well, where is it?
Yes, but you don't understand.
I mean, it's a...
It's a gag.
Yeah, seems like it.
Open this case,
will you, please?
Yes, but listen to me.
I'm the great Maximus.
Yes, very likely you are.
Last week, we had a man here
who said he was Napoleon,
But that doesn't alter the fact
that whiskey is dutiable.
Yes, but you
don't understand.
We're a music hall turn.
We're just starting
on a tour.
I'm a mind reader.
Yes, that's what I
have to be too,
And I'm going to
find that whiskey
If I have to search
all night for it.
Put that in your mind
and read it.
There you are, Max.
I told you this new act
would cause trouble.
You should be
like your father.
Stick to the old routines.
The proof of the
pudding's in the eating.
(Whistle blowing)
Here, look here,
my man.
We shall miss our train!
Yes!
Ah, are you with
this gentleman?
Well, I...
Yes, he is.
Right, well, come on,
open up this case.
Anything to declare?
No.
No perfumes?
No cameras?
No.
No cigarettes?
No cigars?
No.
Oh, nothing to declare, eh?
Cigars!
No cigars?
Well, what about this?
Here, here, don't open that!
What do you think I am?
It's a trick!
Yeah.
Like his disappearing
whiskey, I suppose.
Aw, please, it took me
two hours to pack that.
Oh, did it? Well...
Aah!
(Laughter)
Ladies and gentlemen,
It is
with great pleasure
That I present to you
the greatest mindreading
And thought stunt
special act
That has ever appeared
before the public!
Dear, dear, dear, dear!
Oh,
now don't you worry, mother.
Everything's gonna
be all right.
Max, stick to the old tricks,
just as your dad did.
Remember, fools rush in
where angels fear to tread.
Yes, but nothing ventured,
nothing half-topsy.
Now, will you please
put that table
On the other side
of the stage?
I've asked you to
twice.
Put it on the blue
mark, will you?
Professor.
Yes?
Can you tell me
what it is?
It is a lipstick,
darling.
How do I look?
You look lovely, my sweet.
Do you think you can
remember everything?
Well, that's good,
coming from you, anyway.
Max, I have to warn you,
if anything should happen...
Will you please
go away?
Mr. Maximus, please.
Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh!
(Emcee)
I have the pleasure of
introducing to you
The great Maximus!
(Applause)
I will introduce to you
Mademoiselle Rene,
Who will come down
amongst you.
(Applause)
I ask you to test
The miraculous powers
of this marvelous pair
And to see for yourselves
the most perfect example
Of telepathetic
communication
The world
has ever known!
(Applause)
Ladies and gentlemen,
all the best tricks,
Like all the best things
in life, are simple,
Though sometimes hard
to explain.
I do not profess
to be a superman.
The powers I possess
Are possessed, more or less,
by you all.
Mademoiselle Rene
is among you.
She will ask you to pass her
any small personal article.
The waves of thought
emanating from her
Will come across
the footlights to me.
To put it simply,
It will be as if
Mademoiselle Rene
Were my own
electric battery,
Motivating the force
Which gives me the power to
retransmit to you
My knowledge of
what is in her mind,
And, by the hidden mysteries
of the powers of thought,
I will describe the object
she is holding.
(Applause)
(Rene)
Any articles,
ladies and gentlemen.
Any personal articles.
You, sir?
What about you?
No? Really?
You, miss. Perhaps
you have something.
Ah, yes, the young
lady has something.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Are you ready?
Absolutely, mademoiselle.
I have a very
charming thing here.
Can you tell me
what it is?
It is...
A lipstick.
Got the first one
right, anyway.
Oh, that's beautiful.
May I?
Thank you very much.
I should like you
to tell me
What I have now.
What you have now...
Is a tiepin.
(Applause)
He's getting them
all right.
Yes, but there's many a slip
twixt the cup and the lip.
Miss, ask him to tell you
what this is.
Any personal articles,
ladies and gentlemen?
Anything you please.
Impressed there's one
that's a bit unusual.
Oh, I'm sure you'd
like the great Maximus
To tell you what this is.
Yes.
What have I
this time?
(Max)
That, mademoiselle,
is a watch.
A wristwatch.
There you are.
"Time." Watch.
See?
And now,
Mademoiselle Rene
Will repeat
her performance
For the benefit of the
ladies and gentlemen
In the dressed circle.
Here, that's
all very well,
But what about this?
(People shouting)
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
(Applause)
(Door rattling)
(Overlapping chatter)
I suppose she knows
her way.
How do I get up
to the circle?
Around the front.
Ticket office,
facing...
But I don't want
a ticket.
I'm part of the show.
You mean you're
one of the artists?
Yes, can't you see
my makeup?
Artists aren't allowed in
front without permission.
I've got permission,
and the stage is waiting.
Well, you'll have to
ask the manager
At the ticket office.
Why can't I go
through this way?
'Cause it doesn't lead
to the circle.
Well, will you
please tell me
How I can get up
to the circle?
Is Mademoiselle Rene
up there yet?
No, she's not here!
She's left us!
(Overlapping chatter)
Where's the old girl
gone to?
(Laughter)
Hey, what have I
got here?
It's a pipe!
A pipe!
(Overlapping chatter)
(Man shouting)
(Laughter)
(Whistling)
(Applause)
(Rhythmic clapping)
(Laughter)
(Whistling)
(Rhythmic clapping)
What's wrong?
(Whistling)
(Rhythmic clapping)
(Applause)
Go on!
Go ahead, go ahead!
(Rhythmic clapping)
(Whistling)
Just that, just that.
He calls himself
a mind-reader.
(Laughter)
What have I got here?
It's a letter.
What's it about?
From your wife.
Well, that's where
you're wrong.
(Laughter)
About your wife.
What did he say?
He said it was
about your wife.
Well, he's right.
It's from a hospital.
That letter
is two days old.
You'd better go
to your wife.
Don't tell me
she's worse.
Excuse me, will you?
This isn't the act
they rehearsed.
I know what it is.
And you...
I see...
A railway journey.
(Dramatic music)
I see...
**
(Audience murmuring)
Ring down!
Max, are you all right?
(Overlapping chatter)
(Audience murmuring)
Max!
My God!
What's the matter?
(Audience murmuring)
(Groaning)
Rene?
Re... Rene.
Oh, Max, what
happened to you?
I don't know.
I know.
My father had it...
The gift to see.
(Train whistle blowing)
Take your seats, please,
for the first dinner service.
(Bell ringing)
First dinner service.
Please take your seats.
(Bell ringing)
Well, it may have been
real clairvoyance,
But how can you be sure?
Anyway,
I think it's dangerous.
Don't worry, my sweet.
It only happened once.
It hasn't
happened since.
It may never
happen again.
I hope it does.
We'll make
our fortunes.
These things come and go.
No one knows why.
Perhaps there was someone
in the theater, Max,
In sympathy with you.
Sort of, um,
sort of...
You know, like you
say in the act...
Sort of a battery to
your wireless receiver.
That's it.
Now I'll be
a clairvoyant.
This being
an English railway,
The menu will be
tomato soup,
Roast beef, apple tarts,
seasoned biscuits, coffee...
Ha ha.
(Laughs)
Now, Mr. Prophet,
You show your skill.
What about Blue Boy
for the 2:30 tomorrow?
I'm supposed to be
a clairvoyant,
Not a tipster.
Oh, not much good
foreseeing the future
If you can't double
the dough.
Never count your chickens
before they're hatched.
Talking of chickens,
what about this one?
(Train whistle blowing)
I've seen that girl
before.
That girl?
Yes, right over...
That girl.
A journey.
(Brakes screeching)
(Overlapping chatter)
Did you pull that
communication cord?
This train will not
get to a station.
There will be an accident.
Accident?
What do you mean?
Excuse me, sir.
Darling, don't worry.
This is a very serious
kind of a joke, isn't it?
Oh!
If it's advertisement
you're after,
You'll get all you want
in the police court.
There's a penalty of £5
for this sort of thing.
I advise everybody
to get off this train.
What for?
I've told you once.
Excuse me, guard.
Uh, ladies and gentlemen,
do take your seats, please.
Take your seats.
Mother, Simon.
(Overlapping chatter)
Now, come along,
everybody.
Get aboard again, please.
You don't realize we've
stopped in a tunnel.
I tell you to warn
the rest of the passengers
To get off the train.
Are you coming aboard?
No, I'm not.
Very well, you'll stay here
on your own responsibility.
Aye, you with the lamp.
Gather these people out
of the tunnel, will you?
Why'd you let them
off the train?
Now, don't argue!
Look after these people!
Now, stand clear, please!
(Whistle blowing)
(Engine starting)
Stand clear there,
please!
Here, let's get
out of this.
Come on, then, before
the next train comes through.
Hey, what are you
doing on the track?
I just got off
the train.
You mean
the Manchester train?
Yes, he stopped it.
(Ringing)
Hello, hello?
What?
Where?
How'd it happen?
There's been a smash.
Oh!
Max!
I've closed the section.
Excuse me, can I use
the phone?
No, no.
I want to speak
to my father.
Oh, use that one then.
Can you see the smash?
Hello?
Is it bad?
40?
Can you give me
a London number?
How many of them?
Peak 9000.
Yes, The Daily Sun.
Here, none of your
newspaper stuff!
Here I thought you wanted
to speak to your father.
I do... he's the owner
of the paper.
Hello, Christine, dear.
How are you?
Uh... good heavens.
Wait a moment.
Hello, assignments,
hold your front page.
You'll probably have to
set it up again.
(Knocks)
Excuse me, please.
I've never seen so many
cars in all my life.
(Knocks on door)
Never mind the cars.
They'll have my front door
in with their knocking.
I think it's an outrage.
I should think so.
What's an outrage,
Simon?
These newspapermen
have spelled my name wrong.
You should
be very pleased
To have your name
on the front page
At your time of life.
What do you mean,
my time of life?
If you please.
Now, old man,
what are you doing here?
Must you do that?
I'm sorry, Mr. Bimeter.
Thank you,
I certainly am.
(Knocks)
And thick and fast
they came at last,
And more and more and more.
(Knocks on door)
Hello, Maxie.
I'll have to
let them in.
Mr. Maximus is not
going to see anyone
Until after breakfast.
(Knocks on door)
It isn't his
front door.
And please see you don't
burn his omelet.
I won't burn
his omelet.
Mr. Rupert Boddy,
Variety.
Mr. Sam Leopold.
He's a London manager.
Mr. Joseph Leman.
Mr. Claude Simmons.
You know, Max will offend
some of these people
If he doesn't see them.
Ah!
Here's a man
who really matters.
James J. Bimeter.
Bimeter?
Mm.
J.R. Copeland's
representative.
You can't keep him
waiting.
(Knocks on door)
At last.
They'll break
my door down!
All the big bucks
in the variety business
Are waiting for you.
Let them wait.
But J.J. Bimeter's
amongst them.
I once waited five hours
for Mr. Bimeter,
And then he slipped out
the back door.
And now he's waiting
at your front door.
I'm in no mood
for business today!
Mrs. Jones, show
Mr. Bimeter in.
And what have I here?
Hey!
A baggage.
Don't drop me,
I'm not insured.
I want to talk
business, madam.
Your bath is ready.
Oh, let it wait.
We'll not only go,
and quickly too.
Farewell,
and scrub thyself.
I want to meet
Mr. Bimeter.
(Overlapping chatter)
Oh...
Good morning.
May I present my wife?
How do you do?
I was just on my way
to the bath.
Excuse me.
Good morning.
You've probably
heard of me.
I'm James J. Bimeter.
The Mr. Bimeter?
Quite.
Won't you come in?
My partner.
How are you, sir?
My lady mother,
the duchess.
How do you do?
Won't you sit down?
Thank you, thank you.
I, uh... I happened
to be in Manchester,
And I received a call
from Mr. Coben.
Which Mr. Coben?
The Mr. Coben.
Well, to come
straight to business,
Mr. Coben was impressed
by your, uh,
Shall we say, uh,
performance
In prophesying the Manchester
train accident,
And he's going to
give you £100 a week
For four weeks at
the London Palindrome.
How much?
£100?
He didn't
say 100.
He did, but it
isn't enough.
What?
What are you
saying, Max?
Max!
You may thank Mr. Coben
for the offer,
But I'm not
in the market.
You mean to say you
ought to get more?
I mean that the effort
of true clairvoyance
Is infinitely fatiguing.
Max, you're getting
£30 a week at present.
I want 300.
Good morning.
Ah, Mr. Sam Leopold.
Leopold can't pay more
than Mr. Coben.
We'll see.
Simon,
show Mr. Leopold in.
Just a moment.
I'll make it 150.
Uh, good morning.
200.
"Will you walk
into my parlor?"
Said the spider
to the fly.
You're not worth
a penny more.
Mr. Dick Crow.
Simon, show
Mr. Crow in too.
I'll make it 250.
300.
You're looney.
It's money for jam.
250?
300.
It can't be done.
You're sure?
Certain!
We'll see.
Where are you going?
To get a second opinion.
My opinion is
the only one you want.
Let me tell...
You tell him, not me.
Anything the matter
with him?
Ah, gentlemen!
I am offered £250 a week.
Any advance on 250?
Going, going...
Swollen head.
That's what's
the matter with him.
£300.
Who does he thing
he is?
I've been in this
business for 25...
What?
You still here?
Well, did you
see them?
All of them.
What did they
offer... 250?
300?
Don't you
want your hat?
300.
I don't believe it.
Will you pay it?
No, I won't!
Good morning!
Now who's the 300
merchant?
There wasn't one.
I was bluffing.
I thought he'd fall
for it.
Well, that's torn it.
Well, of all the...
Shh!
Well, I think we may
be able to fix it.
300?
300.
And expenses.
Good morning.
Aye, aye, what
about a contract?
My word is my bond.
Well, what about
a bit on account?
Oh, all right.
There you are...
There's a £10 note.
(Overlapping chatter)
Has Mr. Bimeter gone?
My darling,
we're a success.
We go to the London
Palindrome at 300 a week,
And you can go and buy any
personal article
With rings on your fingers
and bells on your toes.
(Laughs)
(Man)
Mr. Max is a flop.
You're bound
to admit it.
Why, he's keeping people
out of the theater.
All this week,
He hasn't told the
audience a single thing.
What Mr. Coben wants
is prophecy.
(Man)
Mr. Max is doing his best.
Well, Mr. Coben says
his best is bad.
What Mr. Coben wants
is prophecy.
Mr. Max can't turn 'em out
like sausages.
Well, Mr. Coben says
he's got to.
He's a clairvoyant,
not a pork butcher.
Well, anyhow, Mr. Coben
wants results.
Prophecies by Saturday,
or you're through.
Is that what
Mr. Coben said?
His very words.
What Mr. Coben
wants is...
Prophecies.
I'll prophesy a murder
in a minute.
Good morning.
(Door slams)
Darling, I don't think we
shall be at the Palindrome
After this week.
Well...
Now, don't say
"I told you so."
I know when to
keep quiet.
Well, I supposed we've
got till Saturday.
Something
may come to me.
If only my mind weren't
this awful blank.
You know, the more
I try to see things,
The emptier it gets.
Then, all those people
out front every night,
Wanting me to tell them
who's gonna win the boat race
Or how many kittens
the cat's going to have.
I know how you feel.
I think you ought to
give it up.
Yes, I do.
I've been watching you.
This constant effort,
it's making you ill.
Oh, I'm all right.
Sweet, can't we go back
to the old act?
For £10 a week and
lodgings for the night?
We were happy then.
Aren't you happy now?
I've been happier.
Well, don't you like
this sort of life?
I like it if you do.
Aye, sweet,
what's the matter?
Well, I... I haven't seen very
much of you lately, have I?
Well, isn't that
a pleasant change?
I suppose it ought to be,
But you've become
a habit.
Bad habit, darling.
Well, good women always
marry the wrong men.
(Laughter)
You'd pass in a crowd.
Do you know, Max,
You don't even need me
in the act anymore.
Rene!
What's worrying you?
(Phone ringing)
Hello?
Miss Shaw to see me?
All right, show her up.
Christine Shaw?
Mm, nice girl, that.
Lovely head.
(Knocks on door)
Oh, thank you.
Come in!
Good morning,
darling.
Hello, Topsy.
Good morning.
Morning, Simon.
Morning.
Hello, Simple,
how do you feel?
Like yesterday's beard.
You help him
with a go?
I think the entire
hotel did.
He says what Mr. Coben
wants is prophecies.
Well, that's not
unreasonable.
Max, my dear, I'm very
worried about you.
This clairvoyant business
Nearly killed
your granddad.
I know, Topsy.
I adore you, but you are
an old pessimist.
After all,
Coben's only human.
One or two prophecies a week
would keep him quiet.
Simon, I cannot switch
it on to order.
I know,
but don't you think
You could help
yourself out a bit?
Well, what will you have?
Performing elephants?
A bearded lady?
No, you know
what I mean.
Use your imagination.
You mean, think.
(Knocks on door)
Come in.
Miss Shaw
is here, sir.
All right,
I'm coming.
Where's my coat?
Here it is.
Thank you, sweet.
Miss Shaw?
Yes, Christine Shaw.
She's an early bird.
Street's
not aired yet.
Wait a minute, Max.
Here you are.
I like you to look your
best for your public.
(Max)
Hello, how nice
to see you.
(Door closes)
What's the matter?
Do I look different
or something?
No, you're
just the same.
Well, how are you,
anyway?
Terrible.
Too early
to be anything else.
Well, you look
a little worried.
What's the matter?
You don't miss much,
do you?
Sit down
and I'll tell you.
(Simon)
I wonder what she
wants to see him for?
(Mother)
I don't know.
Something about the
newspaper, I suppose.
Perhaps you're right.
Might be another boost.
You know Coben?
The villain
of the piece.
He and father dined
together last night.
Oh, he was horrible
about you.
Did he use the word
"charlatan"?
Do you think I'm that?
Do you think
I'd be here if I did?
Well, he may have
been right.
Do us a bit of good,
that would.
I do hope
it's nothing serious.
So do I.
I've had enough shots
for one day.
What we need
is some advertising.
But your gift's
the real one.
So real
I'm no good to Coben.
Good morning,
Miss Shaw.
Good morning.
Oh, Max, darling, you
forgot your handkerchief.
Thank you.
How are you?
Very well, thank you.
Just in by hand,
sir.
Marked very urgent.
Thank you.
What is it, Max?
It's from Coben.
I know what that is.
What Bimeter said?
Yes.
From Saturday?
From now.
Oh, dear.
There you are.
Is there any answer, sir?
What? Uh, no.
I wish you'd tell me the
winner of the derby, sir.
Ortalicus.
What did you tell
that page?
Page?
What do you mean?
He asked you for
the derby winner.
You told him something.
Aye! Page! Page!
Here, boy, boy,
come here, here.
Look, what did
Mr. Maximus say?
What horse?
He said Ortalicus, sir.
But there ain't
no such animal.
There is!
I remember the name!
Here, where's the paper?
Here it is... Jenny Lynn,
3 to 1, Denny, 5 to 1,
Playful Charles, 6 to...
It's not here.
It is, it is, look!
Ortalicus.
100 to 1, Ortalicus.
That's right,
that's right.
Ortalicus will win
the derby.
Ortalicus?
Ortalicus couldn't
win the derby
If he had ten legs and
they fed him on dynamite.
Ortalicus... he's not
a horse, he's a joke!
Joke or not, he'll win.
If you'll pardon me,
this is my job.
I've had 20 years
experience on the turf.
It's not a matter of
experience, Mr. Brooks.
I know and you know
it's all superstition.
All we've got to decide
is whether we can afford
To let the paper
carry the story or not.
But sir, we'd be
a laughingstock.
Not when Ortalicus wins.
Daddy, Maximus was right
about the train.
Ortalicus can't win!
They're only
running him
In the hope
he'll fall dead
To save the expense
of shooting him.
Can't we run it
in question form?
"Can seer foretell
derby winner?"
Then, whatever happens,
we're all right.
I'm opposed to it!
It's news,
and it's safe, sir.
We'd be backing
a loser.
I'll take a chance.
You win, my dear.
All right,
get the paper out.
Hello, everybody.
It's a brilliant scene
down here at Epsom.
The Downs are crowded,
as usual,
And the interest
in this year's derby
Is greater than ever because
of the sensational prophecy
Made by the great Maximus.
Uh, I think this must be
a record attendance.
Certainly,
the volume of traffic
Is greater
than ever before.
No doubt this is partly
due to the fact
That Mr. Maximus himself
Is expected to be
present at the race.
By the way, I had great
difficulty
In getting here myself,
the traffic was so bad,
So I hope he left his London
hotel in plenty of time.
This way, please.
Excuse me, Mr. Maximus.
May I introduce you
to Mr. Hearn?
How do you do,
Mr. Hearn?
This car, Mr. Maximus.
This car?
And then
we could discuss
Your broadcast on
the way to the course.
This way, madam,
please.
Do you mind going down
without me?
No.
Mr. Maximus,
if you please!
All right,
get in, Simon.
Oh, thanks very much.
Aren't you excited?
How do I look?
You look like the Queen
of Sheba, darling.
(Laughter)
(Car door shuts)
Who is that woman?
Christine Shaw.
Oh.
(Overlapping chatter)
People are still pouring
into the stands,
And there's a steady stream
of cars making its way...
(Whispers)
Oh, I've just heard
That Mr. Maximus
has managed to get here.
I must say,
I think he's lucky,
Because with this traffic
congestion on the road,
I'm afraid there are bound
to be thousands of people
Who'll never
get to the course
In time for
this year's derby.
(Overlapping chatter)
Come on,
get a move on.
We didn't come to see
a motor show.
Turn it on a bit louder,
will you?
Yes, sir.
(Commentator)
Everything seems
pretty well set
For another great derby.
Perhaps we shall be in
time for next year's race.
(Overlapping chatter)
The race has started.
A really perfect collection
of three-year-olds.
Here comes Jenny Lynn,
yesterday's favorite.
She looks
in fine condition.
And Hesperus.
There's Tiger Man.
I like the look of him.
Hello, and here comes
Ortalicus,
The horse tipped to win by
Maximus the clairvoyant.
It seems incredible
the one man
Should have such influence.
In a moment,
I'll speak to him.
Jenny Lynn's the obvious
pick for today.
I'm informed that
nothing can touch her,
Though Tiger Man has suddenly
shown real promise recently.
Yes, yes, I learned
my little piece
On the way down.
I say, I can't
figure out
What's happened
to my wife.
The last time I saw this
horse run was at Newbury.
He finished strongly
on the mile and a quarter.
As for Ortalicus,
Despite Mr. Maximus'
assurances,
I'm afraid I can't see him
finishing the course.
Still, as they say,
The derby's always
a gamble.
(Overlapping chatter)
They're going over
to the start now.
I think
we've just got time.
Here's Mr. Maximus.
Max is going to speak.
Good old Max.
Bless his heart.
Uh, hello, everybody.
Uh, I... I can't
say much
Because they're almost
ready to start.
Uh, as regards Ortalicus,
well, it just came to me,
And, uh, well,
that's that.
Events may prove
I'm wrong,
But I think I'm right,
and, uh, well, that's all.
Uh, good-bye.
Thank you, Mr. Maximus.
Now, they're lining up
at the starting gate.
They're under
starter's orders.
They're... they're
moving up.
They're moving up.
Any moment now.
They're off!
Oh, it's started.
Can't see who's winning
for the moment.
They're all bunched up.
I... I can see Jenny Lynn,
Playful Charles,
Tiger Man, and Hesperus
in front.
Ortalicus seems
to be boxed in.
He'll never make it unless
he gets away from the rails.
They're coming up
to the course bushes,
And now
I can see them better.
It's Jenny Lynn
to the lead.
She's setting
a tremendous pace.
She'll never keep it up.
Playful Charles
is a length behind.
Tiger Man's well placed
and going strongly.
Hesperus is there.
It's a terrific race!
They're coming down to
the captain's wall now.
Jenny Lynn still
leading by a length.
Tiger Man's coming up.
He's passed
Playful Charles.
They're on the corner now.
Jenny Lynn's
still leading!
What a magnificent filly!
It's uphill now, and
Tiger Man's closing the gap.
Tiger Man's now second.
There's Hesperus,
right on the rails.
Oh, now look
at Ortalicus!
Ortalicus is coming
away on the outside!
It looks like
he'll make it yet!
No, he can't do it.
Tiger Man in place!
He's still at his heels!
On you go, Tiger Man!
Tiger Man will win it!
Tiger Man, Tiger Man!
Tiger Man wins!
Max was wrong.
Here are the first
three past the post.
Tiger Man, Ortalicus,
Jenny Lynn.
That puts us among
the also-ran.
But wait a minute.
There's an objection!
Yes, the red flag's
going up!
(Crowd shouting)
And there goes
the green flag!
Objection sustained!
Ortalicus!
Ortalicus wins
the derby!
Ortalicus!
Max was right!
He was right!
(Laughs)
Thanks.
Oh, what a day.
I thought we'd never
get home at all.
Is Mr. Maximus back yet?
Yes, madam.
He returned
about 6:30.
6:30? Oh, he'll be
waiting for us.
I've got a first
I wouldn't sell for 1,000.
Taxi, please.
(Overlapping chatter)
Oh, hello.
Good evening.
Did you enjoy
the derby?
Oh, yes,
every word of it.
Can I offer you anything?
Why, thank you.
Mr. Maximus
gave me a cocktail.
He's just changing.
He really
ought to hurry.
Oh.
Well, I'll tell him.
Oh, hello, darling.
Thank heavens
you've come.
Help me with this collar,
will you?
Oh, come on, sweet.
Going out, dear?
Yes, I'm off
to the derby banquet.
With Christine Shaw?
Good Lord, no.
I'm going with
her father.
It's a stag party.
I sense things have been
moving today.
Yes, I guess some things.
Southwood made me
the most marvelous offer.
He wants me to
be newspaper prophet
On TheDaily Sun.
I say, did you
see the race?
Where were you?
In the car.
He's offering
the most wonderful money.
Have you accepted?
Oh, my darling!
What do you think?
There!
I'm starting
tomorrow, you know,
Looking into the future
and all that.
I like old Southwood.
Yes.
You seem to like
his daughter too.
Well, she's been rather
a brick, you know,
And she's waiting now to
take me across in her car.
That's sweet of her.
I say, darling,
what's the matter with you?
Oh, nothing.
Oh, now,
come on, sunshine.
What... what is
worrying you?
Well, I thought
we might have been
Together this evening.
Yes, I... I know,
but you see,
I've... I've got to go
to the banquet.
After all, it was arranged
by...
By Christine's father.
Yes, darling,
I'd take you if I could,
But it's...
It's a stag party.
And after all, now,
You must realize it from
a business point of view.
Here's your jacket.
Thank you, darling.
Now, don't be hurt.
After all,
now just think...
Think what it's
leading to... our future.
I'm wondering what
it's going to be like.
(Christine)
Max, it's time
we started.
Coming!
"We"?
Darling, you're being
rather silly and petulant.
Here's your coat.
Thank you, darling.
(Laughs)
I say, you're not upset
Because she's taking me
across, are you?
Should I be?
Oh, no, now, now,
darling.
Darling, now let's
meet afterwards
And have food together,
just the two of us.
Do you really think
you can eat
Two meals
in one evening?
Darling, you're being
rather childish!
Am I?
Yes!
It's only because I
love you rather a lot.
(Christine)
Max!
Well, good-bye, sweet.
Oh!
Oh, here's your hat.
Oh, uh, thanks.
Bye-bye.
(Overlapping chatter)
(Gavel banging)
Your grace, my lords,
and gentlemen,
I pray silence for your
chairman, the Lord Southwood.
(Applause)
Your grace, my lords,
gentlemen, to the King!
The toast is to
His Majesty, the King.
The King!
(Overlapping chatter)
(Gavel banging)
Your grace, my lords,
and gentlemen, you may smoke.
(Overlapping chatter)
No, thank you,
I don't drink port.
(Overlapping chatter)
(Gavel banging)
Your grace, my lords,
and gentlemen,
I pray silence
for your chairman.
(Applause)
Your grace, my lords,
and gentlemen,
I hope you'll agree
with me
That we've had
a very pleasant day,
Particularly me.
(Laughter)
Well, really...
It's all right.
I've only come
to fetch Father.
Isn't he speaking now?
Yes.
I expect they'll be
at least an hour.
I don't mind waiting.
(Men laughing)
If the committee knew there
was a lady in the club,
They would think it was
the end of the world.
Shh!
(Gasping)
He has done me
the great honor
To accept an offer
I have made.
From tonight onwards,
gentlemen,
He joins my newspaper
as seer.
In fact, I think we may say
in very truth, gentlemen,
He is the "profit"
of The Sun.
(Laughter)
You're not eating
anything, darling.
I can't.
Stop.
There.
Have a drop
of this, dear,
To keep
your strength up.
Mm.
No, thank you.
I know what you're
worrying about.
I suppose it's dreadfully
foolish of me.
All she did was drive him
to the banquet.
That's all?
I was awfully mean to him
when he left.
He asked me
to meet him for supper,
And I never even said yes
or where or anything.
Well, why not ring
him up and fix it?
I should, shouldn't I?
It'll set your mind
at rest.
Absolutely.
He'll be feeling as blue
about it as you are.
Go on, do it now.
No time
like the present.
All right.
(Gavel banging)
My lord chairman,
your grace,
My lords,
and gentlemen,
Pray silence
for Mr. Maximus.
(Applause)
Bravo.
My lord chairman,
your grace,
My lords, and, uh...
Uh, gentlemen,
First of all,
I would like to express
My indebtedness
to Lord Southwood
And to all those
who have helped me.
Looking into the future,
I see trouble...
Terrible trouble
for myself.
I'm sorry you
all look so relieved.
(Laughter)
If I dare to foretell
the winner of another race,
I shall most certainly be
assassinated by the bookmakers.
(Laughter)
If my prophecy is wrong,
then, uh,
I shall have the public
themselves on my heels.
(Phone buzzing)
Who is it?
Oh, Mrs. Maximus.
Mrs. Maximus?
I'll speak to her.
Hello, this is
Christine Shaw.
Oh, it's
so exciting here.
Your husband's absolutely
the line of the evening
And such
a brilliant speaker.
Hello? Hello?
I've been cut off.
(Max)
It will mean
a greater profit.
What's the matter?
Didn't you get Max?
Christine Shawn.
That's impossible.
(Simon)
Yes, it's a stag party!
That's what I thought.
Rene.
Here's a pretty
kettle of fish.
What's she driving at?
You heard!
You haven't got
coal for ears.
Anything I can do?
(Door slams)
What are you doing?
I'm going.
What do you mean,
going?
I'm leaving.
Oh, but why,
my dear, why?
Isn't it perfectly
obvious?
But you don't realize
what you're doing!
I can't let you go!
No, no, Mother, don't.
Where will you go?
What will you do?
Mother, please!
Please, Mother!
Rene!
I've told you,
I'm going.
Hello?
What are you doing?
Riding a bicycle.
Hello?
Finding Max,
you fool.
Hello?
Give me a line,
please.
(Buzzing)
Hello?
Oh, I see.
Uh, just wait a moment.
(Max)
We live in a frightening...
In many ways,
a very cruel world,
And if I can alleviate by
even the smallest fraction
The burden of my fellow men,
Then I shall feel
that my life
And this gift with which
it is so curiously bound,
Has not been
entirely wasted.
(Applause)
(Overlapping chatter)
Why, hello, Christine.
I didn't know they allowed
ladies in here.
They don't.
Excuse me, will you?
Thank you.
Hello?
Oh, hello, Mother.
Going away?
Why is she going away?
Oh, no, no!
No, she's making
a mistake.
You must talk to her.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
I... I can't come
at the moment,
But you must... you
must talk to her.
I'll get back
as soon as I can.
Yes, yes, hurry,
stop her!
St...
**
Max, what's the matter?
That's queer.
**
Hello?
Cor, she... she rang off.
What was it?
I thought I saw...
Saw what?
My mother.
Max!
Christine!
**
Oh, no, it... it
couldn't have been.
It couldn't.
(Chattering and laughter)
I must go back to
this banquet business.
Rene!
(Doorknob rattling)
Open the door!
Don't be a little fool,
my dear.
Max said... Rene!
Rene!
(Dramatic music)
**
(Mother screaming)
What's the matter,
madam?
Uh, silly of me.
I fell downstairs.
Shall we fetch
a doctor?
No, no.
What happened?
Are you hurt?
I'm all right.
I... I just fell.
Where do you
think you're going?
I'm coming back
with you.
That's right, darling.
Rene, I want to talk
to you about Max.
Oh.
Oh... oh, darling.
Hello?
Hello, get me
Mr. Maximus, please,
If you know
where he is.
Rene, Rene, I must say
something to you, quickly.
No, no, not now.
I must, I must.
It's about Max.
That gift is bad.
It's no good.
He must give it up.
Yes, yes, of course.
Yes.
It's Christine Shaw!
She's what
I said before.
She... she's the power.
He must give it up.
He must give her up.
Tell him, tell him.
I'll tell him.
It's bringing unhappiness
to you both, darling.
Yes.
They say one sees
very clearly
In the face of...
Oh! Oh, Topsy.
Topsy, oh.
**
Oh, Max, you think
you're so infallible.
You couldn't even see
your mother's death.
I did see it.
Or almost did.
Just after
she telephoned me.
But I put it
away from me.
Christine was beside me.
Christine.
What your mother said
was true.
It's Christine's presence
That gives you
the power to see.
Why, you have
no gift at all
When she's not with you.
I feel she's
very close tonight.
Max.
But it's as if there was
a bond between us,
A queer sort of sympathy.
It's stronger than I am.
Is it stronger than
your love for me?
Oh, please God,
I hope not.
Oh, Max.
This thing is becoming
a mania with you.
You've got to break
this bond,
Not for my sake but for
the sake of your sanity.
I can't break it.
It's going on.
I know it.
Weakness isn't
going to help.
Oh, Max, I'm fighting
a battle for your mind,
And I've got to win it!
We've got to go back
to the old life.
Rene, don't you realize
what's happening to me?
I can't go back.
If you'll only use
your strength of will.
What strength of will?
Against... Against...
What?
**
I love you
More than anything
else in the world,
But if you
go on with this,
Then I will leave you.
But it may be
a gift from God.
Or the devil.
(Bell tolling)
It's getting late.
You two ought to be
going back.
Yes.
Come on.
Do you mind if
I stay here a bit?
I'd like to do
some thinking.
So long as you think
along my line.
Don't worry.
Don't be too long.
I won't.
Aye, taxi!
Max, I meant what
I said, you know.
You always do.
You will give it up?
I never argue
with a lady.
(Laughs)
Don't catch cold,
dear.
I won't.
**
(Dramatic music)
Sorry.
Did I hurt your arm?
That's all right.
**
Have these.
Thanks.
**
Here.
That's the first
whole cigarette
I've smoked for a week.
**
But I know your face.
I've seen it
in the papers.
Why, of course!
You're Maximus!
Yes.
I wish my future were
as happy as yours.
**
Down on your luck?
Yes, that's a mild way
of putting it.
How'd it happen?
Oh, a bad break,
I suppose.
I had a chance
At what seemed a good
job offered me,
In the Humber shaft,
Under the river,
you know,
Only it meant
going up the hole,
And I had to choose
Between my wife
and the job.
And you chose your wife?
I chose the job.
Nothing seems to have
gone right since.
Thanks for
telling me that.
What do you mean?
I've been faced with much
the same problem myself.
The choice between
your wife or your job?
Yes, and thanks to you,
I've chosen my wife.
But you're wrong...
100% wrong!
You, Maximus, why
you've got no choice!
I don't follow you.
Then let me
tell you something!
You've got a far greater
gift than any of us!
You can build a new world
By using the gift
as it should be used,
By seeing all the terrible
things before they happen
And stopping them
whilst there's time!
That's your job!
It's more than
your job.
It's your duty!
No, it's too late!
What you said first
decided me!
I'm putting this gift
out of my life forever!
(Dramatic music)
(Machinery running)
(Explosion)
Hello?
This is the Humber shaft.
(Loud banging)
Daily Sun?
Is that Mr. Carther?
Yes, Carther speaking.
Mr. Carther? Dixon here.
Yes, we're right in
the bowels of the earth.
Yes, under the river.
Can you hear the drills?
(Machinery running)
It's deafening here.
What are you
talking about?
(Train rumbling)
Well, that's a train
passing now.
It's going
up to the surface.
(Machinery running)
(Whistle blowing)
(Overlapping chatter)
This will deafen him.
Hey, I heard a whistle.
They're going to
expose the charges.
Are we all right here?
Yeah, just keep well back.
(Worker)
Ready?
Clear!
Now!
(Explosions)
Now tell me you didn't
hear that one, Carther.
(Laughs)
Now, look here, Carther,
what about this column?
Yes, I've got the stuff.
You can run it
in the first edition.
I'm not sure.
This derby prophecy is going
to take up a lot of space.
I'll find out
and ring you back.
Okay.
Good-bye.
Hanging up.
(Bells ringing)
(Knocks)
(Max)
I tell you, I'm definite.
I'm not going on with it.
Yes, but listen.
If you don't mind,
I'd rather not discuss it.
I'm grateful to deserve
the offer you've made me,
But I'm definitely
not accepting.
But Max.
Now, Christine, don't you
try to persuade me.
(Southwood)
Why the sudden change
in your point of view?
I have my reasons.
Well, of course,
if you feel like that...
What is it, Carther?
Oh, excuse me, sir,
it's Dixon.
We've kept that
column open for him,
And I've got him hanging
on the phone now,
From the Humber shaft.
Oh, yes, do you
want me to run
That Humber shaft
story, sir?
(Southwood)
Humber shaft.
What do you think?
The Humber shaft...
That's queer.
A man was talking to me
about the Humber shaft.
Max!
The Humber shaft... there's
going to be a disaster!
The waters sweeping in will
carry the men away!
(Others arguing)
I tell you, I'm right!
You've got to warn them!
What do you mean?
Did I say
I wouldn't go on?
I must go on!
Here's your
first prophecy!
The Humber shaft
will be destroyed!
Splash it across
your front page!
Give it all the space you can!
You're crazy!
Save the poor devils
while there's time!
What do you think I am?
I'd run myself in
For the biggest libel
action of the century!
I was right about
the train, wasn't I?
But there are millions
of pounds involved!
And there are hundreds
of lives involved!
He's right, Father,
you've got to run it!
I will not!
Then I'll go elsewhere!
No other paper
will run it either.
You mean, no one
will warn the men?
Go down Fleet Street
and see.
I'm not going down
Fleet Street!
I'm going out
to the Humber, now!
Max.
Yeah?
My car's outside.
Can I take you?
Yes, come on.
Yes, he's here.
Arrived about
an hour ago.
Crazy isn't the word
for it.
He's been telling
the manager
That the tunnel's gonna
blow up or something.
Yeah, the news spread
through the workers
And the men came
streaming up like flies.
Yes, he's talking
to them now.
I tell you, if you
go down today,
Half of you will never
come up alive!
You've got to believe me!
Do you think I came all
this way just to fool you?
There's going to be
a disaster!
Nothing can prevent it!
Don't you take
any notice of him!
The man's crazy!
You want to be caught
like so many rats?
The Daily Sun wouldn't
publish my warnings!
Your own managers
refuse to listen to me!
They said I was talking
superstitious nonsense,
But it isn't nonsense!
Was I right about
The Manchester Express?
(Overlapping shouting)
Was I wrong
about the derby?
Can any one of you
look me in the eyes
And tell me
I'm wrong now?
You're mad!
Get back to your work,
all of you!
I came up here
to warn you,
To save you from the terror
which I know is coming!
I implore you,
I beseech you,
For the sake of your wives,
your mothers and your sons,
Don't go
on the night shift!
(Overlapping shouting)
Enough, all of you!
Have you all gone mad?
Where are you going?
Are you going to throw
yourselves out of work
For the sake of
a nasty trickster?
Hey, out of work!
That's what I said!
(Whistle blowing)
There's the signal
for the night shift.
The train is waiting
to take you down.
Get to your work,
all of you!
The man who refuses
is through!
(Overlapping shouting)
Through, and you can
take it or leave it!
Well, are you going down?
They'll go down.
(Overlapping chatter)
Well, what are you
waiting for?
The shaft's
perfectly safe...
Safe as your own houses!
Get back to work,
every one of you!
The train is waiting
to take you down.
(Overlapping chatter)
Yes, they're
going down again.
Yeah, I'll ring
through later.
(Overlapping chatter)
Max.
Those poor devils.
You're not to blame,
whatever happens.
Why couldn't I
convince them?
No, Rene was right.
I shouldn't have
gone on with it.
She wasn't right.
You've got something that
belongs to the world.
You've got to go on.
You believe that?
I know it.
Perhaps it's
women's intuition,
Or perhaps it's just
because I love you.
Why do you look
like that?
Because you love me?
Is that wrong?
I don't know.
Max, I love you.
I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, are you
satisfied now?
No, it's on your own head,
MacGregor!
Well, they seem to be
getting on with it.
Come on, come on,
come on.
Some of them
aren't so happy.
I'll be glad when
this shift's over.
Aw, snap out of it!
You're safe enough.
Try that one.
You sure
you're all right?
I'm all right.
Are you ready?
No!
No, wait!
(Explosion)
(Workers screaming)
(Overlapping shouting)
(News vendor)
Humber shaft arrest!
(Overlapping voices
of news vendors)
(Overlapping chatter)
It wouldn't have happened
If he hadn't put
the wind up them!
Murderer...
That's what he is!
He ought to be hanged!
Lynched!
Are you gonna stand here
and do nothing?
No!
Well, you're going to
show Maximus
He can't murder our people
and get away with it!
(Overlapping shouting)
Get back!
(Prosecutor)
This terrible tragedy
in the Humber shaft
Was brought about
by panic...
Panic which is
directly traceable
To the so-called prophecy
of the prisoner at the bar.
The very nature of
the prisoner's activities
Made it vital
That he should keep his name
before the public!
He chose a very terrible means
of achieving that objective.
200 bodies
have been recovered.
110 are still lying
in that shaft, your honor.
The deaths of these men
must be laid at the door
Of one man only...
The prisoner!
I call my first witness,
Miss Christine Shaw.
Miss Christine Shaw!
(Christine)
I swear by Almighty God
That the evidence
which I give this court
To be the truth,
the whole truth,
And nothing but the truth.
(Prosecutor)
You are Miss
Christine Shaw?
Yes.
You are attending here
on subpoena?
Yes.
I understand
that you were present
When the prisoner
foresaw the disaster.
I was with him in the cab
when a state came on him.
Well, if you'd like to
call it that.
The prisoner just lost
his post on The Daily Sun.
He just resigned it.
Well, I suppose we might
put it that way.
He had resigned it!
Quiet, quiet.
We really needn't
quarrel about a word.
At any rate,
at this juncture,
The prisoner was out
of employment.
Yes.
And so he promptly
made a prophecy
Which was bound to
attract public attention.
That's not why he made it.
You don't think it was?
You drove the prisoner
up to the Humber?
Yes.
You were there when
he told the workers
There would be
a disaster?
Yes.
The workers were alarmed?
I might almost say they
were in a state of panic?
What's that
got to do with it?
Were they alarmed?
Of course they were
alarmed.
His prophecies come true.
Exactly.
Then, do you not think,
from what you saw,
That the workers' alarm
was calculated
To bring about
a state of tension
Hardly conducive
to safety?
I don't understand.
Come, come, Miss Shaw.
You're trying to force me
to speak against him!
I am asking you
if you don't believe
That the accident was due to
the prisoner's prophecy.
I wasn't in the shaft.
How am I to know?
Answer the question,
Miss Shaw.
I can't answer it.
You're here
to give evidence.
I didn't want to come!
Why not?
Was it because you
thought your evidence
Would hurt
the prisoner's case?
I didn't think about it
at all.
Oh, well, perhaps
you'll be good enough
To think now.
You were present,
I understand,
When the accused
Prophesied The Manchester
Express disaster.
Yes.
Are you aware that
had the prisoner
Not stopped the train,
It would have
cleared the points
And the collision
would have been avoided?
Miss Shaw?
I didn't know that.
Well, I tell it
to you now as a fact.
Do you still believe
The prisoner is
a genuine clairvoyant?
He foretold
the derby winner.
He's not the first person
To bring off
a 100-to-1 chance.
How do you know this wasn't
merely a lucky coincidence?
Why do you ask me that?
How can any of us know
what is the truth?
Then you agree with me.
You are not sure that
the gift is genuine.
That's not what I said!
Thank you.
But...
Thank you, Miss Shaw,
that is all.
I have no questions
to ask this witness.
Call Arthur Watts!
Arthur Watts!
(Crying)
I let him down.
They told me you were
going to leave him.
I haven't left him.
(Crying)
You love him,
don't you?
Yes.
I wanted to take him
away from you.
Do you still want to?
He doesn't care for me.
(Sniffles)
But you care for him,
and you can help him.
I hate to say this
to you,
But I've got to
make you understand.
You see, the gift only comes
when you're near him.
It's got to stop.
It's got to.
You mustn't see him again.
(Prosecutor)
You are telling us
that it was panic
Caused the disaster?
Yes, panic.
And that but for
this man's prophecy,
Your fellow workers
Would have been
alive today?
As God is my judge,
I believe they would.
I do love him so.
Yes, we both love him,
But it's his happiness
I'm thinking of.
If this thing goes on,
I believe he'll go mad.
Oh, don't you understand?
(Crying)
It's up to you.
(Exhaling)
I'll never
see him again.
Promise?
Never, after today.
And that,
members of the jury,
Concludes the case
for the prosecution.
Members of the jury,
my client's elusive fame...
Many times
throughout history,
Men have stood much
as my client stands now,
Feared by mankind
for no greater sin
Than the possession
of a gift
Which the world
has failed to understand.
Knowing the strength
of my case,
I propose to call
two witnesses only...
My client himself
and his wife Rene.
I call Mrs. Maximus.
Mrs. Maximus, please.
(Overlapping shouting)
Of course I believe
in my husband's power.
I didn't want him
to use it,
But he felt
if he did use it,
He could help people.
Did you believe
it was genuine?
It is genuine.
I only wish it weren't.
I see.
And has it always
been genuine?
Yes, always.
So that right back
in those old days,
When the great Maximus
and yourself were
A somewhat indifferent
music hall turn,
Earning a somewhat
indifferent salary,
Even then you believed
that your husband
Was a genuine clairvoyant?
Oh, no, not then.
He was not genuine?
Well, you see,
I mean...
Was he or was he not?
That's not
a fair question.
It is a perfectly
fair question.
Answer me directly.
Was your husband
a charlatan or not?
Our act was
a professional routine.
A fake routine?
Well, yes,
of course it was.
It had to be,
don't you see?
You have admitted
That your husband was a
professional trickster.
Thank you.
Oh, no, but the...
The gift, that's different.
The one was fake,
the other was not.
I don't wish to
detain you any further.
But I must explain!
This way, if you please.
(Overlapping chatter)
(Judge)
Silence in court!
This way, miss, please.
Mr. Maximus, please.
Mr. Maximus.
(Overlapping shouting)
I swear by almighty God
That the evidence
which I give this court
Should be the truth,
the whole truth,
And nothing but the truth.
Mr. Maximus, I have
only a few questions.
Why did you foretell
the Humber shaft disaster?
Because I foresaw it.
You must tell
what you see?
I must tell what
I see.
You believe you could have
saved these men's lives?
I could have saved them.
You were not prompted by
any thought of gain?
I was not.
Tell the court.
Is this gift genuine
or is it not?
It is genuine,
God help me.
Thank you,
that is all.
(Prosecutor)
I find your statement
most interesting,
Mr. Maximus.
So you really believe
In this clairvoyant
business yourself?
Of course I believe in it.
Quite, it's a gift,
isn't it?
I think that's what
you call it.
You have the effrontery
to assert
That you can
foretell the future.
You claim omnipotence.
You have a gift
from God Himself.
I never said that.
Well, then perhaps it's
from the other source.
Is that it?
Perhaps you'll tell us
it's a gift from the devil.
(Overlapping chatter)
Somebody else
once suggested that.
If this gift is genuine,
Why not
demonstrate it here?
It's simple enough.
Give us a taste of
your quality, Maximus.
Prove that
you are genuine,
And my case
falls to the ground.
Prophesy, Maximus.
Put on your act.
Demonstrate your art.
Tell the jury what
will be their verdict.
Prophesy, Maximus,
prophesy, prophesy.
But I can't...
I can't to order.
But you can for money.
But I... I can't see.
Of course you can't,
and I'll tell you why.
Because you're a
charlatan and a faker!
If you're not,
Why did your wife
threaten to leave you?
Why did your wife threaten
to leave you?
**
I see a man.
Ah, that's better!
Now, members of the jury,
watch him perform.
110 living men.
They're tapping
their way out
By the eastern shaft.
The eastern shaft.
They're weak,
they're famished,
But they're alive!
They're tapping
their way out.
They're at the surface!
Soon, news will come!
News, soon!
(Overlapping chatter)
They're alive!
(Cheering)
Alive? Oh!
What's all this?
It's true, I tell you!
They got them all out!
They're alive!
(Overlapping shouting)
Silence in court!
(Whispering)
I am given to understand
That what you have just
told us is the truth.
These men are free
and alive.
In these circumstances,
I have no option
But to suggest to the
foreman of the jury that...
If, uh, you'll
excuse me, my lord,
We, the jury, are agreed.
Our verdict is
not guilty.
(Overlapping chatter)
(Overlapping shouting)
Come on, step up!
Draw in closer
and be entertained
By the greatest clairvoyant
and mind-reader
America has ever seen!
Why, he's only a taste
Of what you're gonna
see inside, folks,
And all for a dime, ten cents,
the tenth part of a dollar!
Come on,
put him to the test!
Call him anything you like,
but remember, it's $50
To the one that can say
how he does it!
$50!
Come on, mister,
what's $50 to you
If you can tell us
how he does it?
It'd be a shame
to take the money.
Ah, you don't know what
you're missing, mister.
Okay.
(Laughter)
Come on, let's go
get a hot dog.
(Female assistant)
Thanks very much!
What am I holding?
A fountain pen.
Step up, ladies and
gentlemen, step up!
It's all free!
See for yourself
the greatest...
**