Come on
Is this your horse?
No...
Whose is it then? Speak
It's mine
It's mine now
I'm not selling
I'm buying, who dares decline
I have something more valuable
than a horse
...but I doubt if you can get it
Hero
Take me as your pupil
What are you doing?
I want you to be my teacher
and teach me a few moves
Get up
Little brother, I'm so young
How can I take a pupil?
I'm not getting up
...unless you agree
Teach me
I'll serve you forever
Stop fooling around
Get up
Hero
I am a good man
I have no family to worry about
I won't give you any trouble
...if you take me as your pupil
No, I can't take a pupil
This is their silver
You help me to bury them properly
You want to bury them?
I can't let them just lie here
Do you know
...whom you have killed?
I don't care, just bury them
What a fool!
He wants to bury the silver
Good...
No, I'm still a long way off
But you are not bad
You just lack focus
Remember
the trick is speed and accuracy
Eyes, hands and intent should be one
Yes
Lam Hung, show me what you've learnt
on the 18 sword styles with your juniors
Yes. Come
Please
Stop
Lam Hung
Two of your moves weren't powerful enough
You left yourself wide open
This sword style...
is not a dead form
The more enemies there are
the more powerful it will be
You must use it flexibly
It could be used round and round
and spin off into many techniques
Yes, I'm sorry
Stand and watch
Come, let's exchange a few moves
More men
A few more
Good...
Get up...
Practise more
Yes
Master Chiu, these few moves are real good
You're too kind
It all can't yet match your
San He sword style
You're too kind
Nanny, allow me
Uncle, your tea
Thanks
Aunt Jin, clean up the guest room
Put up some clean sheets
Who's coming?
Your second uncle's son
Brother Yu Lung will arrive in
these 2 days
Why is he coming all of a sudden?
I invited him
I hear his kung fu is quite good
You haven't seen it
When he arrives I'll
...ask him to demonstrate
That's good
How long is he staying?
He'll be here
I am getting old
and he will take over my affairs
That's good
I have been worrying
I thought you might hand over the affairs
...to me
It's not that I don't want to do that
You are after all a girl
That's a fact
What do I know?
It's good that Yu Lung
...can come
I can learn kung fu from him
and we'll have fun
Look at you
However, he's new here
so you must guide him
Don't worry. He's my brother
I'll tell him
...all that I know
Right
I'll ask Brother Lau to teach me
San He sword style
Alright
Wait for me at the usual place
Brother Lau, teach me few moves
Miss, your swordsmanship is already
very good
Why ask me?
Stop being evasive,
if you don't want to teach just say it
It's not like that
Alright then, let's fence
Please
Brother, you should make some
allowance for me
Sorry. Get up
I'll teach you how to get through
these moves
Brother Lam
How come you've arrived so quickly?
What are you thinking?
About us
You don't believe me?
It's not like that
I've always thought uncle would hand over
...all his assets to me
Now it's all over
Why?
He said my cousin will be coming
...to take over his affairs
If it's that's the case
...our plans will be nullified
I want you to do something
...dangerous for me
Will you?
Of course
For you, I fear nothing
The only chance we have now
...is to kill my uncle
...before Chiu Yu Lung arrives
...at Death Valley
Oh?
You should understand
When I get the assets
...it will be yours as well
I know
What? Infirm of purpose?
No
How could my skills enable me
to fight teacher?
We'll do it together
It's not going to be done openly
We'll ambush him
It's not easy too
Don't forget Lau is always protecting him
We'll bribe him
Lau is no fool
Will he do it?
Don't worry
Let me handle him
The question is whether you're willing?
You needn't ask
For you, I'll do anything
Good, just listen to me
I have my plans
Intoxicating incense?
There's an assassin!
Yuen Hawk, help
Yuen Hawk
You must write it
...so that he'll come urgently
I didn't expect master
...would be killed like this
We are inadequate
...and must solicit Jin Fu's help
Nanny
If Jin Fu could avenge uncle's death
for me
I'll be grateful to you all my life
Miss, don't mention it
See, is this alright?
Thank you
You...
What?
Why did you kill her?
I don't need her as my nanny any more
Though I've always loved you
I've never dreamt such a day would come
I won't let you down
Swear it
If I let you down,
I'll die a horrible death
Now you should know
how I feel about you
Are you satisfied?
It'll be light soon. Go quickly
I am reluctant to leave
So am I
But you must go
Yuen Hawk
You can find Jin Fu in Jing Jou county
...at Gau Sing Inn
Give him this letter
As long as he's willing to come
...we have no fear
...of Chiu Yu Lung
Return soon
...so I wouldn't have to worry
I'll be back soon
Where is Gau Sing Inn please?
Just over the bridge
Thanks
Does someone called Jin Fu
...stay here?
I have something urgent for him
He's at the back
In the big room
Who is it?
Lau Yuen Hawk
From Death Valley
Are you hero Jin?
Yes
Please have seat
Thanks
Our benefactor Master of Yue Yang Mansion
was killed in an ambush by
his bodyguard Lau
He intended to occupy the mansion
and marry Miss Chiu
No one dared go against him
because of his great skill
So I've tricked him to deliver this letter
Here is the bracelet as a token
You kill him at once to prevent
further problems
So you are Lau Yuen Hawk?
Yes. How can I help you?
Excuse me
You take a look
What?
Who's beating the drum?
Me
Who are you?
The Lone Ranger Er Toe Chi
What's it with the drum?
I want the reward for Snow Five Devils
By you alone?
You killed them all?
The body is out there
Go and see for yourself
Come, men
Yes
Examine their identity
We have examined them
and it is the Snow Five Devils
Pay him
Yes
Stand down
Wait
Quick
I didnt get your name just now
You are...
The Lone Ranger Er Toe Chi, what?
Nothing?
Teacher
I've been looking for you everywhere
Don't call me teacher
What do you want with me?
I want to return the silver to you
Consider it yours
Master Chiu is dead
What?
Lau Yuen Hawk?
Do you know who is Lau?
No
Look
This man is Jin Fu
Hero Jin, you killed him?
Are you kidding?
I just posted this
The body is at Gau Sing Inn
Get someone to collect it
Yes
Gau Sing Inn
Ten
Don't move
The banker is ten. All win
Earth tile
Open
Nine
One and Six
A pair of three
You've lost again
Pay up
Yes, yes
Hurry... come
Come, are you defeated?
Come on
Teacher, I've lost everything
Get up, I'll play a few hands for you
Stand aside
Four
Jin Fu, I have no quarrel with you
what do you mean by this?
As long as I'm here
I won't let you bully others
I am no easy-going fellow either
What if we dare you?
Fight...
Jin Fu
We have a business here
and you are interfering with us
Okay, we will remember this
Show me what you've got
Let's see
Be careful. Let's go
Go...
Make way
Thank you for your help, I'm so grateful
They're bullies, it's not fair
I am Jin Fu, your name is?
Hero Jin, this is my teacher
Shut up
I am Chiu Yu Lung
Waiter
Master Jin, can I help you?
Bring some wine
I want to drink with my new friend
Yes
A pot of good wine
Teacher, you're great
You've killed so many men
...with only a few strokes
He was drugged
and was almost ambushed
Drugged
Hero, don't attack us
We're the good guys
What do you want?
We're here to see you
If it weren't for teacher
you would have been ambushed
You mightn't believe
Go and take a look
...at the dead bodies out there
What should we do?
They planned to ambush you
and I found out
I'll never forget how you saved me
It's nothing
It's all because of me
I should apologise to you
Let's not stand on ceremony
Please sit
Please
Hero Jin, may I take a look at
...your famous sword?
It's nothing
Take a look
It's really a fine sword!
You really like it?
Yes, all good swords
...appeal to true martial artists
If you can use a single sword
I'll make an exchange with you
I should not take away
...your prized treasure
A good sword ought to be
with a good master
It's okay as long as you like it
Then I'll take it
Buns
Hot buns...
Hot buns
Money?
Who's paying?
Who's paying? I have no money
You can't do this
You have to pay
Damn you
I don't have to pay anything
No way
You have to pay
Get lost
Sorry sir
It's okay
They are at fault
Where are you from?
None of your business
Why do you bully a kid?
They ate my buns without paying
I love to bully others, so what?
If you kneel and bow to me
then I might not bully you
What boastfulness!
Beat him up
You still dare to bully others?
Have mercy
You're not getting off that easily
Money for the buns?
Here
Quick
Yes
I'll kill you
Little brother, here's your money
Go home
If you're bullied
...just tell my teacher
Thanks, thank you
It's okay
Go home now
Thanks
Let's take up lodging here
"Yue Lai Inn"
Boss, is there a clean room?
Yes
Hero Jin
The best room has been reserved for you
This is from Jien Ying of
the Chiu residence
...for you
She said to go see her with this
My teacher is not...
Alright
Let me rest a while
Yes
Siu San
Coming
Take them to the best room
Yes
Please follow me
Little Tiger
Coming...
Quick
Ride at once to master Lam
...tell him Jin has arrived
Yes
Master Lam, mercy
I want to pay you
but I have no money
Bullshit, I'll kill you if you don't pay
Master Lam, have mercy
When the autumn harvest is ready
I'll pay you what I owe
I bow to you...
No way. I'm not waiting that long
Pay right now
Even if you kill me
I have no money
I'll kill you
Brother, stop please
You'll kill him
Damn you. Shut up
If you want to live, you have to obey me
If you dare to do otherwise
...you'll die
I don't dare
Master Lam...
Jin has arrived in town
Really?
He's in our inn
Boss Chen has asked me to invite you over
I'll let you off easily today
If you don't pay tomorrow
you'll die
Why don't you take a seat?
I'll serve you first
No, sit, please
This is the rule
I don't have such a rule
We're brothers
If you serve me like this
...don't follow me then
You'd better get lost
I won't
Then sit and eat
What's this?
This was given by uncle
Father said I should look at it each day
when I arise and before meals
It contains the philosophy of life
Philosophy of life?
Let me take a look
This is fun
Same line every day?
Yes
Aren't you bored?
What do you know, eat up
Master Lam, he's here
What does he look like?
Smart, with a pretty face
Right. No wonder she asked him here
Where is his room?
The best room
He's having his meal right now
I'll see him
Is there a clean room?
Yes
Your name?
Jin
You're the cold-faced master?
I'm Jin Fu
I am Lam Hung of Chiu residence
Miss Jien has a token for you
Did you get it?
Is this it?
Kill him
Yes
Chase
Please follow me
Wait for me here
Yes
Weren't you looking for me?
You...
What did you want with me?
Something important naturally
You can't let me talk to you
...in the nude
What's the difference?
Go and sit in the living room
I'll be with you
Alright
Come, let me introduce
This is cold-faced hero Jin Fu
Little fellow
you have the nerve to impersonate Jin Fu?
What makes you say that?
Do you know who Jin is to me?
You should do your home work
Jin grew up with me
Can you fool me?
I ask you. What is your treacherous plan?
I was just going to ask you
What you want with Jin Fu?
You love to be a busy body
I'll teach you a lesson
so you'll tell the truth
Attack
Attack...
Chase...
We must catch him
He is Chiu Yu Lung
Attack
He must be Chiu
We must rid him for good
Let's split up and chase
Yes
We searched inside, nothing
Have you seen
...a wounded young man pass here?
No, Master Lam
Bull shit
I saw him come this way
Master Lam, I really haven't seen anyone
No
Master Lam, my dad is telling the truth
Bullshit, if he's not here
has he flown away?
Master, is it you?
Why are you wounded?
I'll take you to my home
Little doggy, have you sold your buns?
Yes
Granny, this gentleman is wounded
Who is it?
It's the master who saved my life
the last time
Oh, it's him
Then help him
...lie down quickly
Doggy, get a cup of hot tea
then bring our home-made medicine
Quickly
Brother Jin
Miss Chiu
Why address me this way?
Call me Jien Ying
Please sit
I thank you for
...avenging my uncle
My mother and I are indebted
...to uncle Chiu; so it is only right
...I avenge his death
I am deeply grateful
You are too kind
Where is my mother now?
I sent her to bring my father
from the south
This place is unattended after uncle
was gone
...so I plan to have my father help out
Also someone has been impersonating as
...my uncle's relative to steal the estate
That's why brother has been brought
...here to help out
I hope you will do me this favour
Do you know who the impersonator is?
I hear his name is Chiu Yu Lung
Chiu Yu Lung?
I hear his kung fu is very good
...and has arrived here
Brother Jin...
you must help me get rid of him
This...
Chiu is not a villain
You know him?
I have a good friend by the same name
and he is no villain
That's him
He stole into the mansion
...into my bower
and peeped at me while I was bathing
He had a sword
and said he was the cold faced Jin Fu
He molested me
Doesn't that make him a villain?
I think you have been misled
Brother Jin
Nanny asks you to help me get rid of him
so everything depends on you
Although a token has been left
and you have requested my help
I still should investigate thoroughly
But he might ambush me
...before you could find out anything
You are wrong
I know him
How could he harm a woman?
I feel anxious day and night
Brother, stay for the time being
No, I'm used to the inn
Master Lam, a toast
A toast to everyone
Drink up
Cheers...
Thank you for coming
...all the way
Don't mention it
We're brothers
Just tell us what you want
I want you to kill someone
That's easy
We can kill
...ten if you like
Two hundred taels of silver for
each of you
I'll reward you more after the job is done
Who do you want killed?
This person is highly skilled
Don't underestimate him
What's his name?
Chiu Yu Lung
Chiu Yu Lung?
Master Chiu, you're awake?
Yes, madam
Wait, the buns are ready soon
No, I have go out for a while
You're still wounded
How can you go out?
No, it's alright. I'm fine
It's here
Master, look who's here?
Brother
where have you been these two days?
You don't know
I was almost caught
I hide in a small valley with two horses
and dared not come out
I had no food for two days
Little doggy, hide the horses
Don't let anyone see them
The Chiu mansion guys are looking for you
I know
Eat a good meal tonight
I'll bring you to a place
Where?
Chiu Mansion
Chiu Mansion?
Halt
Who is it?
Hero Chiu Yu Lung
Chiu Yu Lung?
Chase
Chase him...
Brother Jin, please sit
What, have you not found Chiu yet?
Is he really here?
How come he hasn't shown up?
He's here
Who knows where he is hiding!
You must help me find him
As long as he lives
...I'm in danger
Brother, I'll do anything you want so long
...as you kill him
I'll give you anything you want
Miss, I'll depart if there's nothing else
Why do you address me like this again?
Don't you want to stay here longer?
It's late
We were closer when we were kids
Why is there a distance between us now?
Good bye
No matter what you do to harm me
...you're still my sister
I won't kill you
Who are you then?
Didn't you say you're Jin Fu?
How can I be your sister?
Let me tell you
I must find out
...how uncle was murdered
Once I do
I will not spare the murderer
...whoever he is
Search
Yes...
Where is Chiu Yu Lung?
Speak or I'll kill you
Are you speaking or not?
Speak up
Granny
Speak
Where has Chiu gone?
You two stay here and wait for him
Yes
He must be near by. Search
Little doggy...
Little doggy, tell me who did this
I'll avenge you
Master Chiu
Don't cry
It's you
Relax
If I were to kill you...
I could have done so through the door
But you'll lose your life too
I was never keen on it anyway
Let's see whom do
I eventually lose it to!
How come you're here?
Everyone is looking for me
...and wants to kill me
Only yours is a quiet place
But it's not a safe place
Aren't you looking for me as well?
How did you know?
You fear that I know?
You should stand up
...for your own deeds, why fear?
I was indeed looking for you
To take my life?
I ask you
What's your relationship with
...the Chiu Mansion?
No one should meddle in the Chius' affairs
You should know that
...I'm your good friend
Why look at me like this?
I have never done any deed
...to betray my friends
Sometimes things change
What do you mean by that?
Maybe due to circumstances
or a woman
or money
A man might change
Brother Yu Lung
You don't know me
You misjudge me
Misjudge you?
Look at this
Are you true to your friends?
Your mission is to kill me
This matter...
You needn't explain this
I won't falsely accuse you
Can you let me speak?
Stop fussing around
There's nothing to say
Let's make a clean break
Since you put it that way
What do you want?
I'll wait for you at Death Valley
Kill me if you can
What time?
Noon
You insist on doing it this way?
It's a deal
We'll each
...use our own weapons
I am sure you'll come
Brother Jin... damn it!
Chiu went to the mansion
...and took all my uncle's
...deeds and documents
You have to find him quickly
and kill him
And bring back the deeds
I'm not going
Why?
He is not an impostor
I believe he is your relative
Never mind whether he is
my relative or not
Just kill him
This is your family business
I shouldn't get involved in it
Shouldn't get involved?
Have you forgotten that
...you and your mother owe us favours
You are servant of the Chiu family
Just do whatever you are told
Let me tell you honestly
Your mother has already been
locked away by me
What do you want?
If you dare to harm me,
your mother will surely die
Release my mother
If you want her to be released...
go and kill Chiu Yu Lung
Well?
When?
I'll be meeting him
Where?
Death Valley
When?
Noon tomorrow
Alright, I'll wait for your good news
Deal?
Let's discuss this later
Be careful
It's an ambush!
Kill
I've to settle some business with
Chiu Jien Ying
See you later
Do you remember that blind old lady?
This stab
...is to avenge my friend Little Doggy
This is for my uncle
Brother
Let me tell you
Last night I saw a woman
...forcing Jin Fu to come to kill you
I misjudged him
You are so cruel
...to have forced me to kill Chiu Yu Lung
You want me dead too
What are you talking about?
I don't understand
Why would I?
Stop fussing around
Let my mother out
You've promised to kill Chiu Yu Lung
Have you done so?
Your family's affairs are
none of my business
Just let my mother go
You have to do
...whatever you've promised me
Speak
Where is my mother?
Let me tell you
I've killed all your men
If you don't tell the truth
I'll kill you too, speak
In the room downstairs
Are you telling the truth?
Go see for yourself
I'll kill you if she's not there
Where else could I go?
There's nowhere for you to flee
Let me tell you
Your mother has already been killed by me
What can you do to me?
You think you can fool me
You've been stabbed by my poisoned needles
You'll die soon
What good are you now?
Where can you go?
You have to let me go
You won't live long
Miss
Leave this place as soon as possible
Something dreadful will soon erupt
Yes
Let's go
Brother Jin
Who did this?
Chiu Jien Ying
I'll have my revenge
No need
She won't live long
Chase!
Brother, look
Over there