Script:
Johnny Mak, Stephen Shiu
Producers:
Chung Kwok-kei, Chow Tak-Hua
Art director: Ho Kim-sing
Music: Wu Wai-lak
Photography: Wong Bao-man
Fights director:
Mak Tan-kit
Fights choregraphy:
Ma Yuk-sin, Yuen Chung-an.
Twenty years later
Moron!
Watch where you put your hooves!
You're useless!
Do you have shit for brains?
How can you swallow that?
You'd eat anything!
Exactly.
Anybody here?
Miss, your bricks order.
She looks strange.
Let's deliver and leave immediately.
Those flowers are magnificent.
They smell good.
What is it?
I'll go.
What is this coffin doing here?
It stinks!
Peasants, build a grave with these bricks.
It's not included in our service.
Move away!
Keep your distance.
Uncle Ping, how do you feel?
What's going on?
Those good smelling flowers are poisonous.
Their poison is lethalin high quantity.
So I'm sentenced to die!
Do you want the antidote?
Then get to work!
Careful!
I didn't touch!
It's not my fault.
I tried to warn you.
We call it
"using a retard as bait".
Sorry?
Hiding poison on a retard
and unleashing it when
he's near the target.
This retard is used as bait.
And this retard is you.
What a good explanation, miss!
Get to work!
Master Mojing
supper time.
Don't drink or eat anything she cooks.
Really tasty.
You're not only very beautiful
but you're also a great cook.
Quiet or I'll make you stop talking.
Alright.
Who uttered such a horrible scream?
The dwarf has been
poisoned by my flowers.
He'll scream to death without my antidote.
What about me, why don't I scream?
Uncle Ping, what's going on?
What are you doing?
Why him?
Why not me?
The antidote was in the meal.
You made the right choice.
That's why the meal was so good.
Miss,
please give me the antidote
to save Uncle Ping.
I put it in the rice.
He deserved it.
You're very kind,
I have to thank you.
I'd like to make
your grave unforgettable.
What a shame, something is missing.
What?
Some pig urine.
Mixed with cement
it would make the grave stronger
and it also protects from insects.
I'll help you get some urine.
Where is it?
What?
Do you know where it is?
I'd like to know.
I'll get the urine myself.
Give me your urine or I'll poison you.
Good night, miss.
Why didn't you hit his girl?
It's not my style.
Yeah, right!
You've been seduced by this nuisance,
- you dirty pig!
- Me?
Buddha,
my husband will be beaten to death!
Pray to ask for his help!
Out of the way!
There's nothing to see!
You're really nuts!
Your son admitted that he ate
young master Fung's goose.
We didn't accuse you without evidence.
Buddha, help my son!
Son, did you eat the goose?
Speak.
Eat what?
I ate...
A goose!
We didn't accuse him without evidence.
We lost a goose. The father
is punished for his son.
Theft is sentenced to death here.
Darling,
accept your miserable fate!
Is there any goose remains in his belly?
Look!
Blood!
It's not goose!
They're just snails!
He secretly ate some!
I didn't know about it!
Buddha,
see by yourself.
He didn't eat some goose,
but only some snails!
Faster!
Buddha, you're divine,
give us justice!
I travelled a long way to come here
to offer them some phoenix meat.
But Fung stole it and ate it.
Buddha, help us to give justice.
You want to get me?
Watch your tongue!
Our young master didn't steal your meat.
Do you agree with me?
My friends, phoenix meat is an
exquisite meal coming from Heaven.
I'll gut him to prove his guilt.
Father, help!
Please, I beg you.
Master Fung,
sorry for being late.
I'm really sorry.
I'll send some men right away
to settle this matter.
Peasant, you're guilty of
kidnapping and blackmail.
Don't you know the Law?
He's just trying to get
the land of this couple.
The victim's wife lost her mind
and their son dead.
You're a Magistrate, but you're
also an accomplice of this man.
You'll be decapitated first.
Lock him up and strike him
twenty times with a stick.
I lost an ear!
Father, he cut my ear!
It's me,
it's mine!
How lucky I am!
Too bad for you! Take it back.
Unworthy son,
two precious items have disappeared
from my library.
You stole them, didn't you?
No, father. I borrowed them to
admire them. I'll bring them back.
I want the original ones back.
Don't make fun of your father
with mimicries.
Your mother died too soon.
Poor boy!
Perfect landing.
Why are you defending
such miserable people?
15 years ago, on New Year's eve,
uncle Ping and I
were starving and sick.
This man helped us and gave us shelter.
He gave us the only cake he had.
Such a good deed deserves recognition.
Do you understand, Mr. Fung?
A man with principles is valorous.
Oh, no!
On your knees, scoundrel,
and bow down ten times.
Uncle Ping.
Bow down quickly.
He tried to bite my foot!
I would have never imagined that
such a beautiful horse could exist.
Was she a goddess
who came down to Earth?
Why did she take my bag?
Be victorious, Mr. Chu!
Safe travel, master.
Honor our school at the tournament.
Just my luck!
Who's there?
There are bad omens around you.
You're probably gonna die.
Give me your school emblem
and let me take your place.
Foolish woman,
how dare you talk to me like that?
In less than a week,
I forced the leaders of the
Eight Immortals, the Mohaus,
the Waitos and
the Thunders schools
to let me take their place.
Here are the emblems
of those four schools.
Come get some, fatso.
- How do you feel?
- Fine.
Come here.
My poor darling!
What's happening to you?
Your face is all swollen.
Does it hurt?
Yes!
This place is bad luck.
I'm outta here.
Tai lo.
You dirty Wu!
Miss,
how do you know my name?
Another dirty trick! And stop
staring at me like that.
Let go of me.
Sorry. I'm not as frivolous
as you think.
Don't always trust appearances.
I'll make the introductions.
They're friends of Mr. Chu.
This one is Fire Ghost Cho Mang.
And this one is Water Snake Tsui.
They're the ones who attacked you,
not me.
Give me the antidote to save my horse.
Your horse is cured, miss.
Can we go?
Give me your weapons.
I have one principle in life:
I only kill one man a day.
Did you kill one today?
Not yet.
Today, one of you must die.
But if I randomly kill one of you,
it won't be fair for the other.
I want you to duel.
Heaven will decide on your fate.
I'll start counting.
Get ready, one,
two,
three...
Stop it.
I'm in a good mood
You're free to go.
- Are you alright?
- Out of my way!
You attacked me like a traitor.
Why are looking at me?
Get lost!
Don't forget to wear something
more decent.
You're indecent!
It was just an advice.
Don't take it wrong.
What's your name?
My surname is Yuen,
and my first name is Tiyi.
Tiyi means "Purple Suit".
So with some green,
would you change your first name?
And what about you?
Wu Ne'er-Do-Weli?
My name is Wu Fei.
Fei has two meanings.
The first one is "Impure Thought",
the second is
"Without Elegance".
A snake bit me!
Where?
Don't move, I'll have a look.
You covered with mud.
You had it coming,
you dirty Fei Without Elegance.
Fine. If that's how you're taking it
then you're gonna get some too.
Stay where you are!
What if we played?
I'll ignore you forever if
you get any closer.
So what?
We barely know each other.
What are you doing?
Enjoy your bath!
Yuen Tiyi.
I'm coming!
Rape!
- Stay there!
- Maniac!
Look!
Don't miss that!
Buy a watermelon, it's cheap!
They're very tasty.
Do you want me to cut them open?
Why are you still following me?
The only thing you deserve is a kick.
Kick him!
Why so many watermelons?
I'm making a soup especially for you.
Are these blankets
for me too?
It's a secret.
Don't look at me like that
or I'll get angry!
Tiyi,
did you come from so far
just to challenge
a few schools?
General Fook is organizing a
martial arts tournament in Nanjing.
He's trying to divide us and
to make us kill each other
so we forget to hunt the Manchus.
My master asked me to thwart his plans.
You're doing it for the right cause.
I misjudged you.
The master also advised me
to find some allies.
You're thinking of me?
When i read the manual of your
ancestors techniques
I learned that you were the son
of the famous warrior Wu.
You're flattering me.
But i really am his son.
I'm offering you this jade phoenix
as compensation
for reading this manual.
I also bought you these clothes.
She's trying to get my attention...
by buying me nice clothes
and offering me a jade jewel.
There's no doubt about it,
she likes me.
We're alone under the rain,
in an abandonned temple.
I'm not stupid enough to not
understand your intentions.
But I'm the son of a famous family.
I can't soil my father's name.
What can I do?
Does it mean that
it doesn't bother him?
I got the message.
I salute you.
Not bad at all.
Now you're worthy of me.
You have good taste.
Why those tears?
It's the first time
that someone gives me a present.
The rice will burn!
It doesn't matter.
Let me do it.
What is it?
Rice coated with caramel,
it's my specialty.
Give it a try.
Excuse me.
I can't hold any longer.
He's smillng again...
I can't resist...
It's so exciting...
Enough.
I must kick him to stop him...
Father, help!
- Father.
- Young master.
This savage followed us here.
But he's wearing new clothes.
He looks rich now.
My boy,
you only have bad manners.
It doesn't bother me.
But you seduced my concubine,
and you're spending too much time her.
It's not decent.
I won't touch her anymore.
Don't cry.
Peasant,
I appreciate your efforts
to get dressed properly.
Thank you, I almost forgot
to change clothes.
It mustn't be soiled.
It's a gift from my dear wife.
She'll be a widow tonight.
Really?
Isn't it your son who will
prepare your funeral?
How lucky, it's not my ass!
Do you like this watermelon?
Not bad, darling!
Those are even better.
Caramel?
- Father!
- What are you doing, young master?
- I'm putting out the fire.
- But it's oil!
- Don't move.
- Move away!
My master forbade me to kill
during the mission.
How are you related?
Thank you for saving my life.
Have we met before?
Does my face look familiar?
I must give you a letter.
Chek, give something to write.
This letter explains everything.
Only the members of the Poison school
can soak paper fibres with poison.
This poison irritates
the eyes.
The victim ends pulling his eyes out.
His muscles decay before he dies.
Only the members of the
school have the antidote.
Does your master know where they are?
They have many enemies and keep moving.
Their leader is hidden
in a secret place.
His name is Mojing.
Mojing?
How do you do?
Aren't you watering your flowers?
What are you doing?
I'll tell you!
Don't come any closer!
Stay away!
Listen!
I noticed that you didn't have
enough materials the last time
so I bought some especially for you.
I can help you build the most
beautiful grave.
It took you a month to find all this?
No,
but it's a long and hard trip.
My donkey is slow.
I brought you some watermelons
and some caramel.
What else did you bring?
Since I was delayed, I brought
a friend to help us.
Last time it was a lame person
and now a blind woman.
She got blind after
she promised to help you.
I heard there's no cure for her eyes.
What can I do?
It's nothing.
She'll be cured in a few days.
Help me.
Stop!
- You're getting too familiar.
- No...
I won't do it again.
Help me.
She's been poisoned
three days ago.
She's been unconscious for half a day.
She'll die in six hours
without care.
This wagon is perfect
to carry her body.
I'm just in time.
Do you want to save her?
Claw her eyes out and she'll live.
Are you kidding? She's useless
if she remains blind.
I'll work and you'll cure her.
I anticipated everything.
I brought some of my pig's urine.
You've got a nerve!
You got me the last time.
Does it smell good?
I feel good.
Now we're even.
Let's get to work.
It scratches!
What's going on?
I put a poison in the urine.
What's happening to me?
You will look like a pig.
- A pig?
- Have a look in the water.
Who are you?
I'm changing into a pig!
Well, I wanted to put on some weight.
You got your revenge.
Now, save her.
Say "pig" three times.
I'm a pig,
I'm a pig.
I have to know if she's your fiancée!
If it's not the case then
she has nothing to do with you.
Why should I save her?
She's the woman of my life.
Help her by any means necessary.
- Why should I help my enemy?
- Your enemy?
She's my rival.
Sorry?
I barely know you!
How dare you reject me!
No! I'm going out with you,
not with her!
Miss,
I'll do anything you want.
Her time is coming.
I'll cure her if
you grant me three wishes.
I haven't decided yet,
I'll tell you later.
There's something
I'd like to tell you.
What is it?
Is it a present?
Yes.
It's ugly.
We're back, come out!
My brother and my sister in arms.
If she doesn't get
the cure now, she'll die.
Cure her and I'll drive them away.
Are you crazy?
They're poison experts.
We must find something,
they're already here.
I burned all your flowers.
Surrender immediately.
Give us the master manual.
Moyung,
Sit Hei.
Master, you're still alive?
I faked death,
knowing that you had bad intentions.
You're not wasting time to
steal the manual.
I, Kotai keung,
salute the Great Master.
Kotai keung?
Aren't you strong?
Great Master,
I used to be as my name suggests it,
big and strong.
Unfortunately, they took me by force
as one of their students
and they're using me
to test their poisons.
I'm shrinking everyday.
You must help me
and purify your school.
I knew that you wanted to kill me!
Help, Master!
You'd go as far as getting rid
of your disciple.
I must eliminate you without delay.
- Give us a chance!
- We won't do it again.
Shut up!
Let me talk!
I'll spare your lives
since you admit your faults.
Take a sword.
Cut off your left hand
with your right hand,
then both of your legs.
Then,
you'll cut off
the remaining hand one another.
Master... as you wish!
You're an impostor!
I'm screwed!
I'll help you.
He won't stop swelling.
It hurts!
How do you feel?
Do you want to get your original size back?
Your wish is granted.
It hurts!
Finally, I got my body back!
Move, peasant.
Stop looking at her!
Do you think she's beautiful?
Piss off!
What?
- What is it?
- Poisoned urine.
- Your chest...
- Poison.
I'll heal you.
No. People must know that she's
the one who attacked me.
Really?
Don't touch it. It's corrosive.
Go get a wok!
It's huge!
You dirty voyeur!
I won't hold much longer!
Go through the roof, stupid.
Don't complain if everything collapses.
What a dirty work!
Careful.
Stay behind me.
Don't say a word. Don't move.
It's the fiancé of our little
sister in arms.
What is this poison?
Don't panic.
It's only caramel.
Delicious.
It's been a while since I ate some.
- I love it.
- It's great.
I was keeping the best for the end.
Yunnan wasps!
I told you not to move.
You were in danger,
so I intervened.
In danger?
Touch me to find out.
Does it burn?
I'm covered with flammable powder,
you moron!
I learned another thing.
How is miss Yuen doing?
You should worry about
your fate instead.
Look at your hands.
My brother in arms poisoned you.
- What shall I do?
- Cut off your hands.
Dinner is ready!
Ling, it's fried fish.
I see...
Too heavy on the stomach!
I'll prepare some, steamed.
No.
Rice is ready.
It's perfumed.
You have no appetite.
I'll make you a seafood soup.
Wu Fei,
come here.
Wait for me.
What do you want? There's some seafood,
some clams and some pigeon.
What do you prefer?
I like everything.
Who is the prettiest?
Me or her?
Beauty is subjective.
Everybody has different tastes.
There are many beauties:
Inner beauty, outside look,
beauty with or without make-up.
Environment and climate
have an influence on beauty.
Weather reports count too.
Beauty and intelligence are
equally important.
Intelligence matters even more.
You're very intelligent.
Who is the most beautiful?
You are the most beautiful.
Repeat it louder.
Do you remember the three wishes?
Firstly,
I want you to stay with me forever.
Can you keep this first promise?
Yes.
Secondly,
you must leave Yuen Tiyi.
And finally,
you'll never see her again.
I knew that you wouldn't be able
to keep your promise.
Remember to not promise anything.
Don't worry,
forget what I just said.
Yes,
I'll remember.
Miss Yuen,
Here are the clothes and the jade
you offered me.
I give them back.
I'm the son of the Warrior Wu,
Descendant of an important family.
I have principles to respect.
You won't let me kill my enemy,
so you're becoming my enemy.
Our ways part here.
I won't stand in your way anymore.
In fact,
I hate him more than you do.
I must kill him.
I'm afraid I don't understand...
Twenty years ago,
at Nanking, a fisherman had
a daughter named Ngan.
One day when she was delivering
fish to Fung,
this monster raped her.
She got pregnant.
Feeling pity for Ngan,
an employee of the fish-shop married her.
Who dares touch my women?
He went to the village with his men.
They killed all the guests
at the wedding.
My mother couldn't endure it.
She abandonned me and killed herself.
My master took me with him
and taught me how to fight.
I came back to get revenge.
In this case,
why did you stop me
from killing him?
He's my father after all.
He gave me life.
I saved him once to pay my debt.
But now I'll avenge my mother
by killing him.
Tiyi,
I was wrong about you.
I'll come with you,
let's go.
I'll tell Ling to come with us.
Ling, it's a tragedy.
Her story is very sad.
So what?
Mine ain't any better!
Why do you ignore me?
You also endured a tragedy?
Tell me.
No way.
I also have a miserable past...
and nobody cares.
It's not as bad as mine.
Well, since we have that in common,
let's help one another.
We'll make a big family.
In fact, I'd like...
I know! You want me to be
your little sister!
No, you're two months older.
You're the big sister.
I want you to marry me
and be my slave!
Your slave!
Miss Ching.
Thank you for saving my life.
- I'm offering you the second phoenix.
- I don't want it!
I don't need any of
your thanks or presents.
"We neighbours should help each other out",
that's what my master told me.
Miss Ching,
these phoenix are a couple.
I give you Wu Fei.
Why should we get to that?
Why should we break up?
Darling,
come to eat!
It's getting cold!
I told you that he was ugly,
why do you keep him?
Look!
I bought you a lot of other clothes.
Do you like it? Look!
Wu Fei!
Fei!
Bastard, motherfucker, scumbag...
asshole, son of a...
Come back!
Come back or I'll poison the river!
May I never see you again,
or else,
I swear that
I'll poison you for good.
Forgive me.
I'm sorry,
my master is a monk.
I follow his way.
I dress like that when I travel.
I don't want to lie to you again.
Eat.
- I don't want it.
- Don't you like spices?
It's not strong enough.
What about some poison?
It's very spicy, do you want some?
Don't worry, I have the antidote.
Darling,
my heart is making me suffer
since a long time.
I decided to sacrifice myself.
She'll be bride,
I'll be the concubine.
You must feel happier.
Smile!
Do something.
Smile or I'll poison you!
Enough!
Who would want a woman like you?
You're only talking of poisoning
your husband! You're unpleassant!
When it comes to happiness,
that's not it!
Forgive me,
I won't do it again.
Listen, I promise that I'll never
poison you ever again.
May I die if I do it again.
Then keep your word.
You're watching another girl?
I'm gonna...
Young master, be careful.
An enemy.
I'll watch him.
Why so much excitement?
Add four jade coins on my
father's hat.
Young master, it would make
the hat look ridiculous.
This old man dares challenge
me for a girl!
There are many other concubines!
This girl with the big boobs is mine!
Come on!
Wonderful!
Come here.
I want to sabotage the tournament.
And you?
I'm here to marry you.
Let's ask your master
the permission to marry.
We'll run away and
lead a cloistered life
if he refuses.
Even if we are sentenced to death
by drowning...
I don't care.
Stop! You're the devil!
- I'm not the devil!
- You are!
- No!
- Yes, you are!
No, I'm not the devil.
I come from a great family.
That's enough!
I'll throw you downstairs
if you insist!
I don't believe you.
What does this smile mean?
Stop it!
Stop smiling like that!
My dear, it's my way of smiling
since I'm a child.
You're the one still tied
to the pleasures of this world.
You're really indecent for a nun.
Me?
I'm must take hold of myself.
Stop tempting me!
Do you want to kiss me?
No!
I'll get angry if you kiss me...
If you kiss me...
Don't kiss me...
I can't hold any longer...
Kiss me...
Do it or I'll get angry!
Let's part.
Alright.
- Why?
- That's true, why?
We sinned.
Let's part to avoid a scandal.
Let's go our own ways.
Take these emblems with you.
I must go.
Take care.
Damn, we're two,
to love the same man.
What are you trying to do?
I don't have to justify myself.
It's all my fault.
What do you want?
Enough talk.
Let's fight.
You're gonna lose without poison.
I don't need any poison against you.
It's too expensive.
I'll crush you like a bug.
I won't use any!
Using poison is out of the question!
Out of the question!
Let's make peace.
It's my fault,
since the beginning.
I'm warning you,
I don't want to see you again.
I'll punish you if we meet again!
Why are they looking at me...
Would people of the capital city
be aware of my relationship...
What?
Little bitch!
Here I am.
Why don't you sleep?
Still working?
I bought you some Peking duck.
I'm sure you'll like it.
How brave!
You're testing a poison on your face?
You idiot!
Is it the famous manual of your master?
Don't touch it!
It's poisoned.
You'll die in two hours
once you're infected.
It's almost finished.
I'll light another.
Don't light it!
There's some poison on it too.
This lethal flower must be
pourred with wine.
Is wine also some kind of poison?
Tiyi gave me two emblems.
She's inviting us at the tournament.
How will we disguise ourselves?
Also, she's asking when you'll
be available
for a good meal.
No way.
She won't be your wife!
She won't even be your concubine!
I'm keeping you for me alone!
You've got no say in this matter!
This wine is poisoned!
You broke your word!
Don't be ridiculous!
But this wine...
I pourred a good dose of laxative
to wash your stomach.
Three days on the bog
and you'll be as good as new.
You're heartless!
Why are you yelling at me?
Are you looking for a fight?
The bog!
Are you afraid to fight?
Fucking coward!
You thought you could get out like that.
At each infidelity
your punishment will be the same.
Here's general Fook.
General.
Bring the wine.
Thank you for coming from so far.
Please, drink this cup of wine.
Don't drink it.
It's poisoned.
It's okay.
Swallow this pill.
They're with my brother-in-arms...
Not easy to get rid of him...
Do you remember my advice?
I'm staying with you, not a word,
not a move.
You deserve a kiss.
Gentlemen, accidents can happen
during a tournament.
Out of kindness,
general Fook
chose the one who will be
the leader of all schools.
It will be Mr. Fung nam-tin.
Mr. Fung.
He deserves our respect.
He's the best person for this position.
Who ever thinks he's better than me
can come to challenge me.
I'm not afraid of your sword.
I'll throw you out of here!
Wait, Mr. Chan.
What? Don't you believe me?
Mr. Chan, these muscles
will be useless.
My fists are invincible!
You fell into their trap.
There's some poison in the wine.
What?
Defend your honor!
Only the master of Shaolin
can measure up to Fung.
Go, Master.
Let's fight, Master.
They've all been poisoned without knowing.
This smoke will cure you.
How do you feel?
Why are you following me?
You ordered me to stay with me.
You finally notice my qualities.
Give me a kiss.
Fags...
Master.
How do you feel?
My name is Wu To,
I'd like to fight you.
Shit...
Can I borrow your staff?
It's the sacred staff
of our ancestor Dhama...
Thank you.
Sir...
Mr. Fung, let's go.
It's you, peasant!
Exactly.
Master Yuen Tiyi, representing
thirteen and a half schools, is coming.
No need to show the world
your real identity.
Why?
This point is coated with a deadly poison.
Go cure him quickly!
No need to worry.
It's only poison.
Don't mind me or my husband.
I'm not here for the tournament.
I'm here to warn you.
Beware of Fung.
You!
You made a pact with the rebels
against the general.
I heard you speak with the rebels.
You pretend to serve the general
to able to capture him.
Do you have any proof?
It's in his hat.
Would you dare to show your hat
to the general?
General, it's a letter from
the leader of the rebels.
My father always obeyed your orders.
He's not your enemy!
It would seem that he also didn't
poison the guests.
Do you have an explanation?
General, it's a plot!
She set up this trap!
For many years I've been
hunting rebels for you.
General, she... She's my daughter!
i raped her mother.
She's trying to get revenge.
What?
May Buddha bless her soul.
What is this stupid story?
Get him.
Don't spare anyone.
Father, help!
Great, no need to fight for you anymore!
I declare that Miss Yuen Tiyi
is the most miserable of us all.
She's really sincere when
she's leaving you to me.
I'll always be very loving
if you remain faithful to me.
I was wrong.
I shouldn't have poisoned her...
What did you do?
No! We're good friends!
It was a joke!
Have a rest while I'll offer
her to eat with us.
Tell her that you want to be
her brother and we'll be a family.
It's decided.
- It's Mr. Chan.
- How did he die?
From a toxic silkworm.
Remember my orders.
Give me your master manual.
Okay, I'll give it to you if you
answer my question correctly.
I'll burn it
if you try to force me.
Speak.
You put some poison on his body
to poison us.
Why didn't you make it
impossible to detect?
It's impossible when it touches the skin.
Wrong. The manuals says it's possible.
Do you want to try?
Not good!
Master, don't listen to her!
How dare you disobey me?
Do you remember what you told me?
Master...
Here.
Mixing the silkworm, the crane blood
and the peacock bile
will get this result.
Show me the manual.
If there's a formula,
there must be a cure.
Sorry. There's no cure when we mix
these three poisons.
We must avoid using it.
i recognize my mistake...
Please give him the antidote.
We must save him!
Little sister!
Test it on her
and find out if there's a cure!
You're not hurt?
It's a good thing that I'm fast,
otherwise...
I told you to stay out of it...
What bothers me the most,
is that after my death,
you'll be alone and without family...
Fei,
I'll never let you die.
The manual says
that there's no antidote...
My master wrote it
because he didn't believe
that a doctor would
give up his own life
to save his patient.
You'll be infected too...
Don't be sad for me...
Don't feel guilty...
Go get Miss Yuen...
tell her to marry you...
I'll pray for your happiness...
In heaven...
Darling, can you tell me...
I love you...
Is it possible...
I scattered your ashes
on my parents grave.
You're part of the family.
From now on, you won't be alone.
This necklace represents
my love for you.
It will keep you company
forever.
Ling!
Help!
General, Fung took the governor
and the nun as hostages.
He threatens to kill them.
The weather is uncertain,
a storm is coming.
We'll hunt them down after the storm.
I'm the governor.
You have no right
to treat me like that!
Damn nun,
you brought me bad luck!
Eat!
How dare you bite me!
Tiyi!
Get lost, you fucking dog!
Don't come any closer
or I'll kill her!
That'll teach you!
Fei!
Don't kill him!
We can be his heirs.
Fifty-fifty!
I'm your brother,
try to make him see sense.
I must get the key to his chest.
My son, I always loved you.
Why do you always betray me?
Why did you try to take my
sword and my concubines?
Why?
Love brings sadness,
love also brings terror.
By freeing ourselves from love,
we get away from sadness and terror.
I'll pray for Miss Ching everyday,
I wish her happiness in heaven.
Tiyi.
Don't come any closer,
stay away.
Don't smile at me.
Turn around, turn around quickly!
Don't watch me go.
Count to one thousand
before turning round.
One, two, three, four,
five hundred, seven hundred,
one thousand...