DISTRIBUTED BY ART THEATRE GUILD
COPRODUCED BY
OFFICE ISODA AND ATG
"The ruler of the country,
the Chief Minister of the Government,
the priest Taira no Kiyomori
in reverse crucifixion?"
"I alone am honored
in heaven and on earth."
"ls this samsara, the eternal
cycle of suffering?"
"Oh, are this vengeful spirits?"
"You damned clan of evil spirits..."
"Disperse. "
"Disperse!"
"Scatter into hell!"
"Sink!"
I will never fall in love again
with someone from
another province.
Because it will end
with a separation in tears.
“Ruler of the country, Chief Minister of the
Government, priest Taira no Kiyomori
in reverse crucifixion?“
What is it Koheiji,
apprentice of Danjuro?
Weren't you with my husband?
Taku had the manager read his new play
and is waiting for his response.
So I left ahead.
I see...
He must be really glad
to hear that response!
Don't worry.
It will definitely be favorable!
I'm taking a bath right now,
you know.
Listen!
The sounds made by Ochika
while jumping into the bath.
Well then now...
It's about time for the princess
to get out and play.
Ochika, would you allow me to see
Kannon's figure while taking a bath?
The entrance fee for seeing the Goddess
is quite expensive you know.
How much is it?
3 Ryo?
No.
10 Ryo?
That's nothing!
1000 Ryo?
Even if you pile up 10000 Ryo,
you won't be allowed to see me.
Then What Will it be?
One kimono to my liking.
Let's seal the deal.
Ochika-san fell down, she fell
For one kimono, she fell
To see the Goddess Ochika
One kimono as offering
A beautiful bath is appreciated
My eyeballs are about to be crushed
Tears of gratitude start to fall
To fall down.
- My dear Goddess!
- Cheer!
Highly esteemed Ochika!
What's with that bamboo rake?
I won this at a tombola.
- And my husband?
- He drew an umbrella.
Ochika, you'll be sharing
that umbrella. Dammit!
Sharing an umbrella?
That doesn't sound too bad,
Danjuro's apprentice.
I may be an actor at a humble
kabuki theater right now, but...
- ..."once I achieve my ambition", right?
- Right. Once I achieve my ambition,
and become like Ichikawa Danjuro VII, the most
popular and best kabuki actor in Japan right now!
Cheer!
As a New Year's custom I'll show you
one of my magic glares!
Cheer!
- Where's Ochika?
- Ochika went to Joshuya's to buy sake.
How did it go?
Did the manager approve it?
After all the blood and sweat
shed to complete this script...
He said: "I can't put this on stage.
Your bribe ain't enough" and he returned it.
Don't mind, don't mind!
Once you achieve your ambition...
I may be a humble musician right now, but one clay
I'll be the best kabuki author of Japan.
As famous as Chikamatsu Monzaemon.
That's if I achieve my ambition...
I'm home!
Oh! Have you returned, my dear?
Dammit, there are lots of mosquitos.
Ochika, hang the mosquito net.
“The bamboo rake of prostitute Kannon“, huh?
“The umbrella of Ono no Komachi“
This reminds me of my childhood.
The "childhood" when you were elegant.
- When we were kids, huh?
- When we were kids, snot-nosed kids.
One rainy day, I took out
a new paper umbrella...
Do you remember?
I've ripped that umbrella...
After ripping the new umbrella,
Ochika's father hit you.
Kohei was beaten by my father.
Despite being beaten
again and again...
...the snot-nosed kid
didn't apologize.
"What's learned in the cradle
is carried to the grave."
"As the twig is bent,
so grows the tree."
- Once upon a time...
- ...there were three kids.
There were three kids.
- Little Ochika was the landlord's daughter.
- I was a pretty girl.
My father was
a primary school teacher.
I was the child of a traveling actor.
- The three of them lined up their desks...
- ...and practiced writing.
Kohei's writing was always sloppy.
- He was always playing pranks.
- Painting Ochika's face with ink.
- I wonder if I hit him out of anger?
- You hit, scratched and bit him!
Little Ochika was
the landlord's daughter.
Everybody hated the snot-nosed kid
and the tenement house owner's child.
- The three had grown up.
- Ochika had become a beauty.
- I fell in love with Ochika.
- Without giving in, I also fell for her.
Ochika became the bride
of a very rich man.
- She became his wife, but...
- ...she quarreled with the bridegroom...
- ...and she became a divorced woman.
- She became a divorced woman.
- She did.
I courted the divorced woman:
"Please become my wife!"
Without giving in, I courted her, too:
The divorced Ochika
became Takuro's wife.
The three childhood friends..
- The three childhood friends...
- ...cried and laughed.
- Shall we...
- ...go home or somewhere else?
...go home?
- Kohei it's about time for you to go home.
- It's difficult to leave, and I'm afraid to go home.
Even if you're afraid,
go home.
“The Love Suicide At Kiso Bridge“
“Oshige - Taro, the last journey act“
“Oshige, let's die.“
“Let's commit suicide.
Let's die.“
Why don't you go to bed already?
This is bad for your health.
What did the manager say?
Has the manager read it?
Shut up!
You did it again...
Bitch!
Don't stick your nose
into a man's work!
I want to break up.
Let's break up.
Write me a divorce letter.
Please give me a separation letter!
Get out.
Get out of my sight!
I'll go.
Bamboo, bamboo pole.
Get out, god of poverty!
The god of good fortune
came in an auspicious visit to mount this
everlasting bamboo pole as an offering.
My husband's out at
a theater meeting.
First of all, in order to finish this
while your husband is away,
the God of Fortune will come in
to take the measure.
Excuse me.
God of Fortune, why don't you set up
the bamboo pole over there?
Ochika,
please become my wife!
I really wanted to ask you this
for a long time.
No matter what,
I can't die in peace, if I give up.
Out of the blue!
My husband's away!
Go home!
Get out! Get out!
I'm fine with dying here today
biting off my tongue,
But let me say
what I want to say.
The God of Poverty carrying a bamboo
pole does nothing but complain!
That Taku, he hit and
kicked you, Ochika.
On top of that he even dragged you
around by pulling your hair.
It proves a man's true worth you know,
because it shows he truly adores his wife.
"Let's break up, let's break up!"
"Give me a divorce letter!", was that a lie?
Are you going to endure it,
even after being hit and kicked?
Be it hitting or kicking,
I'll endure everything,
since I entrusted this body to him
in both, joys and sorrows.
If he weren't around...
For example, if he were dead,
will you become my wife?
Who knows.
What if I kill him?
Do you really have
the guts for that?
I'm gonna kill him and
make you my wife.
He strips Ochika naked...
At night, when I imagine Taku
to embrace and sleep with you,
I feel like I'm going insane.
I'll take my chance.
I'll tell him:
"Give Ochika to me."
He's not the type of person
who'd let me go.
He'd rather die.
Be a man and give up,
Koheiji.
No.
No way. No way.
It seems like I'm pregnant.
It's true.
I'm a pregnant woman.
Hey Kohei!
What's with that sorry ass posture?
You're looking depressed.
- Lend me some money!
- To pay off a woman again?
Good guess.
Let's go over there and
have a drink. Almsgiver Taku.
We're home! We're back!
- The Honourable Chikamatsu Monzaemon...
- ...and the Honourable Ichikawa Danjuro...
...are home!
Where have you been so long
and what were you doing, huh?
We're going on a journey Ochika!
We'll leave tomorrow early in the morning!
- As agreed upon.
- All three of us on a pleasure trip.
At the old elementary school,
the friends lined up their desks:
- "Even the blossoming flowers..."
- "...will eventually scatter"
- "...will eventually scatter."
I'll gladly go on a pleasure journey.
No road is long
with good company.
Sake time!
It's time for some sake to celebrate!
Coward!
"Give me your wife!", have you told him that?
Hey, almsgiver Taku,
you'll lend me some money right?
If we don't bring the money tonight
I won't be able to leave.
- So, hurry up and ask Ochika.
- Money again?
I've impregnated a girl,
so I need some money to pay her off.
- Is that true my dear?
- That discussion is over, over!
It's time to celebrate our excursion!
I don't want to.
Since you've left me out of the loop.
You two should go on this journey.
I won't go!
Ochika got angry,
she got so angry
She became a demon,
she became a snake.
Koheiji made a beggar's bastard
- That's right.
- He doesn't even have one penny to offer.
Takuro made a raccoon dog child.
The raccoon dog's testicles
are huge, so huge.
Ochika laughed, she laughed
The enlightened Goddess of Mercy
is grateful.
The Goddess of Fortune
Everybody, let's act a play for fun!
A play for fun...
What play should it be?
"The Treasury of Loyal Retainers"
"Act VI - Kanpei's seppuku"
"Without making any excuses,
Kanpei will perform seppuku
to end the grief within your hearts..."
MARUYA INN
Year by year,
the sound of Negoro Temple's
ringing bell
can be heard from as far
as a mile away,
it's echoes resound
as far as two.
I don't want to give birth
to this child.
Why?
I don't want to. I won't give birth to it.
If you regret it afterwards,
it'll be too late.
I don't want it!
Because I have a frail body.
If you want to abort the child...
Hey, don't exert yourself.
- Have you seen Ochika?
- Isn't she at the inn?
No. Where did she go?
What's the matter?
Why did you conceal from me
that you were pregnant?
You're tedious.
How many times must I tell you?
I'll keep asking until you bow
and apologize.
There was nothing that could be done
about the miscarriage!
Come now, let's go.
You're vexing! Vexing!
What's wrong? Hurry up!
Not of this world is the story...
I can hear it...
- I can hear, I can hear it...
- What?
The infant's cries.
What do you think?
It's stylish, isn't it!?
I will never again fall in love...
Ta-ra-ra, Boom-de-ay!
Now...
I bring the props that we ordered
some time ago.
"Will you hit me?
Will you beat me?
Will you kill me
with your own hands?
I'm afraid that won't make me
take you as my lover. "
In all the eight-hundred-and-eight
districts of Edo,
everybody knows me for my kimono
adorned with the peony-seal
that I wear walking under the cherry
blossoms of Nakanocho Street.
I'm the youth known as
Sukeroku of Hanakawado,
but I'm also known as
Agemaki's Sukeroku!
(Pause shortly after stomp.)
Bow before this face!
Worship it!"
Congratulations!
Well then, we're finally going on tour
in two days and Ochika will join us.
I wonder if it will be under
a bad or a good luck omen.
Good luck... excellent luck.
Setting off will be okay.
- Good morning!
Wearing that...
Won't you get ready?
- At dawn, in my dream, the Grim Reaper...
- The Grim Reaper?
...was holding a fan upside down
in his right hand, looking depressed.
- Don't conjure it up. Heaven forbid.
- Therefore, I gave up on this trip.
Disperse evil spirits, disperse!
Taku, spread some salt for cleansing!
Already done. Stop this nonsense.
Just say that we quarreled!
- I won't go. Not for the life of me!
- Got it! I won't talk you into it.
Then, let's go Taku.
Everybody's waiting.
- Ochika, take care of the house.
- I will.
Have a safe trip!
- I forgot something.
- What did you forget?
On this tour, I'm gonna tell Taku:
"Give Ochika to me!"
You'd better not!
He's totally crazy about me.
It's much more than infatuation.
Trying to convince him will be
like talking to a wall.
No matter if Taku's like that,
awake or asleep, I won't leave it be.
I can't give up.
What fate is this, when in my dreams
I'm always like "Ochika, Ochika"?
Be a man and give up, Koheiji.
Listen.
If Taku were to die,
will you become my wife?
- Who knows.
- I'll take my chance and do it.
"Hurray!", "Cheers!",
is what I'd like to say,
But he'll never let me go,
until the clay he dies.
I'll do it even if it kills me.
Hey! Koheiji!
Yeah! I'm coming right now!
I'll do it even if it kills me.
Since tomorrow's a day off,
do you want to go fishing?
I hear that you can catch some big ones.
To be honest, I have a favor
that I'd like to talk to you about.
Give Ochika to me.
Give her to me.
Give her.
I planned to tell you this one day.
You must've suspected something from the
backstage rumours for a long time, right?
But it's not true,
that I'm intimate with Ochika.
I've never held her hand,
nor touched her even once.
Shamelessly asking
for another man's wife...
...is what a scumbag would do.
It's fate. Karma, you know.
I can't help it.
I feel like I'm going insane.
I beg you.
I beg you!
I can't die in peace this way.
I'll kill you
and make Ochika my wife.
Ochika did nothing wrong.
As God is my witness.
Stop it!
Bastard.
How dare you speak so shamelessly...
about another man's wife!
Die! Die!
Who is it, this late?
It's me Ochika! It's me!
ls it you, my dear?
What's with that outfit?
You look like a sewer rat!
Haven't you been with the others?
What about Kohei?
Kohei's dead. He died.
Kohei is dead?
I won't fall for this kind of trick.
I killed him! Kohei made his move,
and I killed him!
Dear, you killed Kohei?
He told me: "Give me Ochika.
Even if it kills me."
He'd kill me to make you his wife.
He was saying things like that.
While we're talking, the authorities
might make their move.
After the murder,
I disbanded the troupe.
Night and day I blindly tried to
come home, sleeping outside,
traveling at night,
even when it rained heavily.
I barely slept.
I'm a mess.
In any case, there's no escape.
Either you give yourself up,
or you kill yourself.
Right?
Koheiji was my childhood friend,
and I've just killed him.
I've thought of killing myself,
but couldn't bring myself to do it.
Whatever the final outcome may be,
being with you, I don't care if I live or die.
Whatever will be will be,
I'll give in to desperation.
I feel like my head's about to explode,
and I'm going insane.
Asleep or awake, Koheiji...
Didn't you once say: "No doubt, Koheiji's the
kind of guy, who won't die in his own bed"?
What shall I do?
You can hit or kick me,
I'll endure everything,
since I entrusted this body to you
in both joys and sorrows.
Come on now, my husband,
wash your feet
and let's discuss this quietly again.
The authorities might come.
We'll think about that when the time comes.
Haste makes waste.
Come on, Dear.
I am alive.
The 'Immortal Koheiji' won't die
until he achieves his ambition.
Thank God!
Ochika, bring some sake.
Forgive me!
Let's not dwell on past events tonight.
Let's be the three childhood friends again,
who lined up their desks
and practiced writing together.
How about acting a play for fun?
The final act of Chikamatsu Monzaemon's
famous "Love Suicides at Sonezaki."
We have all the costumes.
Ochika quickly change!
“Farewell to this world,
and to the night farewell.
We who walk the road to death,
to what should we be likened?
To the frost by the road
that leads to the graveyard“
- Taku!
- What is it Kohei?
Let me have Ochika as my wife.
Let me have her as my wife.
- Give her to me.
- Try asking Ochika!
Ochika... please become my wife.
I'll make you my wife
even if it kills me.
Hurray.
Once you achieve your ambition...
I'll call you my Ochika.
I will never again...
You bitch!
Stop it!
Run away! Let's run away!
I will never again...
...fall in love with someone...
...from another province.
Because it will end...
...with a separation in tears.
Even if you kill him...
Even if you kill him,
he won't die.
Damn obstinate guy!
In accordance with his nickname,
Living Koheiji, he'll follow us everywhere.
Shut up!
For how long will you keep grumbling?
Last night at the inn...
...the one that got into the bathtub
was definitely Koheiji.
It's just your imagination,
because you're extremely nervous.
Even in the hallway...
...he was peeking from
a pillar's shadow.
Even the strange guy in the next room,
who was heating an empty kettle...
Maybe you've gone crazy?
Shhh!
- Do you hear those footsteps, right now?
- I don't hear anything.
I can hear them.
Wasn't somebody peeking in?
They say that even a fool
needs to take a break!
Koheiji made a beggar's bastard
He doesn't even have one penny to offer.
Since this is a journey without escape...
Why don't you, gallantly and
remorsefully, surrender?
If it were me, I would've turned myself in
to the magistrate, like a man.
How dare you say such cold things!
Let's break up after all.
Even tho I've followed you this far...
I really don't like this aimless journey.
I'm sick of it.
Do you understand?
A Letter of Separation...
Divorce me.
Seeing your head displayed on a wooden pole
at the prison gate is not that far away.
It's our fate that we were both born
under an unfortunate sign.
Parting ways around here
will be best.
What should I do?
Don't leave me alone.
Help me.
You're the only one in this world
I can depend on.
Well? Surprised?
Did you think I ran away?
Since you're too sloppy,
I tried to play a trick on you.
I was quietly observing you
from the shadows.
Coward, stop being so afraid!
You've told Koheiji that you
were pregnant, didn't you?
Treating me like a cheating woman?
As you please!
Let go!
You call yourself a man?
Brute!
At dawn...
I dreamed of Koheiji.
So, what about it?
Was Kohei resenting you?
He did nothing and
was very depressed.
Is that all?
After killing my childhood friend...
I wonder why I'm traveling.
What am I living for?
Let's commit suicide.
Let's die.
Let's die!
I will never again fall in love
with someone
from another province.
Because it will end...
with a separation in tears.
Die!
TSUTAYA INN
Who's there?
Some strange guy was in the hallway.
It might have been Koheiji!
"The ghost, when examined closely,
was withered silver grass."
Get a grip, dammit!
At the village festival, I drank
and had fun with a young man.
The market is quite noisy,
as usual.
A coward, a drummer and a murderer!
So funny!
Koheiji...
Forgive me!
I can't go any further.
My leg hurts.
I'm cursed with it.
Don't mind me and go on ahead!
Regrettably, our relationship is indissoluble.
I can't leave you right now.
Taking advantage of someone's
weakness is inhuman.
This is creepy.
Human figures.
Someone's death curse.
A woman's vengeance?
Women are said to have 800 million and
3000 worms inside their bodies.
And men are the beasts,
who eat these worms, right?
Let's drive away the evil.
Let's drive away all evil by the living and
the dead from Buddha's Universe.
We will drive away the evil.
We will, we will certainly do.
It seems like we'll soon
reach Sai-no-Kawara.
I'll go ahead, so you just take your time.
Saying prayers for
the happiness of father
they heap the first tower of stones
Saying prayers for
the happiness of mother,
they heap the second tower of stones
Saying prayers for their brothers
and their sisters,
and all whom they loved at home,
they heap the third tower of stones
Such, by day,
are their pitiful diversions
But when...
But whenever the sun begins to sink
below the horizon,
the Oni, the demons of the hells, appear...
The child that you miscarried,
who's child was it? Tell me!
Are you doubting me?
Who's child was it?
If I'd say that it was Kohei's child,
what will you do?
You bitch...
Worms!
Write me a divorce letter!
Don't treat me like a fool!
After committing adultery the bitch
is putting on airs! Dammit!
I've misjudged you!
Didn't I always tell you, that it's
a shame to doubt someone?
Those who trust in others,
are pure hearted people.
Believing this, I've lived,
and followed you, until this clay.
So, you were doubting me.
You don't understand
a woman's heart.
The miscarried child,
was truly yours.
Come now...
Kill me, leave me, kill yourself or whatever,
just do exactly as you please!
You whore!
Die!
I cheated death twice.
The Grim Reaper, that bastard,
fled twice from my back.
Look, right now the Grim Reaper is
sitting on Taku's back, laughing.
Ochika laughed,
she laughed out loud
Ochika got angry
She got so angry
She became a demon,
she became a snake
Demon or a snake,
I don't care.
I'm gonna make Ochika my wife.
Koheiji, sticking your hands into other people's
pockets to steal... Are you a thief?
Sneaking up to other people to steal
someone's wife... You're a foul guy!
You wanted Ochika...
Takuro...
I kept harassing you.
I thought that, if I drive you mad,
you'll die from insanity.
Until one of us dies...
no matter how far we'll go,
this play will never end.
Ochika.
I'm gonna kill you!
Die!
Not of this world is the story of sorrow
At the roots of the Mountain Shide
The story of the Sai-no-Kawara
Not of this world is the tale;
yet 'tis most pitiful to hear.
- Infants but two or three years old,
- I will never again fall in love
- Infants of four or five,
- infants of less than ten.
- I will never again fall in love
- Children of tender age in multitude,
- ...with someone from another province.
- In the Sai-no-Kawara...
- ...are they gathered together.
- Because it will end...
- And the voice of their longing for their parents,
- ...with a separation in tears.
- ...for their mothers and their fathers.
- The voice of their cries...
END
subbed by bLoodZ @ asiatorrents
Cast:
Koheiji - Fujima Fumihiko
Ochika - Miyashita Junko
Takuro - Ishibashi Shouji
Scenario and Directing: Nakagawa Nobuo