23.976
Take Mr. Candler's horse
and lead it in the back.
Thank you. Go on in.
Are you with us then?
I, the Lord, my God...
am a jealous God...
visiting the iniquities...
of the fathers upon the children...
unto the third
and the fourth generations...
and showing mercy-
This is the final-
Hear!
Jefferson McClintock on line one.
Please, Bonny, no more calls.
I'm late enough as it is.
- Did you say "McClintock"?
- Yes.
Put him through.
Mr. McClintock. Renny Jacobson.
Yes, sir, it has been a long time.
What can I do for you?
Okay.
Yes, sir. I understand.
Yes, sir.
Right.
I appreciate you calling.
Thank you.
Sir.
Tell Mr. Barnette-
Tell Mr. Barnette there's nothing
I can do about the signatures...
on the South End
merger documents.
Seems I gotta go to Charleston
to bury my father.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I have high hopes for Mr. Jacobson.
Very high hopes.
#Amazing #
#Grace #
# How sweet #
#The sound #
#That saved #
#A wretch #
#Like me #
#I once #
# Was lost #
#But now #
#I am found #
#So blind ##
I wanna miss him, Mama A.
I know, son.
He was just so different
after your mama died- harder.
All I ever knew was hard.
Well, you know...
he told me, right before he died...
that he knew he might have
been too hard on you.
I guess he never told you.
Come on, honey.
Oh.
There we are in the quad at The Citadel.
Can you find your father?
Yup.
Shall we?
- Uh, have a seat.
- I brought my copy.
Even with the size of the estate,
it shouldn't be too complicated.
He left everything to me.
Renny, uh, what do you remember
about holographic wills?
They're handwritten,
without the legal boilerplate.
Uh, usually no witnesses.
Why?
Well, your, uh,
father added this to his file.
It's dated one month
after the will you have.
We just found it.
- How do we know this is authentic?
- He anticipated that.
This from a local psychiatrist attesting
to his mental competency.
Handwriting analysis.
It's a match.
"A II my residual estate...
"in equal shares to The Citadel...
Charleston Historical Society
and the Episcopal Parish of St. Albans."
Whoa.
He left me nothin'?
- Well, we can just tear it up.
- Renny, you're a lawyer.
You know better than that.
St. Albans Parish?
I mean, he wasn't even religious.
- Yeah, maybe that was the guilt speaking.
- Oh, please!
He's paying his way into heaven!
Well, he did say that you
were to receive his, uh...
gold coin collection and, uh-
"The right, title and interest...
"to any and all assets,
tangible and intangible...
to my share of the Covenant List
of South Carolina, Limited."
We went through the inventory of assets
and didn't find any record of this company.
- You know what it is?
- He never told me anything,
Mr. McClintock. Obviously.
Well, he, uh...
did leave you this key
to a safe-deposit box.
Number 413 at Planters
and Merchants Bank.
Oh, and one other thing here.
Do, uh- Do you recognize
any of these names?
"Desmond Larochette,
Bart Maxwell...
Thomas Layne IV,
Taylor Johnston. "
Families with long histories
in the low country.
No personal connections?
No, none that I know of.
Why?
Well, he left instructions that his obituary
was to be sent to these people.
- Well, any responses?
- No.
Was there anything else, or...
should I not even bother to ask?
Fortunately not.
I'll delay the sale of the house
for a few weeks...
so you can take out
anything you want to.
What about, uh-
What about the first edition
of To Kill a Mockingbird?
Well, you keep it.
And his boat, the Jacobson IV?
Oh, sorry.
That's a titled asset.
Tell me.
What was he worth?
How much did he not leave me?
Well, depending on the value of the securities
at the time of probate...
it was more than $22 million.
#Everybody everywhere #
#Is happy #
#Leads them up the garden path #
#So easily #
#Don't close your eyes #
#Don't look so surprised #
# You had to swallow every lie ##
Also, uh...
contact Mr. Thompson
at New Dominion.
Get a meetin' lined up sometime
in the next week to discuss escrow.
Remind him that Pat Jenkins
promised us prime plus one.
If he doesn't-
"1863."
What's this?
I expect the terms of my will
may have come as a shock.
My father's will contained
those same provisions.
Don't worry.
Your true wealth lies
in the Covenant List of South Carolina...
or, as we call it, "The List."
If anyone else is
in the room with you...
please ask them to leave.
The gold coin has been passed down
from father to son...
for 140 years...
as a symbol of the true source
of financial stability...
for our family.
Toward the end of the war, most planters
and landowners faced the loss...
of everything
their families had built.
Our family, together with
10 other plantation owners...
entered into an agreement,
a covenant, if you will.
This group smuggled gold
out of the Confederacy...
to safe havens
throughout the world.
Funds now flow
through Swiss banks.
For many years, I've had the honor
and privilege of being the keeper of the List.
On the wall next to my desk...
there is a compartment.
In the top left drawer rests a key.
That key opens the compartment
which contains the List.
By now there should be
a letter on my desk...
notifying you of the meeting that will begin
your initiation process.
Do not discuss this with anyone.
Most importantly...
there has not always been
unity among the members.
Be careful.
Preservation of the List is everything.
Carpe diem.
Rice Planter's Inn, this weekend.
Listen to me.
Listen to me!
I am holding in my hand,
as we speak...
a letter from your bank giving me
full ownership of this account.
Now you're telling me that without
this Desmond Larochette's signature...
I can't get access
to my money? Really?
Listen here.
I'm goin' out of town this weekend.
Come Monday,
you better have my money.
No. Not again.
Hi.
Thanks.
Can I help?
No. Thank you.
- Haven't I seen you before?
- Honestly, right now is really not the time.
You were at St. Albans
Cemetery, right?
I was burying my father.
So was I.
- How did you remember me?
- You were crying.
I wasn't.
One of y'all need a tow?
Yeah. I do. Hi.
Uh, shop's right around the corner, baby.
You wanna ride over with me and Harold?
I can give you a lift.
Or at least allow me to wait with you,
make sure everything's okay.
Really, it's okay.
I think I'll just chance it with Harold.
How 'bout, uh, I buy you lunch?
Hey, uh-
Y'all can call my cell, right?
- Yeah.
- How's that barbecue over there?
The best pig in the county. Tell 'em I sent you,
they'll give you extra hush puppies.
- Best pig in the whole county.
- Sugar, you sure you don't want a ride?
We'll be in plain view
the whole way.
Promise.
Renny Jacobson.
Jo Johnston.
Pleased to meet you, Jo.
#And you shiver when the cold-#
I always thank God for barbecue.
At this place,
you pray after you eat.
- Some more tea?
- Yeah. Please.
Mmm. Thank you.
- What was your father's name?
- Taylor.
Taylor Johnston.
Harold.
Ooh. Thanks. Hello.
Mm-hmm.
Okay. Yeah.
Thank you. Yeah. Okay. Bye.
Unbelievable. I'm not going to know
anything until tomorrow.
Jo, are you going to
the Rice Planter's Inn?
Jo Taylor Johnston?
Yeah.
Josiah Fletchall Jacobson.
Let's make some arrangements.
I can bring you back
for your truck.
- Have you tried to get your money?
- Money?
What money?
What did your father tell you?
Nothing.
He left when I was a baby.
I got a letter and that truck,
and you can see how that turned out.
Well...
figure over 140 years'
compound interest.
Is this legitimate?
I'm a lawyer,
and I'm keepin' an open mind.
Hmm.
I just came here to find out
more about my father.
I know too much about my father.
Which one doesn't belong?
Wow.
My mom's always been the volunteer.
She used to volunteer at the library,
and she also volunteered at the hospital...
so that kind of got me interested in medicine,
but I don't know.
School's really expensive, so right now
I'm just taking the semester off...
from nursing school
at Wake Forest.
Hmm. How do you like
the South as opposed to Michigan?
Um, well, when it's like this,
I like it a lot.
You know, it's nice
not having as much snow.
The people are friendlier,
at least when you first meet them.
What about you?
Me? Well, uh-
For me the South is many things.
It's, uh, live oaks
with long memories...
like the ones we passed
coming in here.
Azaleas in April.
Novels, for sure, by Faulkner, Percy.
Characters so real,
they remind me of my neighbors.
The sun rising over
the Ashley River...
with the mist
comin' off the water.
- And barbecue.
- Definitely the barbecue.
Wow.
Impressive, huh?
- You ready for this, Jo?
- I guess.
Good afternoon.
Your father's room, Mr. Jacobson.
Second floor,
turn right, third door on your left.
And your father's room
is across the hall.
The meeting is in there.
7:00.
Thank you.
Are you ready?
A woman!
Well, we can see that, Gus.
You must be Josiah.
You have your father's eyes.
- Desmond Larochette.
- People call me Renny.
I bet they do.
And you are?
Jo Taylor Johnston.
Jo. Ah.
Without an "E," I presume.
Mmm. Very nice to meet you.
Uh-Well, gentlemen, please...
introduce yourself to our guests.
Mr. Jacobson, Miss Johnston.
Bart Maxwell.
- Bart Maxwell.
- Renny Jacobson. Nice to meet you.
- Thomas Layne.
- Michael Flournoy.
- Nice to meet you.
- Welcome.
- Hey. I'm Gus Eicholtz.
- Hey. Renny Jacobson.
Can I get y'all a drink?
Rather, two drinks.
- Um, soda water, with lime, please.
- Yes, ma'am. You, sir?
- Chivas, rocks.
- Comin' up.
- Nervous?
- Not since the bar exam.
You should've had Gus coach you.
He seems to know the bar very well.
- Here you go.
- Oh. Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Who is that?
That's John C. Calhoun...
secretary of state under
William Henry Harrison.
Enduring symbol of the old South.
- Died in 1850.
- He looks mad.
Not half as mad as he'd look
if he died in 1865.
In these parts, when people talk about "the war,"
they mean the war between the states.
Or some of us down here call it
"the war of Northern aggression."
Oh, come on now, Harry.
Hurts no one
to let her dine with us.
What can you tell me
about my father?
He was a brilliant engineer.
Could have designed
the Golden Gate.
But every time I talked to him,
he was in a new town.
At these things, he'd stay at the bar,
kept mostly to himself-
especially about his family.
Why would he keep me a secret?
Dear heart, do you see
any other women here?
Lady and gentlemen.
Would you please
take your places for dinner?
We all have assigned seats.
Your family sits right over there, Miss Johnston.
- This is your father's chair.
- Thank you.
I was, uh, sorry to hear about your father.
Where'd it happen?
He'd just double bogeyed number 17
on the links course at Wild Dunes.
- That hole almost killed me one time, remember?
- Yeah.
Now, I'll give you the real introductions
to these people here.
Flournoy wishes he could put "count"
in front of his name.
Roget there is Desmond's shadow.
Harry nurses his grudge
against Desmond.
Seems that Desmond's great-granddaddy
shot Harry's great-granddaddy...
in the kneecap with a Derringer.
Do you like chateaubriand?
- Yes, I do.
- Good.
Weiss-
He's a bean counter from Virginia.
He looks tough, but he takes a bodyguard
with him everywhere he goes.
And Desmond, well...
he's not enjoying this evening.
He does not enjoy the controversy...
caused by Miss Johnston.
And unless he can pull
a Strom Thurmond...
he'll die without an heir.
Of course, Thomas here...
is enjoying Miss Johnston.
Absolutely.
And poor Bart Maxwell.
Getting married in two weeks.
Gonna lose his freedom.
To a Yankee, no less.
Hear. Hear.
Miss Johnston,
your presence here tonight...
presents us with quite a dilemma.
I'm sure you can appreciate that.
Now, I've spoken to Harry here...
and we believe the issue
should be discussed by all the members...
in your absence.
As for Mr. Jacobson...
why, I see no reason why he shouldn't
be part of these discussions.
Is that fair,
to put him in that position?
I have no problem
with him staying.
- Well, I do.
-  All right. Let's put it to the vote.
I shall abstain.
All those in favor of Mr. Jacobson
leaving the room...
while Miss Johnston's
status is discussed...
please raise your right hand.
Harry, Robert, Michael.
Anyone else- Jerrod.
That's four to three.
Majority rules.
They seem harmless enough.
I'm sure you'll get in.
I'm not sure I want in.
- What?
- I don't know, Renny. Come on.
It's like secret societies
and blood oaths.
These aren't little kids.
They're grown men. It feels weird.
Just play along, Jo.
Think about the money.
Please, rejoin us.
Miss Johnston...
your family...
has participated in the List
since the very beginning.
Uh, nevertheless,
there's something to be said...
for tradition.
Membership has passed
from father to son...
for nearly a century and a half.
Now, it's this-
this dedication to tradition...
that's been our strength.
The Johnston family participation
in the List...
has come to an end.
I'll go...
but first I have some questions.
I want to know more
about my father.
Uh, we don't socialize very much,
Miss Johnston.
- It's a business partnership.
- So you don't know anything.
My father left me a letter blaming
this group for the way his life turned out.
Every old Southern family
has its share of, um, lunatics...
in the back parlor...
and illegitimate children
in the shack down the road.
That's not quite what I meant,
and I think you know that.
- Well, then thank you for dinner, gentlemen.
- Miss Johnston.
- We do hope that you will use your discretion.
- Wait a minute.
- What about her money?
- Participation in the List is for members only.
Even if she's out,
shouldn't she be paid for the past?
That's her father's responsibility.
That's not ours.
Miss Johnston,
you wait here just a minute.
Years ago...
your father and I were fishing off
the Florida Keys...
and a storm wave
washed me overboard.
Your father saved my life.
Now, when you think about him...
try to remember,
that's the kind of man he was.
Thank you. Good night.
Gentlemen.
I'd like to call to order...
the 247 th meeting...
of the Covenant List
of South Carolina, Limited.
Now, I- Renny.
Will you please sit down?
Thank you.
Now at this time,
I'd like to pause...
in honor of the memory
of Benjamin Hammond...
an original signer of the list...
who died childless in 1884.
Right. Harry here-
He's our historian.
The Covenant List
of South Carolina, Limited...
was established during the war
between the states by our ancestors...
to provide for the financial security...
of their families and descendants.
Now, wherefore...
the mutual promises recited herein...
are agreed to by the undersigned-
Uh, in-by blood covenant...
and bind their descendants...
to the rule of primogeniture.
Signed Henri Larochette...
George P. Smithfield,
Alexander Weiss, Frederick Eicholtz-
- Harry. Are you finished?
- Pierre Roget-
- Good job. Good job, Harry.
- Marcus J. Johnston-
Good. Thank you, Harry.
All right, Harry. Thank you.
- Um, right.
- Good job.
Uh- Renny, would you mind?
- I have some questions too.
- There's no need. You're already in.
Would you join me?
It's just a formality.
Now...
just sign here in the space...
underneath your father's name.
Now, for millennia...
blood has represented life.
Now, your life,
along with your forefathers...
is joined to us
by an irrevocable bond.
Congratulations, son.
Welcome.
- Hear! Hear!
- Welcome.
Bravo. Bravo.
- You're one of us now.
- Gentlemen.
I'd like to propose a toast...
to Bart.
- Hear! Hear!
Thank you, everyone.
Uh, tomorrow we're reenacting
the South's defeat at Fort Anderson.
I'm sure you've seen the signs.
Everyone's invited.
Thanks. For the record,
I will be wearing gray.
- Good morning.
- Hey. Good morning, Renny.
Uh, Renny.
We need to talk.
Okay.
Not here.
At the Jamboree later today.
Good.
- So you're gettin' married?
- Yeah. Two weeks.
How'd you know she was the one?
You'll know.
So, you learn
the secret handshake yet?
Somethin' like that.
Could you, uh- Could you meet me
out front in a few minutes?
Sure.
Good morning, Renny.
Good morning.
You have not touched
the shrimp and grits.
That recipe is
from 82 Queen Street.
It is delicious.
A woman scorned.
I don't think she's the type to-
Well, we don't take any chances.
Why, look at how
her daddy deceived us.
Just make sure
she's headed home...
and that she intends on
keeping her mouth shut.
Delicious.
Okay.
- Mr. Larochette.
- Where are you going in such a hurry, huh?
Pursuing Miss Johnston?
I'll tell you this.
It's a better hobby than any of mine.
- Mr. Weiss sort of asked me to-
- Oh, that old goat.
Listen, the List has survived
for over 140 years.
She's not a threat.
You spend as much time
with her as you want.
- Thank you, sir. I intend to.
- Good.
Oh, listen.
We'll be reconvening tonight...
discussing a possible disbursement.
- Sounds good.
- Yeah.
Did you see that Corvette in the lot?
- Beautiful, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Well, it's yours.
Welcome to the List, son.
The title and a little gas money
in the envelope.
- Thank you, Mr. Larochette.
- Renny.
I know your relationship
with your daddy wasn't the best.
- He kind of had his own way.
- Yeah, he did.
I know I didn't see eye to eye
with him either.
I just want you to know
that I am here for you...
whenever you need me.
Thank you, sir.
I- I appreciate it.
- Now, you drive safely.
- I will. Thank you.
Well, looks like you got more
than a secret handshake.
Just found out my transmission's
totally shot.
Hmm.
- Best I can do.
- Thank you.
Ah, but wait.
You gave me the wrong set.
You wanna go for a ride?
My grandfather owned several miles
of beach just north of here.
He sold it in the '20s.
Dumb move, huh?
How can you own the beach?
Oh, wait.
Then again, who needs beachfront property
when you're a member of the List?
- Ah. Ha-ha.
- Ha-ha.
So what are you gonna do
with all your money anyway?
Get free. Quit the firm.
I'm tired of being
lawyer number 104 out of 104...
on that letterhead.
Then- I don't know.
I thought I might... write.
Write? Hmm.
Any ideas?
Somethin' important like, uh,
The Yankees' Guide to Southern Barbecue.
I'm almost done with my research.
Oh, okay.
Actually, I do have
an idea in mind.
I've always been fascinated with the story
about a group of 10,000 Southerners...
who pulled up and moved
to Brazil in 1867.
- Really? I never heard that.
- Most people haven't.
They, uh-They settled in the jungle
near São Paulo.
That's amazing.
Uh-And this is a true story?
Planted sugarcane.
Their descendants still live there.
- Well, what's it called?
- Americana.
Hmm.
Well, I think it's a great idea.
You should do it,
no matter what happens.
Junior year I told my father I was thinkin'
of changin' majors to English.
Hmm. What'd he say?
- He made it easy for me.
- Uh-huh.
Major in pre-law
or go on financial aid.
Hmm. Well, I think you
should write it now.
In fact, if you don't, I will.
You're not an intellectual
property lawyer, are you?
Ooh!
- Wow!
- Uh-huh!
- May I?
- Yeah.
People comb this beach for years
and never find one like that.
- So what's it worth?
- Well, nothing.
You can buy one at any beach shop
for two bucks.
Finding it yourself
is what makes it valuable.
Good answer.
Come on.
Was that a heart attack?
Fire! Fire!
You see Bart?
He's got the flag.
Fire!
Up the hill! Up the hill!
Good night, Jo. I'll, uh-
I'll see you in the morning.
- Good night.
- Renny.
Can I have a word
with you a minute?
The meeting's being postponed
till next weekend.
I presume you want to be present
to discuss the disbursement.
- Yes, sir.
- Well.
I just can't believe he's gone.
He truly was a sweet, sensitive soul.
Please.
My nanny used to read me
Bible stories every mornin'.
My favorite was
the one about Joseph.
In a jealous rage,
his brothers threw him into a pit...
tried to kill him.
But he survived.
And years later, when he was
in charge of the whole country...
they came and knelt before him...
begging for their lives.
Yeah. Power.
True power is when your enemies
beg down before you.
You must take every opportunity, son.
The world is about to be yours.
Bart's gone.
I'm glad you're here.
Hey!
Keep your voice down!
- Okay, okay. Okay.
- Keep your voice down.
Bart Maxwell-
He was with us, me and your dad.
- Have you tried to get any of your money yet?
- Yes.
- Did you get it?
- No.
- What stopped ya?
- Gettin' Mr. Larochette's permission.
Exactly.
Do you think he should have power
of veto over what's rightfully ours?
I don't know.
I just want my money.
Right.
I'll be in touch.
- Here.
- Oh. Thanks.
Hey, um, could we stop
by the family cemetery on the way out?
I just want to visit
my father's grave again...
and I don't know when
I'm gonna be back.
Sure.
- I'll meet you back here.
- Take your time.
I hope I didn't disturb you.
Beautiful, aren't they?
Made in Charleston...
patterned after larger versions
in a cathedral in France.
Pretty fancy for a small church.
- They're magnificent.
- Hmm.
- Renny Jacobson.
- Michael Harriston.
You the church historian?
Uh, some might say so.
You know, you pick up a lot by osmosis
if you stay around long enough.
You might remember my mother's family.
The Candlers.
Sure do. Good family.
- You been to the plot recently?
- Not since I was a little boy
at my grandfather's funeral.
Well, I can lead you right to it.
"Dead at 33."
Here you are.
"Amos Candler.
Though dead, he speaks."
Was he a direct ancestor?
Amos Candler?
Why, he would have been
your great-great-great grandfather.
First Candler to settle around here.
- Did the church put the flowers on the grave?
- No, I did.
Today's the anniversary
of his death.
I do a little something each year.
He was as fit for heaven as anyone
who ever set foot in the low country.
Well, I'll leave you alone.
No, I'm- I'm done.
You know much
about the Civil War?
I know a little bit.
I'm sure I probably had
some ancestors fighting in it.
- I just-
- Hmm.
- I don't know.
- Probably so.
You ever have dreams
about the Civil War?
I can't say that I have.
I do.
We were talkin' about Amos Candler.
Now, Amos, he used to sit...
at the end of the family pew...
right there behind us,
in the second row.
He's probably lookin'
over our shoulder right now.
- How's that?
- Part of the great cloud of witnesses.
That's, uh-That's unsettling.
Well, only if you got something to hide...
which, of course, all people do.
But I like to think of it as positive.
You know, more like
the- the home crowd...
cheering you on at a-
at a football game.
So, if he were here...
what would he be yelling
from the grandstand?
Given our surroundings
and your pilgrimage...
I'd say he'd probably be yellin'...
"Pray, Josiah!
Pray!"
Yeah. I don't know much about that.
Mm-hmm.
Well, supposedly...
he... often left his pew...
to go kneel and pray
at that altar right there.
You know, I should-
I should be leavin'.
Hmm.
I'll pray for your journey, son.
How'd you know my name was...
Josiah?
Hello?
Hello!
- Hey.
- Hey. Have you seen the caretaker?
Was I supposed to?
Question.
Where can we find out
more about your family?
She practically raised me.
Gave me the name Renny.
Said I pecked at my food
like a Carolina wren.
- Mama A.
- Oh!
Mmm.
- Mama A, this is Jo.
- Oh, hello, children!
- Hi.
- Mmm.
But you didn't come here for johnnycakes,
now, did you, boy?
What can you tell us
about the Jacobsons?
Sad tales.
Well, you know,
the old-time Jacobson...
the one that made it
through the war-
- J.F.
- Jeremiah.
Now, as I recall, he was a-
he was a rich planter before the war.
Very successful.
What became of him?
Got himself killed in a bar fight.
His son, Hiram, went crazy.
Locked himself up in a room.
Died from something
they used to call the apoplexy.
- A stroke.
- Mm-hmm.
Now, I knew
your father's daddy personally-
who was one unhappy man.
He was lost on his yacht
at sea, right?
Left Charleston Harbor one bright,
sunny day and never come back.
After that, only your mama
could reach your daddy.
Seemed like he was mad
at the whole wide world.
And now him.
Ah, it's just-
just a tragedy,
that whole Jacobson story.
What about my mother's side,
the Candlers?
Not so much money,
but a whole lot more happiness.
I saw the Amos Candler monument.
Hmm. Now, he was rich
before the war.
By the time it got into
your mama's generation...
all that money had done
gone with the wind.
What else do you know
about my mother's family?
Um, here.
Your mama told me
one day you'd come here...
lookin' for answers
about her family.
And I knew today was that day.
She wanted me to give you this.
How did she know
I was goin' to ask?
Dear Renny, I have said prayers for you...
that I believe will be answered
after my death.
The letter you hold in your hand
is one of them.
Son, your life has
an ordained purpose.
When you were born,
I named you Josiah.
Josiah was a king of Israel...
a righteous man who confronted
an ancient evil.
I know this may sound strange
and unusual to you...
but I believe Josiah's call
is similar to your own.
There is more to life
than we can see...
with our natural eyes...
or know with our finite minds.
My prayers for you
live on after I'm gone.
All my love, Mother.
- Hey.
Look, uh, today at the cemetery...
I saw every List member
in my family...
and they all died
really, really young, Renny.
And just-
Will you look?
And then-And then there were
all these- these baby crosses...
and they're all over the place.
I don't know, Jo, okay?
I just, uh-
But think about it.
Your father, my father, Bart Maxwell.
- Something's wrong.
- I hear you. I do.
I know you need to get back
to Winston, Salem, but...
I was hoping maybe
you'd follow me to Charlotte.
I'd really like to introduce you
to my landlady, Mrs. Stokes.
- It's fine. She reminds me of Mama A.
- Yeah.
- Hickory nuts.
- Oh, thank you.
Put 'em in hot water, boil 'em for 30 seconds
to separate the meat.
Thanks.
Now, you-you be careful, son.
Hmm.
Is it okay if Joe spends the night?
- My guest room's always available.
- Thanks, Mrs. Stokes.
Ah! Barnette's office again. Here you go.
Excuse me.
- So you were a missionary?
- Forty-five years.
- And is that your father?
- Mm-hmm.
What was he like?
He did his best.
And yours?
Absent.
Leaves a hole, doesn't it?
A big one.
You know...
years ago...
I wrote down every disappointment
on a piece of paper...
forgave each one...
and then burned them.
Now I can look at that picture...
and smile.
Hmm.
This is where she prays.
- Can you tell Jo I'll be back in a few hours?
- Sure thing.
So what do you think?
She's great, but I don't think
it really matters what I think now, does it?
I'll be back soon.
I'm sure you will.
Morning.
Jo, hey! It's Renny.
No, everything's fine.
Uh, listen.
I wonder if you wouldn't mind staying
at Mrs. Stokes's house just a couple more days.
Really? Well, that- that'd be great.
Okay, I'll, uh-
I'll see you soon.
All right, bye.
I'm worried about him.
Mm-hmm.
I've prayed for a lot
of people in that room...
but recently it's Renny
who keeps sending me back.
I don't think you and I are worried
for the same reasons.
You wanna tell me?
- Good morning, Bonny.
- Good morning, Renny.
Will you tell Barnette I got the signatures
and I'll have the memo on Monday.
- Will do.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Is he here?
Right behind you.
- Hey, Renny.
- Thomas.
Good to see you.
I'm here on behalf of Gus Eicholtz.
Let's get some air.
How ya doin', darlin'?
Gus says we can trust you
on this matter.
The Larochette family
has maintained a tight grip on the List...
and its funds for far too long.
We now believe that Desmond
and a couple of the others...
are plotting to tip the scales
even further in their favor.
I don't understand, Thomas.
The List has been going strong
since the Civil War.
Well, Taylor Johnston, a daughter.
Bart Maxwell, no son.
The power of attorney we all
sign enables the List...
to reclaim a member's money
if he dies without a male heir.
The power of attorney is invalid
once a person dies.
That's very true. Very true.
So who's telling
the Swiss bankers, hmm?
Well, who gets the money?
- Larochette.
- You're kidding.
From the beginning, that family
has been in total control.
And nobody but nobody crosses 'em.
Till now.
There's a plan in place,
and you play a big part in it.
Me?
I saw the way you stood up
for Miss Johnston the other night.
You got a lot of guts, kid.
We like that.
As it stands now,
there's eight voting members.
But before we put a rubber stamp
on Desmond's distribution plan...
I want you to call for a vote
to replace him as president.
- On what grounds?
- Well, you're an attorney. Be creative.
If Desmond tries a power play,
we'll come up with somethin'.
All we need to act on this
is a simple majority, and we'll have that.
Now, Harry and Robert, well, they'll side
with Desmond. That's no big surprise.
But the others-
well, the others are with me-
with us.
Who'll be the new president?
Well, that would be me.
And my first act as president
will be to make a motion...
for distribution of the significantly
larger sum of money...
than any of us, except for Desmond,
of course, has ever seen.
Exactly... how large?
Does 30 million each work for you?
My second act is to give that girl
what is rightfully hers.
You know, you guys...
y'all keep telling me
how great my father was.
- He was.
- Really? Really?
Well, what kind of man disinherits
his only son with no explanation whatsoever?
Can you answer me that?
I didn't think so.
And Desmond Larochette has been
the only person who has helped me so far.
I'm gonna have to think about it.
Well, I'm sure
when the time comes...
you'll make the right decision.
Something I've learned, Jo...
is that God's children and his enemies
make the same mistake-
they both underestimate
the power of prayer.
Let's keep praying.
Renny Jacobson.
Renny, I want to invite you
to come out to dinner on Friday night.
Yeah. Can you do that?
Well, you can stay here the night.
Right, no problem. Okay.
Listen, I'm gonna put you on to Frank.
He'll give you directions.
I'll see you then. All right.
Now, what have we got?
You know, I like that Jacobson boy.
- Would you like a drink, Renny?
- Brandy's fine.
Good. It's a brandy kind of room, isn't it?
Well, down the hatch.
Here's to all of us.
Mmm. Do you play?
- From time to time.
- Ah. Mm-hmm.
Desmond Larochette.
- Right there.
- Let's see.
A little castle here. Hmm.
Very good. That's good.
Interesting. All right now.
Rook takes pawn.
That would be checkmate.
Smart. That's good. Good.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
You know, Renny...
the benefits of the List are many.
A sense of belonging to history,
to a brotherhood, loyalty.
Prosperity.
Yeah.
There's more to your inheritance
than just money.
It's called power, Renny.
There's tremendous power in the List.
It's something that
your daddy knew about.
It can either be used
for good or for evil.
Come with me.
Here, come here.
Give me a hand a minute.
Now-
Yeah, nice and clean.
Now, I want you to totally
have your mind a blank.
Touch this. Now, Renny...
is there someone in your life,
someone whose heart you wanna touch?
Now just concentrate.
Picture them, Renny.
Picture them.
See their face.
Good, good, good.
Now, release the power.
Release the power and touch 'em!
Yeah!
Good. How do you feel?
- All right?
- Good.
That's enough for tonight.
- Good night, gentlemen.
- Good night. Sleep well.
Was it the girl?
I think so.
I like him.
He's a good man.
Jo?
Yeah, right. Well, let me know
as soon as escrow closes.
Right. Oh, Renny. Here.
Yeah, all right.
I'll talk to ya later. All right, bye.
Lawyers! Sit down.
Ah, coffee?
- Please.
- Ah, well...
Renny, I'm real proud of ya.
Real proud of you.
You did real well last night.
- It was exhilarating.
- Exhilarating?
- Yes, sir.
- Some milk?
- Please.
- Ah.
I think it's time
we had a money talk.
Now I've decided,
given the global economic picture...
I think maybe we should hold off
for a year or two.
What do you say?
Oh. You look disappointed.
Uh, Mr. Larochette-
Listen, son.
I'm always gonna take care of you.
I mean, there'll be tens
of millions soon enough.
Sugar?
Help her, Lord. Heal her.
Lord, please, help her.
Help her. Help her.
Heal her.
Heal her. Heal her.
Help her.
Help her, Lord, please.
Heal her.
Thomas!
- You were right.
- Of course I was.
- About what?
- No disbursement.
All right, look.
I'll do this on one condition.
I get to be custodian,
like my father, to keep the List.
- You serious?
- Of course I'm serious!
All right, done deal.
All right, look. Before Desmond speaks,
you have make the motion. All right?
- All right.
- You okay with this?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Give me a little head start.
I don't want people to see us walk in together.
Gentlemen, please.
I'd like to call to order...
the 248th meeting of the Covenant List
of South Carolina, Limited.
- I'd like to make a motion.
- So be it, Renny.
I move for the election of Thomas Layne
as president of the List.
- You are crazy!
- The boy has every right.
Is there a second?
I second.
- Discussion?
- I realize I'm a new member...
but I think there needs to be
more openness about our finances...
and a more liberal distribution
of funds.
Maintaining heavy central control
is no longer necessary, gentlemen.
This isn't 1863.
Do not make his mistake.
It's time for a change.
Look at the small number in this room.
You know it. I know it.
He knows it.
Don't be blinded by commitment
to the past.
Well, you can tell
the man's a lawyer.
Any other discussion?
No? Right.
Well, let's put it to the vote.
All those in favor of
Thomas Layne becoming president?
One.
You seconded the motion?
Just so we could vote
on it and move on.
- I'm perfectly satisfied with Desmond's leadership.
- Well-
Thomas?
Where did you come up
with this bull?
I can assure you I have never had
any aspirations for that office.
Never have, and I'd venture
to say I never will.
Oh, I see.
This was a test.
If you choose to call it that.
Now, please be quiet.
What on earth
were you thinking, son?
Now, as I was saying...
the sole purpose
of this meeting tonight is...
to discuss the distribution of monies.
Now I propose a distribution from...
the corpus of the List
to our individual accounts-
excluding Renny here-
to the sum of $30 million.
That's 30 million each, gentlemen.
As for Jacobson here...
I move that we delay
any payment of monies to him...
for a probationary period
of, say, 24 months.
No- 36 months.
I second.
Hmm.
Three missed calls.
I ever tell you the story behind this picture?
This is Vusi-Vusi Lakota.
It was taken just outside of Cape Town.
One day someone says
there's a deadly black mamba in the bush...
and that everyone must get inside.
Panic. But not Vusi.
He just calmly grabbed a shovel...
headed straight into the bush.
Thirty minutes later, he came
out holding the dead mamba.
That's when we took the picture.
That night...
I asked him why he did it.
And he just said,
"When you know evil exists...
you must fight it."
The ledger.
Welcome back.
Well, nice to see you again, Renny.
Oh, thank you.
I was just looking for that. Thank you.
Gentlemen, would you mind
giving us a minute?
All right. Well, come with me.
You cannot seize power, Renny.
You have to be groomed for it.
I didn't come here to steal it.
- What did you do to her?
- Me?
No. You did it.
That's all right.
We can fix it because
you are the key, Renny.
How am I the key?
There were 12 invitations...
to the first meeting in 1863.
Only one of the 12-
a Judas-
decided to go his own way.
What does that have
to do with Jo? Or me?
Amos Candler.
He foolishly then walked away.
Your mother's family
then faced financial ruin.
But you- a Candler and a Jacobson-
you complete the List.
Now you've felt the power, right?
How did you describe it?
Oh, yeah. Exhilarating.
It is written,
"A cord of three strands...
cannot easily be broken."
Larochette, Candler, Jacobson.
I can be the father that you so long for.
What about Jo?
Come on! That's no problem.
No, she can be fine.
That can be part of
our pilgrimage together.
- How?
- Unity.
It's time for the Candler
and the Jacobson blood to join.
And it's time for you
to stand up and be a man!
It's time for you
to make your mark!
And unlike your daddy,
I will be here for you.
All right.
All right. No way.
I'm out! It's over.
You better think
about our future, boy.
Trust me, I have.
Someone with your potential...
doesn't come along
but once in the generations.
But let me tell you this.
Before this is over,
you're gonna be beggin' for mercy.
Call the police.
We have an intruder.
Jacobson, your lawyer's here.
A.L. Jenkins.
You can thank Mama A
for bringing me down here.
That doesn't mean I'm staying.
You got four charges facing you.
Criminal trespass,
possession of burglary tools...
criminal damage to property
and attempted burglary.
That last one's a felony.
And, uh...
your law firm just called
the desk sergeant.
You're fired.
You got one hour.
Oh, Father...
God, you got to do something
about Renny now.
I can't help him no more.
I can't.
You see the trouble he in.
His mommy and daddy
leave me to care for him.
But he needs you, Jesus.
I can't help him no more.
He in this mess
as he is in trouble...
but, Lord, he just need
to know you, Jesus.
Help him, Lord.
Help my Renny.
Help my baby boy.
Oh, Lord.
Save his soul.
Is that it?
Yeah.
You got any evidence?
No.
I mean, uh, nothing except three dead,
a woman in the hospital...
and me stuck here
about to lose everything.
What do you want, son?
What do I want?
Well, let's see.
I want the money.
I want the girl.
And I want no criminal record.
Okay. No problem.
Let's just call Desmond Larochette.
I'm sure he'll be willing to drop
the charges and take you under his wing.
What do you really want?
I want Jo to be okay.
I want no jail time.
And I would just like...
to start over.
Now, that's better.
We've got problems legal and spiritual,
but we can handle both.
First, let's just face Judge Austin.
Let's post bail.
Great.
Larochette.
Who's there?
Who are you?
What do you want?
Renny!
Oh, shoot. Renny.
What is this, Lord? Victory?
What do I need to do?
My strength is almost gone.
"For I am poured out
like a drink offering...
"and the time
for my departure has come.
"I have fought the good fight.
"I have finished the race.
I have kept the faith."
Do you understand that with
a guilty plea to these charges...
you'll never practice law again?
Yes, Your Honor, I understand.
Mr. Jacobson,
you are hereby sentenced...
to three years confinement
in the South Carolina State Penitentiary.
Said sentence to be served on probation.
I further order you
not to go on or about...
the person or the property
of Desmond Larochette.
I hope you get
your life together, son.
Court adjourned.
Well, that's one of your problems solved.
Disbarment?"
But no jail time.
Let's walk outta here.
Robert, inform the members...
that there'll be a special
meeting tomorrow night!
So how do we handle Gus?
Something unique would be nice.
I called the hospital.
She's still hanging on.
I'm surprised
she's not dead.
Ah.
The others submitted
to the power of the List.
But don't worry.
I've seen the end
right from the beginning.
I call that my wall of faith.
Look at their eyes.
Before God got hold of them...
and after.
All those people
had one thing in common-
they thought they were 1,000 miles
from the promised land.
Truth is, they was
just one step away.
Amen.
"The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want."
Heal her.
"He maketh me to lie down in green pastures"-
"And leadeth me beside the still waters."
Heal her.
"He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me in the path of righteousness
for his namesake. " Surrender.
"Yea, though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil"-
Surrender. Strength. "For thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me.
"He preparest a table before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
"Thou anointest my head with oil.
My cup overflows.
"Surely goodness and mercy
shall follow me all the days of my life.
And I will dwell in the house
of the Lord forever. "
Yes! Yes,
I, the Lord thy God...
am a jealous God...
visiting the iniquities
of the fathers upon the children...
unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me...
and showing mercy...
unto the thousands of them
that love me...
and keep my commandments.
This is what the Lord said.
I've got something to say.
I kept asking myself, "Why?"
Why did my father
leave me nothin'?
Why did you trick me?
And why did all this
have to happen?
And then I realized...
you're all blind.
My father. You, Larochette.
Even you, Gus.
You're all blinded by this.
You're nothing but a bunch
of selfish, greedy old men.
And I don't want any part of it.
Whatever has happened
in the past...
whatever will happen
from this point forward...
your power over me,
over my family...
over the people I love,
ends now!
He signed in blood.
I own him.
Rower? I'll show you power.
Blessing.
Bless-
- What's this?
- It's Daisy's holographic will.
- Her what?
- It's a will in her own handwriting.
She wrote it four days ago.
Perfectly legal.
Believe me, I should know.
Renny, she gave you the house.
She gave me a lot more than that.
They all did.
So why weren't you?
Why wasn't I what?
Crying.
Well, why were you?
My entire life
I've been looking for my father.
So, when we buried him,
that was it. You know?
I'd never know him.
But... here, with Mrs. Stokes...
I think I found what it is
I'm looking for.
Thank you.
Isn't it gorgeous?
Yes, it is.
This place kind of reminds me of Lake Moultrie
in Charleston where I grew up.
I was... five years old, I guess...
the first time my parents
brought me there.
It's where my father
taught me to swim.
I was horrible at it too.
I mean, I'd struggle
in the water, flailing my arms...
trying anything
I could just to stay afloat.
My mother,
she'd stand on the bank...
lookin' down.
She'd just pray.
Jo.
There is something I've learned, Jo.
God's children and his enemies...
both make the same mistake-
they both underestimate
the power of prayer.
Let's keep praying.