Subtitles by Nostromo
BOAC announces arrival
at terminal 5E.
705, from Sydney,
Darwin, Jakarta, Singapore
Calcutta, Karachi,
Cairo and Rome
All customers with
passport examination...
there will be transport
available...
direct to London terminal.
Thank you
I have no passport.
I see
I expect you'd like to see
the airport's code(?)officer
Yes, thank you and
I know the way
Hello, Mac.
Good Morning, Sir. I'll tell
Mr. Chubb that you're here.
Good.
Mr. Somers is here,Sir.
Yes,Sir
Yes ,yes
- He'll see you now,Sir
- Thank you, Mac.
You managed to get out ?
Only just
So I heard
You used the emergency route, why?
I had too,the frontier was blocked,...
besides I had a bit of trouble
And?
No, I've got a rib strap up
but it will be all right
Same old room,
nothing changes.
But people do
They get old you know
Of course there are some
jobs where it doesn't matter
My job,for instance
Not mine.
How was I to know that Mark Bamm
was going to change his mind halfway?
There was a time when you'd sensed it
And brought Bamm safely back.
Anyway I got Mark Bamm in the end
You were responsible from then
I know I was.I'm very sorry.
Let's see, you
joined us in 1939
In 1940, parachuted into Bavaria.
Captured by the Gestapo, interrogated.
He escaped with Professor Jacob Werner
Yes, 1942, Paris.liaison Darrieux.
Returned Germany
and escaped with Professor
Karl Cesare and wife
From 44 to 45 in charge of contra espionage
UK Northern Area
Headquarters,Liverpool
Hamburg, details
of mine defences.
Yes.
Yes,quite a good record...
...until now.
Aren't I allowed one mistake?
No
I see
What happens now?
The way you came in...
You are not a regular.You'd had
to go sooner or later anyway.
I used to be a newspaper man once.
Do you think there'd be any future in the
real life story of the secret service?
I should think of a very short
future, Major Somers.
Very short.
You got a little money,haven't you?
Well, then forget all this
go back to real life again.
Real?
And how do I start?
Well,to begin with stop carrying a gun
You're going to miss me, you know.
I am one of the
best men you got
Had is the operative word,old boy.
You ought to start something
think about a jump for yourself
Something quiet, in the country.
I might be able to help you
So that you can keep tabs on me
Something like that,yeah
There will be decoration for you,
of course,you wouldn't mind that
What for,missing van?
No,for the time you didn't miss
Oh, very touching.
Down right sad
Good bye, Sir.
Good bye, David.
And thanks.
Get Mr.Shepley.
Hello, Shepley.Remember what
I told you about Somers?
He just left.
- Same for me.
- Thank you.
Oh, my dear fellow
Back, again?
Marvellous life.
Always fancy myself
as a newspaper man
If only didn't get so tiled
What do you do for a living,Willy?
Nothing, old boy.They never
found anything to suit me.
Pity
That's what my old man's thinks
- How's the pen pushing?
- Rotten,I'm looking for a job.
Terrible life, isn't it?
Cheers.
So apart from your languages and
this newspaper work that you did once
You have no qualifications
at all, Major Somers.
Mr. Somers.
So,sorry,some officers like to retain the
Yes,yes I know
Well, we must see what we have for you
I suppose you haven't
working knowledge
of commercial Portuguese?
No,I'm afraid I haven't
Well, there's is one here.
I don't miss recommend it, I
just mentioned in passing.
Why is it dangerous?
Oh,not at all, not exactly.
I think I should tell you we
had greatest difficulties
in even getting people to consider it
What is the job?
Cataloguing butterflies.
Do I have to know anything about them?
Well,no
The only mentioned(?) qualifications
seems to be..
... a sound general education
and an amiable disposition.
-You appear to have both if I may say so
-Thank you
But I think I must point
out that, in our opinion,...
... there is very little future in it
Butterflies.
Well, I could think about it,I suppose
Yes, I'm afraid that's
what they all say
- Hello,Willy, have a drink?
- Hello old boy,thanks.
-How's the job hunting?
-Fine,all fixed up,I'm celebrating
-What will you have-Scotch?
-Two whiskeys please
Hello Chubb? Shepley here
He is fixed up.
Yes, all OK
Nice quiet family,nice quiet place.
Cataloguing butterflies.
I'm looking for a house
called White Lodge.
Yes,I know
- Do you know it?
- Yeah, I know it.
Do you mind telling
me how to get there?
I'll do better that that
I'll show you.
I'm going there myself.
That's jolly decent of you.
-Do you know the Fentons?
- No,and you?
Yes, in a manner of speaking
-What manner would that be?
-You'd better ask the Fentons.
Everyone knows me around here
That'll be your personality, of course.
Are you the chap that's come and help
with the butterflies?
That's right
Nice part of the country this
If you stick to the butterflies.
Codius Croceus
Clouded yellow
Where's Sophie?
Oh Jess, the light, you're
blocking the light
Nicholas, do stop for a minute
and listen to me.
I always listen to you, my dear.
I can do almost anything and at
the same time and still listen to you.
Nicholas, I'm serious.
Jess, let's have peace.
Where's Sophie?
Over in the far meadow trying
to find clouded yellows.
Why?
Well, this man who is coming,this Somers
He must be warned about her.
I'm afraid,my dear,that's
a little unnecessary.
What should he be warned about?
After all he's just a young man who's
coming to stay with us and do a little work
You know Sophie just as well as I do.
But I really don't see what could happen
A local young man I can deal with
.
but this is something quite different
Somebody here living in the house
Oh,no don't let's start
of imagining things.
I don't like a stranger here
talking to Sophie...
asking her questions.
You'd no business to arrange
it without consulting me.
Well, I'm sorry,my dear but it's done now.
I'm David Somers.
Makes a nice change to come
round to the front door
I've brought you a couple of rabbits
for you, Mrs.Fenton.
-Take them around to the back, will you
-Anything you say,Mrs Fenton
-How do you do
I'm so pleased to meet you.
I think my husband is here
Nicholas, this is Mr. Somers.
- How do you,Sir
- How are you
I see you've done making friends already
Hick is quite well known
round here,isn't he dear?
-I'll tell Addie to bring your bags
-Thank you.
- I'll show you where to put the car.
- Thank you,Sir
Come in.
Hello sir.
Our Addie has brought
up your bags,I see
Please go on.
Usually she has to be told
things twice..
You must have made an impression on her
BTW there is a bigger room at the
back of the house,if you prefer it
This is the one that has
a view of the garden.
This is perfect, thank you,Sir
Good,well, I hope you'll be comfortable.
I'm sure I shall
If you don't mind my saying
so you hardly seem to be
the sort of man that.
- Want to catalogue butterflies?
- Well yes.
Of course you made it quite clear in
your letter that you were not interested
in the butterflies as such ..
but I can't help wondering
what attracted you to the job
Your references were
really excellent.
They did make it clear to you it was only
temporary,did they?
Oh yes,they did,Sir
It's simply that I got rather tired
of people and cities...
Well, the thought of two three
months doing something quiet...
peaceful in the country seemed
to me just what I wanted
Yes I understand.
A convalescence of the mind
peace
That's what we all strive for,don't we?
I well understand
-I hope you'll be happy.
-Thank you sir.
We are very quiet here there is
just my wife and myself
... and my wife's niece.
I feel perhaps I ought to
tell you something about Sophie.
Your wife's niece?
Yes,we're her guardians
She has not had a very happy
life and may find her a
... a little strange
in certain respects.
Well I thought I just tell you that...
She is a sweet child but
she is very highly strung.
She isn't always quite reasonable
in the things she says.
Jess,my wife,understands her
Please don't think too much about it,
but I thought I let you know
I'll remember,Sir
Well.,that's that
Tea will be a little late today.
My wife always go down to
Tapgrove on Tuesdays and Fridays
... so it will be five o'clock
instead of half past four
Well, I'll leave you to it.
If there is anything you want
you will ring ,won't you?
Yes thank you
I can't promise that Addie
will answer the bell.
... But it's always worth trying.
-Five o'clock downstairs,I'll see you then
- Fine thank you,Sir
I'm sorry.I'm very sorry,
I thought you'd gone down to the village.
I don't
Who are you?
My name is Somers.
David Somers.
Are you the one is going to do
the butterflies for Nicholas?
That's right
You must be Mrs. Fenton's niece
Yes.
How do you do
You play very well, Miss Sophie.
Do I?
Jess hates me to play
I thought you were
Jess when you came in.
I see
Are you a doctor?
No, I'm not a doctor.
And you haven't come here to explain
to me that I get things muddled and wrong
No, I came to help
with the butterflies.
That's what Jess said.
But it's true.
There was a doctor who
came here once before
Yes.
- You think I'm very foolish,don't you?
-Oh,no, I don't
They asked me down to tea...
can you tell me where
they have it?
On the terrace.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I disturbed your playing
Jess is back, so I couldn't go on anyway
What a pity.
Mr. Somers...
You won't tell Jess what
I said to you, will you?
No, I won't
Good Morning Sir
-Good Morning Addie
-Good Morning
Here is the list of my collection,you
see how it goes,it's in alphabetical order
It tallies with the butterflies
in these trays
And with those over there
And here are the reference books
I'll just muddle through this morning
That's right see how you get on
and BTW when you push these
trays in again will you do it very gently?
If they jar too much it
harms the specimens
I'll be careful
Good
And if you want me I shall be
just outside in the garden
Right,Sir,thank you
I told you not to come to
this part of the house.
I don't mind which part
of the house I come to.
Why can't I still come to you?
Because I like it better here.
I like the view
Get out of here before
I call my husband.
You should have called
him a long time ago...
... if you were to call him at all
Jim, sorry, I didn't mean to say that.
I didn't really,please.
Please.
Got any honey to spare?
What are you doing here?
Do not be so high and mighty
Why do not you relax a bit?
Don't you like me?
All the other girls do
You have no right to be here.
Go away.
That's not very friendly.
Give me my comb.
Say please.
Please.
No,not friendly enough.
Well, I can't get any honey
and I can't get friendly so
... I'll keep this.
Hick!
Something matter?
He's taken my comb.
Is he a friend of yours,too?
I don't know.
He does stupid things.
What's Hick been up to?
Nothing
Well, I'll get back to my butterflies.
I should avoid Hick if I were you child
I do.
How long is Mr. Somers going to stay here?
A month or two.
I like him.
I shouldn't say so
Not to your aunt.
Well,I wouldn't,not to Jess
I must get another comb.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I forgot.
Forgot? You do it purposely.
- No I don't
- Don't you lie to me.
Mr. Somers,I didn't
see you standing there
I'm really very sorry.
Sophie,please go
I expect you think I'm
very unkind to Sophie.
Well,it's none of my business, Mrs.
Fenton.
But you must be
thinking it.
That was her father's
music she was playing.
Her father?
It was George Malraux, the composer.
Malraux?
Didn't he shoot himself and his wife?
She was my sister.
The marriage was hopeless from the start
But why the suicide?
He was unbalanced.
He needed someone strong
who could understand him.
Sophie was only six
when it happened.
It was dreadful
You see, she found them.
When Nicholas and I arrived...
She was kneeling by her
mother, she bent over her...
... and it was blood in her hair
How dreadful
Mr. Somers, I have to tell you this
Sophie is like her father...
... and it is very bad for her
to be reminded of the past.
We have to watch her.She
get things twisted and wrong
It can be dangerous.
She's right,I do get things muddled
We've all get muddled sometimes
Good Morning.
I was happy to see you Sophie
Why?
I have an apology to make to you.
You mean about last night?
- It was not your fault.
- No
You once told me that your Aunt
would not let you play the piano...
... and I didn't believe you
I'm sorry.
You are very kind,Mr Somers
No, it's not that
It's just that I suddenly
realized how very lonely you must be.
You never go out and nobody
ever comes here.
Except Hick.
Yes,but you haven't really
got any friends,have you?
No
Or relatives apart from Mr. and Mrs.
Fenton?
When you always been alone,
you get used to it
Oh,is that quite true?
No,it isn't.
It's nearly true.
You wouldn't know
I know what it is like to be alone.
And I know what
despair can feel like too
Do you ?
Even the sun looks Gray.
And self pity is such a dreary thing
you despise yourself and wonders if
it matters if you go on living or not
Yes I know.
Sophie, would you let me help you?
Help me?
Now I've got you.
No, I can shut you out
Sophie!
Sophie,where are you?
It's your move
Sophie!
That's the idea.
Yes,you're really doing a very good job.
Far more quickly than I could
It's a practical mind.
I started a catalogue three times...
... but always when I come
to one of my old favourites...
I stopped and think how I caught it.
Yeah, I know and then you're lost.
How well you understand
You have become a quite
stabilizing influence...
... during the weeks
you've been here.
I shall be very sorry
when you have to leave us.
I shall be very sorry too,Sir,
I've been very happy here.
I'm glad
Got it
Silver-washed, see them all over the place.
All right, fly away.
Don't you ever get tired of butterflies?
I get tired of people first
Well of course.
But I've only had three weeks
with the butterflies.
What do you do when you
get tired of people?
You can't stick pins
through their middles
I think sometimes I'd like to
Yes, I know that feeling.
What was that?
What?
I thought I heard something cry out.
Yes,there it is again.
Why did you do that?
It was caught in one of
these beastly spring traps
... its legs were broken.
Poor little thing
I hate traps.
What do you think you're playing at?
What are you doing
with that rabbit?
How many of those traps have you got?
About a dozen.
Are you happy with that sort?
I bought them cheap.
Any objections?
I give five pounds for the lot
Well, that suits me fine
And I'll take delivery now
I can't bring them now,
I'm meeting someone
- I said now.
-You'd better get them,Hick
Five pounds is certainly
better than any girl.
Maybe you got something there
I'll bring them round
Hick...
... could I have my comb?
I'll throw it in with the traps
He spoiled it.
I do not want it anymore.
Nice chap
He's one of the people I like to throw away
I'd stick to butterflies if I were you
- You see?
-Well, he brought her back
-That's bad for her.
-Nonsense
There you are, Sophie.
Any luck?
No, only silver-washed
I told Hick not to come here.
I have some work to do.
I'm afraid it's my fault, Mrs Fenton
I've just bought some
rabbit traps from Hick
Oh,right
He's sorry for the rabbits.
What are you doing
with my knife?
I'll give it back to you later on.
I'll go and collect the traps
Mind you only give him five pounds.
I will.
- Mr. Somers.
- Yes.
He'll try make you give him
more,I know Hick.
So do I
More tea,Sophie?
But I hadn't had any...
You really must remember
what you do, Sophie.
You really must
I better go upstairs and change.
There is no one to impress here.
Have you been with Mr
Somers all the afternoon?
Yes,he likes being with me.
That's because he's kind
You mustn't take advantage of it, Sophie.
- It's nice to have a friend.
-But not for you,it's not safe.
Your father loved your mother,
and you are very like him.
I don't mind
I want to be like him.
Oh, Mrs. Fenton.
Hick asked me to give you this.
He said it was his bill
Oh! Thank you.Thank you Mr. Somers.
Mr. Fenton, Mr. Fenton!
What's it, Addie?
- It's Hick,he's dead.
- What?
Down by the stables.
There's a knife in his
back,it's horrible
I saw him lying there,I saw the knife.
who could have done it?
You must have been seeing things.
Somers,go with her,like
a good fellow,will you
Let's see what this is all about.
I'll put on a coat
He's dead all right
You'd better send for the
police, Somers.
Yes,Sir
Come back into the house,Jess.
I'm all right, Nicholas.
Sure we'll have to remember where
we were when he was killed.
You, I, Addie, Somers.
Sophie.
She'll have to remember too.
All right, Mr. Somers,thank you very much.
Perhaps,you'd be good enough
to send Ms Malraux in now?
Very well, Inspector.
Yes, Mr. Somers?
I know this is none of
my business, Inspector.
... but the girl is likely
to be a bit nervous
I wouldn't get too much
by appearances,that's all
That's all right, Mr. Somers.
It'll just be the facts that count
Right,I'll get her
Yes,I'd like to know something more
about Mr. Somers.
I bet he's talked to the girl already
this morning,so it can't be helped
You know these people,Stuart, what
do you think of Mrs.Fenton's evidence?
I think she's trying
to protect the girl,Sir
You noticed
She didn't really want to tell us
about seeing her go out
in the middle of the night.
I think she's too honest not to
Yes, and she tried to hide the girl's coat.
It's beginning to look like an
open and shut case all right
Sit down, Miss Malraux.
I just like to ask
you a few questions.
That is if you are prepared
to answer them of course
I don't know anything.
Last night..
... did you go out at all?
Out?
Yes,Miss Malraux, out
Out of this house.
Yes, I think I did.
Aren't you sure?
Yes, I did go out
What time would that be?
I don't know, in the night.
- Where did you go to?
- To the wood, by the church meadow
And why did you do that?
Was it to meet someone?
No
-You knew this man,Hick,didn't you?
-Yes, I knew him.
- Did you like him?
-No, I didn't
But I didn't kill him.
Was it to meet Hick
that you went out to the wood
at three o'clock this morning?
-No,it was to get my comb
- Your comb?
I left it at the edge of the wood
Hick had spoiled it so I left it there.
And so in the middle of the
night you put on your coat...
and went to get a comb you'd
left in the wood. Is that it?
Yes.
-Will you show me the comb,Miss Malraux
-I haven't got it,I couldn't find it
-Had Hick taken it again?
- No
I get things muddled, I get
things wrong way around
You're like Jess trying to confuse me.
We're not trying to confuse
you,Miss Malraux.
We only want the facts.
Bur I was angry because
he took my comb.
Yeah, well, we are back to
the comb again,Miss Malraux
This comb that you went out to look for
this morning and couldn't find,...
... what exactly was it like?
I brought it from France,
it belonged to my mother
Yes, Miss Malraux, but what was it like?
Was it like that for instance?
Yes, it was.
That's my knife.
That belonged to my mother too.
I see, Miss Malraux.
That'll be all for now,
thank you very much.
I'll have to ask you not
to leave the house,if you don't mind
I'll think we should be wanting you for
questioning a little later on.
They want to see you again, Jess.
Well child?
Sophie
What happened?
They think I killed him
just because of my comb.
Where did you get it?
You told me that you could
not find it last night
But I found it,it was in the
wood where you dropped it
I couldn't find it,not in the dark.
I had no no light with me
You see, I think I didn't think
It was because of a
nightmare I have.
Are you sure?
I think so.
Well, this's one thing the
police won't find.
They've got your coat.
How did the blood get on it?
What blood? I haven't seen my
coat they took it away
There is a blood stain on it
They found it because Jess tried to hide it
Did Jess try to hide it?
- I remember, she came and took it away
- When?
This morning,after the police came, she
said it had to be cleaned.
David, I'm so frightened.
-You will help me,won't you?
- Yes, of course I will.
But what you really need is a lawyer.
I know the very man.We drive
up to London this afternoon
I can't, the police said I
wasn't to leave the house.
Oh they did,did they
We'll that settles that
Never mind,you listen to me, I'll tell
you what we're going to do.
What's the matter,why
aren't you ready?
I'm not going,David
Do you want to stay
here and get yourself arrested?
I mustn't run away.
Sofie,if things were different,
you'd be right
But not know don't you realize
how strong the case is against you?
I did not kill him.
I know,bur someone trying to
make it look as if you did
- and they are succeeding.
- But who?
Your aunt,perhaps.
Jess would not do that to me.
Besides she was trying to hide the coat.
They found it just the same.
David, perhaps I did kill him and
I can't even remember
Of course you didn't kill
him,you couldn't kill him.
So who did ?
I'm not certain
But one thing I know
As long as you're free the
real killer won't feel safe.
Something more has to happen...
... and it is then the killer
make mistakes.
You mustn't help me they'll blame you too.
There is no crime in taking
someone to see a lawyer
Besides, I hate traps, and I'm
getting you out of this one
I've done a bit before for
people I didn't even know.
So I can do it for
... for someone I love.
And don't you argue anymore
Go back to your room and
get your things ready,quickly
Had you had enough breakfast?
Good,I'll think I'll get along now
Aren't I going with you?
No, Sophie, better
I see Chubb alone first
Really, it's better that way.
Have you any money?
Good,now then, where shall we meet?
Do you know the Holborn underground?
No, but I'll can find it
Fine
Go to the Holborn underground and wait
on the King's Cross platform
... until I come, I'll get there by
by ten-thirty.
All right?
Holborn Underground, King's
Cross Platform.
- Good. Bye now
Well, I expected you before this.
I missed my breakfast.
What do you mean?
You've been staying with
Nicholas Fenton...
... at White Lodge,
Tapgrove, Hampshire.
So you did keep tabs on me
I thought Willy was too good to be true.
Do you know Fenton?
No
Do you know his wife?
And I don't know her niece.
The girl who is wanted for murder
What is this, Somers?
What makes you think she did it?
The knife, the coat, the cock
and bull story about the comb..
... the nature of the girl
The aunt been expecting it, blames
herself for letting it happen.
What are you doing in all this, Somers?
She had the opportunity too,
you forget that,Chubb.
She is on her head, she won't
hang, they'll shut her up.
But what has that got
to do with you anywhere
Where did you leave her?
Corner House, Piccadilly
Do you mind if I go myself?
As you like,the police
will be with you there
They have been waiting
for you since crack of dawn.
Yeah
Catch
It's yours.
It works now.
There she is, overt there in the corner.
You coming over?
No, I'd rather wait outside.
Excuse me Miss.
Hello boys.
Come on.
Excuse me,Miss
They were ahead of us.
- The police?
- Yes.
There's a warrant out for your arrest .
-I should have to go
-No, Sophie.
There is too much against you.
We got to get away
- We're going north.
- How?
By boat.
Thank you.
Where are we going?
Newcastle.
Where do go when we get to Newcastle?
China, South America,
you choose.
We can't go abroad just like that
You have to have passports and
tickets and things don't you?
I've got friends.
You'd be surprised at
the chums I pick up you know
People will help us?
Yes,people have helped me before.
There are some clothes in there for you,
I bought them in Oxford Street.
I hope they fit
You'd better change into them,
there maybe a police description out.
Won't the police be checking
people getting off the boats?
No,they'll be watching
those leaving the country
... not those coming in.
The trouble is Superintendent, you
can never tell with these chaps
They are trained to look at
one thing and think another.
Any idea where he might make for,Sir?
Might be anywhere.
Remember that chap has
got contacts all over the place
Our men have a free rein, we
don't ask questions.
Yes,they have some pretty funny
friends one way or another
Yes,I'm afraid you will have
your work cut out to find him
If he lasts that long. He has that
girl with him, remember.
I'll tell you what.
I'll lend you someone who knows
the ropes,if you like.Another agent.
It's very good of you,Sir
No, it isn't,I'm being good to myself
I don't want this department in the news.
Scotland Yard has now
has now been called in
for the enquiry into the murder
at White Lodge,Tapgrove,Hampshire.
The police of five counties are now
looking for a man and a girl.
Who,it is thought,may
be help with the enquiries
We haven't got a chance,have we?
Of course we have,don't
you worry,we'll get away
You shouldn't be helping me,
they'll blame you too
Sofie,I don't like traps.
Traps of any kind.
Besides, you didn't kill him.
Then who did?
I don't know,but we are
getting time to find out.
If you can the girl at the
same time,so much the better...
... but Somers is our job.Bring him in.
I see
He knows half the secrets
of this department.
He had 18 months on counter-espionage
at the end of the war...
... and knows more ways in and out
of this country than a carrier-pigeon
It might be nice reading for
the Sunday papers,wouldn't it?
Yes very
This is his history ever since I known him
The answer may be there.
With his experience in the north,
I'd say he'd make for Newcastle.
This is Newcastle.
Passengers from the London train
travelling to Edinburgh...
... should move over to
platform 8.
Fares, please.
Fares,please
Two for Jesmond, please
Thank you.
Get in,Mr. Somers, and the lady
No arguments,get in
Minna,he's here.
Minna
Dear Minna.
I didn't know.
I must be grateful to be here at all.
I'm very happy you came to us.
It was the last thing
I intended to do.
I'm afraid Karl persuaded me.
Karl was right.
Now perhaps we can
pay a little of our debts
You see,I dare not come back
to Minna without you
I'm Minna...
... and this is my husband, Karl.
We're friends of Mr. Somers.
And we want to be your friends.
We want to help you.
It's good to have friends.
Professor Werner.
Paul Duclas.
Max Reiner.
And Karl and Minna Cesare
Yes, Cesare
No, just their latest addresses.
And check them on the trains
to Newcastle,there's a pal
Yes, I'll be here.
Sir.
Good afternoon.
- I want..
-Won't you sit down?
I'll take Pongo.
I give them all names
because they are so many.
Yes of course.
A gentleman has asked me to
call for the red fox.
Is the fox male or female?
The fox is female.
Will it remain with your
friends on this voyage?
Yes, that's the idea.
I'm told that there is
a good market in Mexico City.
Mexico City?
Right, I'll tell my
friend what you say.
Now then, when may I
call for the fox?
My daughter will bring
it to you tonight.
Kyra.
- Kyra is my daughter's name
- Yes Dad?
-Hello!
- Yes...
We've met before.
She will meet you down at the old
steps near Surtees' house.
Good,eleven o'clock?
She will be punctual.
The price of the animal
will be 150 pounds.
Yeah,yeah, it's ridiculous.
Inclusive.
You look very
tired, my friend...
You should take a holiday
Me?
Holiday costs money.
Would a hundred pounds give you
a pleasant weekend at the seaside?
There
Perhaps 125?
I will give it to you.
With your experience, it should be easy.
Yes.
Karl.
It might be easy but it will be expensive.
We grouse this out,we thought
you might need it.
Minna, I knew you would do this,
but I can't take it.
But you must have money,
where were you going to get it?
There are ways.
And take more risks ?
Now where would we be if we
refused your help?
He gave Karl and me our freedom,
now we want to help you
-Don't be silly.
- Thank you, Minna.
I'll see you get it back
We can manage,we don't
care with that money
There is something more important.
We've been talking to this child.
She is very troubled.
While you were away I found out
that Karl was a doctor.
He's been trying to help me
You know, Mr. Somers...
... we had much experience of persecution
We know it's only necessary when
very big lies have to be told.
The girl is suffering from such a lie.
Yes, I think so too
But in one part of her mind
she still knows the truth.
-Are you expecting anyone?
- No
Into the kitchen.
Wait in there
Thank you, Karl.
Sophie.
- Doctor Cesare?
- Yes.
- My name is Shepley.
I trying to find a friend of yours.
We have only a few friends in England.
If it were not for this friend,
you wouldn't be in England now.
I haven't seen him not for years.
May I come in?
By all means
I'd like to meet your wife,
she may be able to help us.
Of course
Minna, we have a visitor.
Come on we go
I want you to understand...
... that I have nothing
to do with the police force.
I'm not looking for the girl.
So you see if you have helped him,
you may have done him a disservice
We don't worry...
... wherever he is, Mr Somers
can take care of himself.
And of her
Hello!
Hello, Kyra.
Here you are big boy, this will
get you on the boat.
Thanks
They sail a week tonight from Liverpool
And what about passports?
Be outside the Hainan coffee
on the same day at twelve-thirty.
There will be a street bookie waiting
You must speak from your
language learning
... 'Har yen chow fan ber Lou gai'.
He'll answer: 'Yung chow Dan'.
'Har yen chow fan ber Lou gai'.
- And then 'Yung chow Dan'.
- Clever boy
Butterfly girl.
It's a pretty name,isn't it?
Did she do it?
No, but that's difficult to prove
Poor little thing.
- Well, goodbye.
- Bye, Kyra thank you.
David.
They're working very hard,aren't they?
They blocked both the bridges.
Never mind,we'll take that boat,
come on,the road across
- What about this one?
-No,no,too obvious.
That's ready
We'll soon fix this
Nothing safe is it?
We'll look after her
Right
All right,thank you.
They found the car abandoned
on the moor
Gives them a good start.
Not good enough.
You'll see, we'll get them.
I'll take this one.
Have you any buns,sausage
rolls or something?
Sorry, sir, the baker doesn't
deliver until nine-thirty or so.
How about some apples?
They are good eaters
All right,two pounds of apples, please.
That'll be four and six
What do you do up there?
I'm hungry, David, can't we
stop here and have something?
You're always hungry,what
about those apples?
There are still some left in your bag
I want some tea, I'm sick
of apples,aren't you?
Well,yes, but I don't
think we ought to stop here.
There's nobody in then and
we needn't stay long
All right just this once then.
Sophie, what did
you and Karl talking about?
I asked him about getting muddled and
that did happen to people.
He asked me a lot of questions.
Then he said it did happen
to some people...
... but not to me.
And the he said that there was
something I forgotten...
that I had to remember
And when I do remember it I
won't feel muddled anymore
Was it something about finding
your parents dead?
That
Something else.
Come on, we'd better get our bus.
Mike.
What's the matter, Eric?
Fares, please.
All the way,please
-Two for Patterdale.
- Thank you.
I was looking forward to that tea.
You left your bag.
No, I've got it here.
- No, your hand bag.
- But I haven't got it..
You had it at the caf.
- Yes, I left it on the chair.
- Come on.
That young man spotted
you,the one at the tea place
What are we going to do?
They will comb the lakes.
But we shan't be here
we cut across to Liverpool
They got on the Patterdale bus.
Yes, about ten minutes ago.
Right, sir.
The main party is going up the
hill with the wireless van,Sir
- Straight ahead
- Good thank you.
Straight on
- Joining ahead.
- Right,thank you,drive on
We'll give them a minute and
then we'll double back
Still hungry?
I'm scared
I know.
Here.
Put these things into your bag.
We got to travel light now
This is rough country, we are
damned to use the roads,not by daylight
Hot ?
All right
It's theirs all right
Anything interesting in it?
No,nothing they couldn't have
bought anywhere.
No,there wouldn't be
Look, we made
three rings of police
This is where we found the bag,so we know
that they came through the outer ring
There is only one way they can go,
to the mountain.
And when they do that,
we got them
He's got out of tighter places than that
I believe you want him to get away
Well,I'm sounding the tally-hos this time
... but I tell you quite frankly
I hope I don't give the bush
They've been sighted towards Copley Wood
Jess.
It's Jess.
Nonsense,nonsense
Of course it isn't
It was Jess.
I thought I saw Jess.
No, Sophie, you didn't
Come on here, we got to get moving
All right now?
That wasn't Jess you saw.
I thought,it was for a moment
I was so frightened.
-Because I remembered.
-Remembered what?
That's how what is was when I saw
my mother and father.
Someone was there with a gun.
I thought you found them first?
That's what Jess said.
She always explained it that way
She said I had a shock
... and I thought I saw someone.
That's what I remembered
in the woods just now.
I wasn't muddled
Someone was there with a gun.
Who was it, was it Jess?
I don't know, I can't remember.
The night when Hick was killed, you
didn't even see him, did you?
No, but they tried to
make me think I did.
You believe me, don't you?
Yes, Sophie,of course
I believe you.
But I'm not the police.
Okay, fly captain, message understood.
Out
The helicopter chap said there was
no sign of anyone in Copley Wood
Black mark,fly catcher
Helicopter report,couple seen
near Sourmilk Gill,Sir
Telephone Keswick,tell them to send all
mobile reserves..
...to the bottom of
Sourmilk Gill,immediately.
- Priority one.
- Yes sir
This must be Sourmilk Gill.
Well, if we follow
the waterfall down...
take us to old track that
lead us to the main road
Keswick Section Station,
here, Message 1350.
Superintendent requests all
available mobile patrols
Yes
Concentrate north of Sourmilk Gill.
We're trapped,aren't we?
Look, Sophie, we just got time to
jump before they see us.
Do you think you can make it?
I can't,David, it's too wide.
All right
Never mind
Do you see that ledge down there?
Get in there and make
yourself small as you can
And what are you going to do?
I'll draw them off
Give me your raincoat.
After they've gone and when it's dark.
... make your way back to the lake side
where we got off the bus.
Do you remember?
And wait for me there.
Supposing they catch you?
They won't,I'll come
for you,I promise.
Lakeside, where we
got off the bus.
See you tonight.
- Be careful.
- I will
Where's the girl?
She's not here?
-No, she's gone away
- Which way
That's your worry.
Well, we got Somers.
The girl won't be much trouble on her own
You'd better move the men to the other
side of the gully as quick as you can
Is that wise?
If she got away on that side and Somers
would not leave her behind.
There's no point for a whole lot
of men standing around on this side
How bad is Somers?
The say he broke a couple of ribs and
may have fractured an ankle.
My ribs.
Thanks
How are your legs?
Hurt.
Sorry, chap
Open the door!
What?
Get after him, quick,move
Get a car as quick as you can.
Knocked out the policeman
and struck the driver,I suppose
- Come on.
- I told you
Sophie.
David.
I was so afraid
Are you really all right?
Of course I'm all right
Just worried for you.
I thought I was going to
have to give myself up.
I'm very glad you didn't
... because we got to take
things into our own hands now.
And the first thing you
got to have a talk with Jess.
With Jess?
It'll be all right, only
on the telephone.
They are coming through
Hello!
Hello, Jess?
Where are you?
Now I see
Why are you telephoning?
I need help, Jess, to get away
Abroad
Where are you?
You take the very wrong to run away,Sophie
You must give yourself up to the
police, mustn't you,Sophie? "
No, I need help, Jess.
Things are not quite the same any longer
Tell her you started
remembering.
I don't get muddled anymore.
What do you want?
No, that's too much,
I haven't got it
Two hundred?
Yes,all right
How can I brief them?
No, the place wouldn't be safe.
I'll bring it to you myself.
All right, Jess.
Yes, all right
- I'll be at...
- 5 Coronation Way, Liverpool.
5 Coronation Way, Liverpool.
Thursday.
Yes, Coronation, Thursday
afternoon at three o'clock
You won't fail me, will you, Jess?
No, I won't fail
-Supposing she brings the police?
-No, I don't think she will.
Anyway it is a chance that we got to take
Sorry, we missed catching the Five
- All right, Sir,hop in
- Thank you.
Hello, Nora, anything
wrong with Glasgow?
Yes, I try like a change
sometimes
Your room will cost you a fiver
this time, Somers.
She is hot.
I only want it for an
hour or two, Nora.
We're expecting a visitor
this afternoon, a lady
We want a private
talk at three o'clock, you understand?
I do, but it still cost you a fiver
What's the matter?
Is this stuff getting more expensive?
I like the room ready in an hour,Nora
All right, but watch yourself,
I do not want any trouble
Nor do we.
How do you feel like
... 'har yen chow fan ber low gai'?
'Yung chow Dan'.
What time is
red fox on?
Midnight.
And the jockey?
Francesca.
-What about the passports?
-Another twenty-five nickel
Foxes are up today.
So are butterflies.
Thank you.
Listen,Royal North Atlantic Dock, Bay D.
Shed opposite a big crane.
Packing case marked with
letter K, red chalk.
Side opens easily,room for two.
Ship closely watched,but
captain willing, got it?
Royal North Atlantic...
-What was he saying?
-Scram Charlie, it's the cop.
Mr. and Master Fox
Master Fox, that means you've
got to have your hair cut off
Waiter.
Yes, the bill, Si.?
'har yen chow fan ber low gai'.
This way,please
Where are we going?
Better have some photographs taken
Thank you.
Put my coat on.
What about this hair?
She can cut it later, for the photograph
I'll retouch
Good
You're all right?
Look straight in the camera.
No, no smiles.Serious, please.
Here you are.
Upstairs, first floor on the right.
And if you hear me buzz it'll means
the boys is back again..
... so down the fire escape quick
both of you
Sophie, get into my pullover
and your slacks
I'm going out to get you a jacket.
And while I'm away
cut some of that hair off
- Do I have to ?
-Yes, Master Fox you do
If the police do come, you have to go
down the fire escape...
... you know where to go,don't you
North Atlantic Dock, Bay D.
Packing case with red  K.
Room for two.
Good
Goodbye, Sophie, I won't be long.
I'll take this.
-Nora
-Yes
I'm just going out for a few minutes.
I'll be back before three.
You might send some tea up
to the girl, will you?
I will,be assured
Third degree,third degree not
allowed in England.
Fourth degree, if you don't talk.
Now then, what name?
Come on, what name?
Mr. Fox and Master Fox
Master Fox
The old girl said you
might like a cup of tea
I'll put it down here,shall I?
Good morning, Mr. Croft.
- How's tricks?
- So and so
You got those clothes for me?
I wasn't quite sure of the size.
To fit a boy.
- Yes - A slim boy.
Well, one of these?
No, too big.
Not too big.
No, no...
Hello Chum
Bring you sporter(?)
shopping for Master Fox?
Well, shall we push off?
Yes, if you wish
I shan't ask you where she is.
No, of course not, could be
a waste of time,wouldn't it?
Anyway,it's you I'm after
The train now standing
at platform 7...
... is the Express. for London..
... and will be leaving
in two minutes...
... stopping at Crewe,
Rugby and Euston.
If the department did things properly,
Willy, you have reserved seat for us
Yeah, I know,old boy
but then we couldn't absolutely depend
on a chap like you to fill them
You underestimate yourself
I am a realist
You ought to have done
it at the station.
I did not want to
- Madame, excuse me.
- David.
Let me help you.
I'll take care of the child.
Come with me.
Thank you very much. Go with the gentleman.
- Excuse me, ma'am.
- Do not push.
That's right
Let me through,madam
- Take your hands off me.
- Madam, please.
I'll find out, how your son has
probably been kidnapped
Ernie!
Yes.
Nicholas.
Now we mustn't make a sound
child,we must be very quiet.
- I know.
- You must be quiet.
Nicholas!
Do not scream or I'll have to stop you
and I don't want to do it that way
You see, I am very fond of you
Where is Jess?
She's waiting for me,
she won't be here.
This is something that I have to do
It was you who killed my mother.
I remember now.
I saw you.
And then Jess came.
That day in the garden.
... you killed my mother.
Only because she interfered
I didn't want to kill her.
It was him.
Jess liked him
He had to go
Just like Hick had to go
I warned Jess, but she
wouldn't take any notice
I'm the only one she protects.
As long as I have
Jess, I'm safe
I'm sorry, child
It's locked
We shan't be disturbed
Sophie!
Fenton.
- Willy.
- Get in
Willy.
(?),Sir
Little boy in blue here
is getting impatient.
If this another game of yours,I don't think
the department will be able to help.
Hurry them up, Willy,hurry them up
Inspector.
- Sir.
-Bay D.
-Well, drive on
Go right.
She's up there.
Yes, there's she is,let's get her.
Now wait, there's your man.
Come on quick
Can you lift me up there
Right!
Hold on, Sophie!
David!
Subtitles by Nostromo