Wait a minute, where to?
What cleaning at this time?
But this is not you!
You think you are a man now?
Shame on you Faruk,
where have you been?
I was worried. You didn't
answer your phone either?
I was strip club hopping Melek.
Faruk?
- Well then, Mr. Ömer, see you later.
- Of course.
- Master, what the heck does he want again?
- What could he, me.
I don't get his insistency...
Come on Levent, get in the car,
we're late.
I am here master...
No sir, he didn't accept it again.
I got it sir, will talk to you later.
To the airport.
Gentlemen! Every city has its needs.
Its deficiencies, mistakes...
...its questioning, stuffy, left alone
people. That's when you get into...
...the picture and say, I am here... you
roll up up your sleeves and startfighting...
...so that those people
can live a better life.
You start sweating so that city can
be in peace with its government...
That's when the nation's love
and devotion follow you.
Manager, those night clubs are like a
knife stabbed into the heart of this city.
Dear governor, you are so right.
But owners of the management
had prepared...
...all necessary papers and
done their application.
They also cut the music at midnight
we are in desperate straits...
So there is nothing to be done legally...
What do you mean there is nothing?
People who live at that street
have no life security.
How can a hospital, mosque, school and
a night club coexist in the same place?
How did those men
get their permit president?
Sir, couple of managements had applied
before we came in charge.
And?
They got their permit by taking
advantage of legal gaps in the system.
And?
After we were elected, other managements
pointed at those couple as an example...
...therefore we had to give them
their new permits as well.
I got it, got it.
Now you will take the chief of police
force with you and go to that street.
Then you will close down all those
managements one by one...
Dear governor, how could it be?
We don't have any legal support.
It can and it will.
I am the legal support.
If they ask,
tell them it's the governor.
I mean which one is more important?
Our citizens safety or keeping
those night clubs open?
Certainly our citizens dear governer.
Well done president.
Dear governor, we will immediately
enforce your instructions sir.
Yes chief ASAP. Those night clubs
will shut down today.
Then I, actually we...
...will take our wives and walk up and
down at that street all together.
Then people will see, that
street is safe and it's ours.
That street belongs to Denizli people.
End of the meeting, come on.
Come on, chief.
Prove me good president, come on.
Based on an announcement, Tarik Sarac,
the management president of...
...Sarac Holding company lost his life
after an armed attack yesterday afternoon.
He will be buried today at 2p. m.
Based on police headquarters explanation
an illegal left organization...
...took the responsibility of the attack.
The police announced that...
...they will be doing a large scaled
national operation on the issue.
- My love did you come?
- Nop, I didn't.
- How are you?
- Good, you?
Good.
Are we leaving right now?
Yes. Let's go and eat some food
immediately, I am hungry like a wolf.
You're logged in for your e-mail,
I am logging you out.
Yeah I was checking it while
waiting for you. You can close it.
OK.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
Denizli Karahayit M.T.A. Research center
Samples from 20th meter are done too.
I think we definitely found it master.
Based on the reports, we did. I hope all
our efforts won't be for nothing.
I hope so.
Will you be able to hit the road
tomorrow? Did you call Ankara?
Yes I will master... I talked with
Mr. Ahmet, they are waiting for me.
Good, may it go well... Ok I am leaving.
Will see you in the morning.
- See you later master.
- May your work go well.
USA and Turkey are two friend countries
that act together on many issues...
...such as middle-east politics.
Turkey that can become self-dependent
and powerful with its energy sources...
...and economy is also
for the advantage...
...of our strategic partner; USA.
Our country, just like the others...
...will meet the necessary inspection...
...requirements and will create
alternative energy sources.
Nuclear energy is our
priorority in these days...
...when many resources and
oil are about to be exhausted.
Our main purpose here
is to make national...
...services continue in most easiest and...
...cheapest ways without
interrupting the...
...production and consumption
of our country.
Considering our current
technologic deficiencies...
...best way to reach our underground
wealth is by benefitting from...
...our friend countries' technologies
based on our interest.
Multi-national and long term investment
partnerships on mines such as oil...
...gold and boron has
benefited our country.
Follow it.
Ömer. Are you sure?
This is very serious.
I know Faruk.
Sarp got the first tests
done in the university.
Result is positive.
If the sample's uranium values turn
out to be expected on top of this...
There will be a chaos.
Right, I hope they won't walk on us.
They will dear, they will.
There are guys who wait on alertjust to
make sure nothing good happens to...
...this country. Those will
come after us as well.
Stop by my house tonight.
We'll see what we can do.
Melek has been asking about you anyways.
- This will be an excuse for her to
finally see you. - See you tonight.
Ömer...
Let's take a walk together
before you enter my house tonight.
At that night time?
What kind of walk?
Walk bro, usual walk you know.
Ok, calm down.
Tonight, first the walk
then dinner.
- First walk then dinner.
- All right cool.
He's asking the kind of walk! What kind of
walk can it be... Walk is walk.
Open it.
What's it?
I'm drinking sugar-free.
Let's see.
Dear governor, welcome.
- Simit seller, how have you been?
- Thank you sir, how about yourself?
- Not bad.
- Welcome Mr. Governor.
Welcome Mr. Governor.
- How is your business going?
- Thanks Mr. Governor.
- Sir welcome.
- Hello.
Dear governer, eat some
sunflower seeds before you leave.
Yilmaz.
The street has been great,
it's been so peaceful.
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- Ömer.
Do you have a plastic bag,
we should't throw the peel.
Go ahead sir throw it.
Since our streets has gotten rid of those
bastards. Go ahead and throw it.
I will clean it up till the morning.
Throw it.
All right. Ok.
Hello.
- Thank you.
- You still have more to go?
Yes a lot more.
My head can't get it no more.
Then let's sleep I will wake you up
early in the morning and you can work.
Let me finish it, I want it to end. If I go
to bed now, I won't be able to sleep well.
Ok.
Then I should remind you how much
you'll be missing and I am gone.
- You'll see when this project ends.
- Yeah right.
- Good night.
- Ok good luck.
Cheers to my old friends and to Istanbul,
where I missed a lot.
Yes, let's talk about our subject.
Ceyda, alternative energy sources and
especially nuclear energy are very...
...important nowadays, just like
you said during the panel today.
Ok, we may have enough oil for 40 years
for us in Iraq and in whole middle-east.
But we need to consider
the future afterwards.
Future coming years' oil is uranium.
And we are seeking to be the suitors
of that with the support of you, our...
...precious friends. We did some
research. We discovered rich...
...uranium beds in foremost Denizli
and many other cities.
Mr. Kamil is the general manager of
American Stones which has been operating...
...for 4 years in Denizli. He'd like to
add a new marble quarry to his factory.
And he finished all legal application
process. Now Ceyda, my request...
...from you is that you help Mr. Kamil
on land designation he wants.
I will do my best sir.
Considering how Turkish government
loves foreigner investors...
...I don't think it will be hard at all.
Right Mr. Ender?
No doubt.
Foreign investment is the product
with the brightest pack.
Opposed force was
convicted 28 years ago.
Good.
Are all this preparation just because
Uranium was found in Denizli?
What good does it do unless
you can process it?
Unfortunately, our country doesn't have
neither the science nor the technology to...
...process that metal.
- None. India has it, Iran has it.
I mean if they don't keep bothering
we could have it as well.
- Faruk, Chernobyl.
- Don't start Melek.
Hiroshima, Nagasaki.
What's important is that energy needs
to be used for the development...
...and relief of the country not
for armament purposes.
Japan is particulary the country where
nuclear energy is being used the most.
Whether or not having uranium
is not as important as...
...being able to claim the value of it.
That area's MTA manager is Ömer Ucar.
And he has been working on the land
that we want to have for a long time.
I offered Ömer Ucar a job position
with great conditions many times.
But I wasn't able to convince him.
What can be done about this you think?
Do you have any idea on what kind
of project he is working on Mr. Kamil?
No, but he mentioned it as a project
he has been working on...
...for many years during
our last meeting.
Ceyda, do you think this guys
knows what we know?
I don't think so.
If that was the case, he would have
needed to get a permit for the samples...
...from MTA Ankara, and I'd have been
informed about that.
Let's say he found Uranium.
If he sends it to Ankara,
what can we do?
A council starts an inspection after
samples are received in MTA.
There is nothing I can do
about that step sir.
Understood.
Then, samples shouldn't
reach Ankara no matter what.
Are you taking the samples to Ankara?
Levent is taking them.
If the results are positive, then we'll
go to ministry together.
Hope so Faruk.
- We will need huge support
from the government. - Definitely.
Definitely.
That's if they want to of course.
Not that far dear... No one can dare
to look into the eye of the nation...
...and lie them about a subject that
would benefit our country.
What if that nation is
looking somewhere else?
What is they are being brainwashed
with fake agendas and crises?
Then it is ourjob to wake those
people up, ourjob my mate.
- Ömer.
- Thanks dear.
How is Sarp? He never calls.
To be honest I don't know either.
- He is love drunk nowadays.
- What love?
- Call that donkey for me.
- Don't call him at this time.
- It's so inappropriate dear.
- Of course we call at this time, when else can we call?
It's ringing.
Hello.
Why are you whispering?
I guess your little lady is sleeping huh?
Yes she is bro, what's up?
I can't hear what you're saying,
talk louder.
I said she is sleeping, sleeping.
What do you want from me at this time?
Look at him. He is obstinating
his brother. Give it to me.
Hello.
- Faruk bro!
- Damn right Faruk bro.
What's up with you not
calling not asking us?
On top of it, were you just obstinating
my 40 year old friend?
- Not at all bro, would I ever do that.
- Of course you wouldn't, couldn't anyways.
- Enough. Don't make a fuss over the kid.
Give me that phone. - Melek stop.
- Sarp How are you?
- I am fine Melek sis. Fine.
I'm doing the only thing I've been doing
in last 5 years working. How are you?
I am fine too.
So, how is it going with Ayþe?
- Tell him to take Ayþe too and come here.
- Did you hear what Faruk just said?
I did, I did Melek sis.
School has been
very hectic.
Ayþe is working on her
master thesis.
It's really hard for us
to come there at this point.
Well manage an appropriate
time and come.
I hope so Melek sis,
I miss you you all.
Abraham Lincoln, James Garfield,
William Mckinley, John F. Kennedy.
Ender what do those name mean to you?
In the history of USA, there was an
assasination to every one president out of ten.
Yes I am not proud of this but,
things have to keep working somehow.
The foremost requirement to be big is to
get what you want, whenever you want.
Now are you telling that a
small administrator from...
...a small city of a small country
will be an obstacle?
Sir I actually meant.
Bull. I don't think that governor will
have the courage to stand in front of us.
And if he does, whatever is necessary
will be done without a doubt.
Dear governor. Don't you think shutting
down the club managements...
...at Istiklal st. Is a bit of
an arbitrary operation?
Arbitrary?
Now listen my friends...
Government should first of all
destroy the elements...
...that are threatening for
the safety of our citizens.
This is the purpose of a
government's existence.
It is the fundamental duty.
That duty involves its police,
its soldiers, its justice and laws.
This has nothing to do with being a socialist
government or democracy for that manner.
Citizens should be able
to trust its government.
We provided that trust,
what's so bad about that?
Sir, how about the alcohol ban and
Murat the 4th comparison?
My friends...
We are not opposed to no one's drinking, we
don't have the right to say don't drink either.
We didn't ask
why do you sell alcohol either.
But, freedom...
...doesn't mean that anyone can behave
however they want.
Personal freedom ends, when it stops
someone else's freedom.
Sir have you been threatening by
the management owners?
Threat? Did we receive any Veysel?
No sir.
Now my friends...
The first condition to have trust and
peace in this country is if honorable...
...people are as brave as
the dishonorable ones.
And if couple of swag men ever
dare to threaten a governor...
...then it is my obligation as
the governor to stand in front of them.
Yes?
Yilmaz is calling.
Connect him.
How are you Ms. Ceyda?
Thank you sir how about yourself?
Thanks Ms. Ceyda.
I am sorry, apparantly you had called
but I couldn't answer the phone.
They called from Denizli MTA. I had to
prepare the lab immediately.
How come?
Is it uranium?
Ok Mr. Ahmet. Please keep
me updated. Later.
I see... Ok.
What happened to that land in Heybeli Island?
Did you receive the construction permit?
No problem there sir.
Thanks to you.
Don't even mention it.
A foreign investment at this scale is
a big chance not only for Denizli...
...but for our country as well.
Unfortunately, there are still minds who
approach foreign stocks with suspicion.
I am sure your positive writings on that
matter would be very beneficial.
- Don't even doubt I, of course sir.
- Thank you.
Sir there has been talks on how you will
get back into politics in the lobby.
It would be a lie if I say I didn't think
about it, but of course it would be with...
...a new party that fits our mission. We
are continuing to work on that subject.
When the right time comes we will
certainly need your help.
This is done too.
Master, see you later.
Later.
I will call you
when I get to Ankara.
- Have a nice trip.
- Good bye.
Stop.
Yes.
M.T.A vehicle?
Levent.
Let me go.
It's not Levent right?
That's not Levent,
it's not him... Let me go...
Levent.
Ok calm down.
Its passed now.
Guys take Mr. Ömer to the headquarters.
Ok, calm down...
Levent.
Why in the hell you didn't
cover the body?
Quick, come on quick.
How did it happen?
Chief, he couldn't take the
curve and rolled down.
Ok, I am going to the head office.
- Crime scene?
- They will be here in a minute.
Ömer!
May your life be spared.
Come on sit down.
I am so sorry Mr. Ömer.
I can't believe this,
we were just together today.
That's how it is Ömer...
That's how this fucking world is.
How did it happen Tahir?
Sir, he couldn't take the curve
and rolled over the cliff.
We loaded the samples to the vehicle
together around 1 p. m.
And he hit the road.
I received the news
half an hour later.
There were many boxes on the ground of the
scene, they were spilled all over the place.
Are those what
you mentioned as samples?
Yes...
He was taking them
to Ankara for an inspection.
What inspection?
We had been doing some work in
that area on Uranium for 3 months.
Uranium?
I am flying to Denizli early
in the morning sir.
Howcome?
I will ask a permission from dear
governor for an investment...
...that will be made by an international company to Denizli.
- From Faruk?
Yes, I don't think there will
be any problems but...
No worries, I will call
Faruk myself if needed.
No doubt.
Uður, send the crime scene team
towards the upper curve.
Tell them to investigate tire marks
on the ground very well.
Also, I want to know which car do
these broken glass piece belong to.
Sarp?
I am fine, fine. Don't worry.
We need to get used to these stuff.
I'll prepare my baggage.
I am coming to Denizli too.
You are coming too?
I don't think this is
a right time Ayþe.
I'm not interested whether
or not the time is right.
I just think that I should be with you
during these times that's it.
Why are you looking at me like that?
I love you so much.
I love you so much too.
Chief?
Come in Ugur.
Chief, glass pieces from the scene
belongs to rear stop lights of the jeep...
...engineer Levent was driving. Also, tire
marks belongs to his vehicle as well.
There were some other tire marks close.
To the cliff's edge
that blong to another vehicle.
Those marks ends right
by the edge of the cliff.
- So you are saying that there is
another vehicle in this. - Yes chief.
Talk with the traffic and learn if there
was any accident reports in that area.
Got it.
Send a team to the industry
for an investigation.
Update all the patrols on this.
Yes sir.
Brother.
I couldn't take care of Levent.
I couldn't protect him.
Brother...
Sir I postponed all your meetings...
...before the funeral to afternoon.
Ms. Ceyda?
I explained the situation to
her dear governor.
She said that she will be
joining the funeral herself.
Good.
One more thing, Chief Tahir is
waiting for you in your room.
- Tahir?
- Yes sir.
Really?
Good morning Tahir.
Tahir.
Dear governor, forgive me.
It's ok sit, sit.
Dear governor I am so sorry.
Sit down bro it's ok.
I was looking for a car till
the morning, so I fell asleep like that.
What's going on?
I bothered you to present
just that dear governor.
We found another vehicle's tire
marks on the ground where engineer...
...Levent had the accident.
What does that mean Tahir?
It means this sir.
There is either someone who caused
the accident or at least witnessed it.
We lost a young man who served
his country with honor.
He sweated himself so that our society
could be more improved and peaceful.
He tried to discover new treasures
for us deep underground.
He spent a lifetime in soil.
He loved the soil, very much.
Who knew it is time to give him to soil
that he loves very much forever.
I am sorry.
Welcome Ms. Ceyda, Mr. Governer
is waiting for you, this way.
Dear governor?
Ms. Ceyda, please come in.
- Welcome.
- Thank you sir.
This way please.
Unfortunately, we happen to meet
on a sorrowful day.
Unfortunately Ms. Ceyda. We lost
a very precious young man.
Right sir. It is very hard to digest.
Yes, hard, very hard situation.
I should have gone.
What does that have do with anything
bro? Please don't do this for god's sake.
Let's leave this place, I feel like
the walls are coming over me.
Dear...
Sir, this company will make a 2 billion
dollars worth investment for the first 5 years.
They also signed prudential, long term deals
with many other, multi-nation companies.
Nice, nice.
And the company is a claimant
for bigger marble reserves.
I see.
Necessary permits are taken
from the ministry.
You can see them in
the folder in front of you.
As we know, your signature is needed
in order to complete the file.
But Ms. Ceyda, I can't see
the name of the region here.
Excuse me sir.
Karahayit sir.
Karahayit?
MTA is currently working in that region.
I know sir.
If you know that, you must as well
know that the young man we buried...
...today was working for that region.
You are right sir, but as you know
our ministry has some agreements...
...with foreign investors.
Don't make me start with your ministry and
the foreign investors and their agreements.
I don't give
a damn about your ministry.
I don't care.
What a nerve, what boldness!
You misundertand sir.
No I didn't.
There is no misunderstanding.
I just don't want to hear anything
related to this right now.
Dear governor, you are acting arbitrary.
Arbitrary? I don't think so Ms. Ceyda.
Because I am not in the mood,
no mood no signature.
Now please excuse me.
Excuse me.
That's not good.
That guy won't give a yes easily.
It is in your hands to make him.
It's not that simple. This governor is
not like other guys you know.
All right then.
I will inform Mr. Peterson.
Faruk what is this topic with
Ms. Ceyda all about?
Ms. Ceyda asked Karahayit from me.
A factory is a suitor for a marble
business. The ministry stands behind them.
And?
- And what?
- You're giving away the land?
Listen for a minute, stop and listen.
I'm not giving no one anything.
You can't give away that land to anyone.
That's Leven't land.
Did I say any different?
Listen for a second listen.
Ms. Ceyda came with a file
signed by the ministry...
...it only lacks my signature...
You need to hurry up and...
...get that report from
MTA as soon as possible.
How soon is that?
I will try to put it off
as much as I can.
But I don't think we have much time.
Those guys came with
a billion-dollar investment huh.
Faruk, what you're saying is hard.
It might take months for another
engineer to replace Levent.
How can I find one
in such short notice?
Here.
- No way.
- Of course not.
- If one of you could give me a reason why not.
- Are you going to quit from school?
No bro, but I was considering
the permission option.
Don't be arrogant.
Ömer, wait let the kid explain.
Bro, wells are ready, there
is no other digging work.
If I am in, we can finish
this job in a week.
Fine. We might
consider it. Maybe.
I can enter the wells too.
Sure. What are you planning
to do in the well dear?
Are you going to teach samples
how to speak English?
Look Melek, see? Solidarity is in
this country's people's fabric.
That's the spirit of a strong army.
What would happen to
your situation with the school?
Not important Ömer bro, since
I am writing my thesis nowadays...
...profesors don't mind
it If I don't go to school.
And like Faruk bro said, it is important
to stick together during these days.
Well down dear, very good.
Are you in English literature major?
No Melek sis, American
language and literature.
Really, that's needed too of course.
- Ok Ayþe then ok.
- Perfect.
Since I got the job, if you excuse
me I need to call my family.
How did you get this girl yo?
You're right Ömer. You caught a mouse
since you've been a cat once.
Ok, got it.
Who the hell does this guy thinks he is?
We don't have much time left.
We need to finish the job
from a higher power position.
Don't worry, Ceyda is taking care of it.
How?
Ceyda is finishing the job from up.
- You couldn't persuade him huh?
- Unfortunately.
I am not surprised at all. Faruk is
a hard man. So what should we do then?
I need help, maybe if you talk with him.
If I talk with him huh?
Sure why not.
Phone.
But sir... It's yet...
I got it. Don't worry.
See you later.
Sir, our delegate is on the line.
Connect it.
How are you dear delegate?
Thanks I am fine.
I was going to ask
your favor on a matter.
3 days later.
What the hell.
Connect it.
How are you?
I am fine thank you.
Sure ok yeah... I see sir, I see.
I will take care of it eventually.
Have a good day to you too sir.
What is it again, what is it?
Who? Send her in.
Our lady has come for
a second round Veysel.
Let her come sir, if she comes,
the consequences will come as well.
- Dear governor.
- Ms. Ceyda.
- Wouldn't you like to sit?
- No sir it's better like this.
However you like, go ahead.
I'm bothering you with
the same subject sir.
When am I getting the
necessary papers?
You are not getting any Ms. Ceyda.
Excuse me?
You're not getting it, because the
region that was mentioned has been...
...declared as a afforestation
field, by the command of the governor.
What? When?
It's been 3 or 5 minutes maybe.
Right Veysel?
- Yes sir, just happened.
- You don't have such authority.
No I do.
You know what this means don't you?
Yes I know Ms. Ceyda.
I see dear governor.
Excuse me.
You are excused.
- Bro, I think this will finish by tomorrow.
- I think so too.
What happened bro?
I am so glad you are here. If not,
I wouldn't be able to handle it.
- Coffee?
- Please.
Sir, didn't happen.
It is impossible to persuade him,
unfortunately this is I could do.
Yes sir, you too.
I'm hungry. How nice it would have been
to have a watermelon and some cheese.
Ok. Your food will be
ready in an hour.
Why didn't eat from the delivery food
son, why are you torturing the girl.
I am not hungry yet bro.
- You mean you are spoiled.
- That too.
Yes.
What?
Understood.
Sarp!
Ömer bro, help me.
Ayþe.
Ömer bro, do something.
Ayþe...
Bro bro... Hold me, I am going down.
Bro bro, I am here bro.
Bro I am here, I'm here bro.
Bro. Answer me for god's sake.
Did you hear what that woman just said?
I don't have the authority.
Like I was going to learn
authority from you.
- Not at all sir...
- Not at all of course.
What is it again?
Dear governor.
Dear governor, dear governor.
Bro please don't die, please don't.
Sarp, hold this and
tie it up to the machine.
Send it quick.
Extraordinary problems has
extraordinary solutions Ceyda.
Sir maybe so, but I am not sure
if this much was needed or not.
You can be sure! Big steps
are taken in big projects.
Sometimes it's necessary to sacrifice
some people, no big deal.
Yes but the death of two engineers
in the same region?
Call it an uncertain death.
But won't uncertain death will make it
harder to get the designation for the land?
Contrary, it will speed it up.
We cut the problem from the root.
Thousands of people died in Chile.
One of them was a head of state.
The whole world knew him
and no one even knows your MTA manager.
You know what's the best characteristics
of Turkish people that I love?
You forget quick. No one will remember
any of these after 3 days.
I see.
Where is my son?
Where is Ömer?
I am sorry Remzi dad.
- Dad...
- Where is your brother?
Come on Remzi dad sit here.
Where is Ömer?
Take me to my Ömer!
What are you looking at Ugur?
Chief.
Some of the screws that were holding this
steel bulk are spilled all over the place.
But the rest is in its place. But they
are bent towards opposite directions.
Give me that.
Look around, let's see if there is any
key or something to open the screws.
Yes sir.
Chief, do you think it is homicide?
- Is there something?
- Yes chief.
A woman's glasses.
- I think it's Ms. Ayþe's.
- Should we take it chief?
- What time is it?
- 11:45 a. m.
My shitty head! If you find
anything update me.
I will try to make it to the funeral.
Turn this place upside down, every inch,
and keep your mouth shut.
Yes chief.
Let's pray for the decedent's soul.
My son.
My brave one.
Ömer...
This soil is yours.
It's your land now.
I didn't separate you from your soil.
This village's river's water.
We had washed you with
your deceased mother...
...when you were born. Your life water.
Accept it son.
Death, where are you?
Which wrong are you knocking I wonder.
Dad we are here.
Dad.
The scent of my Ömer,
scent of my Ömer.
Scent of my Ömer.
Ömer...
Dad. Dad don't.
I'm fed up Melek.
I'm fed up from losing
the people I love.
I'm tired of burying them
with my own hands.
I know my dear.
I lost a lifelong friend.
I can't stand it no more.
After this point, every way to go
are the same. If I don't have my Ömer.
I will wait for my day in my house, my soil.
Dad...
There is no going like this.
What happened to your hand?
That day... when I was trying...
When will you be back?
I don't know, don't know.
Dear... I'm so sorry again.
I love you...
Welcome.
- You did a good job.
- Shut up.
Calm down.
Why are we here?
Are you scared?
Yes I am.
I was scared of you, from
myself, I was. When is the flight?
- We'll leave soon. Was it your first?
- What first?
First time that you killed someone?
Things that are offered to you,
your life standard.
What do I have? What was offered to me?
I don't even have a life on my own.
You are wrong. You do have your own
life and you choose what to live.
What do you say?
Did I want to kill Sarp's bro.
Look, questions that you are not supposed to
ask will have answers that won't satisfy you.
You are an employee, and
you do whatever duty is given to you...
...and keep on living your daily life.
Be aware of what you are in.
I am but you should be aware of this.
Since I came back to Turkey, I succeed
every mission that was given to me.
Collecting information from the school
and from the computer of the man I sleep...
...with every night a murder in a business
center that had security like an army.
Whatever the mission was,
I did it successfully.
But this last one. Ömer bro. Why did I
have to do it why did you make me do it.
Police, clean up and disappear.
Yes, I wish it wasn't this way...
...but it was and the life you
think you don't own keeps going.
- You need to forget this.
- I need forget it.
Mr. Peterson organized a party
for you and is waiting impatiently.
Ok then let's go.
Stop!
What are you suspicious of Tahir?
The glasses dear governor.
Is there something?
Yes chief, a woman's eyeglasses.
Ms. Ayþe's probably,
I will try to catch the funeral.
- Should we take it chief?
- No, I'll handle it.
Since I came back to Turkey, I succeed
every mission that was given to me.
Collecting information from the school
and from the computer of the man I sleep...
...with everynight a murder in a business
center that had security like an army.
Whatever the mission was,
I did it successfully.
Agents keep living their lives
after a certain training period.
Organization activates
them whenever it wants.
I will prepare my baggage.
You are coming too?
I don't think it's the right time Ayþe.
- I can get into the wells too.
- Ok Ayþe Ok.
You mean my brother's murderer is...
Understood.
Ömer bro. Help.
And the marble factory.
What was it really about.
For now an old minister.
The consultant of the factory that
belongs to the organization...
...if they let us to work on it, other thing
might come up as well dear governor.
- If you excuse me I need to
go the headquarters. - Sure Tahir go, go.
I will come to see the manager anyways.
- May god give you patience.
- Thanks.
Thanks.
What kind of a world is this Faruk
bro. The woman you love betrays you...
...and you pay it by
losing your brother.
The one who betrays doesn't
have a right to choose who to betray.
A month later.
Yes dear minister, I am about leave soon.
There's lots of information. A big
organization is surfacing from the tragedy.
And unfortunately, some government
officials are involved in it too.
All of them are documented sir,
all of them.
The most important one is the flag. I took
over from honorable people 15 years ago.
Wait wait Faruk, are you?
Yes sir, I exactly mean that... exactly...
Unless the road signs fool me and cause
me to end up in the opposite lane...
...I will be with you
before the night falls.
What are you thinking?
What do you have in your hand?
For now, I can say that it's not
an accident as it seems.
Faruk if it is not then...
Yes dear minister, it's like that.
If the documents I have won't be enough.
I am ready so resign in your presence.
I am calling the prime minister right
now and will inform him on this.
I will see you tonight.
However you'd like dear minister.
I will be careful dear minister,
don't worry I will be.
Connect me to the line
of prime minister's office.
Sir, I will bother you later on.
Excuse me sir.
- Dear governor.
- Come veysel come.
- Is everything ready?
- Yes sir.
I checked every document twice sir.
Ok then.
If only we can solve this
case without messing it up.
The account responsible for all the
sorrows will be closed right dear governer.
Yes it will Veysel, it will.
It won't bring back gone people maybe,
but the case will close.
Yes Mr. Veysel... this place is
under your safekeeping.
Don't worry about here sir,
just arrive there safe that's it.
Thanks Veysel.
My long journey friend.
Come on come on.
- Lady Melek, what's the occasion?
- Good.
You didn't sleep last night didn't eat
anything either. It didn't feel right.
I made little something...
you can eat on the road.
Yilmaz.
- Yes, traveller needs to be on the road.
- Come on
- Melek!
- Faruk!
May your roads be open.
Ok then.
Governor Vali Faruk Yazici lost his life
after staying in coma for 6 days.
The documents inside his briefcase are
still missing despite all searching efforts.
The End