What fresh fish!
Excellent with pasta and broccoli, folks!
It doesn't look that fresh to me.
- You must be joking, ma'am! Blasphemy!
It just arrived by plane.
We're three: fisherman, pilot and myself.
"The Peppino Organization"!
Oranges! Get your oranges!
Oranges from Palermo, 3 lire per kilo!
What apples I got today!
What apples!
He's alive! His eyes seems to be saying,
"I was underwater just a half hour ago."
Be careful, don't let it escape.
- Put it on a leash.
Peppino, what will you give me?
- For you? A pearl necklace! - How sweet!
I'd like something good.
I have guests, don't make me look bad.
Look: it's a beauty. Shines so
brightly it could be a reflector.
Salt, pepper, garlic, olive oil, herbs and
you'll eat your fingers too. - From rage!
Hey, bad hair day, can't
you mind your own broccoli?
That stink is drying up the fruit.
- Your tongue should dry up.
You don't like to hear me, eh?
Find another market!
Mr. Peppino!
One shouldn't be too familiar with some
people. - Big deal, some loss!
Mr. Peppino! - Go on,
the lady is claiming the corpse.
You make me want to hurl, got it?
- I'd like to hurl you!
Oranges! Lovely oranges!
These truly are fresh! Come to me, folks!
Come here.
- Sorry, ma'am, common people.
Give me two anchovies. - I want it clean.
- Right away. To the surgeon!
Merlino, laparotomize it!
You know I don't like water!
- That's why you should bathe!
You know I like clean people!
Wash your own conscience then!
- Will you give me some anchovies?
She wanted to kill herself.
They're young, who knows
what they get in their heads.
And they don't know..
Is that clear, Mr. Eugenio?
And then, I hadn't said anything to her.
Just one tiny word, like that. Bam!
You know what? It's true.
We Neapolitans, we have a charm,
we have a special attraction,
just a look, one word to a woman, and..
You'd think this a blessing,
Mr. Eugenio, but it's a curse.
A curse we have in our eyes.
Have you ever thought of taking a wife?
- A wife!
Come now, let's not even
joke about it. A wife!
How can it work? There are too many
women who wouldn't leave me alone.
Just as well, deep down I'm
just a romantic. - There you go.
Thank you, Mr. Eugenio.
- Ah, for the boy. - Thank you.
Thank the gentleman.
- Thank you.
I don't like how you said, "Thank you".
You're fined, see?
If anybody wants me, I'm with Peppino.
Damn it to hell!
Hurry or my lady'll yell at me.
- How could she yell at a doll like you?
Peppi, you rule, eh?
- Always, Lambchop.
Cut the "Lambchop", my name is Aurelio.
Whatever! What do you need?
Two mullets? A mackerel? A whale?
Two anchovies.
- One at a time. Well then?
She wants them without bones. - There
are always bones. Right, Lambchop?
Again, "Lambchop". My name is Aurelio.
It's no use telling her, for her there's
only Peppino. The others are ugly.
What a rosebud!
His beauty has no equal!
Who'll take this here vegetable?
Who'll ever take it?
Merlì, remove the bones!
Don't forget the game, eh?
- How could I? It's Rome-Lazio.
It figures. When it comes to
playing around, he's always there.
Hi, Elide, how are you?
- He made my head blow up like a balloon.
Tie it down, or it'll fly off.
Be careful, or I'll make
something fly on your head!
Here you go, don Peppi.
Shall we say, 18 lire?
- Let's say 17.
What 17? You crazy? Causes bad luck.
- Will you give me two anchovies?
When shall we give you a permanent?
- Knock it off, Lambchop, I'm busy.
Leave her alone, Lambchop,
or he who invented her will get mad.
Oranges! Such lovely oranges!
Oranges from Palermo, 3 lire per kilo,
folks! What apples I have!
Checking to see if it has a fever?
Always touching!
Will you give me two anchovies?
Over one kilo. - Peppino, patience.
With women you must rule, but with class.
Mr. Aurelio, there's people in the shop.
- I'm coming.
We meet at three at the bus stop.
Bye, Peppi. - Bye.
You want some chicory, hey!
What chicory!
Chicory, lettuce, broccoli! Hey!
Peppi! There's the goods, the goods!
Come on all, no time to lose!
Sardines, mullet, cod, all fresh stuff.
Please, how can I serve you?
Some mullets or something to fry up?
Two anchovies.
Octopus, squid, sole? Or shrimp, tuna,
sturgeon, perch, anything you want.
No, thanks so much.
I only want a fish I can boil.
In a blink, I'll get you a beaut!
Something unique. A marvel!
One moment!
Look, what a beauty! Shall I weigh it?
- No, I'm taking that.
I'm sorry, but this is for lovely lady.
- No, it's not for the lady.
We'll say 80 lire and pay him. - Why?
- Because you act like you're the boss.
Young man, this attitude is inappropriate.
- Where did this guy come from?
All strangers, today. Any Romans here?
Roman or not, you're all witnesses
that I've been here nearly an hour.
Nearly an hour you've been touching
not saying a word. What do you want?
I want that bass!
I'm sorry, but the lady's getting it.
Thank you. Come to me whenever you like.
Sorry, ma'am, but out of principle,
I won't give in.
You're rude. - No, I'm not.
I'm not an imbecile, that's all.
You're not?
If I wore a skirt, a bonnet, and
lipstick, you'd be acting differently.
And how! How I'd laugh.
- This isn't a joke!
Who's joking? I'm busy working.
- Busy cheating the public!
What?
- You cheat and deceive us!
Now, you're being offensive.
- No, sir, I'm only giving the facts.
What facts? I put this aside for me.
Let him have it, it doesn't matter.
- No. Damn it, I gave the bass to her!
Two anchovies.
- Shut up! Don't you see I'm in a mess?
This individual not only
cheats an honest professional
to flirt with ladies, but takes
advantage of the state of emergency,
allows himself, in a public square,
to make illegal sales.
This results in a dearth of
goods for the people's consumption.
In my country, we call that oppression.
What a blabber after
he was mute for an hour!
How can one speak?
You're always talking!
But you won't fool me.
The bass is mine!
No, the bass is the lady's!
Alright, get it over with!
Who came first? Him or the lady?
- I did! They're all witnesses.
Why didn't you buy it first?
- Yeah. Why? - Because..
I wanted to find out the price first,
but he was busy flirting with the lady.
Me? But how..
May I be struck by lightning!
I do what I always do.
There was this one over here..
I said, "Sir?" and he just kept
touching things without saying..
You're a liar. I have witnesses!
- He's a liar! How true.
See. They all know him.
Why wasn't there a price on
the fish you sold to the lady?
Because I wanted to eat it.
- Why did you give it to the lady?
I get it.
Let me see your license.
Excuse me, ma'am, but it's a matter..
She's gone, your lady.
I see that. But you're always here.
You're worse than Giordano Bruno!
Sorry.
Let me see your license.
- Here.
Give him the bass.
- It's there. Is he crippled?
I have good legs and a great brain.
- Sounds good fried.
We agreed on 80 lire.
- Yeah.
May I go?
- Yes, go ahead.
See you later, Don Giovanni!
- Watch out for the bones!
For now, keep it.
Couldn't you say something?
You stood there as mute as a codfish.
Whenever I talk, you get mad.
You just should've said what happened.
- I though the gentleman was right.
Yeah? I'll put your head in here!
Don't get angry! For 50 lire?
The lady was worth it, right?
- You can say it out loud.
If you don't mind your own business,
you'll get a mullet on your muzzle.
I'd like to see it.
When I say the truth, I say it!
And when I throw a mullet, I throw it!
Can I get two anchovies?
- I don't have any! Got it? Yes or no?
So I told him, "The fish is for
the lady. Shut your face." - What?
"And shut your face." He turned pale as
a corpse. He wanted to get me in trouble?
He almost got himself in trouble.
- And the lady?
She looked at me with those eyes,
Lambchop.. - Aurelio.
Two eyes that looked as big as four.
Four! - Then she smiled
and said, "Thank you, Sir".
"Sir"?
- Well, "Thank you, young man."
She took my hand and as she held it
she said, "See you tomorrow".
Come on! - What?
You think only you have adventures?
Peppi, go on.
- Go on? I'm done. That's it.
That's it?
Where's the adventure?
- And the handshake, Lambchop?
So what?
- What? It's a sure thing.
How does she look up close?
Does she look one of mine?
The usual? - No, she's a unique type,
young man. This time, we're there.
Piazza del Popolo!
Is this a dream? - Are you nuts?
- Lambchop, come on.
Who did you see, may we know?
- Look, it's her.
Let's go.
Are you sure?
- Of course, she looked like a queen.
Aren't you going in?
- You think so?
We got off the bus to look
at her in the window?
So I should go inside?
- But of course! Come on, go ahead.
Then it's true that you.. - Uh!
- Shook her by the hand? - Uh!
Go forward, then, and show them..
Peppi, rule!
Don't worry, Aurelio, you know me.
Give me.. Well, you know..
come on..
And now?
Now, I'll pay, tell me how much.
Yes, how much.
You can't find stuff like this anymore.
In that case, it's unnecessary to pay.
I'll ask the manager.
Fine.
Good day.
You don't recognize me?
I can tell.
You're looking at me like, "Who's this?"
You really don't remember?
The gentleman, this morning.
Then they fined me.
Yes, the fishmonger!
- The fishmonger! Is it he? - Yes, it is!
Forgive me, I'm to blame.
- For heaven's sake, it was nothing.
I'm sorry I couldn't please you.
- It doesn't matter. Maybe another time.
May I.. offer you something?
- No, thank you.
May I ask you a favor then?
What is it?
Well, I'd be pleased to send to your home
something nice, some fresh fish.
Yes, why not?
If only our butcher were like him!
Certainly.
It matters a lot to me.
I have a delivery boy,
if you don't live too far..
Great! We'll give you our address.
This way we'll have the most
elegant fishmonger in the whole city.
Is it clear?
- Very clear.
Hello. Diana wasn't home.
I'll call her later.
OK then, Mr..
- Peppino Corradini.
Very good. Thank you. Good day.
Giorgio, why don't you call Carla?
No, she always goes
to the match on Sundays.
Who's that?
- A nice guy.
A fishmonger.
- Damn!
Sir!
- Ah, right.
How much? - Two cups,
two glasses, two drinks: 120 lire.
It's expensive, eh?
- Oh, well..
I'm sorry.
- Imagine how I feel.
I was about to go in.
- If you only knew!
What did you do?
- I did it all. All!
Driver!
- What now?
I need some air, to breathe.
To the Pincio, Casina Valadier.
What a service. And what women!
Lambchop, I feel like a gentleman.
You're telling me?
Get on!
She invited you so quickly?
- "They" invited me, little one.
They were two ladies.
One was her friend.
Ah, a friend!
Why didn't you call me?
She's high class, they were drinking tea.
Real tea, with lemon slices.
Tomorrow we'll go then.
- Where? - Their place.
Are you crazy? I'm bringing the fish.
What would you bring? Some bangs?
Peppi, I was kidding.
I'm too busy tomorrow.
I have this lady on my hands.
A hot little number!
Peppi, if Campo de' Fiori
could see us now!
Let's not speak of such riffraff.
- Well,
now you're exaggerating,
because you were born there.
You're wrong. I look good in gloves..
- My gloves!
and with women of a higher class.
If Elide could hear you.
- Don't speak of her. - Well.
But something was there.
Yeah, she was always around, so..
I can't stand to see women cry.
- She's a good girl.
She works, she's sure of herself.
And she's honest.
Heavens, who can deny it?
But.. she's a fruit seller.
She's not for us, Peppi.
Can you imagine tomorrow?
She is truly something else..
Careful, they'll give us a fine.
Good day. Is the lady in?
- Who are you?
Who is it?
Oh, good day, ma'am.
- Good day. What do you want?
But don't you remember?
I'm.. that gentleman from
yesterday from the tea room.
The fishmonger?
Heck, I didn't even recognize you!
Wait a moment and I'll get Elsa.
- Thank you.
Elsa! Elsa!
Here's our nice fishmonger
who's kept his word.
Unlike our grocer!
What a rogue he is.
He promised us ham for days
but what did we get: nothing!
Did you bring something? - Yes,
my boy couldn't come, so I sent myself.
I brought some fish bisque.
- Soup bisque!
Great! Let's see it!
Let's go in the kitchen.
Come, let's see the fish bisque!
It's nothing special,
but it's not frozen, it's very fresh.
How they shine!
They're full of phosphorus.
At night, instead of using a flashlight,
I put a mullet in my buttonhole.
How nice!
Are they really fresh?
The freshest, ma'am. Smell?
- How scary.
What a smell!
They remind of the sea, the beach.
That one's still alive, poor thing.
- They all are. - No, that doesn't move.
Well, he's bashful. He's in awe
in being somebody else's house.
How much do we owe you?
- Please, it's on the house.
No, you can't. Sorry.
- Please, be so nice as to accept.
But, why?
- Well, let's accept or he'll be offended.
We'll pay him another time.
- No, I'll get some money.
Ma'am, you tell her.
- Elsa, it's not polite to insist.
How do you prepare it?
- There's only one way: mine.
How then?
The old way.
- Which one?
With garlic and olive oil.
- And the modern way?
Just garlic.
- Just garlic? Pull the other one.
What's that? Listen,
I'll explain to you how it's done.
Take two cloves of garlic and slice them.
Put a whole one for the scent.
Slit it, first, or it'll burst.
Sautee everything with a lot of oil.
A lot.. but not too much.
When it turns golden, add the tomatoes,
salt, pepper, a little parsley,
let it simmer slowly,
and then add the fish.
Got it?
- No.
And you? - Me neither.
It's simple.. - Easier said than done.
I've done it many times.
- What, you're also a cook?
Not a cook,
but for seafood I'm second to none.
If the fish were sure to be cooked
by me, they'd be fished smiling,
as to say, "How wonderful,
we're in Peppino's hands!''
Bravo, Mr. Peppino,
but you must tell me what we owe you.
If you keep saying that I'll throw
myself on the ground and start crying!
You're such a meanie, Elsa.
Isn't that right?
Are you talking about her?
On the contrary, I'd say..
that..
Yeah, whatever. But this fish
bisque, how do you make it?
I can do it! If the gas is steady,
it's all done in half an hour.
No, God forbid! It's too much trouble.
- If you don't want to, that's different.
Would you really make it?
- No, don't insist.
Let me insist, or it's useless! I brought
the fish, you don't know how to cook it,
so let me do it. - Right! But you're sure
it's not too much trouble?
Trouble? It's fun, a pleasure indeed.
Then it's decided, Elsa, let's not argue.
Rosa, help him. Do whatever he says.
Take off your coat.
- Immediately.
This soup will knock your socks off!
- Bravo, Peppino.
Here is my apron with pretty flowers.
Perfect! You're the most
elegant cook in town.
But it's a bit loose. - No, it's perfect.
- Now, to work!
I appoint you my assistant.
Give me a pan, garlic and olive oil.
- Even oil!
We're going to watch, it's interesting.
- No, if you stay, I'll get confused.
I get it, you want to
flirt with your helper.
OK, we'll see you later.
Good luck. - Thanks!
And don't seduce Rosa, OK?
- He'd find it a little difficult.
Is that so?
- Keep your hands off!
Peel the oil and give me the garlic.
I mean, give me.. what? Here!
Black market, eh?
Have you been here long?
- Four months.
You like it, right?
What's the name..?
- Rosa Muzi from Tagliacozzo.
I mean the tall blonde lady.
- Ah, Mrs. Elsa.
Her name is Bianchini.
Does her husband come home late?
- She has no husband.
Yeah, the boyfriend.
Not either.
What the hell you doing? That's expensive!
- Hey, don't yell! It'll be tastier.
What's the fuss? As if you paid for it!
It's served. - Bravo, you're even a waiter!
- Waiter, cook, all.
I'd like to taste it.
Sure, at the place of honor.
Elsa is next to you, OK? - I'm honored.
So, how did our Peppino behave?
He asked me a ton of questions!
I see why you wanted to be alone with her!
He wanted to know the name of Mrs. Elsa.
And if she were married.
Did he ask anything about you?
- No, he always spoke about Mrs. Elsa.
Mr. Peppino, how discourteous.
I confess, I'm a little jealous.
But when I smell this bisque,
I forgive you.
Shall we sit?
Now let's the judge the cook.
- I'm not worried.
Young lady!
If you allow, I'll serve, because you
must know how to catch the fish. Please.
Bravo! Fishmonger, cook, waiter,
dancer, and a grand gentleman!
Ma'am.
The telephone.
- Coming.
It's your turn. Are you happy?
Come on, don't make me beg you!
Finally!
I wish this record were
as large as St. Peter's Square.
Wouldn't you get tired?
- Dancing with you?
That's enough, Mr. Peppino.
I'm a little tired.
I'm sorry. I have much to do.
And it's getting late.
I'm leaving now.
Don't worry.
But.. May I come back in the evening?
Mrs. Olga was kind enough to ask me.
And I would be so happy.
Rosa!
Good day.
And thank you.
Well?
- Well?
What do you want from me?
Get my hat, I'm ruined.
Then we talked about music
In fact, at some point I put on a record..
What a tune!
# If I miss you..
"Slow"?
- Almost.
We were sitting..
Some armchairs!
"Frau" brand?
- Yes, almost.
She looked me in the eyes,
as if to say,
"Mr. Peppino, shall we dance"?
I understood right away.
I said neither yes nor no.
I got up,
with a certain gesture,
I went before her
and I magnetized her with one look.
She rose up, like that.
I put an arm around her waist..
- And you clasped her.
Easy.
And then we began dancing.
In the middle of it.. you know
when you start to shake.. - From cold.
From emotion.
- Of course.
African?
- Almost.
Yet, I trembled.
In conclusion,..
we were close,
the warmth, cheek to cheek, eye to eye..
Tooth to tooth.
Almost.
So, she..
She collapsed.
Then I..
"What do I do?"
I threw myself.
What a kiss!
Just imagine the kiss!
Bravo Peppino!
What did I always tell you?
"Go on. Go on!"
And the girlfriend?
- I don't like the girlfriend.
I mean, was she there too?
She was on the phone in the hallway.
And.. her?
She remained a little.. dizzy, y'know..
Then she left as if to say,
"It's better if I go."
And you?
I..
I left too.
And when do you see her again?
I don't know. They invited me
in the evening. Maybe I'll go.
You know what?
Let her wait two or three days.
You think so?
- It's better.
How come?
Peppino, you get it?
- I get it. And then?
I'm afraid to hurt her.
Is she sensitive?
- Too much so.
Then I'll give you such a scalp rub
that it'll shock you and her.
Mr. Peppino, it's done.
- Good, young man. For you.
Thank the gentleman.
- Thank you.
Goodbye.
- Bye.
Young lady, don't you recognize me?
- How could I? You look like a puppet.
But a pleasing puppet, right?
You stink, what's in your hair?
- ''Spring''.
It sucks. Aren't you ashamed at
your age? Where's your wisdom?
Listen, Elide, why do we
always have to fight?
Wouldn't it be nice to be friends?
I know you, you won't charm me again.
I don't want to charm you. It'd be so nice
to go together, mornings, afternoons,
in the evening..
How sensitive!
Would you like to go to the movies?
Yes, I would.
Wanna go?
They're showing a good movie today.
Yes? Which one?
- ''Love and Torment".
It must be nice, right?
- Very.
Wanna go?
But, alone or with company?
Well, with company.
With a handsome young man?
Hmm? Wanna go? Yes?
Merlino, bring her to the movies,
I've stuff to do.
Bring that!
We rule, Peppi! We rule!
Who is it?
Friends.
Which friends?
Peppino.
I'm not dressed.. one moment.
What do you want?
Sorry, maybe I'm mistaken.
I'm looking for Mrs. Olga and Miss Elsa.
Ah! It's Mr. Peppino, a friend of ours.
Giorgio, open it,
I'm going to make coffee.
Good evening. Come in. Please.
And the ladies?
- They're in there, they'll be out soon.
You're the one not dressed?
- Yes, Giorgio Raggi.
We have to be careful, right?
Come in! Give me your hat.
I play tennis.
- Well done. - Thank you.
If it fell on the ground..
It's brand new. - Yeah?
100? - 160.
- 160? - Yes, but it's a friend.
No ration points.
Soccer player!
- With the hands. Roojby
Please, come in.
This is another game.
Only you were missing.
Yes, it's a very interesting evening.
Eight!
- Come in!
They're all friends.
No introductions, they waste time.
A good friend.
- Good evening. - Evening.
I should've been a cardsharp.
- Here you go. Have a seat.
And Miss Elsa?
- She's making coffee with Olga.
Please make room.
Good luck, eh!
- Would you give me four of 50?
What a jinx! When it starts..
Gentlemen, your bets.
1,000 on the bank.
Your bets, gentlemen.
Thank you, 1,000 first.
How much? Three is OK?
Excuse me, sir. Sir!
Excuse me, I'm talking to you.
How much? Three?
Huh? I don't..
- Is it three?
You want five?
OK, here's five.
Five cards, eh?
You play boldly!
Well then?
- Well then?
Then, not for mistrust, but it's
the rule of the house. You pay upfront.
You pay upfront: 5000 lire.
Gentlemen, you may bet. It's on.
Please, Leila, some chocolates?
- Yes, they bring good luck.
There you go.
- Thank you.
You should never had him come.
- Come on, they won't rob him.
Moreover, they are good people.
- Not so much.
Fishmongers are rich, you know.
Well, I'm tired!
Tired of this life.
What would you do, tell me?
You won't take a lover.
you still think of that guy who left
you nothing. One has to live, no?
Gentlemen, the game is on.
Can I bet 2000 on the bank?
- Fine. 2000 lire.
God forbid!
You take them.
If I touch them, I jinx myself.
Why always me?
Yes, it's the third time you had 9.
- Go on, you got a lucky hand!
Shall we?
- Go on, take the cards.
Cross the cards! Cross them!
- Cross them.
Well, do you want cards? Yes or no?
Yes.
- No!
Don't touch them!
- Who's touching?
Eight!
Nine!
- You drew on seven, eh?
Did I do something wrong?
- Heavens, no! You're a phenomenon.
He's right. You have a lucky hand.
- A miracle of intuition! A miracle!
But it's not allowed. He drew on seven.
- It is allowed!
At Monte Carlo, a Turk drew on a nine.
- But the Turks are extraordinary.
It's you who are extraordinary!
A phenomenon, I say!
So then, do we want to play?
- He's an ace!
Mr. Peppino is such a wag.
He likes baccarat a lot.
- And you like chocolate.
That's a good one!
- It's the chocolate that's good.
How are you?
- Elsa is coming with the coffee.
Mr. Peppino, how much will you bet?
- One moment.
Want me to play for you?
Yes.
- Here she is.
Good evening.
Excuse me, if I took the liberty to..
This is for you.
- Thank you.
You know, Elsa, he's been very lucky?
- Congratulations!
I didn't mean to do it.
- Mr. Peppino!
We're losing all.
- Eh.. it doesn't matter.
Come here yourself!
- One moment.
Shall we start the table?
- As you wish.
But, if you're so lucky,
why don't you play?
I wish I'd lose.
- Why?
It's because of the proverb..
And then I didn't come to play.
Excuse me, but the maid is away, and..
I left something in the kitchen.
Damn, what bad luck!
Will you come here!
- I'm coming.
It's hopeless. Since that idiot left,
I had nothing but bad luck.
Don't let anyone out!
What's going on?
Eh, one knew that one day or
the other it would end up this way!
Two o'clock.
Where you going?
It's late.
We're leaving together.
Get in.
Go on.
What a dump!
What a perfume! We're settled!
Tomorrow morning, we'll all be out.
It's not a mistake?
- Oh, no.
We deserve this?
- We were gambling.
Then we won't get out tomorrow.
- Yes, we'll wait for the Commissioner.
You feel like crying, huh?
- Me? No, for goodness sake.
Gambling is gambling.
Thank you.
And Miss Elsa?
- She's in the women's ward.
Well, for her it's a different story.
But Olga.. She's sly.
The house is not in her name.
Oh, it's Elsa's?
- No, it's a rented flat.
But in her name.
But..
with a good lawyer..
Who knows!
Are you really sure he wasn't there?
- I'm positive.
I even went to where he buys his fish,
but they haven't seen him.
What do you think?
What do I know? I even sent Merlino to
his home to see if he was sick, but nil.
Sick? He's probably asleep
and didn't wake up. - How come?
Well, he had a certain invitation,
and probably returned late.
The same lady, eh?
If I had a stall next to yours,
I wouldn't search too far for her.
Like I care! He can do what he wants.
Hey! Miss Elide!
- Merlì!
Well? - Even the porter was angry.
- And Peppino?
I knocked and knocked,
then he said he hasn't come home.
Maybe he had an accident?
- Let's check the hospital or police.
Forget hospital, police or accident!
It's all my fault.
I should've never given him that scalp rub.
- What's that got to do with it?
Yes. For, when one wants to live that way,
one needs to have gone through storms!
And to know the ropes.
I wouldn't seek that far,
with a stall next to yours.
Lambchop, what whining!
You're boring!
Merli, is Peppino here?
- The boss isn't here. No sale today.
Why aren't you selling today?
What is this novelty?
There's just some for frying.
- So? You want some for frying?
Is it fresh? - Of course it's fresh,
it just arrived! Come on now.
How good you are.
You're all heart.
Shall I expect you for the permanent?
- Aurè, I have no wish for a perm.
Elide!
What did I tell you?
Look who's coming!
Well, how goes it?
Well? Haven't you seen me before?
We wanted to go to the police!
What do you mean?
We were worried.
You've never done that.
You were worried.
We wanted to go to the hospital too!
What's with this hospital, police..?
What's with you?
We're asking you!
You think it's fair to keep us so worried?
What am I, a kid?
Nothing happened to me.
Nothing at all.
Let's go get an espresso.
Go put the stuff in the storehouse
and then you're free. - OK.
What a big jerk!
Speak! I'm dying of curiosity.
- There's nothing to tell.
You're out all night, you return with
that face, and got nothing to tell?
Alright, I was there.
- You were there, but.. How did it go?
Fine.
It couldn't have been better.
And that's all you're telling me?
Two espressos.
- Coming up.
I want to know.. what..
- Aurè!
It's simple: dinner, records, dancing..
At a certain point, I wanted to leave..
and I was held back.
I see!
Peppino, you know what's new?
You've got a crush.
You can't do without her,
and you'll go back.
No, not today.
Indeed..
Say, do you know some lawyer?
- A lawyer?
Mama Mia! What did you do?
Why? A lawyer? What happened?
That's it, see, I knew you'd say that!
You fell for it.
Forgive me if I took the liberty to..
But, since I found out from..
I thought I'd visit you.
- Thank you.
The others were released immediately,
didn't they tell you? - No.
Didn't they come to see you?
Not even Mrs. Olga?
- Not even her.
I would've come earlier, but only
yesterday the attorney got permission..
He told me that
you'll be released in a few days.
In the end, I was the luckiest of all.
I got out first.
You must forgive me if, for my fault,..
Heavens, what are you saying?
For me, it was..
like an entertainment.
How good you are!
- It doesn't take much to be good with you.
But if you only knew how
much bad they've done me.
If it weren't for him.
Poor little one!
A child?
Yes.
And.. is he with his father?
No, I no longer know anything about him.
He left for Milan because of..
financial trouble.
For a few months he wrote me,
also sending something for the baby.
But then, that too came to an end.
So I was alone in Rome.
I happened to meet Olga, and..
the rest..
you can imagine.
And the child.. where is he?
In Abruzzo. With a good woman.
Indeed, I wrote her that
I'd go see him within the week.
But now..
Who knows when?
You want me to go? When I return
I can give you news about the child.
I really like children.
Write down the address here.
You won't tell that woman that I..
- Mrs. Elsa, are we kidding?
I'll tell her that..
Leave it to me.
Bianchini, we have to go.
Thank you.
What's the kid's name?
Carletto.
Carletto!
Carletto! Carletto! Carletto!
Carletto, where are you hiding?
Oh, finally!
I've been calling you for an hour.
Why didn't you answer?
Come!
Come and see who's here.
Look what a big boy he's become!
You put them into the world and
don't expect them to grow like that.
Yeah. You don't expect it.
Feel, feel how much he weighs.
Oh, my goodness!
Wow, how much you weigh!
Yes, yes. Be good. Be good.
My husband's father.
He's a bit touched.
Carletto, don't act like that!
If you knew who this gentleman is!
I prepared everything: t-shirts,
woolen socks.. I couldn't find one.
Shall I put the coat in?
- No, it's cold, he'd better wear it.
THE TRUMPET!!!!
He wants the trumpet, it's his passion.
Teresa, go fetch it.
Here is the milk! It's still warm.
- Yes, that's fine.
You'd better bring some milk.
He may get hungry on the train.
Why, is he leaving?
- With you, right? - With me?
We wrote it in the letter.
Teresa and I are leaving tomorrow.
My husband was drafted
and we go to work in a shop.
THE TRUMPET!!!!
Here's the trumpet.
Didn't you get the letter?
Oh, yeah. I forgot. How stupid of me.
I thought it was for another month..
Carletto, let's go.
It makes me sad, I love him so much.
Now you put your coat on, Carletto.
Come, Teresa, let's go.
Excuse us, we'll be right back.
What's with him? - Since you haven't
recognized your child, he's cussing at you.
You hear?
You must pity him, he has a bad temper.
You see him now. But when young,
with a punch he could flatten a bull.
Giovanni!
- Coming. Excuse me. Here I am!
What a mess!
What a scare you got!
Watch out, you can fall.
Be careful, eh?
See the sunshine?
Give me the trumpet.
- No.
Give it. - No!
- Give it to me.
Watch it, you can hurt yourself.
- No!
You stupid!
- What? Am I stupid?
I'm a stupid?
What are you, crazy? - But who made
this trumpet? - Are you crazy? Darn!
Give it to me, come on!
- Damn it!
Who made this trumpet?
Later. I'll give you something else.
A nice thing. You want it?
Gimme.
- No.
- I'll give you..
What can I give you?
Are you nuts?
Some chocolates!
You like chocolates?
Chocklits!
- Chocolates? - Gimme.
But you mustnt play anymore.
They must be here.
It'd be just great if I couldn't find it.
Look at this mess!
Seek and ye shall not find.
Under my eyes for three months,
now that I seek it I can't find it.
It's probably on the ground.
It must be lost.
And now?
- And now?
I must find it. It must be here.
Where did it go?
Here it is. It was inside
this sock. Here it is!
Gimme!
- Will you give me a chuckle, eh?
No fingers in the nose!
Come and get it!
I'm coming and getting it!
No more.
No more.. Ow!
I'll make you a hole,
I'll make a hole in your belly!
Hold still!
Here, you see?
Gimme.
Who can it be?
- Who knows?
Who cares?
- Here. Here it is!
Did you get it?
- Here it is.
You be good and I'll see who it is.
Keep sitting just like that.
Just like that.
I'll be back soon.
- Gimme dat trumpet!
Starting that again?
Just be good.
Be good. Act like a little gentleman.
Let me see the gentleman.
I'll be...
I'm coming.
Who is it?
- Open up!
But, who is it?
- Come on, make no fuss!
Less chatter!
Here I am, excuse me.
Excuse me, lives here, Mr..
You're always joking!
- You fell for it, didn't you?
You have a guilty conscience, young man.
Tell me the truth: Scared, huh?
How are you?
- Fine. I came to see you.
Late last night you weren't there.
You've become a mystery man.
You sneak about, we don't see you.
But I'm an old friend, I've the right..
You're right, but you know how it is,
one has stuff to do, and..
I'm in a hurry.
- Then, you won't ask me in?
Where? I have to get dressed
and go to the market.
What's this? - A trumpet.
- What are you doing with it?
I'm studying music.
The trumpet?
- It's a musical instrument, isn't it?
Be honest, I'm interrupting.
You got it.
Well, blow me down!
Who is it? That girl?
- Another one. - Another!
Hot damn!
Is she beautiful?
Let me take a peek..
THE TRUMPET!!!
Is she young?
- Yeah.. you see..
Ah! Peppi!
- Ah, Aurelio, see you later.
What did he do?
Hey! What did you do?
You broke the vase? Eh? Are you crazy?
Tell me!
You broke it!
- Me? I broke the vase?
You slap me and tell me lies?
What have you done?
Here's what happened:
I'll have to post an ad.
"Whoever lost baby on tram please
retrieve him at Piazza Cancelleria 3".
Come on!
Yes, that's right. You know
what it's like on a tram? - What?
The tickets, the confusion,
the conversation..
What conversation? - Why?
There's no conversation on the tram?
Fine, there is.
- You act like I was lying.
A shove and suddenly, you look:
you have a child in your arms.
In your arms? On the bus?
- Why? That never happened to you?
Not me.
- Well, it has to me.
Then after the push,
I got off, in the dark..
It was dark?
On the bus?
No, when I got off. There's no light.
Wartime blackout.
"Is this your child?"
- No. - "No".
What do I do, throw it away? A child?
- So you kept him.
There he is.
Here he is. - Here he is.
- The trumpet.
He's never still.
You know my personality,
I can't stand kids.
But he's cute, eh?
How.. how rude!
Lambchop, to get too close is dangerous.
He has some slap in him!
Two slaps!
Whose baby could he be?
Well.. who knows?
Tomorrow, we'll see.
Yeah, let me tell you..
Nowadays, anything can happen.
Did he sleep here?
- Yes.
Yes.
And this was your idea, right?
I had to, as you can see.
And you'll bring him with you?
- Of course. Do I leave him alone?
But first I'd like to give him a bath.
Yes. Let's give him a bath.
Let's.
Fine. Give me a hand.
No, give me a hand to bathe him.
- Is there gas?
Yes, but we need..
We need to do it right away
or there won't be any left. Come!
What do we do?
- Put the water in the pot.
What's the water like?
- Rotten.
Damn, it's cold.
- That's why we'll heat it up.
Stupids!
What do you have against us?
- Your brains.
Oh, well..
At most, it'll boil in 15 minutes.
I said 15 minutes, instead it took
less than an hour and a half.
It's boiling!
Get the spaghetti!
Damn it!
Here we are.
It's ready. Ready.
They're draining!
And now, Carletto,
we'll give you a little bath.
Ah, so you even know his name?
- Yes. He told me himself.
Which he? The driver of the tram?
- No, him, Carletto.
If you can't believe a child,
then it's the end of the world.
And the soap?
Beats me.
We'll try a substitute.
What are you doing?
- I'll give him a shave.
If you don't mind, this is my field.
Now then, we'll put this here.
What a nice almond scented bath!
Peppino, smell this perfume.
Here, Carletto, over here!
Turn over! And we'll do the bottom, too!
We'll even shave him against the growth.
Be careful of the pimples!
Dry him well.
Be good!
Get the talcum powder.
- What talcum powder? I've some flour..
Well, get it, it's all the same.
Hurry.
See how we treat you?
With white flour.
Peppi! You have a little oil?
We'll fry him!
Close your eyes! Close your eyes!
It's late, I got to go.
If you're quick, I'll wait.
I have stuff to do. - What?
You said you were going to the market.
Well.. I have to get dressed
and give the baby to the porter.
Why the porter?
Did you really believe
I found him on the tram?
Ah, Lambchop!
- My name is Aurelio.
My name is Aurelio.
- No! - Yes! - No!
Both of you stink.
You're nice instead!
Say!
If you see Merlino,
tell him to put my stall out. - OK.
How cute!
Mrs. Pè!
Mrs. Peppa!
Yeah, what do you want?
- Please, come down for a minute.
What is it? What's the matter?
Nothing. I want you to see..
to see.
I want you to see some business.
OK, I'm coming down.
- Thank you.
Can I fill it?
All like that! They fill, and my bucket is
never filled. I've been here a half hour!
It's two hours! How long does it take?
- Everybody does what they like.
Come on, for a drop of water!
See, they get angry as well.
Get out of here!
- Like it's killing you!
Even the kids don't respect you.
But.. - Quiet! You were here first, why
didn't you fill the bucket? Why? Come on!
You were here first, that's it!
They wait!
Me, as well, Mr. Peppìn?
- For you, it's different.
After her, nobody else, got it?
- Got it.
What do you get? Get the tray of fish,
and we'll wash them here.
Does your lady know
that you eat her apples?
This one she gave to me.
Want a little bite?
After you.
No, where you bit it.
What manners!
What's with you?
The fountains are made for water,
not for chitchat.
I had to wash the apple.
- Don't wash it, it's tastier that way.
But, ma'am!
- What "ma'am", I'm a "miss".
Go home instead of
staying here like an idiot!
"A little bite"!
I'll give you a little bite.
I'm leaving because I want to, got it?
- Better you just go.
We laid on the jealousy
just a little strong there.
Jealous, me?
Keep on dreaming!
What is it then?
- That fresh girl gets on my nerves.
I bump into her everywhere!
Oh, I see.. And what are we here for?
- To wash broccoli.
Why didn't you bring your bucket?
- Why? - That one is mine.
Oh, so it's yours?
I'd make you a nice hat out of it.
Say, we don't want our heads to end
up under the fountain now, do we?
Mr. Peppino, is it filled?
- Yes, it is. Go. I'll take care of it.
Fine.
Careful now because
the famous mullets have arrived.
Oh, yeah?
You know I'm really sick of this?
-So?
You and your damn mullets! Here,
take them on your face! - You crazy nut!
Let me go, you're hurting me!
- I'll put your head under the fountain.
Mr. Peppino, what are you doing?
- We were joking. Why, what's it to you?
What do you want? Get the hell out of here!
One can't have a few words in peace!
Do as you please.
See how you make me look?
What vulgarity!
I'm ashamed like a thief.
You should be ashamed
of the life you lead.
It's no use, nothing to do.
You'll never learn.
What should I learn?
To be well-mannered, refined.
It takes some polish.
If you knew what it means to a man.
I'm made like this.
I have no polish.
I'm not one of those.
- Yet, I like just those.
Go to them then.
What are you waiting for?
I will, don't doubt it.
I can hardly wait.
- Go on, then.
Go. What are you doing here?
Why don't you go?
Come on, I'm here now, don't be silly.
- Don't touch me.
Do I annoy you?
- What do I care? Your loss.
You'll see what happen.
Calm down, young lady,
nothing will happen.
Mr. Peppino!
Finally I found you!
I'm very sorry, my dear Peppino,
but when I said yes this morning,
I didn't know any better.
This is not a child,
this is the Apocalypse!
For heaven's sake, don't say a word.
Sorry, but...
I even had a fight with my husband.
Here's to you. Keep him well!
Ah, thank God!
What is there to look at here? Eh?
What is it? You've never seen
a man holding a baby before?
Everybody spellbound?
Is there anything extraordinary?
Is he yours?
- Yes, why?
Is that so strange? Ever seen him before?
- No.
Of course, he arrived this morning
on furlough. Wanna know more?
Peppi! Peppi, what happened?
She brought him back? So it's yours?
Yes, it's mine. And I've got 20 more,
got it? 20 more!
Well, why?
Somebody not like that?
Wherever I roam, I have kids!
- What a rogue!
What are you doing? - Nothing.
What I'm doing is plain to see.
What're you looking at?
What do you want? - Like I care!
Look at these open mouths! How cute!
With those mouths you look like toys!
Am I a freak? Look at me for the last
time for you'll never see me again!
Never again! I'm leaving! Goodbye!
Did you know? - About what?
- Mr. Peppino.
It seems he'll marry a millionaire.
- A countess!
He was always crazy about the nobility.
He got his wish.
- Imagine how jealous Elide is.
You guys know nothing.
- That's the latest news!
What millionaire? She's a slut who eats
up all his money and gets him drunk.
Really? - If he keeps it up he'll land
in jail. Indeed, he already did.
What a big mouth!
- It's the truth.
None of it is true.
Because he has a kid with this woman.
And sluts don't have kids.
Hey, are you finished over there?
Shall we go on? Gossips!
He's probably gone.
But at least, he should've written me
saying he's well and hi to his friends.
Why, where is he?
- No one knows.
No, I was just saying.
It was just a supposition.
Dear Elide, there's nothing to do.
Who cares? The less I see him, the better.
I pity that poor wretch.
Did he put the kid in boarding school?
- Who knows? He didn't tell me anything.
Yet he used to tell me everything.
But he never told me he had a baby.
A mystery.
That guy shouldn't be left alone.
Lambchop, knock it off!
Mr. Aurè, people in the shop.
Male or female?
- Seems a lady.
Age?
- What do I know?
I'll be right there.
If I may.
Anyway, Elide.. I'm there for you too.
- I'll come later.
Excuse me.
Merlì! - What?
- Listen.
You gotta find him. - But I..
- For your own good, understand?
Here's 50 lire. Go to the police,
go to hospital, wherever.
Take a taxi, a tram, but don't return
until you find out what happened.
I'll be right there, ma'am.
In a blink of an eye.
You played a joke on me, eh?
This is for the lady.
You fell for it, Lambchop, eh? - Ah!
Finally, we remembered we had friends?
They're all asking about you. Have you
seen Merlì? Up and down looking for you.
Really, who else you want to conquer?
Aren't you satisfied?
You want all the women for yourself?
Are you really trying to beat me?
I've beaten you for some time,
Lambchop, I rule.
Suit, shirt, tie: all new, eh?
Even the shoes! Come on,
you must create your masterpiece today.
As you wish, take a seat sir!
Make me gorgeous, fragrant, a superb
scalp rub. Today is a great day.
What are you up to?
You found another kid?
- No, Lambchop.
If you weren't so mouthy, I'd tell you.
No need to speak. Just looking at you
I realize you're more hooked than ever.
Am I wrong?
- You're not, that's it.
Is it the young lady of the fine?
Didn't you tell me that.. - What I said
doesn't matter, she's really a good girl.
Then that child was hers? - Yes,
but now I love him as if he were my own.
You should've heard him calling me Papa!
The gentleman is served!
Now, I can only wish you good luck.
Your wishes later today, young man.
In my new apartment!
High places!
You should see how nice it is.
It's got everything: radiator, lift,
bar, salon.. And then, what a street!
Via Roberto Mauro.
What a name.
It smacks of cologne.
And the number: 72-A!
- Ah!
Then there's a maid:
if you saw her, you'd faint.
Wait a second.
You're more handsome than the sun!
- We always rule, little one!
Always Peppi.
Even too much.
Dear Lambchop, even though
I were not to come back here,
I'm leaving my heart in this chair.
And you don't forget to dust it, OK kid?
Here.
This is for you personally.
Thank you. It's a tip!
Shall we do this permanent?
- Right away. It's all at your disposal.
We finally decided, eh?
Elide!
Come on, give me your hand.
I don't like to stay like this.
Today I don't want to see long faces.
Don't look in the mirror then.
Aurelio! 72-A!
Elide?
Miss Elide?
Elide!
This way.
It's the day of the masterpieces, eh?
I'll take first prize, today.
Did you see how I served Peppino?
How content he was!
He was happy.
Today, everybody's happy.
Instead, I must work in this shop
from morning til night.
Whereas I'd like to go to the movies,
the theater. Enjoy myself a little.
Today, at the Savoy Cinema, there's a film.
I'd really like to see that film.
But, alone..
I had to go with Peppino. But he had
things to do, "A great day for me".
Indeed, he asked me to go to his home.
His new home: 72-A.
He wants to introduce me to somebody.
How's the movie like? Good?
It's wonderful.
Shall we go?
Wouldn't you like to, with me?
- You bet!
Damn, I rule!
Then we'll meet at 5 o'clock
sharp at the Savoy? Great!
Mr. Peppino.
Well, shall we go?
I don't like this street.
I'd like to drop in at home and
leave immediately to go to Carletto.
No, don't go home.
You might run into Olga.
You'd better not see her.
I.. I took the liberty..
I fixed you up a room.
For you alone.
There you can rest,..
and..
and maybe tomorrow go to Carletto.
Have you lived here long?
- Three days. That is, three months.
The apartment is small,
but nicely partitioned.
And there's a lot of light.
As if it's always noon.
Welcome, ma'am.
Careful, it's slippery.
What a mess!
Carletto!
Oh, Carletto, my Carletto!
What could he break?
- I'm afraid it's the vase with flowers.
Damn it!
Wait for me in the dining room.
- Yes, sir.
I'll be right back.
Yes, darling, mama has come to get you!
And she'll never leave you again.
Papa!
Have you kept him with you all this time?
- Yes.
He must have driven you crazy, I guess.
- No, we soon came to an understanding.
How good you are!
- Not true, I'm trouble if I get angry.
Right, Carletto?
- The vase was like that!
Carletto, Carletto.. Don't tell lies!
Or the wolf will come and eat you.
What a pity!
Come on!
Apologize to Mr. Peppino.
No apologies. We'll buy another one,
right, Carletto?
Now, if I may, I'll go in
the other room, I must..
But I'll be back soon. - Please.
- Excuse me. - Yes.
Oh! By the way, there's mail for you.
A telegram and three letters.
The porter gave them to me.
Mail!
- Thank you.
While you read, I'll be inside..
Mystery!
I'll be right back.
Piero!
Good, good, good, there's everything:
butter, jam, cookies..
I also found three eggs, you see?
- Wow! Bravo!
And this? - No, this has to be brought as
last to create an effect, see? - Right.
Now put it somewhere, then,
when I give you a nod, you show up..
you know, with a bow,..
That's it. I leave it to you, eh?
- OK.
So, shall we go to the dining room?
It's him!
Him who?
Carletto's father.
The child's father. He wants to see him.
He seems sincere this time.
He says he can no longer live far away,
and is full of hope.
And he says that close to me..
What do you think?
Of course, close to you..
Where is the Milan Hotel?
Do you have a phone?
I'd better call him, right?
And then, if he wants to see the baby!
The phone is in the hall.
Papa! Hey!
Hello? Hello?
Yes, it's me, Elsa.
Carletto? He's here with me, he's fine.
Yes, I'll tell you everything. All.
You want to? Right away?
I'll take a taxi, 15 minutes at most.
Sooner?
I don't know.
I'll do what I can.
Goodbye.
Yes.
I'm sorry, but I must leave.
I must go right away.
Yes. It's better.
Please, the child's coat and hat.
- Alright, ma'am.
He's at the Milan Hotel.
Will I find a taxi?
I hope so. He wanted to come here,
but it's better that I go.
He's impatient to see me.
We're going to see dad!
Hold still, honey, we must hurry.
What a nice fur jacket with a hood!
How nice!
- With a white hood!
Yes! Papa will love it!
How nice, my Carletto!
Oh, my dear!
I'll call you before I leave.
He wants me to go to Milan with him.
Your phone number?
35-4-6-1.
- I won't forget it.
Thank you.
For everything.
Come here.
Papa!
Come on, Carletto.
We'll be right back.
Isn't it true that we'll be back?
Yes, it's better that you go.
And then he was naughty today!
You broke the vase!
I don't wanna see you anymore!
So then, Mr. Peppino?
What should I do?
Nothing.
Today you're free.
And tomorrow as well.
Indeed, forever.
Here's what I promised you.
But..
- But. You did what you had to do, right?
I'm very sorry.
- What for?
# But, if you're not here with me,
I can no longer live,
# you are life to me.
# Only you can give me happiness
# that my heart no longer has
away from you.
# Trembles at night,
the light of the stars,
# looking at them, I try to dream.
# But, if you're not here with me,
I can no longer live,
# you are life to me, you are love.
Is Mr. Peppino Corradini here?
- He's inside. In the salon.
Well then.
Here we are.
Well?
Well? Well what?
- What do you mean "what"?
Oh, right.
I promised you a surprise.
You thought you'd find a lady?
Instead there's nobody.
I'm alone.
Alone.
More surprise than this!
Well, not bad as gimmick. Bravo!
Lambchop, you believed it?
Tell me the truth, you fell for it?
I blew everything, Lambchop!
Everything!
You really think I could be tied
to one woman all my life? Me?
To play the good husband? Me?
I laugh at the thought. Can you imagine
me leading a family life, all serious?
Lunch for two, digesting on
the armchair, reading books..
Ah, Lambchop! How could I give
up freedom, the life that we live?
I quickly realized what a mistake
I was making. What a mistake!
The poor thing didn't want to go,
but I spoke bluntly.
Nicely and with finesse, but clearly.
"But, lady,
you really think you can stay here?"
Oh, no.
Free!
For heaven's sake, free!
She was beautiful, yes..
and even refined.
But she's only one, and men
like us need many, Lambchop.
And then that kid, mama mia!
How he had bored me!
"Chocolates, trumpet, papa!"
I almost slapped that rascal! Get out!
What do women want from us, Lambchop?
What?
Forget marriages, husbands,
children, relatives!
We're not the type!
They're all slaves!
- All the same, even the ladies.
You're telling me? A martyr?
They'll do anything. Even be brought
to the movies to spite someone!
Freedom, freedom, no strings attached.
Ah, Peppì, far better with humble women!
Sometimes they're not
up to our level, true.
But at least they're good girls.
And they don't give surprises.
I feel reborn, Lambchop. I'm cured.
We have to celebrate, where do we go?
Wherever you want.
Oh,..
I can't.
If only I had known.
Lambchop, don't leave me.
Don't leave me alone today.
I can't.. Peppi, I swear..
it's not possible, I'm busy.
She's a foreigner.
You know: "Mon cheri, mon amour.
Be with me, with me. Oui, oui! Wa, wa!"
When they find out you speak foreign,
they won't leave you alone.
Yeah, it's a pain!
- Yeah, a pain indeed! You're right!
You're right, what do these
women want from us? What?
Don't they know that we're rulers?
We rule!
Indeed, you know what?
The foreign lady is awaiting me
at the Savoy at five.
Well, I won't go.
I'll make her wait!
You rule, Peppi?
- Strongly. And you?
I feel like a lion. - Lambchop,
we're born and we'll die rulers.
We rule! - We rule!
WE RULE!
SHATTERED LOVE
Madame.
Aurelio said he had a date
around here with a foreigner..
and since I get by with all languages..
So, you've decided to get back
in the lower districts. - Yeah.
Wow, how elegant!
What a beautiful coat!
You look taller.
You took off the low heels, eh?
What became of that disheveled girl?
What lovely hair!
- This is nothing.
You'll see tomorrow!
I'm gonna have it dyed: Titian red.
They told me it would suit me.
What do you think?
Well, I say it's time to call it quits.
Elide, should we talk seriously?
- Seriously? What happened to you?
Nothing happened to me.
And it is precisely for this...
The film begins, I don't want to miss it.
See you.
And who's leaving you?
Mind you, it's a sad film.
With an ending that makes you cry.
Why, how does it end?
With a marriage.
Take off those gloves!
Well? Are we starting?
W-e  r-u-l-e
English subtitles @KG by
sineintegral & edam17.