Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Josef, what are you doing?
- I want to protect myself.
- From what?
I don't know what exactly.
If you do not know what you are doing,
take your hand away, you look a fool.
There is diseases out there.
Who told you that?
I can smell it in the air.
Only disease is the smell of those
who do not conform to our chosen society.
Take it away.
Well, if there is a disease,
maybe I can help them.
There are some things you cannot control.
I won't ask again.
Hello, Sylwia.
Oh.
Shh.
Mother, you are an inspiration to me.
A giver of life.
What's wrong?
God is a giver of life.
And I am merely an assistant.
I cannot be responsible
for the achievement
of the mothers who give birth.
Come.
Let me show you something.
Life. We often forget that life
from birth needs nurturing.
Consistent care, from birth until death.
The Lord gives us the opportunity,
the start, the tools
to nurture future lives.
We must care for not only the poor,
sick and weak.
Each life without care
can become poor, sick and weak.
What I do is just a small role
at the beginning.
The stone entered the water,
it's the beginning.
Creator of the energy to make the ripples.
I assisted the beginning.
The ripples are life itself,
of which I have no control.
The stone, I had no part in its creation
and the ripples are beyond my control.
The Lord creates the stone.
And the Lord determines
the duration of the ripples.
It cannot last forever.
Why another stone?
We are the ripples. Are you?
Let's enjoy you.
Get it out. That's fine.
You can make as much noise as you wish.
The baby will be with you very soon.
It's time.
That's it. That's right.
Almost over. Now, push.
Now my dear, one small push.
It's the placental expulsion.
So?
Twins.
Twins?
Bring me as many twins as you can.
Why twins?
If they are not blond
and blue-eyed, or twins...
you drown them.
Your role of midwife...
has changed.
How so?
I need you to help me with something else.
Just as important.
More important, in fact.
You are here for your crimes
but... not for your ethnicity.
Child killing?
- How many abortions...
- I...
It's OK.
We all make mistakes.
However, we have to learn from them.
This is why I need you.
You taught yourself how to kill a child.
That makes us have a similar interest.
Expect my children are Jews and Gypsies.
You like killing children?
For research, of course.
I get to make my mistakes
and learn from them.
Especially on these Jews.
We have many to choose from.
For fun? No.
But to help the future of Germany
and to ensure good health
for the future generations
of the thousand-year Reich,
I would do... anything.
And so must you.
But I'm a midwife?
A good midwife
with many years of experience.
Many of which, mostly successful.
Obviously, the conditions here
do not help and...
I will, of course, do as you say.
I have no right to disagree
with any of your orders.
- I am just a midwife.
- Not anymore!
Too afraid to look at me?
You will have to look at God one day
and explain why you are a child killer.
Medical research
will be my answer.
And your answer will be?
Can I ask why I was taken
from my midwife duties?
41335, Stanisława Leszczyńska.
A Catholic?
- Occupation?
- Dressmaker.
Dressmakers.
- Occupation?
- Dressmaker.
Bless us, O Lord, for these dying gifts.
Which we are about to receive
through thy bounty.
Through Christ, our Lord.
Amen.
She should be dead.
She has lied about her occupation
but has come to us with the offer
and honesty of her true occupation.
She is a midwife and she isn't a Jew.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women.
And blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, mother of God.
Pray for our sinners.
Now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
She is highly accomplished.
She will do her duties
and you will do yours.
Duties?
Drown the offspring of these parasites.
Being rid of them early is the only way
to cut these leeches from our lives.
From existence.
Once I have,
where do you want me to put them?
Do you want me to bring them to you?
Most certainly not!
You will need some help, too.
Who do you have in mind?
Sister Pfani.
She is a strong woman.
Most prostitutes are.
But, doctor, I am still unsure.
Where do you want the children to go?
After we have killed them?
Feed them to the dogs or the rats.
I don't care.
Typhus will kill us
before the SS will at this rate.
You think I'm a sinner?
What I think has no relevance here.
If the world needs to be clean
of the Jews,
then so be it.
Amen.
27893.
Remove this. Get me another.
No prayers today, my dear?
I gave up praying a while ago.
And has that made a difference
to your life?
Just as much difference as praying did.
Faith is all that will
get us through this.
Tell that to my family.
Taken.
All of them.
And they left you all alone?
Yes.
So that means
even more reason to pray, no?
There comes a time
when your mind can't accept hope
and optimism.
We need to fight through this.
We need to work together.
You're a stranger.
Strangers are those
who want to separate us.
Our family
are those who sit in the ark together.
Ark? This is slaughter.
What is this?
My paperwork.
And the 15 different names?
You help these pigs?
Why?
You know that falsification of documents
is against the Third Reich.
And punishment is death for treason.
You want to help the Jews?
I will allow you to.
You will travel with them on the train.
The train?
Your new home.
Regular work.
Food and plenty of opportunities
to help the Jews.
But I have a family.
Your family too.
It's OK.
Nice?
Good. Good.
These women need these for their babies.
But they also need the bread.
We all need bread.
It's OK, my dear.
We're all hungry here.
I'm sure it will be met with need
rather than greed.
Thank you.
God bless you.
I...
killed... my...
child.
My...
intention...
was not...
to kill... my...
child.
Can you pass the water, please?
Dr Mengele is waiting.
Run along. Fetch the water.
Why?
I'm sorry.
Shh. Rest.
You will be with your child very soon.
You see.
We remove a piece of the skin on the back,
the wrists and the back of the calf muscle
on both subjects.
Then we simply attach them to each other
back to back.
Attach them?
But surely this...
they will reject each other?
In theory, yes.
But if twins are identical
from the same egg,
mono twins can be conjoined in the womb,
so why not outside the womb?
I... What about infection?
This will not
allow you to test this theory
and it will make it difficult to rule out
whether it is rejection or infection.
You are absolutely right.
But we have quite a few.
It's me or typhus. So, why waste them?
No, it is very true.
17854.
Bring me the twin boys.
and 648323.
You refuse an order from me?
No, Artz Mengele.
Look at me!
36543.
Bring me 20 children
and line them up outside.
Yes, Dr Mengele.
I know. I know.
You want to save your people.
You wish for liberation
and freedom.
Well, I am afraid to tell you
that Germany rules the world
and will do for at least a thousand years.
When I give an order
you must follow.
The children, you...
personally are responsible
for their death now.
20 children for your defiance.
But they would have died anyway,
so don't feel too bad about it
and they won't feel a thing.
A simple injection to the heart.
Now...
I will try again.
OK?
Get me the twin boys.
Yes, Artz Mengele!
I need your help.
The milk. There is not enough.
The baby will need more
when Klara returns from sick bay.
My dear.
And I have been drying this on my back.
Just like you told me.
My dear, listen to me.
May I have another piece of bread?
But I must have another diaper.
Eat the bread.
It is for the baby.
The baby is with the Lord.
But Klara said...
Klara is untruthful, not to be trusted.
She is with the Lord now.
You have been given the responsibility
of midwife here.
And I understand your deliveries are many?
In order to monitor the survival rate
and to test the resilience
of mothers and children,
for the purposes of future research,
can you please tell me how many
of your 1,800 deliveries were stillborn?
Come along.
How many?
None.
All the children were born alive and well.
Your delinquent behavior astounds me.
You were ordered to register
all births as stillborn,
yet I see from this list...
that all the children were born alive.
You may be a good midwife
but I do assure you,
you won't last very long here
if you persist like this.
I witness many atrocities here.
Life tends to find a way.
Even under the conditions,
the life starts.
No different from an animal in the wild.
Although a wild animal
can forage for food,
a mother cannot.
I understand that you would like for me
to declare the baby dead once born.
But if they are alive...
I will not.
OK.
Let's begin at the beginning.
I'm intrigued by your... research.
My research is merely fact.
None of the children were born still
and all the mothers
also survived the birth.
One thousand eight hundred and twenty four
of my patients and their children
all survived...
the birth, that is.
The intervention of the SS to those lives
after that, I cannot say.
It's impossible.
Even the finest German physician
could not claim such a success rate.
The mothers' suffering is beyond belief.
The children are drowned in the...
I see that many of your patients
are marked as suffering
from the influenza virus.
Surely it's typhus?
No.
Although my midwife title
stays my profession,
it does not state my experience.
These women just have the flu.
You do understand the consequences
of lying, don't you?
I understand.
Good.
These people...
it is essential that they are eliminated.
To prevent the spread
of this foul disease.
It's all very confusing.
What is?
The process.
To avoid cross-contamination.
But to work everyone to death.
Dr Mengele has a very keen interest
in certain children.
Twins.
We would appreciate it
if you would notify us of such births.
Also all children with blond hair
or blue eyes.
For Germanization.
Ahh, you see.
Those can be saved.
Miss Janina.
I cannot fathom
what I have just been informed of.
I'm sure nothing you are going to say
will surprise me but...
you have my attention.
Where to start.
Doesn't the fact that we are here
surprise you?
This is beyond anything
of our imagination.
This is not a war of countries.
This is a war against humanity.
Walk with me.
This is more safe than inside.
Do you think
we're safer out here, in the open?
I would rather risk being caught outside
by an SS officer
than anyone hearing of the atrocities
that are being conducted on them
that lay dying only feet away from us.
You think I'm not aware of the disease?
Of the famine? Of the gas,
Mrs Leszczyńska?
This entire place has no room.
Stop for a moment and smell the air.
Take it in. Tell me, what is it?
Death.
Death is what we know.
Evil is what is coming.
Evil is already here.
It has been from the beginning.
I know this entire place is more evil than
anything in all of my years
I could have ever imagined.
They aren't just killing the children.
They're experimenting on them.
Selecting twins.
I hear experimentation,
although I cannot be sure of this.
The risk of not assuming is too high
for innocent lives to be wasted.
Along with this, I have been ordered
to deliver all children with blond hair
and blue eyes
directly to the superior.
A puzzle that cannot be solved.
Hitler is of small build,
dark hair, dark eyes
and wants to create a race
opposite himself?
I thought you were going to mention
the rise in typhus.
This is a serious issue
that is affecting the whole camp.
To liquidize anyone
who has a typhoid virus.
They could recover.
I am willing to disobey
in the hope that we can save
as many lives as we possibly can.
But how can you guarantee that disease
will not spread further?
We do not have medicine.
Are you suggesting that we kill
our future generation of mothers
out of laziness
just in case it spreads?
No.
But to risk the lives of everyone else.
The sick are in our hands.
The innocent children.
The twins. The fair.
What do you suggest we do to help?
Do we not have any power?
Any say?
Why did you bring me here?
To make you aware that we are in charge
of ensuring that the future mothers
who are sick are our responsibility.
If we can continue to help every mother
survive their flu,
safely deliver their children
and make sure every child
delivered is delivered alive,
we live in hope that these children
can live a long, happy and Nazi-free life.
If we forget to look for that hope,
we may as well forget our sanity.
I am sorry, Stanislawa.
Sorry for what?
Sorry that...
The realization of this
has only just been delivered to you.
You know about this?
I'm a doctor, you're a midwife.
You are the angel of life.
Mengele, the angel of death.
Of course, there is a group resistance
in here.
And when it is possible, they will resist.
Too soon... they will die.
Too late...
they will die.
We have no power.
We have no choice but...
to do our duty and...
deal with this
in the best way that we can.
Stanislawa.
You work tirelessly day and night.
You too need to rest or you will not
be fit enough to care for these women
and children.
You are saving two at a time.
Without you...
they would die.
Especially if Sister Klara took control
of delivering the babies again.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
Do you think this will ever end?
It must.
And it will.
One way or another we...
we will be free from this place.
We are the survivors
and whether we live or die...
we will have helped others to survive.
And they in turn will help out others.
So you see all we need to do is...
continue with our work,
whatever Mengele is doing.
We have no control.
Are you OK?
Of course.
I'm tired but I'm fine.
Take care of yourself.
We need you.
How are you doing today?
Issue with...
voice box.
Voice box.
He speaks!
How are you feeling
about the surgery today?
What are you going to do to me?
Well, a wise man once said
that curiosity killed the cat.
Just as well I'm not working with felines,
isn't it?
Why?
Well, well, well.
You feel you are entitled
to ask me such a question?
No, Dr Mengele.
Farming.
My father. A hobby
that went on to be big business
producing farm machinery in Germany.
However, farming was not the fascination.
Medicine was my focus.
To assess and deliver
extraordinary results.
University taught me the basics.
Everything that a young medical student
would desire to know.
Human genetics.
They are most baffling.
Constantly changing factors to discover.
I served my time.
For the Nazi Party, of course.
Even after I was wounded,
I remained true to my leader
and my people.
My goal has always been
to increase the world's knowledge
on the biggest mystery
we have yet to solve.
The human race.
Why we get sick.
Why we dysfunction.
Why we die.
And why the Jews
are such a disability to the world.
To help the imperfect.
To create a race of people
who do not fear for their imminent death
by natural selection.
Your blood is beautiful...
but wasted.
Dr Mengele, may I ask you
why you are putting the subject to sleep?
If I am to make any use of a fail first
I must make sure
that the second is not far behind.
The results can be used
accurately this way.
So, what would you like me
to do with them?
Stop the heart of this little one.
Dissect and label the parts
individually for measurements.
We shall begin testing
while the blood is still warm.
The measurements of the organs
is of great interest to me.
You need to quieten down.
No, no.
You don't understand
the pain I am feeling right now.
You will stop this selfishness at once!
Screaming is only going to bring attention
and attention is not what you
or your baby needs right now.
You need to move to the furnace.
He is coming. I cannot move.
You are one of the lucky ones.
The fire in the furnace only burns
a few times a year.
Most of the women around you
have dealt with the cold icy conditions
this camp enjoys to torture us with.
So, for you and your baby,
let's move.
He's coming.
Slowly.
That's it.
I need you to breath.
What's wrong?
You're suffering from preeclampsia.
The blood pressure is too high.
If we don't deliver this baby right now,
you and your baby are both at risk.
The next contraction, I need you to push.
Just take a nice deep...
That's it, keep pushing!
Every life is as precious as the next.
I cannot guarantee that life
will last longer than this moment.
But if I can bring a mother
and her child together
for any amount of time,
then I have done my duties.
Keep her safe.
Keep her hidden.
Keep her alive.
I will go.
You feed the dogs.
Hello, sir.
Now, before we start,
you know what you paid for?
All look. No touch.
Or big man finds out.
And we don't want that happening,
do we now?
I hear you have package for me?
It's a shame I won't be able
to see what's inside.
For a price.
Double it.
And you can do whatever you like.
I want you to dance.
And I haven't got all day.
You are a dancer, correct?
So dance.
Go.
We should be ready for phase two.
It is time.
Record the time of removal.
21:47.
Which will make it
50 minutes in immersion.
Still alive.
Just.
- How long was the last subject?
- 57 minutes.
So we have already proven
that the body cannot handle
the icy temperature
beyond the extra seven minutes.
Where there is the differential
of the subject, Herr doctor.
Which is why we must repeat this
to get the most accurate result.
At least with this patient alive,
we will be able to discover
how to treat someone with hypothermia.
Intriguing.
Boiling water will warm him up.
Help us.
You do need help. I agree.
It's because you are a filthy Jew.
Spotted fever in your blood stream.
You must all think that I am evil.
That I am doing this for sole enjoyment.
If I can use your results
in finding a way to defeat
the typhus disease,
some of you may live
to see the end of it.
But if they die?
Then we will try again
with new test subjects.
- If you are sure...
- Please!
Don't question me again, doctor.
I wouldn't choose to challenge
your intelligence
and I would appreciate the same in return.
Kill her.
What is your purpose?
I need no purpose.
I am in charge of your decisions.
Kill her.
How dare you suggest I kill this woman!
She can be saved.
Who do you think you are?
You realize why they made you Kapo?
Why you're in charge?
Because I can see what is right
and what is wrong.
Therefore my decision-making is accurate
and efficient.
You are delusional.
They chose you because you
are an unprofessional criminal.
Why waste someone who lacks a conscience
on delivering children
when they can use you to murder
without a second thought.
What makes you so competent
in killing an infant?
Your hesitation
tells me you might actually have something
pumping in there.
I do what I have to do.
You never have to kill a child!
I am in charge. It's my job.
If you keep retaliating like that,
it will not just be infants
that I'm killing.
It's your job because most are forced
into leadership in this camp.
Now you get on with your day
and let me help this poor women
deliver her child.
I'm suggesting we follow up the experiment
with female barracks.
- Maternity?
- Yeah.
They're diseased.
Not only with dysentery and typhus
but with children.
I may need some of those children.
Correct.
With the information similar to that
in the latrines
but from pregnant women.
We may push our research
in further direction.
For now, I keep them alive.
I'm finding it...
entertaining watching the Catholic
save the day.
What an earth are you doing in here?
You need to come to the female barracks.
- Leave her alone.
- Her number was called.
She's done nothing to you!
Get off her!
Her number was called
moments after she gave birth.
And?
And it is not in good standing
for a new mother and her offspring
to be among all this stress
so soon after the birth.
If I may...
I shall test their health
to ensure the children shall survive.
Her number was called?
Then take them both.
Do you know how old you are?
Where are you from?
The world isn't yet perfect.
It can be.
You are a strong one.
What if it's dysentery?
Then you will fight it,
as all these women have for the terror.
The disease.
What are your symptoms?
Stomach cramp.
Diarrhea, blood.
Then you shall rest.
I'm lifting you from any duties
for a while.
Hmm, yeah. Right.
Your condition seems
a little more serious.
Ahh, and you're a doctor.
Yes, flu, right. You already told me.
Only your desperation tells me otherwise.
If I may?
Proceed.
I care as much as you do.
Why would I want the babies I deliver
to be exposed to illness?
Continue.
This woman is a little sick.
But what you're forgetting
is that she's also carrying
an eight-month-old child.
You will never know the sensations,
especially in these conditions.
Flu as well?
She is in recovery.
The flu has already left her system.
A nice cold shower
will bring you back to life.
I will bring her back to life.
Up and around in no time.
Very well.
Flu?
Mother. Am I going to die?
The disease nor the evil
will destroy you.
You're a survivor.
Angel of the heart.
You are the strength of the future.
And the beauty of past memories.
You are the love,
the light
and the hope.
You are life's precious gift.
An unbelievable miracle.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and the Holy ghost.
Amen.
Stanislawa
- Stanislawa.
- I'm fine.
I would like you to lie down
while I go and get a doctor.
I would like to see Dr Janina
regarding an issue with data.
An issue?
Easily fixed
by a woman of her intelligence.
I will notify her.
The midwife has requested to see Janina.
Why's that?
She claims it's something to do with
a data issue and the doctor can fix it.
Why not just call Lagaraztem?
She didn't give me a...
A chance to what?
Demand?
Direct?
You are in charge.
No, Klara, you are in charge.
Fine. Get Janina.
I'm far too busy.
I'm just a messenger.
You're the one that has the control to
bring Janina back to the barrack, not me.
You understand why we do what we do?
Of course.
We are part of a larger scheme
that will make the world better.
A superior version of the one
we have lived in before now.
I know that.
What did you do before?
You know what I did before.
If you're not ashamed, tell me out loud.
I slept with men for money.
And did that make you feel powerful?
Yes.
The death of an infant is relevant.
It's life. It's destined for diseases.
And fatalities, regardless if we kill it
or nature does.
We have the power to survive this place.
Don't waste it!
Take this to Artz Mengele.
And bring Janina.
What's that?
We're being relocated.
Why? What's happening to the house?
The Nazis are turning this into a ghetto.
Can we stop them from doing that?
You know full well we can't.
Pack lightly.
Doctor.
My guess is that you didn't just
request me regarding a data issue.
Stay down. You need your strength.
You know I would
never have called you away from work
unless I needed to.
Coming from a woman that has delivered
over 2,000 babies alive,
that's actually not so hard to believe.
They rely on me...
to make sure they are healthy
and protected from the doctors
who claim to look after us here.
To make sure their children
are born safely into the world.
I... I am sick.
Who assists you normally?
I work alone.
The other two are murderers.
- Of the women?
- Of the children.
So what do you need me to do, Stanislawa?
I need you to take over
my duties until I am well again.
And does that include lying to the SS?
Do you think I would
have been as successful in here
if I hadn't lied to the SS?
You are a good women.
You need your rest.
I'll take it from here.
What is the purpose of your travels?
I have been ordered to deliver
this bicycle to Heimlich Abelard, sir.
I'm not aware of a delivery
to Mr Abelard.
With urgency.
So I shall be on my way.
What we're doing is being good people.
Does that make us stupid?
Would you not rather die stupid
then die guilty?
Well, whatever happens with any of this,
we must stay true
to the people we have decided to be.
I will, my love.
Are you suggesting to me
that this is only flu?
I'm not suggesting, I'm telling you.
And the rash on her arm?
Excuse my lack of appreciation,
doctor, but...
have you seen the environment
these women are living in?
Rats,
feces, the dead.
Why are you still on duty here?
This is her job.
The woman is exhausted.
She has worked 18 months without a break.
Sleepless nights.
Now, if you will,
my shift is not yet over.
I'm keeping a close eye on you.
I will be better soon.
Until then...
...you rest.
Catch your breath.
They could still be following us.
What about Mother?
She will bring your brother
and sister to safety.
Will we see them again?
We need to run.
Dr Mengele, what are you doing?
There are rumors of liberation.
This research must be destroyed.
You're going to abandon
all your present subjects?
In two weeks' time, there will be no walls
for the subjects to be tested on.
Oh, and where are you going?
The Gross-Rosen camp in the south-east.
You will continue to run away
until you're caught.
I will run until I need to.
I suggest the same for you, doctor.
What are you doing here?
I'm admiring your naivety.
I can assume you're good at reading data.
But I can assure you,
you cannot read my mind.
You think?
I have... doubted myself.
That I can get well.
And you stopped doubting yourself.
Why?
Because the hope I have invested
in everyone around me
cannot be unless I demonstrate it myself.
To live for others.
I had a similar conversation
with an optimist once.
After she prayed
and after she preached to me about hope.
And how did that end?
However you want it to.
Why?
Lord.
Answer me!
Why, Lord?
I shall conquer this.
We shall conquer this.
How are you?
I have been very sick, my child.
But you're strong.
As are you.
The child?
Taken from my arms.
Murdered before my eyes.
My child that lived inside me for so long,
safe and healthy,
has been killed.
The camp is being liberated.
How do you know?
We need to be ready.
What's the point of living
knowing that my child is dead?
And I... I couldn't protect her.
Every life has the chance to be full.
You will have other children.
You will live a full life.
I have faith in that.
For something so silent...
you say so much.
My name is Fritz Hollman.
For now.
You scare crows.
Inspiring.
I grew up in the country, not far.
And now...
I'm a prisoner.
Fugitive.
I am a man...
who has been sinned against
more than sinning.
I'll share a secret with you.
I'm going to Buenos Aires.
I have friends from the Fatherland there.
I will be safe.
What happens to you eventually?
Do you just fade to dust in the wind?
I guess we all fade to dust.
Sweet?
Signature, please.
Sir?
Sir.
Thank you.
My boy.
Come in.
You have a lovely home.
Thank you. I painted it myself.
Now Hitler, there was a painter.
How was the journey?
It was good.
I ate on the train.
Good food?
Train food.
Thank you...
for writing.
The letters...
I would wait for the postman to deliver.
I can't imagine what you've been through.
I've seen the pictures.
Please. Do not believe all the crap
you see from these people.
It's like I've been living a nightmare.
That's a waste.
I'm concerned.
That you may have a different
frame of mind.
You should see the data,
the information I collected
with my experiments.
Now...
nothing.
But you are pleased that the camp
has been liberated?
The Jews won the day.
And I am scratching around
trying to find documents
so I can lead a guilt-free life.
Alright.
You look like you disapprove, boy.
You're my father.
I would never betray you.
You stay as long as you need.
Thank you.
Are you comfortable?
If you hadn't slept in two years
would you be comfortable?
Were you forced not to sleep?
There was nothing more rewarding
than hearing the cry of a newborn baby
that I had just assisted into the world.
What were the conditions?
We have all seen the pictures
but are they as gruesome as they look?
The pictures are...
a mouse's squeak to a lion's roar.
Rats, feces, urine,
old hay for bedding,
no space for the women to sleep
or deliver their children.
Without heat, freezing almost to death.
The smell was...
unimaginable.
I did my best
to keep the women away from infection,
infested bodies.
When the rain came down
we were all soaked through.
Walking in puddles 12 inches high
just to get from one end of the barrack
to the other.
They were the best days
because they drowned the rats
and kept the evil doctors out.
And you dealt with this alone?
Soon after the baby was born,
I would tattoo the newborn
under the armpit.
What gave you the motivation
to not give up?
Because I had the power
to bring life into the world.
In the two years that I was in Auschwitz,
I delivered over 3,000 children.
Life gave me the motivation to
help the mothers in need.
To deliver their child
as safely as possible.
And together they cherish
the most beautiful thing in this world.
The smile of a child.
Precisely.
Mother, who are you talking to?
My dear daughter,
you will think I have
completely lost my mind.
The only way I have managed
to get through this
is by talking to others
and inspiring them with my words.
I need to do that for myself now.
The only person who will completely listen
and completely understand
what I am saying...
is me.
Wolfgang, huh?
I'm talking to a spirit who's identity's
turned more times than the tide itself.
A drowning. Over in second.
You're an alias to the world.
An alias to me.
OK, now, we're going to take
big deep...
I can't do it.
Of course you can.
Now, push.
That's it. That's it.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull