[MUFFLED YELLING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
There's some stolen Russian
subs, military US subs.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[INAUDIBLE]
Now [INAUDIBLE] you
know, I'm working
with-- against the cartel.
And you know how it is, right?
I have a price tag on my head.
Too much shit in here--
intel, knowledge.
So I'm a walking death sentence.
Cartel's motto is
dead men don't talk.
So you know, here I am talking
on national television.
And--
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
I can only blab about
so much, but I'm
hoping that this interview
will help flush out where
this fucking sub might be, OK?
Scene four, three--
Good evening, I'm Mark Harris.
And tonight we have with
us none other than the head
of the United States Drug
Enforcement Administration Mr.
Craig Ford.
Tonight we're
going to be talking
about international
drug smuggling
and how it's a problem for the
citizens of the United States,
even before the
drugs hit our shores.
Tonight it's about
organized crime
and what we are doing to
combat these evil cartels.
Mr. Ford, it's so great
to have you with us.
Um, just-- just Ford.
Ford.
No mister, just Ford.
Ford, if you could, please
paint a picture for us,
this personification of evil
that is the international drug
cartel.
Well, that's just it, Mark.
The cartel employs
what I'm calling now
an active evil, which are
the worst kind of scumbags,
worst kind of people, sexual
slavery, torture, rape,
forced prostitution,
forced castration.
You get the picture, right?
Now the cartel heads,
they know what's going on.
But they turn their
backs and they behave
as if it's business as usual.
Now, seeing as I know
as much as they know,
if I weren't doing
everything, I mean, everything
in my power to stop it--
I mean, you get
the picture, right?
I mean, what difference am
I from these motherfuckers?
Ford, it's going to be much
better for our television
audience if you don't use
words like "motherfucker" when
I'm asking the questions.
I'm sorry.
OK.
Being as close as
you are to the cartel
in this demanding
and dangerous job,
does it make you
fear for your life?
I'm sorry, are you asking
me if I'm afraid of dying?
Well, yes, if that's the
way you want to put it.
I welcome death.
You understand?
I welcome it.
There's only one thing, I mean
one thing that I'm afraid of,
you understand?
I'm afraid of living, man.
And that makes me the
perfect man for the job.
[SHUTTER CLICKING]
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
Come on, Courtney, just--
one more drink and then and
then we'll go back to the room,
I promise.
One more Stoli.
You know that your daddy
would not approve of this.
Cheers to senator
Jack Stanfield.
Decent Senator but the best--
Fucking dad ever.
You see that guy over there
that keeps looking at us?
Yeah.
But there's no way I'm
letting either of us
out of each other's sight.
So you might as
well just drop it.
Yeah, I know but there's no
harm in a little flirting.
Hey, keep to yourself.
Save it for the boys back home.
OK, OK.
So your dad's a big
US Senator, huh?
Senator?
That's crazy.
We know nothing
of such senators.
No, our families are poor
potato farmers from Idaho.
Tell you what,
last drink's on me.
To the poor American
potato farmers.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Do you know who the
fuck I work for?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Now do as you're told.
Take that bitch to the beach
and put a fucking bullet
in her fucking head.
You girls are in trouble.
In trouble from who?
Me.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
Mr. Stryker, how
are you doing today?
I'm doing very well.
Thank you, Ms. Tan.
And you're finding
everything OK in the office?
I am, yes.
Everyone is super friendly,
showing me around.
And what better place
than Medellin, right?
It's a gorgeous city,
just like our office.
That it is.
Yeah.
Yeah, we're super
excited to have you here.
I'm excited to be here.
Thanks for the opportunity.
The family settling in OK?
Yeah, you know, it
started out a bit hectic,
but I think they're
doing all right.
Alison made some friends.
Wonderful.
She's got a sleep over tonight.
Good to hear.
Yeah, it'll provide a lot
of much needed alone time
with me and the missus.
Oh, alone time with the missus.
[EXHALES] Well, I'll
let you get along
with the rest of your day, OK?
You have a good weekend.
Thank you, you too.
Thanks.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[KNOCKING]
Hey, mom, have you
seen my hairbrush?
No, sweetie, I haven't.
Hey, mom, have you seen
my cellphone charger?
No, honey, I haven't.
Ew, dad.
That's just gross.
Sorry, sweet pea.
Sorry, baby.
Well, I'm going over to Janie's.
Call me when you get there.
Have fun, sweet pea.
Love you.
I didn't know.
(SINGING) Hey.
[VOCALIZING]
What's going on?
You know damn well, Bruce.
She's fine.
It's OK.
It takes Allison one minute
to get to Janie's, unless it's
raining.
And it's been 90 seconds.
How about you just
give her a call?
Just give her a call.
She probably just forgot.
Yeah, maybe.
[PHONE RINGING]
She left her phone.
Sweet pea?
Allison?
[PHONE RINGING]
Stay right here.
Dad's not going
back to work, is he?
I'm not sure.
What happened?
What is it?
We just got Intel that
two girls were taken while
on spring break at a bar,
Senator Jack Stanfield's
daughter and her friend.
They believe it was tied to
the drug cartel for some kind
of ransom money or worse.
You'll always be
safe with me, OK?
You wanna come help daddy pack?
Yeah.
[? Had ?] to help.
Come on.
Let's go.
How excited are you
to see Uncle Ford?
Really excited.
He did great on that
television show.
He did, didn't he?
What the heck was that?
I think it was a
great white shark.
And that's supposed to scare me?
Of course.
It doesn't?
Dad, there are no
sharks out here.
I mean, we're 38,000
feet up in the air.
This is no ordinary shark.
What do you mean?
This is a flying shark.
Blah, blah, blah.
Can't get anything by you.
You want to hear a
real shark story?
All right.
When daddy was young,
he was navigating
in a small little
submarine, routine.
But we used to hear thumps
like that all the time.
And this one time, daddy's
friend Captain Ken Kennedy
and I decided to go up
top to check it out.
Guess what we saw
when we got up there?
What did you see?
We saw the biggest fin.
It was huge.
It was like-- it was
like a scene from Jaws.
It was cool until we realized
that thing was headed right
for us.
And it was coming fast.
It hit the sub
with so much force
that it knocked Captain
into the waters.
Before you know it,
the shark was on him.
And it was shaking him around
like a dog with a bone,
you know?
[YELLS]
OK, you got me, dad.
I admit it.
I did.
Thanks for bringing us
to Washington with you
while you train.
Well, I'm going to be helping
others train for their mission,
you know?
It's good to have you and
mom with me before I leave.
Love you, sweet pea.
Love you too.
[HONKING]
[THUD]
[MUFFLED SPEECH]
Speak up.
I can't hear you.
[MUFFLED SPEECH]
Oh.
[GROANS]
Ah!
I said are you the faggot
that's going fix the leak.
You're the plumber, right?
You come here to fix the leak?
Ow!
That was unpleasant.
You know, they call
me the extractor.
And I need some
information, dog.
And being that you're
the head of the DEA
with privileged
information, you're
going to tell me exactly
what I need to know
or you're gonna die a horrible
fucking death, fat man,
I promise.
(HISPANIC ACCENT)
Really sorry, man.
You got the wrong guy, man.
I am from [INAUDIBLE], Mexico.
I'm a Mexican [? jumping ?]
[? beans ?] of shit like you.
Oh!
[GAGS]
Oh, shit.
Motherfucker.
Oh, wow, my memory
just came back.
Yeah I am the head of the DEA.
That's me.
Yeah, they call you the--
the Extractor, right AKA Spyder.
How you know my name?
I'm the head of the the DEA.
I got privileged information
like your dumb ass just said.
What exactly do
you know about me?
You're the biggest dope
dealer South of Panama.
You work for Pelon.
Others would say that
it's the other way around.
And your main client
this last year
was a cartel
[? Mongrel ?] Dallas.
But shipments have been
prevented and delayed.
Is it making that
metal pipe you're
holding all that much harder?
That's just delightful,
like for me, you know?
[LAUGHS]
Let's see if I can adjust
your perception in terms
of who I really am and help
you see the real problem you
face right now.
Be right back.
You promise?
What are you gonna do?
Oh, you brought your
mother's underwear?
I used to fuck her.
Yeah, she wore bloomers.
She had one of them
Mexican asses that
bounced off the curb, you know?
Put your head back.
Put your fucking head back.
[INAUDIBLE]
Oh, you know what?
Maybe I wanna smell your
mother's pussy again.
Let me see.
Oh, it's there.
There she is.
[GROANS]
Wow.
Oh, fuck.
[VOCALIZES] Oh, I'm gonna
kill you, you son of a bitch!
You little pussy.
You're such a little pussy pig.
Put it back.
Yeah, come on, ready?
What's with the jokes?
I wanna hear a joke.
Tell me.
What happened?
You're not funny anymore.
You're not funny now!
What happened!
You motherfucker, I'm gonna
kill you, you son of a bitch!
You intercepted my
shit from Pelon.
Big problem for me, which
means big problem for you.
Now listen, you
can have the drugs.
You have my personal
fucking guarantee
I will red carpet 'em.
I don't give a fuck
about the drugs.
Where are the girls?
That's our focus.
You know what the real focus is?
Stryker's plan.
I want [INAUDIBLE].
I want to know where he lives.
I want to know
who his family is.
You tell me where he is, OK?
[GUNSHOT]
[THUDDING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[THUD]
[LAUGHS] Your wish
is my command.
I'm right here, my gun
pointed at your head.
Hey, Bruce, what
took you so long?
Took you long-- You
see that, Spyder?
When I say something's gonna
jump, I deliver the product.
Now slowly hand over the pipe.
What are you waiting for?
Shoot me.
When you hesitate, your
conviction is weak.
There's no mercy in
the world for weakness.
Haven't you figured
that out yet?
Where are the girls?
[INAUDIBLE]
[THUD]
[EXERTION SOUNDS]
He's gone, huh?
Yeah, he got away.
You OK?
Yeah.
I knew that fucking
TV spot was gonna
give me my own personal
Colombian bath,
and look happened.
Yeah.
[LAUGHS]
Yeah, man, but you're
still tough as nails.
What?
Yeah, I know.
God damn right I am.
All right, let's
get you out of here.
Come on.
You all right?
[GROANS]
[INAUDIBLE] come on.
Come on.
You good?
Yes.
Being old sucks, doesn't it?
Fuck you.
[LAUGHS]
My name is Craig Ford.
And I am head of a little
shit ass agency that I adore,
the DEA.
So this is how this shit
goes down, you know,
with the cartels.
The average
transportation of cocaine
has always been
problematic for the US.
However, they began to
take more serious notice
when these cartel pricks
got into the sex trafficking
business.
And selling them back into the
US for ransom to their parents.
The part that really
fucks with my head,
you can only imagine in your
holy hellish nightmare, that's
what these girls go through
if they don't make it back
and they get washed ashore
like this little girl did.
Anyway, that's how
we all got into it.
That's how we all got into the
mix, Bruce Stryker, the DEA,
my dumb ass, and
the head of the CIA.
But trust and believe this,
it's one hell of a story.
Huh?
Oh.
Hey, where are my
two DEA agents?
They should be
standing at the door.
Mr. Ford, you've been
rushed into intensive care.
But I need my men back here.
Until I ID you,
I'm gonna have to--
take your goddamn
hands off me or I'm
gonna take that
syringe he's holding
and stick it up your
goddamn ass, all right?
Mr. Ford?
What?
If you could take these pills--
Listen, you'd be a better
nurse if you took off
your fucking clothes.
Anyone ever tell you that?
You been to nursing school?
[INAUDIBLE] Oh, come
on, I'm just playing.
Hey, Ford.
Those three nurses,
they checked out.
Your men are in the hallway.
You OK?
Excellent.
Hey.
Good to see you, Bruce.
You never can be
too fucking careful.
No, you can't.
That's right.
Watch your family.
Don't fuck it up like I did.
Holy Popsicle, look who's here.
Uncle Ford.
Hey, honey.
How are you?
Oh.
Are you OK?
Oh, I'm fine, fine.
Enough about me, though.
How's your dad's
training going, honey?
Great.
It really is good.
You'd be really proud.
That's great.
Hey, listen, listen, get me out
of here and we'll go have lunch
together with Rebecca.
All right.
It's good we scared
them docs off.
Hey, your dad and I
gotta do something.
There's a window of opportunity
to get me out of here.
OK, hey.
Come on, let's go.
Just don't forget what
I said, all right?
If I had half the life you
have, I wouldn't have lost Carol
and had a pretty
goddamn good life.
You know?
Just don't fuck
it up, all right?
And you three are all
I have left anyway.
You hear me?
You understand?
I understand.
So training tomorrow, 0700?
God damn right.
We got 26 missing Americans.
Let's bring that number
down by two tomorrow.
OK?
Yes, sir.
All right.
Where are my clothes?
In the car.
All right, let's go.
[GROANS]
I'll ask the fucking questions!
Get this piece of
shit out of here!
[GUNSHOT]
[INAUDIBLE] Back to staging.
All right.
Get some water.
That's what I'm talking about.
Good job.
Good job, John.
Good round, everybody.
Bruce, that sucked.
If we do work like that,
we'll be speaking Russian
before Christmas.
Unit three.
Follow me, move out.
Hey, Ford.
Hold on for a moment.
What?
Is it really that bad?
Yeah, oh, it's that bad.
What do you think?
Hey, look, man, I'm the second
best guy in the exercise,
we have problems, you know?
I'm 50 fucking years old.
Are you serious?
We gotta do better.
Much better.
10-4.
Let's get these
goddamn sparks to fire.
[INAUDIBLE]
[INAUDIBLE] cartel.
Unit 3, Stryker's got
something to tell you.
You guys sucked.
You guys really sucked.
If I [? check ?] that score what
Stryker is gonna tell you about
was me.
I know what kind of people
are taking my daughters.
He's right, guys.
This is a very
important mission.
We just got some intel that
23 teenage US female citizens
were abducted while on spring
break in Central America,
all related to the drug cartel.
This is an epidemic.
They all have families
that want them home safely.
We are the ones that are
going to bring them home.
We're the only ones
that can do it.
And we can't do it like that.
Now pull your asses together.
I want you thinking
and I want you killing.
Come on.
Let's do it.
You're better than this.
We're all better than this.
Let's go.
Move out.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Come on, let's go.
Come on, get up.
Come on.
Get in there, all right?
Look at me.
Don't be a hero.
You're not that valuable to me.
No, not my type, sorry.
[GUNSHOT]
No!
[GUNSHOTS]
Leave her alone!
You wanna die?
Keep struggling, I'll
shoot you right now.
You want to die?
I'll shoot you right now.
Huh?
[GUNSHOTS]
[PHONE RINGING]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Let him go.
He's one of us.
Bring him to me.
[HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[GUNSHOT]
[GUN CLICKS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Spyder knew he fucked up.
But much like a wolf
pack, a cartel pack
is an exceedingly
complex social unit.
The alpha of the cartel
is a man named Pelon.
And the job of maintaining
order and cohesion
falls largely to
the alpha wolves,
Pelon being the number one wolf.
So Pelon makes the
call to release Spyder.
Second in command
are called the betas.
That would be Spyder followed by
mid-ranking wolves like Javier,
and finally the omegas,
or as the cartel refer
to as prairie dogs or
murder dogs, the ones that
do the dirty work.
Spyder relentlessly kills
the injured prairie dogs.
As they say, dead
men tell no tales.
Ah, fuck it, dead
men don't talk.
See, what makes this
story interesting
is the nature of wolves.
Any temptation to be an alpha
will be the cartel's undoing.
Keep watching.
It's just a matter of time.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
We will no longer
travel to Mexico.
From now on, we go directly
to the US, Florida.
Pelon, how are we getting there?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Javier.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hey, beautiful.
Hey, daddy.
Hey, sweet pea.
Hey, Bruce.
We just picked up Allison and
we're on the way to the office.
But where is it again?
Because I need to
tell the bodyguard.
Seven months, we've
been here seven months
and you still don't
know where my office is?
It was one time that
I've been and it was
for the welcoming party, so--
And one too many margaritas.
We can turn around.
Look, Becs, I don't
know if I'm going
to be able to wrap up by
the time you guys get here.
Maybe you guys should just
go to the beach without me.
Bruce, you promised.
Yeah, come on,
daddy, you promised.
All right.
How can I say no to
that kind of love?
Bruce, something's happening.
Hold on.
[INAUDIBLE] why'd you pull over?
Get down!
[SCREAMS]
What was that?
Down, down!
What's wrong?
Allison, down, down!
Stay down!
[GUNSHOTS]
[GROANING]
[SCREAMING]
Let go of her!
Stop!
[CRYING]
No.
Rebecca?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
If you want to see 'em alive
again, there's a van out front.
Get in it.
[EXERTION SOUNDS]
Take me to my family now.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Where is my wife?
Your wife is safe, as
is your little girl.
They will continue to be safe
as long as you cooperate.
Why me?
I have nothing to offer.
Well, since you knew enough
to expose our last mission,
Pelon expects you to
make this delivery.
And if I don't?
Your wife, your
kid, you will watch
them die before I cut every
one of your limbs off.
The last will be your head.
But if you work with
us, we will let them go.
You're fucking insane.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Do not snort the product.
Do not fuck the other product.
Yeah.
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Don't
let Stryker play you.
Keep him down.
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Once
the drug wears off,
he will kill you like that.
We don't need that
fucking idiot.
Stryker knows how to
avoid the authorities
since he was their superior.
[INAUDIBLE],, Alessandra will
be waiting for you in Florida
with her grand
contact named Dallas.
Give him the sample
bag as instructed, OK?
I got this.
Trust me.
Let's pray for your
sake, [SPEAKING SPANISH]..
Hey.
Hey, hello?
Anybody home?
OK, I know you can hear me.
You fuck this up for
me, your wife and child
will never see the light
of day, I promise you.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Look at me.
Do you fucking understand?
Nothing to worry about.
I'm not worried.
You should be worried.
Are you worried?
Yes.
Good.
Take him.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
It's OK, baby.
Mommy's here.
Ow!
What's your name?
Rebecca.
That's a pretty name.
Your husband, is he a smart man?
I hope so.
[SOBBING]
[RUMBLING]
Daddy, wake up.
Come on, daddy.
Daddy!
Hi, daddy.
Hey, sweet pea.
Are you excited to
go to the beach?
Of course.
Where's your mother?
She's packing.
That's good.
You remember our promise?
Of course.
Do you remember which promise?
No, sorry, which one?
The one where you're supposed
to keep me and mom safe.
Dad, we need your help.
I'm scared.
They're hurting me and mom.
No.
We need your help.
Dad, come on, help.
[GROANS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
You're too young to
be in the cartel.
Old enough to put a fucking
bullet in your head.
Like that's the hard part.
Get these fucking
things off of me.
Don't try anything
stupid, all right?
Don't be a fucking hero.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
What the fuck is that?
Whale shark if you're lucky.
If you're not,
great white shark.
And that's supposed to scare me?
Yeah.
I remember I was
navigating [INAUDIBLE]..
Yeah, we used to hear
thumps like that.
[THUD]
This one time a buddy of mine
Captain Ken Kennedy and I
went up top to check it out.
Got up there, I turned
around, saw the biggest fin
I've ever seen.
It was enormous.
[THUDDING]
It was heading
straight for the sub.
It hit the sub so hard
that Captain Kennedy
fell in the water.
That shark was on him so fast.
It shook him around.
It shook him around
like a dog with a bone.
Tired of this bullshit.
Get up.
Look, tough guy, go
upstairs you're gonna
get us to fucking Florida.
Figure out your fish situation.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
OK.
Got a flare gun in
this piece of shit sub?
Hey.
Get out of the way
so I can do my job.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Hello?
Will you tell your
brother to give me
the helm so I can do my job?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Here's where things
got a little tricky.
No one at the CIA knew
Stryker did a little favor
for Senator Stanfield.
It was Stryker's
own code of honor
that compelled him to do it.
Much like the wolf pack
of the cartel, myself,
the head of the CIA, and its
top men, we all had our rank.
The difference between
the cartel and us--
we don't eat our own kind.
Eh, most of the time.
Ford?
Hey.
Here's five good ones.
How are you?
Good to see you.
Good to see you too.
What's up?
We've got problems.
Um, let me guess,
cartel problems.
Yeah.
I have a briefing with the
president in 30 minutes.
You guys said this is level one?
Yes, sir.
My friend Bruce Stryker, he's a
highly decorated Naval officer.
He's been kidnapped by
the Colombian cartel.
Everybody knows that, all right?
Come on.
Tell him.
Why is the DEA involved in this?
Hey, look, I don't like
these assholes either,
but I'm their boss, all right?
If we want to topple
the cartel, then we
gotta stop all this
bullshit and work together.
What the hell was he
doing in Colombia, Jim?
Oh, he has family
down there, sir.
Mistress?
No, I'm talking
about his family.
I don't mean there's
some old whore,
I mean his real
mistress, his job.
Oh.
[INAUDIBLE]
OK.
Anyway, they wanted
him down there
after he retired from the navy.
Look, I can vouch for him.
I trained him, OK?
And he is one bona fide bad
ass motherfucker with one
big bad problem.
He loves his family very
much and they're gone.
Sir, he's a hero.
He was awarded the Navy Cross
after he saved eight Navy
SEALs.
He deserves to be rescued.
He's earned it.
You may not know it, but you
are better, you're safer.
We are better.
Bruce Stryker, he's an artist
like van Gogh, like Modigliani,
like, um-- like Lennon,
like the Stones, OK?
And blood is his paint.
And the cartel is his canvas.
So what do you guys expect
me to do about this?
Just give us your permission to
go and turn over a few stones
so that we can help save him.
All right, save your buddy.
But I don't want your people
knowing anything about it.
What?
As far as they're
concerned, he's as big
a criminal as the cartel.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Who's in charge here?
I am.
Who the hell are you?
I'm the one in charge here.
Well, you're a real shitty host.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
Are you bored?
I get bored, too.
This is boring.
I think we could figure
out something to do.
Pass some time.
And I won't tell
if you don't tell.
So tense.
Give in to me.
It's OK.
It won't hurt.
Mommy likes me.
She's confused.
[INAUDIBLE]
And you're gonna
[? do it, too. ?] And then
the time will go by like that.
Huh?
Don't do anything
fucking stupid.
[INAUDIBLE]
Get up nice and slow.
[INAUDIBLE] Turn around.
Oh, shit.
[LAUGHS]
[GROANS]
Mommy!
[LAUGHS] You wanna play.
You wanna play.
Yeah, let's play.
All day.
You're like that chica
in the movie, man.
You know the one?
The mermaid, you look like
a mermaid girl, right?
You know the one?
You know the movie, right,
the Hollywood movie?
That's you.
Spyder!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
The job is to get me my money.
Now where's the sub?
They just passed Cuba.
They're headed
straight for Key West.
Good, they're making good time.
How soon should I travel there?
You're not going anywhere?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
I'm sending my wife
to the location.
She'll be staying with
my contact in the US.
Plus, I need a
break [INAUDIBLE]..
[SPEAKING SPANISH] She
shouldn't go alone.
At least she'll
be away from you.
Oh, you don't trust me, Pelon?
I can't trust anyone, especially
anyone who's fucking my wife.
How do you know?
I didn't.
I do now.
Bap.
So how we looking?
All right.
I've gotta go up top.
Sit tight, all right?
You're gonna want
me to have that.
You think I'm stupid?
Look, the shark is all over us.
If it gets sucked by the
propulsion, a shark that size,
will snap the metal of
the propellers like that.
[SNAPS]
The shots from the gun
will alert the shark.
It'll scare it off.
Give me the gun.
No funny business.
I'm a man of my word.
10-4.
[GUNSHOTS]
The shark won't be
bothering us anymore.
No funny business.
We're in the clear.
What you doing, pretty boy?
I like that.
I know these waters.
So I gotta ask, where'd
you guys get the sub?
That's a good question
and a fucked up question
at the same time, hmm?
Yeah.
I bet.
You and I are not that
different, actually.
How so, pretty boy?
No, that's not how this works.
We're not gonna go around in
a circle telling our stories
like we're at a campfire.
I have a family I have to save.
OK?
I have to stay focused.
I don't want to be here.
But we are here.
But let me get one
thing straight,
I would do anything
for my family.
And if you get in my
way, I will kill you.
[NON-ENGLISH SINGING]
Nice fucking voice.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
We make peace?
[GAGGING]
You don't fuck around
with a guy like Pelon.
He is the alpha.
But more than that, his whole
life and his father's father's
whole life and his
father's father's father's
founded their family
principle on respect.
You could say Pelon
smelled a rat in the room.
And more than that, he could
sense a bigger one right
outside the door.
[MUSIC - RACOON RACOON, "DAWN
CHORUS"]
And like any great
alpha, he knows
how to treat his pack--
pardon me, his people.
Keeps 'em fed.
Keeps 'em warm.
Get's 'em laid.
[LAUGHS] Oh, and keeps
them happy and content,
the pieces of shit they are.
No disrespect.
(SINGING) Across the
ocean of our lies.
You know what's
wrong to be with you.
I never felt you wanted to.
Like all those
parties without fun.
Like a summer without sun.
You know what's wrong--
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Melissa.
This is beautiful.
Gorgeous.
This would look so nice on you.
I need you to
[INAUDIBLE] business
in Miami with our
big client Dallas.
He awaits you on his yacht.
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Why
don't you go to Miami
and meet with Dallas?
And then I'll stay here
and watch everything.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
I trust you.
I have to tell you something.
Now is not the time.
OK.
OK, [SPEAKING SPANISH].
(SINGING) Everlasting
game, no one ever won.
Now it's just you and me apart.
Each other with a broken heart.
You know what's
wrong to be with you.
I never felt you wanted to.
Like all those parties--
Aye, yay, yay.
Don't shoot.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Do you know who I am?
I don't give a fuck.
Give me the jewels.
Get out of the car.
Come on.
Don't shoot.
[INAUDIBLE]
Stupid.
My God, Pelon.
Do you know who I am?
Pelon, I didn't know it was you.
[GUNSHOT]
[SCREAMS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[GUNSHOT]
Don't worry.
It's OK.
[SPEAKING SPANISH] You're right.
I love you so much.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Let's go home.
[RUMBLING]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
You still don't trust me.
Trust you?
[INAUDIBLE]
You have one job.
Get us to America and
you get your family.
We get caught, your family dies.
You have your family kidnapped.
You're an asshole like me.
I like that.
Hello, beautiful.
I want you to know your
eyes look lovely today.
That's nice.
How often that bullshit
line work for you, huh?
Once, maybe twice.
What's up?
I just want you to know the
informant is arriving now.
Now?
Now.
Our source in Medellin says that
a shipment is about to arrive.
What's the shipment's ETA?
They're bypassing Mexico and
coming by way of Key West.
So they're going to
arrive sometime tomorrow.
Your job is to arrive
before those two get
a chance to escape.
Now, I gotta tell you, there's
gonna be three undercover CIA
agents there to help.
Work with them.
I know how you feel about
those sons of bitches,
but you've got to
work with them.
Swallow your pride.
So I can't kill
anybody tomorrow.
Not this time.
OK.
See you buddy.
All right.
How'd it go?
Shipment's coming in tomorrow.
Opportunity to redeem ourselves,
do something right, OK?
Get moving.
Duty calls.
Go!
Asshole.
Listen, I need you to
be brave for me, OK?
You mean like dad?
Exactly like dad.
Will daddy come save us?
Will he?
Your father's the
bravest man I know.
And he'll do whatever
it takes to come get us.
And do you know why?
Because we're family.
And we're always
there for each other.
Yes, exactly.
So stay strong for me, OK?
I'll protect you.
What the fuck are you doing?
[EXERTION SOUNDS]
Come on, big boy.
Show me what you got.
[EXERTION SOUNDS]
[THUDDING]
Don't do this, man.
Stryker!
One phone call,
that's all I gotta do.
All right, Tom, what do you got?
I fold.
Oh, man.
Full house, king high.
Wow.
Well, you know what?
My house is a little
bit bigger than that.
Aces high.
Oh.
You always were
quite the charlatan.
[LAUGHING]
I'm never playing
cards with you again.
Hey, sweet cakes.
Where's my product?
Have you heard anything?
I just saw it get loaded
into the [? pickup. ?]
Tell him to take it
to the secure dock.
We'll meet him there.
Well, ain't this a lovely site?
Let's go into the dock.
Come on, let's get
you out of here.
Let's go.
I assume you're our contact.
You betcha.
And if I wasn't, you'd be
in Hell's Kitchen right now.
Let's see what you got.
Well, looks like we have a deal.
Looks like the end of
the line for you, Bruce.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Javier, no!
[GUNSHOT]
What the--
Take her.
Get off!
Get off me!
Calm the fuck down.
[YELLING]
It's all right commander,
you're safe, CIA.
When we heard an American
veteran was taken hostage
by the Colombian cartel,
Richard Bishop called me in.
Thank you.
And who might you be?
Agent Dallas Chapman,
godspeed, commander.
Agent Bell.
Commander Stryker.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you too, sir.
This here is Agent Juarez.
Come on, Ford's waiting for you.
Oh, shit.
I should have known.
How was your trip?
You look like hell.
Yeah, a lot better than
you did when I saved you
from that cartel sewer.
You mean my little pipe and--
my pipe and shower
dance with Spyder.
Yeah, that's the one.
Look, Ford, it's
good to see you, sir.
Thank you for saving
my life again.
I assume it was your
idea to use Dallas
as a mole to save my life.
Nope, that was
Richard Bishop's idea.
Actually, Dallas
is CIA, top agent.
I was gonna do it myself,
but Spyder would ID me, so--
Hey, look, that's enough
talk and enough bullshit.
We need to get your
family back, all right?
Exactly.
And I need your help.
I know.
I'm already on it, OK?
I'm already on it.
I have a swift boat
waiting for you
and Agent Bell at MacDill
Air Force base [INAUDIBLE]..
All right, so let's not have
their lives lost in vain.
Most importantly, let's get
Rebecca and Allison home.
You know I won't stop
until [INAUDIBLE]..
What next?
Well, you know, Pelon
and Spyder are not
gonna stop hunting you down.
And that means your
family as well.
This could be just
the beginning.
Maybe we'll get lucky.
[EXERTION SOUNDS]
[THUD]
Daddy!
Sweet pea.
Oh my God.
Are you OK?
I'm so sorry.
It's OK.
You're here now.
I'll get you out of here, OK?
Have I told you
how brave you are?
I'm gonna need you to
be brave for daddy, OK?
It's not over.
I love you.
I love you too.
OK, come with me.
I've got you.
I gotta put you down.
We're not out of it yet,
so stay by mommy, OK?
Wait.
OK, come on.
I need you to trust me.
Be quiet and go over there.
[EXERTION SOUNDS]
[GUNSHOT]
What's intel say about security?
It's a fortress.
It's heavily guarded.
Where's my entry?
You're going swimming.
There's an entry point
on the north side.
You've gotta swim
through the channel.
Easy enough.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[GROANS]
[SNAP]
[EXERTION SOUNDS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[GUNSHOT]
No!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SOBBING]
[SCREAMING]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[GUNSHOT]
It's that simple.
Like I said, wolves
will turn on wolves.
Then Bruce just steps in
and takes out the new alpha.
I would have loved,
I would have loved
to seen Spyder's expression.
Spyder had just 30 seconds
to be the new alpha
in their [? shit-driven ?]
operation.
That's it.
Then he's taken out.
Just a flash of a
moment for Spyder,
just enough to pick up
a cigar and not even
get a chance to light
the son of a bitch.
[LAUGHS] Yeah, that's it.
In the end, a man will become
a criminal to save his family.
I mean, he will do
just about anything.
Bruce is the new alpha,
and rightfully so.
And until every girl is
returned and more importantly
this cartel is brought to its
knees in absolute submission
so that Bruce's family will be
safe, it will be up to Bruce
to run this cartel
like it was his own.
You could say Stryker would
become more than a mole
for the CIA and DEA.
He is the new alpha
criminal of this cartel.
And that, ladies
and gentlemen, that
is just what the boys back home
in Washington had hoped for.
God bless America.
[MUSIC PLAYING]