- ( computer keys clacking )
-Boy's voice: - "DEAR SANTA, GREETINGS - TO YOU AND MRS. CLAUS.
- I HOPE EVERYTHING - IS FINE AT THE NORTH POLE.
- THINGS ARE A LITTLE DIFFICULT - HERE AT MY HOUSE.
- WHAT I WANT FOR CHRISTMAS - IS FOR MOM AND DAD - TO GET ALONG
- AND FOR MY BROTHER - BUTCH TO GO AWAY
- TO BOARDING SCHOOL.
- OH, AND I STILL WANT
- THAT AUTOGRAPHED - BUSTER RANDALL BASEBALL CARD
- I TOLD YOU ABOUT - IN MY LAST E-MAIL.
- IN SCHOOL - THEY TOLD US
- IT'S NOT HEALTHY - TO GET SO HEAVY.
- SO INSTEAD - OF COOKIES AND MILK,
- I'LL BE LEAVING GRANOLA - BARS AND MINERAL WATER - FOR YOU THIS YEAR.
- YOUR NUMBER-ONE - E-MAIL PAL, JEREMY."
- ( beeping )
-( door creaks )
-OKAY, YOU CAN LOOK NOW.
- ( electronic beep )
-HO HO!
-WELL, SANTA, -HOW DO YOU LIKE
-YOUR NEW STATE-OF-THE-ART -HEADQUARTERS?
-Santa: - WELL, POINTER, - IT CERTAINLY IS
-NEW AND MODERN.
- ( beeping )
-LOOK! E-MAIL!
- ( beeps )
-HO HO!
-GOOD BOY, THAT JEREMY!
-BUT THIS IS -ALL SO CONFUSING.
-IF YOU WEREN'T CONFUSED,
- I WOULDN'T HAVE A JOB.
-IF I STAY CONFUSED, -YOU WON'T HAVE A JOB.
-HO HO!
-A LITTLE BIT OF HUMOR!
-HO HO! -WHAT KIND OF -SANTA WOULD I BE,
-FIRING AN ELF THREE DAYS -BEFORE CHRISTMAS?
-HO HO HO! -I'LL CAN YOU IN JANUARY.
-( laughing )
-POINTER IS AN EXCELLENT -TEACHER, ISN'T HE, DEAR?
-- HE IS. -- I'VE BEEN SENDINGE-MAIL FOR DA
-HERE. ENJOY. -BRAIN FOOD.
-- WITH THIS NEW DATABASE... -- ( electronic beeping )
-YOU CAN DETERMINE -WHO'S BEEN NAUGHTY -AND WHO'S BEEN NICE,
-WHO GETS A RED BICYCLE, -OR HOW MANY IN BLUE -OR WHITE,
-ALL JUST BY OPENING -THIS FILE.
- ( beeping )
-WELL, THIS IS ALL VERY -IMPRESSIVE, I'M SURE.
-OH, BUT I MISS -THE GOOD OLD DAYS
-WHEN IT WAS JUST -MRS. CLAUS, MYSELF,
-A SMALL TEAM -OF HAPPY ELVES
- AND MY REINDEER.
-THE WORLD WAS A SMALLER -PLACE, MY DEAR ONE.
-THERE ARE SO MANY CHILDREN -NOW IN SO MANY PLACES,
-AND THEY'RE ALL -COUNTING ON YOU.
-WE HAVE TO KEEP LEARNING -IF WE'RE TO KEEP UP -IN THE CIDER WORLD.
-THAT'S "CYBER" WORLD, -MRS. C.,
-NOT "CIDER."
-OH, RIGHT.
-- WELL, BACK TO WORK. -- COOKIE?
-Man: - NO MISTAKES!
- WE GO IN - JUST AS PLANNED.
-IT'S THREE DAYS -BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
-MY BROTHER SANTA -AND HIS MISERABLE ELVES
-WON'T KNOW WHAT HIT THEM.
-( laughs maniacally )
-- OH, BOY! WE'RE GONNAKICK SOME -- YEAH!
-LISTEN UP!
-I AM GOING TO PUT AN END -TO CHRISTMAS FOR ALL TIME,
-TAKE OVER THE NORTH POLE, -AND MAKE MRS. CLAUS
-MRS. ATNAS.
-- AND YOUR BROTHER SANTA? -- FORGET ABOUT SANTA.
-BUT, O GREAT ONE,
-WHY WOULD THEY LET US -INTO THE NORTH POLE?
-PURE GENIUS.
-I SCARE MYSELF. -I REALLY DO.
-OH, YOU SCARE ME -TOO, BOSS.
-WH-WHAT IS IT?
-WHERE WERE YOU, BRONTOS, -WHEN THEY PASSED OUT -BRAINS, HUH?
-OH, I WAS WITH -MY PALLY SQUEAL.
-YEAH, BOSS. -HE WAS WITH ME.
-BRAIN-FREE BUDDIES! -HOW PROUD YOU MUST BE.
-- YEAH. -- I WOULDN'T WANT TO BRAG--
-SHUT UP AND GET -IN THE BOX.
-- BUT, BOSS-- -- DON'T "BUT" ME!
-- GET IN THE BOX! -- NOT THE BOX!
-HOT HOT HOT!
-OW OW OW! -HOT!
-WE'RE GETTING -INSIDE THE BOX.
-- BUT SANTA WON'T LET YOUIN HIS -- THAT'S RIGHT.
-BUT THOSE ELVES -WILL OPEN THE DOOR
-WHEN THEY SEE THIS BOX -DELIVERED DIRECTLY -TO MY BROTHER.
-AND WHEN THEY DO,
-THEY'LL GET -A BIG SURPRISE.
-A SURPRISE?
-THEY'LL LET US IN,
-BUT THEY WON'T KNOW -THEY'VE LET US IN.
- ( laughing )
-OH, YEAH. -( laughing )
-( laughter continues )
- ( maniacal laughter )
-FOR GOODNESS' SAKE, BOB, -YOU HAVEN'T HEARD -A WORD I'VE SAID.
- OH, YES, I DID.
-- WHY DON'T YOUEVER LISTEN TO ME -- I LISTEN.
-- I THOUGHT YOU WEREBRINGING HOM -- UH-HUH.
-- A TREE? -- YEAH.
-IT'S THREE DAYS -TILL CHRISTMAS, BOB.
-WE STILL DON'T HAVE A TREE. -WHERE'S THE TREE?
-LOOK... -( clears throat )
-THERE'S SOMETHING -WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT.
-I THINK WE MIGHT NEED -TO POSTPONE CHRISTMAS -THIS YEAR.
-- POSTPONE CHRISTMAS? -- WELL, YEAH, YOU KNOW,LIKE A LE
-WE'LL JUST -SORT OF SKIP IT.
-BOB, IS THERE SOMETHING -YOU'RE NOT TELLING ME?
-- LET GO NOW, JEREMY! -- BUT IT'S MINE!
-WHY DO YOU ALWAYS -STEAL MY STUFF?
-CONSIDER IT -A HAND-ME-DOWN.
-THAT'S THE LAW -OF THE JUNGLE, JEREMY:
- EAT OR BE EATEN.
-LATER, SHRIMP!
-MOM, DAD!
-GIVE IT BACK NOW, BUTCH! -GIVE IT BACK!
-HEY, POP, -WHERE'S THE TREE?
-GUESS YOU FORGOT AGAIN?
-GUESS YOU'RE LOSING MORE -THAN JUST YOUR HAIR, -HUH, DAD?
-WE WERE JUST -DISCUSSING THE TREE.
-AS A MATTER OF FACT, -I DID NOT FORGET THE TREE.
-I'VE PICKED OUT -A SPECIAL ONE.
-COOL. WHAT'S -SO SPECIAL ABOUT IT?
-UM... WELL...
-IT'S... UM...
-YEAH? WHAT?
-SPEAK UP, BOB. -WE'RE ALL EARS.
-I BET IT'S A GREAT -TREE, RIGHT, DAD?
-RIGHT, SON.
-Pointer: - CALIFORNIA-- SURFBOARDS - AND ROLLERBLADES.
-VERMONT-- -THE SNOW IS FALLING,
-AND THE KIDS WANT -THOSE NEW SNOWBOARDS.
-SNOWBOARDS? -MAYBE MRS. CLAUS AND I
-SHOULD TRY SNOWBOARDING -THIS YEAR.
-- HO HO HO! -- ( laughs )
-OH, NO! -WHERE'S MY CLIPBOARD?
-POINTER, YOU NEED -TO LIGHTEN UP.
- ENJOY YOURSELF!
-HERE. -LET ME HELP YOU.
-THANK YOU! -I SUPPOSE YOU'RE RIGHT.
-IT'S JUST THAT -WITH ONLY THREE DAYS -BEFORE CHRISTMAS
-AND EVERYONE COUNTING -ON THE NEW CYBER ROOM,
-I GUESS I'M -A LITTLE NERVOUS.
-I GUESS SO. -( chuckles )
- ( doorbell chimes )
-WHO'S THERE?
-A GIFT FOR SANTA. -HOW NICE.
- ( computers beeping )
-"SURPRISE FOR SANTA CLAUS.
-INSIDE YOU'LL FIND -A BIG SURPRISE. -OPEN IMMEDIATELY."
-WHO BROUGHT -THIS BOX, FRIZZY?
-I DON'T KNOW. -IT'S MIGHTY HEAVY, THOUGH.
-IT TOOK SEVEN OF US -TO BRING IT IN HERE.
-WELL, BACK TO WORK.
-HMM. YOU KNOW, -I DON'T KNOW
-IF I SHOULD--
-SOMETHING ABOUT THIS -ISN'T QUITE RIGHT.
-- ( Brontos laughing ) -- SURPRISE!
-- YOU! -- ME!
-AREN'T BROTHERLY -REUNIONS WONDERFUL?
-( laughs ) -I SEE THAT YOU -STILL CAN'T KEEP
-YOUR FINGERS OUT -OF THE COOKIE JAR.
-I ONLY HAVE TWO -SQUARE MEALS A DAY.
-YEAH, A SQUARE OF FAT
-AND A SQUARE -OF CHOLESTEROL. -( laughing )
-WHAT IS IT YOU WANT?
-THIS IS A VERY BUSY TIME -OF YEAR FOR US.
-OH, YES, OF COURSE.
-I KNOW IT'S A VERY BUSY -TIME OF YEAR FOR YOU.
-YOU WERE ALWAYS TOO BUSY -TO PAY ANY ATTENTION TO ME.
- NEVERTHELESS, I'VE - BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
-AREN'T YOU GOING -TO ASK WHAT IT IS?
-ACTUALLY, ATNAS,
-I MUST INSIST -THAT YOU LEAVE.
- SO IF YOU DON'T MIND--
-BUT I DO MIND. -I MIND VERY MUCH.
- IT WOULD BE - UNFAIR OF YOU
-TO TURN ME OUT -INTO THE COLD POLAR AIR
-WITHOUT OPENING -THIS SPECIAL GIFT.
- ( chuckles )
-COME ON. -OPEN IT.
-WELL, I'LL OPEN IT, -AND THEN YOU MUST GO.
-A GIFT FOR YOUR -NEW CYBER OFFICE.
- ( Atnas chuckling )
-ISN'T IT WONDERFUL?
-- Santa: - WHAT'S WRONG WITH IT? -- WRONG WITH IT?
-IT'S A WORK OF ART.
-YOU REALLY MUST -SIT, BROTHER.
-SIT YOUR BIG HIPS DOWN
-TO APPRECIATE -THE MAGNITUDE,
- THE EPIPHANOUS JOY!
-SIT IN THE CHAIR, -BROTHER.
-HMM... COMFY.
- THANK YOU, ATNAS.
-YOU'VE REALLY -SURPRISED ME.
-RIGHT PAST -THE MOON, ALICE!
- HAVE A NICE TRIP - TO PLUTO!
-SEE YA NEXT FALL!
- ( buzzes )
-OH-HH!
- BON VOYAGE, - BROTHER DEAREST!
-- ( laughing ) -- OH-HH!
-BRONTOS, SQUEAL,
-GATHER UP ALL -THOSE ELVES NOW.
-SEAL OFF ALL ENTRANCES -AND EXITS.
- SECURE THE POLE!
-NOBODY MAKES A MOVE -WITHOUT MY SAY-SO.
-BUT, BOSS, YOU -PROMISED WE COULD KICK -SOME SERIOUS ELF BUTT!
-DON'T BUG ME!
-OKAY.
-COME ON, -GANG WAY.
-AFTER YOU.
-NOW...
-LET'S GET TO WORK.
-( beeping )
-( laughing )
-Jeremy's voice: - "P.S. SANTA, I HOPE YOU HAVE - TIME TO WRITE ME BACK.
- PLEASE LET ME KNOW
- IF THERE'S EVER ANYTHING - I CAN EVER DO FOR YOU.
- YOUR FRIEND, JEREMY."
-( beeps )
-BUTCH, LOOK! -A U.F.O.!
-YEAH, RIGHT.
-HEY THERE, SPORT, -WHAT ARE YOU DOING -UP SO LATE?
-- DAD, LOOK! -- NICE MOON, JEREMY.
-NOT THE MOON. -A SPACESHIP OR A--
-OH, A SPACESHIP, YEAH.
-- I SEE IT. -- NICE TRY, DAD.
-NO, YOU DON'T.
- IT'S GONE NOW, - BUT IT WAS THERE.
-DARN. I'M SORRY -I MISSED IT.
-YOU WRITING SANTA -ANOTHER LETTER?
-- E-MAIL. -- OH.
-- WHAT DID YOU ASKFOR THIS TIME? -- AN I.Q.
-THAT YOU AND MOM -COULD GET ALONG.
-WE GET ALONG.
-WE'RE JUST-- -MARRIED PEOPLE GO -THROUGH ROUGH PATCHES.
-WE LOVE YOU, -AND WE LOVE EACH OTHER.
-I REALLY SAW A BRIGHT LIGHT -HEADED THIS WAY.
-WELL, SURE YOU DID.
- I KNOW YOU DON'T - BELIEVE ME,
-BUT I SAW SOMETHING,
-SOMETHING SPECIAL.
-NEXT TIME YOU WRITE TO SANTA -CLAUS, TELL HIM THERE'S -A FEW THINGS I WANT, TOO.
-- WHAT DO YOU WANT, DAD? -- ME? I WANT TO BEMY OWN BOSS.
-START YOUR OWN BUSINESS?
-SURE. MORE TIME, -MORE MONEY.
-CAN WE HAVE A TREE?
-- I'M WORKING ON IT. -- YOU PROMISE?
-NIGHT, SPORT.
-NIGHT, BUTCH.
-EXPERTLY HANDLED, DAD.
-GOOD NIGHT, BOYS.
-- YEAH, GOOD NIGHT, MOM. -- GOOD NIGHT, MOM.
-( groaning )
-OH OH OH OH!
-( grunts )
-HEY, MISTER, YOU OKAY?
- YOU'RE NOT DEAD, - ARE YOU?
-( grunts )
-- ( screaming ) -- ( screaming )
- BUTCH!
-BUTCH, BUTCH! -THERE'S A BIG RED MAN -OUT THERE, OUTSIDE,
-- IN THE BACKYARD! -- AND THIS WILLBENEFIT ME HOW?
-I'M SERIOUS! -I THINK HE FELL -FROM THE SKY.
-- ANOTHER U.F.O.? -- I KNOW THIS SOUNDS CRAZY,
-BUT YOU'VE GOT TO -COME OUT AND SEE!
-IF YOU'RE LYIN', -YOU'RE DYIN'!
-NO BIG RED MAN OUT HERE. -MAYBE HE WENT BACK TO MARS.
-HE WAS HERE! -I TELL YOU I SAW HIM.
-WAKE SOMEONE ELSE -UP NEXT TIME.
-THEY'VE GOT US -LOCKED IN HERE!
-WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO? -HE'S GONE.
-WAKE UP, ALL OF YOU! -WE'RE DONE FOR!
-- HE'S RIGHT. -- OF COURSE I'M RIGHT.
-NO SANTA, NO CHRISTMAS. -AND WHERE DOES THAT LEAVE US?
-WHERE INDEED?
-- ( yelling ) -- ( Brontos, Squealmuttering )
-( Squeal mutters )
-JOIN YOUR PARTY, -YOU LOSER!
-LOSER!
-( barks )
-( laughs, groans )
-- AW, GEE! -- WHAT DID YOU DO THAT FOR?
-- Brontos: - GET GOIN'! -- POINTER, DID THEY HURT YOU?
- WHAT HAPPENED?
-I SAW WHAT THEY DID WITH SANTA. -THEY PUT HIM IN THAT CHAIR.
-IT'S SOME SORT -OF LAUNCHING MECHANISM.
-SANTA DEMATERIALIZED, -AND, ZAP, HE WAS GONE!
-( all gasp ) -NO!
-AND LOOK-- -HE LEFT BEHIND -HIS MAGIC HAT.
-WE NEED TO FIND OUT -WHERE THEY SENT HIM.
-WITHOUT HIS MAGIC HAT, -IT'LL BE HARD FOR HIM -TO GET BACK.
-- WHEN SANTA COMES BACK-- -- IF SANTA COMES BACK--
-WHEN SANTA RETURNS,
- WE MUST BE READY - FOR CHRISTMAS.
-- WE CAN'T LET HIM DOWN. -- OR THE CHILDREN.
-- AHA! -- ( yells )
-A SUPPORT GROUP MEETING -FOR THE VERTICALLY CHALLENGED,
-- I PRESUME. -- HEY!
-- SILENCE! -- ( all gasp )
-YOU WEREN'T PREPARING
-FOR ANY SORT OF LITTLE -REBELLION, WERE YOU, HUH?
-HUH?! -WHAT ABOUT YOU, HAROLD?
-NO, ATNAS.
-BUT YOU'D TELL ME -IF YOU WERE?
-NO, I WOULD NOT. -I DON'T LIKE WHAT IS -GOING ON AROUND HERE,
-BUT I'M OLD ENOUGH -TO KNOW THAT THERE IS -NOTHING I CAN DO ABOUT IT.
-- I WILL OBEY. -- AH, OBEDIENCE.
-THE SOUND OF -COWERING SURRENDER
- IS MUSIC TO MY EARS.
-AND NOW, IF YOU -WILL ALL EXCUSE ME,
-I HAVE A GLOBAL -TELECAST TO PREPARE.
-MY AUDIENCE AWAITS.
-NO TRICKS, MY OBSEQUIOUS -LITTLE REBEL.
-( laughing maniacally )
-( all laughing maniacally )
-Bob: - YES, I AM FULLY AWARE THAT - I'M LATE WITH MY PAYMENT.
-- Man: - Pay up, loser! -- WELL, SAME TO YOU, PAL.
-- ( beeps ) -- ( doorbell rings )
-HEY, MISTER, YOU'RE LATE -WITH YOUR PAYMENT AGAIN.
-I HAVEN'T GOT -MY CHECKBOOK ON ME.
-HA! CHECK? -SO I CAN DRIBBLE IT -AGAIN TO THE BANK?
-CASH ONLY!
-FINE. -WHO NEEDS THE PAPER?
-I GOT ENOUGH -BAD NEWS AS IT IS.
-- HEY, BUPPO. -- ( splat )
-- OW! -- BULL'S-EYE!
-THAT HURT, BUTCH!
-MISSION ACCOMPLISHED.
-COME ON, MAN. -DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
- COME ON. - DO SOMETHING.
-COME ON.
-NO? -YOU'RE PATHETIC!
-NOW GET YOUR BUTT -DOWNSTAIRS BEFORE I RELOAD.
-- OH, BROTHER. -- YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
-YOUR BIGGER, -YOUR SMARTER BROTHER,
- AND DON'T YOU FORGET IT.
-IF IT WASN'T FOR ME, THEY'D -HAVE SENT YOU TO THE WIMP -ACADEMY A LONG TIME AGO.
-WHAT'S THE WIMP ACADEMY?
-THE WIMP ACADEMY -IS WHERE THEY SEND
-LITTLE TURTLE-HEADED -WIMPS LIKE YOU.
-TIME'S UP.
-YOU ARE NOW A DEER -IN MY HEADLIGHTS.
-NO!
-YEAH! -( laughs )
-MAYBE I REALLY -AM A WIMP.
-JEREMY, YOU'RE TOO OLD -TO BE MAKING SUCH A MESS.
-BUT, MOM, I DIDN'T DO IT.
-Bob: - THEN WHO DID, JEREMY? - HUH? SPEAK UP.
-WHO WAS IT? -WAS IT BUTCH?
-IT'S OKAY, SON.
-TAKE A BREATH, -LOOK A PERSON IN THE EYE, -AND SAY WHAT YOU GOT TO SAY.
-IF SOMEONE DID THIS TO YOU, -DON'T TRY TO PROTECT THEM -BY NOT TELLING US.
-- NOW WAS IT BUTCH? -- BOB, DON'T START ON HIM.
-WHO IS STARTING? -WILL YOU CUT ME SOME SLACK?
-NOT IN FRONT -OF THE BOYS.
-HE'S A GEEK, DAD. -THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
-AND I'M NOT TALKING SOME -CIRCUS FREAK THAT BITES OFF -THE HEADS OF CHICKENS.
-I'M TALKING -BONA FIDE, PARANOID,
-HALLUCINATING, -OUT-OF-TOUCH-WITH-REALITY,
-KRIS-KRINGLE-OBSESSED GEEK.
-DON'T TALK THAT WAY -ABOUT YOUR BROTHER. -BOB, SAY SOMETHING.
-BUTCH, DON'T TALK THAT WAY -ABOUT YOUR BROTHER.
-- GEEK. -- THAT'S IT.BUTCH, GO TO YOUR RO
-DAD, IT'S OKAY.
-BUTCH IS TEACHING ME -TO BE TOUGH SO I'M -NOT SUCH A WIMP.
-HEY, DAD, WHY ARE YOU -SLEEPING ON THE COUCH?
-YEAH, DAD, HOW COME?
-- WHOA! -- IT'S ABOUT TIME.
-( giggles )
-IT'S GOOD TO BE KING!
-OH, YES, IT IS, -O GREAT EMINENCE!
-WHERE'S SQUEAL -AND THOSE ELVES?
-I NEED MY MINIONS -TO BECOME ACQUAINTED
-WITH THEIR NEW MASTER.
-MRS. CLAUS WANTED TO SEE YOU, -SO WE BROUGHT THEM HERE.
-I'M PERFECTLY CAPABLE -OF SPEAKING MY OWN MIND.
-NOW, WHAT HAVE YOU -DONE WITH SANTA?
-I'VE STEPPED IN -TO GIVE HIM
-A MUCH-NEEDED SABBATICAL. -OOH!
-( chuckles )
-YOU WOULDN'T POISON -YOUR BROTHER-IN-LAW, -NOW WOULD YOU, DEAREST?
-NO. I JUST WANT -SANTA BACK,
-YOU-- YOU BRUTE!
-- SQUEAL? -- ( gibbers )
- YOU LIKE COOKIES? - TASTE ONE.
-THEY'RE GOOD, BOSS. -MMM!
-OW. OOH.
-- WHERE IS SANTA? -- HE'S TRIPPINGTHE LIGHT FANDANG
-NOEL, I'D DO -ANYTHING FOR YOU.
- IN TIME - YOU'LL FORGET HIM.
-CLAUS HAS FLAWS.
-( laughs )
-OH, WHAT A WOMAN.
-- OH! -- NOW THEN,
-DURING MY BROTHER'S -ABSENCE,
-I'LL BE IMPLEMENTING -A FEW CHANGES AROUND HERE.
-NUMBER ONE: -YOU WILL MAKE ALL -THE GIFTS FOR ME,
-TO SUIT ME, -TO CELEBRATE MOI.
-NUMBER TWO: -I WANT A DATABASE LIST
-OF ALL THE WONDERFULLY NASTY -LITTLE GIRLS AND BOYS.
-FORGET ABOUT THE GOOD -LITTLE GIRLS AND BOYS.
-SEND ME THE DIRTY -ROTTEN SCOUNDRELS.
-THEY WILL BE MY ARMY.
-THEY WILL HELP ME -RULE THE PLANET
-ONE HOLIDAY AT A TIME.
-NOW GO TO IT.
-AND NO MORE MOPING -FOR MR. HO-HO-HO.
-HEY, WHAT MAKES YOU THINK -YOU CAN JUST WALTZ IN HERE,
- ABDUCT SANTA, - TAKE OVER THE NORTH POLE,
-AND RUIN CHRISTMAS -FOR EVERYONE, HUH?
-EEE-EEEH!
-I THINK -I UNDERSTAND NOW.
-YOU'LL DO AS I SAY, -OR I'LL TURN YOU
-INTO REINDEER FOOD. - CAPISCE?
-WOW! -THE BUSTER!
-"F-O-S"? -NEVER SEEN THAT BEFORE.
- ( coughing )
-( groans )
-WHERE AM I?
-YOU'RE IN OUR BACKYARD. -ARE YOU OKAY?
-I DON'T KNOW. -I'M NOT SURE.
-I SEEM TO HAVE TAKEN -QUITE A FALL.
-IT SURE LOOKS THAT WAY. -HI. I'M JEREMY. -WHO ARE YOU?
-- WHO AM I? -- YOU'RE DRESSEDLIKE SANTA CLAUS
-IS THAT WHO YOU ARE?
-I FEEL LIKE I FELL -FLAT ON MY HEAD.
-IT MUST HAVE BEEN -ONE HECK OF A NIGHT.
-I JUST CAN'T -REMEMBER WHO I AM
-OR HOW I GOT HERE.
-I SEEM TO RECALL
-THAT I WAS GOING SOMEWHERE
-AND DOING SOMETHING, -SOMETHING IMPORTANT.
-AND THEN--
-AND THEN...
-THERE YOU WERE.
-DO YOU WANT TO TALK -TO MY DAD, OR MAYBE MY MOM?
-MAYBE THEY CAN HELP.
- ON SECOND THOUGHT,
-MAYBE YOU SHOULD STAY HERE -UNTIL YOU REMEMBER -WHO YOU ARE.
-GOOD IDEA, JEREMY.
-YOU CAN STAY HERE -UNTIL YOUR MEMORY COMES BACK. -I'LL GO GET YOU A BLANKET.
-HOW ABOUT SOME -PIGS IN A BLANKET? -I AM TERRIBLY HUNGRY.
-YOU'LL BE SAFE -IN HERE, I PROMISE.
-I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT -PIGS IN A BLANKET -MEANT, BUT HERE.
-I FOUND SOME LEFTOVER -SAUSAGE AND PANCAKES.
-THAT'LL DO, JEREMY. -THAT'LL DO.
-LISTEN, WHEN YOU DO REMEMBER -THAT YOU'RE SANTA,
- THERE'S SOME STUFF - I REALLY WANT.
-I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU'RE -SO SURE I'M SANTA CLAUS,
-BUT I DO REMEMBER SOMETHING.
-I WAS FLYING.
-THAT'S IT! -THAT PROVES IT! -I SAW SOMETHING!
-IT WAS YOU! -YOU FLEW ACROSS THE MOON!
-BUT SOMETHING HAPPENED, -AND YOU FELL -INTO OUR BACKYARD.
-MIGHT I HAVE SOME SYRUP?
-TAKE THIS. -( snickering )
-WHEE WHEE WHEE -WHEE WHEE WHEE!
-BOSS, WE GOT SOMETHING -TO TELL YA.
-- WHAT NOW? -- UH... SANTA'S MISSING.
-WHAT DO YOU MEAN, -SANTA'S MISSING?
-WELL, NOT -"MISSING" MISSING.
-HE JUST DIDN'T LAND WHERE -HE WAS SUPPOSED TO LAND.
-- HE SORT OF BOUNCEDOFF THE MOON -- OH, REALLY?
-- YEAH. -- AND WHERE, PRAY TELL,
-DID THE JOLLY BOY WONDER -OF CHRISTMAS CHEER
-SET HIS GELATINOUS -JELLYROLL DOWN, HUH?
-LOS ANGELES.
-INCOMPETENCE.
-I'M SURROUNDED -BY INCOMPETENCE!
-BUT, BOSS, IT WAS YOU -WHO SET THE COORDINATES -AND PUSHED THE BUTTON.
-- WHAT DID YOU SAY? -- NOTHING, YOURWORTHLESSNESS.
-GO AFTER HIM.
- GET IN THE CHAIR - AND GO AFTER HIM!
-BUT DON'T YOU THINK -WE OUGHT TO DO
-A LITTLE MORE TESTING -BEFORE WE JETTISON AGAIN?
-YEAH YEAH YEAH. -VERY UNPREDICTABLE -RESULTS LAST TIME.
-FIND HIM NOW!
-- ( gibbering ) -- ( yelling )
-- AAH! -- UH...
-YOU WOULDN'T SEND US -TO PLUTO OR SOMETHING, -WOULD YA, ATNAS?
-I WOULDN'T DREAM -OF SENDING
-MY LOYAL THUGS -TO PLUTO...
-- WHEW! -- ...UNLESS, OF COURSE,YOU FAIL
-BUT, THEN AGAIN, -YOU CAN'T FAIL,
-NOT IF YOU -WANT TO LIVE.
-Y-YEAH.
-( blubbering )
-IDIOTS. -I'VE GOT TO FIND -BETTER HELP.
-MOM, I WANT YOU -TO MEET SOMEONE.
-( screams )
-MOM. MOM. MOM.
-- Santa:I'M SORRY. -- ( whimpers )
-I DIDN'T MEAN -TO FRIGHTEN YOU.
- I GUESS I MUST - BE A SIGHT.
-YES, YOU ARE. -I DON'T MEAN TO BE RUDE,
-BUT WHAT ARE -YOU DOING HERE?
-YOU MUST BE -JEREMY'S MOTHER.
-WHO ARE YOU?
-PRECISELY! -I DON'T REMEMBER.
-I'M AFRAID I'M GOING TO -HAVE TO ASK YOU TO LEAVE.
-BUT, MOM, HE'S NOT DANGEROUS. -HE'S SANTA CLAUS.
-OH, YES. -WELL, I UNDERSTAND.
-I AM A STRANGER... -EVEN TO MYSELF.
-HE COULD STAY IN THE TENT. -PLEASE, MOM?
-HE DOESN'T EVEN -KNOW WHO HE IS.
-WE CAN'T JUST LEAVE HIM.
-UM...
-WELL, HE DOES -SEEM HARMLESS.
-I SUPPOSE IF HE DOESN'T MIND -STAYING IN THE TENT,
- THEN I CAN'T - SEE THE HARM.
-THANKS, MOM! -YOU'RE THE BEST!
-THANK YOU -FOR YOUR KINDNESS.
-STRANGE.
-I KNOW THERE'S SOMETHING -I'M SUPPOSED TO BE DOING
-RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
-MAYBE YOU WERE WORKING
-IN ONE OF THE LOCAL -DEPARTMENT STORES?
-PERHAPS I COULD -RAKE THE LEAVES
-IN THE BACKYARD FOR YOU.
-WAIT TILL MY FRIENDS -HEAR ABOUT THIS.
-- Winona: - JEREMY? JEREMY! -- WHOO-HOO! YEAH!
-WHOO WHOO -WHOO WHOO!
- ( transmitter buzzing )
- ( buzzing continues )
-( groans ) -WE'RE CLOSE.
-( laughing )
-WHOA.
-- TAKE A LEFT! -- INITIATING LEFT TURNIN THREE,
-- WILL YOU CUT THAT OUT? -- SORRY. - I'M A LITTLE NERVOUS.
-HOW COME HE DOESN'T KNOW -IF HE'S REALLY SANTA?
-HE FELL, MAYBE -FROM HIS SLEIGH, -AND LANDED ON HIS HEAD.
-WE'VE GOT TO HELP -HIM REMEMBER.
-DOES THIS RING A BELL?
-HMM.
-NOT REALLY. -SHOULD IT?
-YOU HAVE TO REMEMBER -WHO YOU ARE.
-IT'S ONLY TWO DAYS -BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
-REMEMBER THIS -X-17 WATER LASER -YOU GAVE ME LAST YEAR?
-CAN'T SAY AS I DO.
-- SANTA? -- YES?
-AREN'T YOU GOING TO ASK ME -WHAT I WANT FOR CHRISTMAS?
-OH... YES, OKAY.
-UH... OH, UM...
-WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE -FOR CHRISTMAS, SAMUEL?
-I WANT A NEW BIKE
-WITH A REALLY COOL -ELECTRONIC SPEEDOMETER.
-I SEE.
-AND, YOU... WHAT WOULD -YOU LIKE, LISA?
-I'D LIKE A PUPPY,
-A SOFT BROWN PUPPY -NAMED BUDDY.
-OH, THAT'S -A WONDERFUL WISH.
-OH, JEREMY, -AND YOU?
-SANTA, I REALLY -APPRECIATE
-ALL THE GREAT GIFTS -YOU'VE GIVEN ME -OVER THE YEARS,
-- BUT THIS YEARI DON'T WANT ANY -- OH?
-I WANT MY MOM AND DAD -TO LIKE EACH OTHER AGAIN.
-THEY HAVEN'T BEEN GETTING -ALONG TOO GOOD LATELY.
-YOU THINK YOU COULD -HELP ME OUT?
-GOOD COOKIE?
-THE BEST, -MY DEAR NOEL.
-OH, THE BEST EVER.
-LOOK AT THIS TEDDY BEAR.
-IT'S THE BEST -WE'VE EVER MADE.
-AND LOOK AT THIS CAR. -ZOOM ZOOM!
-LOOK AT THIS GUITAR. -IT ROCKS!
-RIGHT PAST -THE MOON, ALICE!
-- OH-HH! -- ( Atnas laughing )
-OH-HHH!
-SANTA? SANTA?
-NOEL, ATNAS.
- I REMEMBER, YES.
-YES.
-SANTA-- THAT'S ME.
-I AM SANTA CLAUS.
-I'VE GOT TO -CALL MRS. CLAUS.
-I'VE GOT TO GET BACK -TO THE NORTH POLE. -THERE'S NO TIME TO LOSE.
-I AM SANTA!
-Kids: YEAH!
-HO HO HO HO HO!
-I'M SANTA CLAUS, YES!
-- ( kids cheering ) -- I REMEMBER!
- ( cheering continues )
-Santa: - I REMEMBER!
-AH! -( laughs ) -GOTCHA!
-NO MORE "HO HO HO!"
-MORE LIKE "NO NO NO!"
-PARK HERE.
-- COME ON! -- I'M GOING, I'M GOING!
-Brontos: -YEP, THIS MUST -BE THE PLACE.
-WE SET UP HERE.
-Brontos: - OH, PRETTY HOUSE.
-Squeal: -KEEP IT DOWN, OKAY?
-Radio: - The heat wave keeps - pounding the Southland...
-Squeal: -HEY, LOOK.
- ...downtown at - a record 88°
- while it climbed up - to the low 90s - in the valleys.
- Beach cities had a nice--
-Kids: -YEAH!
-( cheering )
-- WHO ARE ALL THESE KIDS? -- HEY, DAD, ISN'T THIS GREAT?
-SANTA REMEMBERS WHO HE IS. -WE HELPED HIM REMEMBER.
-WHAT IS GOING ON HERE? -WHO'S THE LOONY TUNE -IN THE RED PAJAMAS?
-THE KIDS FOUND THIS MAN, -AND THEY THINK HE'S -SANTA CLAUS.
-- SANTA? -- YEAH.
- HE COULD BE SOME ESCAPEE, - SOME MADMAN FROM - COUNTY LOCKUP.
-- I WANT HIM OUT OF THE YARD. -- HE'S NOT HURTING ANYONE.
-HE MIGHT HAVE AMNESIA.
-BOB, I CAN KEEP AN EYE -ON HIM FROM RIGHT HERE.
-GO ON, KIDS. -GO HOME. SHOO!
-TIME FOR DINNER. -PLENTY OF FOOD -AT YOUR OWN HOUSE.
-GO ON. GO BOTHER -YOUR OWN FOLKS.
-THAT'S IT. -EXCELLENT. -ADIOS.
-- WHERE'S YOURCHRISTMAS SPIRIT? -- THIS IS L.A.
-IT'S 90°. -I'VE HAD A LOUSY DAY.
-THE SMOG IS -BURNING MY RETINAS, -AND THERE'S NO SNOW.
-CAN I TALK TO YOU -FOR A MINUTE?
-I CAN SEE YOU'RE NOT -TOO HAPPY ABOUT ALL THIS.
-ACTUALLY, I'M FINDING IT -QUITE INTERESTING MYSELF.
- YOU SEE, I TEMPORARILY - LOST MY MEMORY,
-BUT THANKS TO YOUR SON -AND HIS FRIENDS
-I NOW KNOW -WHO I AM AGAIN.
-I REALLY NEED TO CALL -THE NORTH POLE.
-LISTEN, BUB, TAKE -YOUR PIED PIPER ACT -SOMEWHERE ELSE.
-TAKE IT SOMEWHERE, ANYWHERE. -AM I MAKING MYSELF CLEAR?
-OH, YES, QUITE CLEAR.
-I'M ONLY CRAZY, -NOT STUPID.
-- ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT. -- BY THE WAY,
-BOBBY,
-THAT SLED YOU WANTED -WHEN YOU WERE FIVE -AND DIDN'T GET,
-THAT WAS A TOUGH CALL.
-IT SADDENED ME -TO DENY YOU YOUR WISH.
-BUT YOU REALLY -HADN'T BEEN
-A VERY PLEASANT -FELLOW THAT YEAR.
-LOCKING YOUR SISTER -IN THE CLOSET?
-THAT WASN'T VERY NICE.
-DROPPING EGGS ON OLD -MR. FISHER'S HEAD?
-TSK TSK.
- CLOGGING - THE SCHOOL TOILETS...
-HOW COULD YOU -KNOW ALL THAT?
-HE KNOWS ALL KINDS -OF THINGS, DAD. -HE'S SANTA CLAUS.
-DON'T BE RIDICULOUS, JEREMY. -THERE IS NO--
-DAD, DON'T DO THIS.
-DAD, PLEASE.
-SANTA, WAIT.
-- OH! -- PLEASE DON'T GO.
-DON'T YOU WORRY, JEREMY. -I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
-BUT HOW ARE YOU GOING TO -GET BACK TO THE NORTH POLE?
-I DON'T KNOW. -I HAVEN'T FIGURED -THAT OUT YET.
-IF I HAD MY MAGIC HAT, -IT WOULD BE A LOT EASIER.
- MAYBE I WILL - NEED SOME HELP.
-I COULD HELP YOU.
-PLEASE, DAD. -HE DOESN'T HAVE -ANYBODY TO HELP HIM.
-( sighs ) -ALL RIGHT, FINE. -COME ON.
-THANKS, DAD.
-ALL RIGHT. -I'LL TELL YOU WHAT, BUB,
-GO INTO THE GARAGE, -AND THERE'S SOME BEDDING -AND STUFF IN THERE.
-BUT THERE IS A LIMIT. -YOU FOLLOW?
-LOUD AND CLEAR.
-ANYWAY, I NEED TO FIND -MY WAY BACK TO CHRISTMASTOWN.
-I REALLY NEED -TO USE YOUR PHONE. -ONE QUICK CALL TO THE POLE.
-PERFECT. -THE POLE, DEFINITELY.
- ( phone beeps )
-- ( line rings ) -- Hi there. - Atnas here.
- Santa can't come - to the phone. - He's moved.
- And Mrs. Claus - is all tied up now.
- ( laughs )
- Leave a message, - and no one will get - right back to you.
- Don't forget - to send money,
- lots of money, - and gifts to me,
- me, Atnas, King - of the North Pole!
- Santa schmanta, - I'm in charge now!
- ( laughs )
-OH, DEAR.
-THANKS FOR NOT -CHASING SANTA AWAY. -HE REALLY NEEDS OUR HELP.
-We've GOT TO HELP HIM -GET BACK TO THE POLE.
-( chuckles ) -NOW LISTEN, SON, -HE CAN STAY HERE
-TILL THE MEN IN THE WHITE -COATS COME FOR HIM,
-BUT YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND -HE ISN'T SANTA CLAUS.
-- TAKE IT EASY, BOB. -- BUT, DAD--
-LIGHTEN UP. -THEY WERE HAVING FUN.
-THEY WERE GETTING INTO -THE SPIRIT OF CHRISTMAS.
-ALL RIGHT, -ALL RIGHT, -ALL RIGHT.
-- I GOT SOME BAD NEWS. -- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
-THEY GOT INTO THE HOLIDAY -SPIRIT EARLY AT WORK.
-THEY SENT 200 OF US HOME -AND TOLD US NOT TO COME BACK.
-NO BONUS, NO THANK YOU, -NO NOTHING.
-THEY CALL IT DOWNSIZING.
-IT'LL BE OKAY, DAD.
-ONCE WE GET SANTA HOME, -HE'LL HELP YOU GET A NEW JOB,
-A BETTER JOB, I'M SURE.
-- WHEN? -- LAST WEEK.
-WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN -GOING EVERY DAY?
-LOOKING FOR ANOTHER JOB.
-I JUST COULDN'T TELL YOU -I'D BEEN FIRED, OKAY?
-I GUESS CHRISTMAS -IS BEING DOWNSIZED, -TOO, CHIEF.
-CHRISTMAS ISN'T -ABOUT SIZE, DAD.
-IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY. -IT IS.
-ISN'T IT?
-SURE, SON. -BUT I'M NOT EXACTLY IN -A "JINGLE BELL" SORT OF MOOD.
-BUT, BOB, THE TREE?
-YOU PROMISED.
-I'D BETTER GO CHECK IN -ON THE PIED PIPER -OF MERRIMENT.
-SOMEBODY'S GOT TO KEEP -AN EYE ON THAT ONE.
-HEY HEY HEY! -WHAT IN THE NAME OF--?
-WHO TOLD YOU TO MESS -AROUND WITH THIS?
-HEY, THAT'S ME.
-LOOK AT THAT FORM.
-I WAS QUITE AN ATHLETE -IN THOSE DAYS.
-WHAT HAPPENED, BOB?
-I DON'T KNOW.
-HAD SUCH DREAMS -FOR MYSELF.
-THEN I GOT A SO-SO JOB -IN A SO-SO COMPANY.
-THEY FIRED ME LAST WEEK -WITHOUT SO MUCH -AS A THANK YOU.
-NOW I CAN'T EVEN AFFORD -A DECENT CHRISTMAS.
-I CAN'T BELIEVE -THIS IS HAPPENING.
-SURELY, YOU MUST BELIEVE. -IT'S NOT TOO LATE -TO CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
-IT'S NEVER TOO LATE.
-SOMETIMES WE LOSE -ONE DREAM.
-THAT'S WHEN WE NEED -TO DIG DOWN DEEP,
-GET CREATIVE, -FOLLOW ANOTHER DREAM.
-YOU'VE ONLY GOT TO -BELIEVE IN YOURSELF, BOB,
-AND YOU STILL HAVE A CHANCE -TO LIVE A NEW DREAM.
-I HAVEN'T GOT -TIME FOR DREAMS. -I NEED A JOB.
-CREATE YOUR OWN JOB. -TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
-ASK YOURSELF, -"WHAT IS IT PEOPLE -NEED MOST?
-YOU'RE A PRETTY -CREATIVE FELLOW, BOB.
-CLEAN POOLS. -PEOPLE NEED CLEAN -SWIMMING POOLS.
-- THAT'S RIGHT. THEY DO. -- I KNOW WHERE I CAN GETSOME POO
-- HEY, I THINK YOU'RE REALLYONTO -- ( laughs )
-I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M -GETTING CAREER COUNSELING
-FROM A GUY THAT THINKS -HE KNOWS PRANCER AND DANCER.
-I'VE GOT TO GET -OUT OF HERE.
- ( engine starts )
-HE'S IN THERE. -WHAT ARE WE -GOING TO DO NOW?
-WE GO IN AFTER HIM -AND GRAB HIM.
-THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
- ( Brontos snickering )
-( pants )
-- READY? -- I WAS BORN READY!
-( beeps )
-WANT TO TRADE? -I WANT THE ORANGE ONE.
-HEY, SANTA, YOU WANT TO -PLAY SOME VIDEO GAMES?
-QUICK, JEREMY, -YOU'VE GOT TO HIDE ME.
-TWO OF MY BROTHER'S -DREADFUL HENCHMEN
-ARE RIGHT OUTSIDE -LOOKING FOR ME.
- ( doorbell rings )
-- CAN I HELP YOU? -- OH, YES.
-UH... -( clears throat )
-EXCUSE US, MA'AM.
-WE'RE FROM THE DEPARTMENT -OF WATER AND POWER,
-- AND WE NEED TO CHECK - YOUR LINES. -- EXCUSE ME?
-THERE'S BEEN A SURGE -IN THE LINES,
-AND WE'VE NARROWED IT -DOWN TO YOUR HOME.
-THE POWER SURGE -IN THE ELECTRIC CAPACITOR
-INDICATES THAT THE OBSTRUCTION -IS LOCATED SOMEWHERE -IN THIS HOUSE.
-- EXCUSE ME. -- PARDON ME.( giggles )
-WE'LL JUST BE A MINUTE. -OFFICIAL BUSINESS.
-YES. -COULD BE SERIOUS.
-COULD KNOCK OUT POWER -IN THE WHOLE NEIGHBORHOOD.
-- MY WORD. I SUPPOSE YOUNEED TO -- YES, MA'AM, EVERY ROOM.
-HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE?
-UH...
-WHAT?
-WE'LL START UPSTAIRS.
-PARDON ME! -EXCUSE ME!
-OH OH OH OH!
-HO HO HO HO -HO HO HO HO, OH!
-( speaks gibberish)
-- OH OH OH! -- THAT WAY!GO GO GO!
-HURRY HURRY HURRY!
-( gasps )
-( gibbers )
-COME ON! -GO GO GO! -HURRY HURRY!
-( whimpers )
-- COME ON, COME ON! -- Brontos:WHEE WHEE! OKAY.
-( blubbers )
-( spits ) -I REALLY HATE -WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
-( grunts )
-I'M SORRY. -WE REALLY SHOULD GET -THE CHIMNEY CLEANED.
-- I'LL SAY. -- ( door opens )
-- THANK YOU VERY MUCH. -- GET HIM!
-- WHOA! -- HURRY HURRY HURRY!
-THIS AIN'T OVER YET. -COME ON.
- EXCUSE ME. - HI.
-UH... MISTER--
-MR. WHATEVER-YOUR-NAME-IS,
-I JUST WANT TO APOLOGIZE -FOR MY HUSBAND.
- HE'S...
-HE'S...
-IT'S HARD BEING BOB.
-NO APOLOGIES REQUIRED.
-THANK YOU -FOR PROVIDING ME
-WITH A WARM BED -AND A CHANCE -TO FIND MYSELF.
-YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT'S -WHAT BOB NEEDS, TOO.
-HE'S A MAN WHO -STILL CARRIES AROUND -A BROKEN DREAM.
- HE JUST HASN'T BEEN - ABLE TO LOOK UP
- AND SEE THAT HE'S GOT - A NEW DREAM RIGHT HERE:
- A BEAUTIFUL WIFE
- AND TWO FINE BOYS WHO - BOTH NEED AND LOVE HIM.
-YOU SEE ALL THAT?
-A BLIND MAN COULD SEE
-HOW MUCH YOU LOVE HIM -AND YOUR SONS.
-THANK YOU.
-ALL RIGHT. -IF YOU NEED ANYTHING, -JUST CALL, OKAY?
-WHAT I REALLY NEED
-IS A WAY TO CONTACT -MRS. CLAUS
-AND HITCH A RIDE BACK -TO THE NORTH POLE.
-THEY MUST BE TERRIBLY -WORRIED ABOUT ME.
-UH... YEAH,
-I SUPPOSE THEY ARE -WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
-OKAY.
-- NIGHT. -- NIGHT.
-( sighs )
-UNHAND ME!
-ATNAS, YOU'RE -SUCH A SORE LOSER.
-REALLY, AFTER -ALL THESE YEARS, -GET OVER YOURSELF.
-OH, THAT HURT, -DEAR LADY.
-I THINK OF NO ONE -BUT YOU, NOEL.
- I LONG FOR YOU.
-I'D SCALE -A WALL FOR YOU.
-I ITCH FOR YOU. -( laughs )
-PLEASE. -YOU'RE SUCH -A SCOUNDREL, ATNAS.
-I MADE MY CHOICE -YEARS AGO.
-YOU HAD YOUR CHANCE,
- BUT YOU WERE BUSY CHASING - EVERY GIRL THAT MOVED.
-YOU ONLY WANTED ME -BECAUSE SANTA WANTED ME.
-OH!
-THAT CUTS ME -TO THE QUICK!
-( sobs )
-GOOD.
-NOW, STOP ALL THIS -NONSENSE AT ONCE.
-RELEASE MY HUSBAND. -BRING HIM BACK TO ME.
-I WOULD DO ANYTHING -FOR YOU, MY DEAR,
-ANYTHING BUT THAT.
-LET ME SHOW YOU -THE WORLD.
-LET ME SHOW YOU THINGS -YOU'VE NEVER EVEN DREAMED OF--
-VOLCANOES, TIDAL WAVES,
-- DINNER THEATER. -- EWW!
-GIVE ME A CHANCE. -GIVE ME A CHANCE.
-LET ME SHOW YOU -THE DARK SIDE OF LOVE.
-GET A GRIP. -YOU NEED HELP,
-IMMEDIATE -PSYCHIATRIC HELP.
-( laughs )
-HATE ME! -HATE ME IF YOU MUST, NOEL.
-THERE'LL BE NO HATING HERE. -WE DON'T HATE PEOPLE -AT THE NORTH POLE,
-EVEN IF THEY ARE -EVIL LIKE YOU.
-NOW PULL YOURSELF TOGETHER.
-WELL, TELL ME AT LEAST -THAT THERE'S SOME HOPE.
-I SHALL PERISH WITHOUT -A KIND WORD FROM YOU, NOEL.
-THERE'S ONLY ONE MAN FOR ME, -AND THAT'S MY HUSBAND.
-I LOVE SANTA.
-THEN YOU HAVE DOOMED HIM -FOR ETERNITY!
-I WILL BANISH HIM -TO THE DARK SIDE OF PLUTO.
- MY VENGEANCE - WILL BE SWIFT!
- MY ANGER WILL - KNOW NO BOUNDS.
-SHOW ME SOME -SMALL KINDNESS.
-ONLY THEN WILL I CONSIDER -SPARING SANTA
-FROM THAT LONG, -COLD RIDE
-THROUGH THE COSMOS.
-WHOA! -( groans )
-( snoring )
-- SHH! -- ( whispers )
-( both grunting )
-YOU GO.
-OUCH!
-OH!
-- SHH! -- HO HO HO HO HO.
-( snores )
-- GOTCHA, BIG GUY. -- ( muffled protests )
-- WHAT DID HE SAY? -- ( mumbles )
-- ( muffled protests ) -- Brontos: HURRY UP!
-- ( grunting ) -- Squeal: IT'S HEAVY!
-Santa: -OW OW, OH!
-OW! OH!
-SANTA MAN IS -IN THE BAG.
-ALL RIGHT, I'M GOING -TO CALL THE BOSS.
-- COME ON. -- OKAY.
-- ( beeping ) -- YOUR EMINENCE,
-KING OF THE DARK WONDERS -OF THE UNIVERSE, -WE HAVE HIM.
- Oh, good good!
- Good! - ( laughs )
- Now will you pull - yourself together - and take him to the cave!
-- TAKE HIM TO THE CAVE. -- TAKE HIM TO THE CAVE?
-- THE CAVE. -- THE CAVE.
-Both: -TAKE HIM TO THE CAVE, -THE CAVE, THE CAVE.
- TAKE HIM TO THE CAVE.
- ( Santa protesting )
- ( computer beeps )
-Mrs. Claus' voice: - A MESSAGE TO ALL CHILDREN
- FROM MRS. CLAUS - AT THE NORTH POLE:
- SANTA IS IN TROUBLE. - PLEASE BE ON THE LOOKOUT - FOR HIM.
- IF YOU SEE HIM,
- LET HIM KNOW - HELP IS ON THE WAY.
-SANTA. SANTA?
-SANTA?
-MOM, MOM, -I LOOKED FOR SANTA.
-I CAN'T FIND HIM. -HE'S GONE. -AND HE NEEDED MY HELP.
-IT'LL BE OKAY. -GO BACK TO BED.
-BUT I DIDN'T EVEN GET -A CHANCE TO SAY GOODBYE
- AND TELL HIM THAT MRS. CLAUS - HAD A PLAN TO GET HIM BACK.
-I'M SURE THE OLD MAN, -WHOEVER HE WAS, -WILL UNDERSTAND.
-HE ISN'T AN OLD MAN. -HE'S SANTA CLAUS, -AND HE'S IN TROUBLE.
-HOW IS HE GOING TO GET -BACK TO THE NORTH POLE -IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
-JEREMY, BED.
-( groans )
-Mrs. Claus: - GOOD. IT'S BEEN DECIDED.
-POINTER, GOOD LUCK.
-ME? BUT I'M A CYBER ELF. -I'M GOOD WITH COMPUTERS.
-I DON'T DO -THE RESCUE THING.
-FIND SANTA AND GIVE HIM -HIS MAGIC HAT.
-- I DON'T WANT IT. -- NEITHER DO I.
-- NOT ME. -- YIKES!
-- NO, SIR. -- OH, BOY.
-- NO, SIR. -- OH, NO.
-- NOT ME. -- OH, NO.HERE YOU GO.
-I DON'T WANT IT.
-I REALLY DON'T THINK -I'M THE RIGHT ELF -FOR THE JOB.
-CAN WE SEND ONE -OF THE REINDEERS?
-IT IS AS IT SHOULD BE. -WE'LL START WITH THE BOY.
- LET'S GO.
-OH! OH!
-- OH! -- COME ON.MOVE IT, POINTER.
-TAKE A RIGHT -AT THE NEXT TUNNEL.
-Pointer: - OH!
-Harold: - THIS IS IT. - YOU'RE HERE.
- WATCH YOUR HEAD. - BE CAREFUL.
-- YOU READY? -- NO!
-OH, COME ON.
- ( buzzing )
-( whimpers )
-ONE, TWO, THREE!
-OH-HHH!
- ( whooshing sound )
-( grunts )
-WHEW!
-WHO ARE YOU?
-THERE'S NO TIME -FOR IDLE CHITCHAT. -WE MUST GO. WE MUST!
-AND WHAT ARE YOU? -HOW DID YOU GET HERE?
-I'M AN ELF...
-FROM THE NORTH POLE -ON A MISSION -TO FIND SANTA.
-SHH! YOU'LL WAKE UP -MY BROTHER BUTCH.
-( snoring )
-HE DOESN'T BELIEVE -IN SANTA CLAUS,
-AND HE DEFINITELY -DOESN'T BELIEVE IN ELVES.
-WELL, I NEVER!
-HERE, STEP INTO MY OFFICE. -WE REALLY MUST GET ON WITH IT.
-( snorts )
-MY NAME IS POINTER. -THERE'S NO TIME TO WASTE.
-I'M HERE TO BRING SANTA -HIS MAGIC HAT.
-HIS HAT? MAGIC?
-OF COURSE. -HOW DO YOU THINK HE GETS -DOWN THOSE CHIMNEYS?
-- HIS MAGIC HAT? -- EXACTLY.
-ATNAS HAS TAKEN OVER -SANTA'S WORKSHOP.
-- WHAT'S AN ATNAS? -- ATNAS IS SANTASPELLED BACKWARD
-HE'S SANTA'S EVIL BROTHER.
-- HIS BROTHER? -- YES.
-AND HE'S BAD -TO THE BONE.
-HE'S EVERYTHING BAD, -WHERE SANTA'S -EVERYTHING GOOD.
-WHERE SANTA WANTS TO GIVE, -ATNAS WANTS TO TAKE.
-AND IF HE SUCCEEDS, -HE'LL CHANGE -CHRISTMAS FOREVER.
-- NO MORE GIFTS. -- NO MORE GIFTS?
-NO MORE SANTA.
-WHAT CAN I DO?
-YOU, JEREMY, -CAN SAVE CHRISTMAS.
-I CAN? HOW?
-BY HELPING ME FIND SANTA.
-NOW ACCORDING -TO OUR CYBER RECORDS,
-HE WAS LAST SEEN HERE -IN THIS HOUSE WITH YOU.
-LET'S VERMOOSE.
-WHERE ARE WE -VERMOOSING TO?
-FIRST, WE MUST FIND -A SPECIAL ALLY.
-- WHO? -- F.O.S.
-F.O.S.?
-I KNOW WHERE -THERE'S AN F.O.S.
-HEY, OPEN UP.
-- WELL? -- HE'S ON HIS WAY.
-IT'S IMPERATIVE THAT -JEREMY AND POINTER
-FIND AND RESCUE SANTA.
-WHAT IF WE DON'T -FIND SANTA?
-IF SANTA DOESN'T RETURN -IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS,
-THERE WOULD BE -NO CHRISTMAS.
-IT WOULD BE THE END.
-( all scream )
- ( shop bell rings )
-HELLO THERE. -WELCOME TO EARL'S.
-IF THERE'S ANYTHING -I CAN HELP YOU WITH, -JUST LET ME KNOW.
-GREETINGS, FRIEND.
-( laughs )
-- WHAT'S GOING ON? -- AH, WELCOME, FRIENDS.
-WHAT BRINGS YOU -ON SUCH A LONG JOURNEY?
-I HAVE TERRIBLE NEWS.
-SANTA HAS BEEN KIDNAPPED -AND WE NEED YOUR HELP -IN LOCATING HIM.
-- WHO WOULD DOSUCH A THING? -- ATNAS.
-AH. I WAS AFRAID -YOU WOULD SAY THAT.
-COME WITH ME.
-COME ON.
-I STILL HOPE -THIS WORKS.
-WHAT DOES F.O.S. MEAN?
-FRIEND OF SANTA.
-- TAKE A GOOD LOOK. -- WOW, IT'S COOL.
-ALL RIGHT, -ALL TOGETHER.
-- ME? -- MM-HMM.
- ( buzzing )
-THERE HE IS. -WHAT DO WE DO? -EARL, DO SOMETHING.
-WE MUST BRING SANTA -HIS MAGIC HAT.
-- HE'LL TAKE IT FROM THERE. -- HOW DO WE GET THERE?
-- WE JUMP. -- JUMP?
-JEREMY, YOU'VE BEEN CHOSEN. -GRAB THE CHANCE.
-YOUR COURAGE IS NEEDED. -IT MUST BE SOMEBODY -WHO BELIEVES IN SANTA,
-SOMEONE WHO BELIEVES -IN CHRISTMAS.
-I BELIEVE IN CHRISTMAS.
-AH.
-THE MAGIC WORDS, JEREMY. -COME. WE MUST GET -A RUNNING START.
-ONE...
-TWO... THREE!
-REMEMBER, BE YOURSELVES.
-AND WATCH OUT! -THERE MAY BE A TRAP!
-WOW, THAT -WAS UNREAL!
-BELIEVE ME, -IT WAS REAL.
-THE QUESTION IS, -WHERE ARE WE?
-YOU MEAN, YOU DON'T KNOW?
-NOPE, I HAVEN'T A CLUE.
-( groans ) -THIS IS NOT GOOD.
-WHAT KIND OF ELF -ARE YOU, ANYWAY?
-A SCARED ELF. -I WISH I WAS BACK -AT THE NORTH POLE
-OPTIMIZING SANTA'S -HARD DISK.
-POINTER, SNAP OUT OF IT. -YOU'RE NOT AT THE NORTH POLE.
-YOU'RE HERE.
-BUT... WHERE IS HERE?
-OH BROTHER. -WELL, WE MUST BE CLOSE.
-LET'S GO THIS WAY.
-BUT WHAT IF IT'S -THE OTHER WAY?
-OH, I JUST DON'T KNOW -WHICH WAY TO GO.
-SOMETIMES YOU'VE GOT -TO GO THIS WAY.
-Sign the paper, Santa.
- Sign it, - and stop all this.
-You've lost. -I've won.
- The only stocking to be - stuffed will be mine.
-And someday, when -they finally tell
-the story of my life,
-I will be right there -to publish it.
-I'LL NEVER SIGN -AWAY CHRISTMAS.
- CHRISTMAS IS - BIGGER THAN I AM.
-CHRISTMAS IS -BIGGER THAN US ALL.
-You've had your turn.
-Let the dark side rule.
-Sign the paper, -blubber boy.
-- SIGN IT. -- YEAH, SIGN IT!
-SO, STARTING YOUR -OWN BUSINESS, HUH?
-I CAN'T AFFORD TO WAIT AROUND -FOR SOMEBODY TO HIRE ME.
-NOPE. I'M SETTING UP -SHOP RIGHT HERE.
-- BOB'S POOL SERVICE. -- GEE, BOB--
-NO, ALGAE, AND I'M -ITS NUMBER-ONE ENEMY. -( laughing )
-IT'S A TOUGH BREAK, -LOSING YOUR JOB RIGHT -BEFORE CHRISTMAS, HUH?
-THINK POSITIVE, FRED. -THINK CHEMICALS.
-THINK SWEEPERS. -THINK FILTERS.
-THINK THAT LONG-HANDLED POLE -WITH THE NET ON THE END -FOR THE LEAVES.
-THAT LONG-HANDLED POLE -WITH THE NET ON THE END -FOR THE LEAVES.
-HEY, DOES THIS WORK?
-YEAH, I THINK SO.
- ( static )
-Greetings. -It is my great pleasure
-to inform the world -that there will be -no Christmas.
- ( laughs ) - Not this year.
-Atnas is the new -kid in town.
-Atnas rules.
-Atnas wants those gifts -delivered el pronto,
-or Atnas will continue
-referring to himself -in the third person.
-And not only that,
-the fat boy gets it.
-( laughing maniacally )
-Uh... that just in
-from Santa's -evil brother,
-identified as Atnas.
-Preparations are taking place -to comply with his demands.
-We're getting reports.
-Calls are flooding -the White House from -people all over the world
-as this heinous news -spreads across the globe.
-- ( TV clicks off ) -- WHAT THE HECKIS GOING ON HERE?
-IT SOUNDS LIKE SOMEBODY -KIDNAPPED SANTA... CLAUS.
-YEAH RIGHT, AND THE TOOTH -FAIRY'S MIXING MY MARTINI -AS WE SPEAK.
-BOB, WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM.
-- JEREMY'S MISSING. -- HECK OF A DAY.
-OH, GREAT.
-LET'S GO, FRED.
-- Fred: WHERE DO WE START? -- Bob: THE PLAYGROUND, - THE MALL, EVERYWHERE.
-I'M SCARED, JEREMY. -SCARED SCARED.
-ATNAS IS BAD BAD, -REALLY REALLY BAD.
-HE DOESN'T SCARE ME, -EVEN THOUGH I DON'T -EVEN KNOW HIM.
-SOMETIMES YOU -HAVE TO BELIEVE.
-YOU'RE RIGHT. -WHAT'S WRONG WITH ME?
-SANTA ALWAYS SAYS -THERE'S NOTHING -YOU CAN'T ACHIEVE...
-IF YOU BELIEVE.
-YEAH, BUT YOU STILL NEED -TO KEEP PUTTING ONE FOOT -IN FRONT OF THE OTHER.
-Winona: - DETECTIVE, THIS - ISN'T LIKE JEREMY.
-- DO SOMETHING! -- MRS. BUKOWSKI,
-DON'T PANIC.
- ALL RIGHT. - OKAY, LET'S REVIEW.
-NOW ON THE PHONE, -YOU MENTIONED SOMETHING -ABOUT A CARD STORE?
-YES, SPORTS CARDS. -EARL'S CARD SHOP.
-JEREMY COLLECTS CARDS -AND HE GOES THERE A LOT.
-BINGO.
-DID YOU HEAR THAT?
-- WHAT? -- THAT.
-THAT WHAT?
-YOU SEE ANYTHING?
-I SEE YOU.
-COME ON! -REMIND ME TO FIND -A NEW PARTNER
-ON OUR NEXT MISSION.
-( beeps )
-- LET'S GO. -- I'M GETTING HUNGRY.
-- WE AIN'T EATING - TILL ATNAS SAYS. -- FINE.
-OH, PRETTY WILDFLOWERS. -( giggling )
- ( overlapping dialogue )
-TELL MY MOM WHAT -SHE WANTS TO KNOW.
-EVERYBODY PLEASE -CALM DOWN!
-YOU'RE MAKING THIS HARDER -THAN IT HAS TO BE.
- YOU ADMIT TO TALKING - WITH THE BOY.
-YOU ADMIT TO FILLING -HIS HEAD WITH THESE IDEAS.
-NO, SIR.
-YOUNG JEREMIAH HAS -HIS HEAD ON STRAIGHT.
- HE'S A BRAVE LAD.
-HE'S OFF ON A QUEST, -ON A HERO'S JOURNEY.
-JEREMY. -MY SON'S NAME IS JEREMY.
-NOT JEREMIAH, -YOU OLD LOON.
-WHERE THE BOY HAS GONE...
-YOU CANNOT FOLLOW.
-WHAT ARE YOU, -THE RIDDLER?
-LISTEN... MISTER, -IF YOU KNOW SOMETHING,
-ANYTHING ABOUT WHERE -JEREMY MIGHT BE,
-YOU'VE GOT TO TELL US.
-THE LAST THING -JEREMY SAID
-THAT HE WANTED -FOR CHRISTMAS
-WAS TO HAVE -HIS PARENTS GET ALONG.
- NOW WHY WOULD - HE WISH FOR THAT?
-THE BRIDGE WAS HERE -A MOMENT AGO.
-BRIDGES JUST -DON'T... GO AWAY.
-YOU CAN'T JUST WALK ACROSS. -THERE'S NOTHING THERE.
-I GOT TO DO IT. -I JUST GOTTA.
-I DON'T THINK -I CAN WATCH THIS! -( whimpers )
-I BELIEVE IN SANTA.
-I BELIEVE IN CHRISTMAS.
-COME ON, POINTER!
-YOU DON'T NEED -A FRIGHTENED ELF.
-HERE, TAKE -SANTA'S MAGIC HAT.
-- WOW! -- GO ON, JEREMY.
-COME ON, POINTER.
-I NEED YOUR HELP. -SANTA NEEDS YOUR HELP.
-SO JUST TAKE A BREATH -AND RELAX.
-YOU DID IT, JEREMY! -YOU DID IT!
-( laughs )
-THE GLOBE SHOWED SANTA -INSIDE SOME KIND OF CAVE,
-BUT I DON'T SEE -AN ENTRANCE.
-OKAY, I BELIEVE -I SEE A BIG ROCK.
-NOW WHAT?
-NOW WE WAIT FOR A SIGN.
-I LOOKED EVERYWHERE FOR HIM. -ANY NEWS?
-- NO. -- COME ON.GIVE ME A HAND WITH TH
-( sighs ) -BUTCH, AM I A WIMPY DAD?
-- GRUMPY. -- WHAT DO YOU MEAN, GRUMPY?
-I'VE ALWAYS TRIED -TO BE A GOOD FATHER.
-DAD, DON'T GET ALL WEIRD -AND MOPEY ON ME NOW.
-YEAH, OKAY.
-I MEAN... HAVE I EVER -LET YOU GUYS DOWN?
-GET A GRIP, DAD. -TELL MOM YOU LOVE HER.
-PUT THE PAPER -DOWN AT BREAKFAST. -GIVE HER A KISS GOODBYE.
- HAVE A NICE LIFE.
-HI.
-THE DETECTIVE SAID -TO WAIT BY THE PHONE
-IN CASE HE CALLS -WITH SOME NEWS.
-I DON'T WANT THINGS TO BE -THE WAY THEY'VE BEEN.
-I WANT ANOTHER CHANCE -TO MAKE IT RIGHT.
-WE'RE TALKING. -THAT'S A START.
-I JUST GET PREOCCUPIED.
-SOMETIMES I-- -I GUESS I'M GRUMPY.
- BUT I LOVE YOU.
-I'M WORRIED.
-WILL WE EVER SEE -JEREMY AGAIN?
-HUH?
-WATCH YOUR STEP. -THERE'S ROCKS AROUND.
-( muttering )
-HEY, IT'S ONLY A MIRAGE.
-COME ON.
-MAYBE WE SHOULD -SPLIT UP.
-ARE YOU KIDDING? -DON'T YOU WATCH THE MOVIES?
-WHENEVER YOU SPLIT UP, -SOMETHING BAD HAPPENS,
-LIKE YOU GET KILLED -OR WORSE.
-WHAT'S WORSE -THAN BEING KILLED?
-LOOK! SANTA!
-- ( muffled protests ) -- SANTA, THANK GOODNESSWE FOUND
-LOOK OUT!
-( screams )
-Winona: - THANK YOU. - NO, WE'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
-PLEASE CALL,
-NO MATTER WHAT YOU FIND.
-- WELL? -- THE DETECTIVE SAYS THEY'VESCOU
-CHECKED THE PARKS, -THE MALLS--
-NOTHING. I'VE CALLED -EVERYONE I KNOW.
-HEY, ALL THE NEIGHBORS -HAVE THESE POSTERS.
-- WE GOT 'EM UP ALL OVER TOWN. -- IT'S A COOL POSTER.
-THERE'S GOT TO BE -SOMETHING ELSE WE CAN DO.
-- I CAN'T STANDTHIS MUCH LONGER. -- YOU GUYS CALL ME
-- IF THERE'SANYTHING I CAN DO. -- THANKS, FRED.
-Fred: - WINONA, DON'T - WORRY SO MUCH.
-JEREMY'S A TOUGH KID.
-I'M BANKING ON HIM.
-YOU'D BETTER PREPARE YOURSELF -FOR THE WORST, PAL.
-IT'S A TOUGH WORLD -OUT THERE.
-SO LONG.
-SOMETHING TERRIBLE'S -HAPPENED TO OUR BOY. -I JUST KNOW IT.
-DON'T SAY THAT, HONEY. -DON'T GIVE UP HOPE.
-DON'T BE SCARED, MOM.
-JEREMY'S TOUGHER -THAN YOU THINK.
-HECK, HE'S SURVIVED -LIVING WITH ME
-AND I'VE TORTURED THE LITTLE -GUY WITH SPITBALLS -AND INSULTS FOR YEARS.
-- HE'LL SHOW UPBEFORE WE KNOW IT -- YOU MISS HIM TOO, DON'T YOU?
-UH... OOH!
-HMM.
-UH!
-BOOP, WHOO!
-( laughs )
-I'LL RAISE YOU ONE SKULL.
-- DONE. -- HUH?
-GO FISH.
-OH! TIME FOR -ANOTHER GAME.
-WHAT'S WITH THEM? -DON'T THEY KNOW
-THAT THEY'RE SPOILING -CHRISTMAS FOR EVERYBODY?
-THEY LEARNED -FROM THEIR MASTER.
-ATNAS HATES CHILDREN.
-HE HATES ELVES. -HE HATES EVERYBODY.
-SOUNDS LIKE A PERFECTLY -HATEFUL GUY.
-HE HATES ME.
-WHY DOES HE -HATE YOU, SANTA? -HE'S YOUR BROTHER.
-HO HO! -BROTHERS CAN BE TOUGH.
-TELL ME ABOUT IT.
-IT'S HARD TO BE -AN ATNAS.
-I'M AFRAID I CAN'T -QUITE EXPLAIN MY BROTHER.
-( sighs ) -HE WASN'T EXACTLY -POPULAR GROWING UP.
-HEY, SHUT UP OVER THERE!
-WE'RE PLAYING BLACKJACK -AND YOU'RE THROWING OFF -MY CONCENTRATION!
-- 20. -- HIT ME.
-OH!
-OH! I THINK -YOU BROKE MY FACE!
-IT LOOKS -THE SAME TO ME.
-WE'VE GOT TO GET SANTA -HIS MAGIC HAT.
-RIGHT.
-HERE'S THE GOOD NEWS: -JEREMY AND POINTER -HAVE FOUND SANTA.
-THANK GOODNESS!
-- IT'S WONDERFUL! -- WHAT'S THE BAD NEWS?
-THEY'VE BEEN -CAPTURED BY ATNAS. -ALL HOPE IS LOST.
-OH-HH!
-WHERE WERE YOU -WHEN SANTA HELD HIS -SENSITIVITY-TRAINING COURSE?
-DON'T BLAME ME. -IT'S NOT MY FAULT.
-YOU'RE EXACTLY -WHO I BLAME.
-WHO LET ATNAS AND HIS THUGS -INTO THE NORTH POLE, ANYWAY?
-WELL, I FOUND A BOX. -I THOUGHT IT WAS A GIFT.
-WELL, WHO JUST CAME -IN HERE AND HAD TO -BLURT OUT THE BAD NEWS?
-LOOSE LIPS SINK SHIPS.
-BUT BUT BUT...
-HEY, HE'S -GETTING LOOSE!
-GRAB HIM!
-HEY, BRONTOS.
-OH, NO!
-COME ON, KID. -GIVE ME THE HAT. -COME ON.
-- COME AND GET IT. -- ( screams )
-OH, NO!
-( yelling )
-- OOPS. -- BETTER CALL THE BOSS.
-- ( both whimper ) -- ( electronic beeping )
-UH-OH.
-( flushing )
- THAT WAS GOOD, JEREMY.
-THAT WAS REALLY GOOD.
- HO HO!
-HOWEVER, WE STILL NEED
-AN F.O.S. TO GET -BACK TO THE POLE.
-Both: -NO PROBLEMO!
-BUT HOW ARE WE GOING TO -GET BACK TO THE CARD SHOP?
-HO HO! -TAKE MY HANDS.
-ONE FOR ALL -AND ALL FOR CHRISTMAS.
-Both: -ONE FOR ALL
-AND ALL FOR CHRISTMAS!
-- ( Earl laughs ) -- HO HO!
-I HAVEN'T HAD -THIS CLOSE A CALL -SINCE THAT MIRACLE.
-OH RIGHT, WITH THAT -LITTLE GIRL ON 34th STREET.
-YES, THAT ONE.
-OH, AHH.
-AHH.
-WELL? -COME ON, JEREMY.
-WE STILL NEED YOUR HELP.
-THAT'S RIGHT. -ATNAS IS HOLDING
-THE ELVES -AND MRS. CLAUS.
-ONCE MORE -INTO THE BREACH, -MY FRIENDS.
-All: -ONE, TWO, THREE!
-HO HO HO! -WE MADE IT. -WE'RE BACK.
-OH! -( laughing )
-HO HO HO HO!
-Mrs. Claus: - I MISSED YOU.
-I MISSED YOU SO MUCH, -YOU BIG BEAR!
-HO HO HO! -I MISSED YOU, -TOO, MY CUPCAKE.
-BUT, PLEASE...
-NOT IN FRONT -OF THE ELVES.
-THANK GOODNESS -YOU'RE BACK.
-THANK GOODNESS FOR POINTER -AND JEREMY HERE.
-( laughs ) -OH, COME HERE.
-I HATE TO BREAK THIS UP, -BUT ATNAS IS PREPARING
-TO COLLECT ALL THE GIFTS -FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
-IF WE DON'T STOP HIM, -IT'LL BE TOO LATE.
-HE STILL CONTROLS -THE CYBER ROOM.
-- HMM. -- WE NEED A PLAN.
-- HMM, WE DO, WE DO. -- YES.
-I GOT A PLAN.
-- HEY. -- COME ON.
-- ( overlapping dialogue ) -- (Jeremy whispers )
- ( computers beeping )
-I'VE... RECONSIDERED
-YOUR PROPOSITION -OF MARRIAGE, ATNAS,
-AND I'VE... GIVEN IT -A LOT OF THOUGHT.
- I KNEW YOU'D COME - AROUND, MY QUEEN.
-OH! EVER SINCE -I FIRST SAW YOU,
- I KNEW THAT SOMEDAY - YOU'D BE MINE.
-I HAD TO HAVE YOU.
-OH! I WILL SHOWER -YOU WITH GIFTS.
-I'LL MAKE YOU -PRETTY THINGS
- THAT THOSE ELVES NEVER - EVEN DREAMED OF MAKING.
-I'LL BE EVERYTHING -THAT THAT FOOL -OF A BROTHER OF MINE,
-AND HAS-BEEN HUSBAND,
-NEVER COULD BE.
-UNHAND MY WIFE, -YOU VIPER!
-OH, NO YOU DON'T, -NOT THIS TIME.
-I SHOULD HAVE WASTED YOU -WHEN I HAD THE CHANCE. -GET HIM!
-CHARGE!
-- YAH! -- HEY, YOU!
-- GET HIM! -- JUST TAKE THE ELF!
-- THIS WAY! -- GERONIMO!
-GET HIM, PAPA! -GO!
-THE EVIL YOU DO COMES -TO HAUNT YOU EVERY TIME.
-( thugs shouting )
-OH, MY!
-- OH-HH! -- OW!
-OH-HH!
-( groans )
-OH, NO!
-YOU NEED SOMETHING DONE, -YOU GOT TO DO IT YOURSELF.
-GOODBYE -AND GOOD RIDDANCE!
- ( laughing maniacally )
-( yelling )
-OH! OH!
-OH, NO. -OH OH!
-OH, NO!
- ( buzzes )
-( wails )
-OH!
-( hysterical wailing )
-YES! -HE'S GONE!
-- YES! -- ( laughing )
-ALL RIGHT! -YEAH!
-HURRAY!
-HO HO HO HO!
-( all laughing )
-QUICKLY, LET'S ACTIVATE -THE SEARCH CONTROL.
-( beeping )
-- ( laughing )BON VOYAGE, BRO! -- BYE!
- ( laughing )
-- GET TO WORK HERE.YES INDEED. -- QUIET!
-CONGRATULATE -YOURSELVES LATER, HUH?
-IT'S CHRISTMAS EVE. -WE'VE GOT TO SEND -SANTA ON HIS WAY.
-- GOTTA GO. -- ELF COUNCIL.
-HAROLD, IS -EVERYTHING READY?
-BLESS YOU, SANTA. -THANK GOODNESS YOU'RE OKAY.
-YES, THE GIFTS ARE READY. -WE WERE AHEAD OF SCHEDULE -WHEN ATNAS TOOK OVER.
-SAVE THE HUGS AND KISSES -FOR LATER, HUH?
-HE'S RIGHT, SANTA. -IT'S LAUNCH TIME.
-DID YOU SAY LUNCH?
-BUT WE HAVEN'T -EATEN FOR HOURS.
-( clears throat ) -VERY WELL THEN.
-I WANT TO THANK YOU ALL -FOR EVERYTHING YOU DID -WHILE I WAS AWAY.
-AND I WANT TO THANK YOU -FOR KEEPING THE SPIRIT -OF CHRISTMAS ALIVE.
-HO HO HO HO! -AND NOW I MUST AWAY!
-HO HO HO HO!
-BUT WAIT.
-HOW DO I GET HOME?
-- OH, DEAR. -- OH, MY.
- ( people cheering on TV )
-IT'S BEAUTIFUL, -JUST BEAUTIFUL.
-TV anchorman: - This just in:
-Atnas has been stopped.
-Santa is on his way.
- And we have - unconfirmed reports
-of Santa sightings -all across the world
-as he makes his -Christmas run on time.
-- That's the late - breaking news. -- ( TV clicks off )
-I ONLY WISH JEREMY WERE -HERE TO ENJOY THIS.
- ( rumbling )
-- ( gasps ) -- OH!
-HO HO HO HO! -MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYONE.
-MERRY CHRISTMAS!
-YOU! WAIT A MINUTE. -YOU MEAN, YOU ARE -SANTA CLAUS?
-YES, BOB... -( chuckles )
-THERE IS A SANTA CLAUS.
-AND I'VE BROUGHT -SOMETHING FOR YOU.
-SURPRISE! -I'M HOME!
-JEREMY!
-OH, THANK GOODNESS!
-OH, THANK YOU, SANTA.
-NO NO, THANK -YOUR BRAVE SON JEREMY.
-WITHOUT HIM, THERE -WOULDN'T BE A CHRISTMAS.
-( clicks tongue ) -OH, BROTHER.
-I GUESS I'LL BE GOING. -I STILL HAVE A BIG -NIGHT AHEAD OF ME.
-BUT WAIT, SANTA.
-WILL I EVER -SEE YOU AGAIN?
-HO HO! -DON'T YOU WORRY, JEREMY.
-I'LL BE AROUND.
- ( chiming )
-WELL, IT'S OFFICIAL.
-MERRY CHRISTMAS!
-HO HO HO HO HO!
-FOR YOU, BOB AND WINONA,
-TO KEEP THE LOVE -LIGHT BURNING.
- ALL YOU TRULY NEED - IS LOVE.
-- FOR YOU, BUTCH. -- WHAT'S THIS?
-A FULL SCHOLARSHIP
-TO THE TORPEDO MILITARY -ACADEMY FOR BOYS.
-COOL.
-OH, YES,
-I ALMOST FORGOT--
-FOR YOU, JEREMY.
-( clears throat )
-"JEREMY, FOR YOUR COURAGE,
-FAITH, LOYALTY -AND DETERMINATION,
- LET IT BE - KNOWN HEREWITH
-NEAR AND FAR -ACROSS THE LAND
-AND AROUND THE GLOBE
-HENCEFORTH JEREMY -SHALL BE KNOWN
-AS 'THE BOY WHO -SAVED CHRISTMAS'."
-- I'M SO PROUDOF YOU, JEREMY. -- WE BOTH ARE.
-SQUARE BIZ, JEREMY.
-BYE, SANTA.
-HO HO HO! -MERRY CHRISTMAS TO ALL
-AND TO ALL -A GOOD NIGHT.
-HO HO HO HO HO!
- MERRY CHRISTMAS! - HO HO HO HO!
-MERRY CHRISTMAS, SANTA.
- ( Santa laughing )
-Jeremy's voice: - "DEAR SANTA,
- THANKS AGAIN - FOR EVERYTHING.
- MY PARENTS LIKE - EACH OTHER AGAIN
- AND DAD'S NOT SLEEPING - ON THE COUCH.
- BUTCH IS GOING AWAY - TO SCHOOL.
- WE EVEN GOT A TREE.
- ON THE JOURNEY TO FIND YOU - I LEARNED A LOT.
- I LEARNED FROM POINTER - THAT A PERSON CAN BE AFRAID
- AND STILL HAVE COURAGE.
- I WAS SCARED, - PLENTY SCARED,
- BUT I KEPT GOING.
- SOMETIMES IT TAKES COURAGE - TO BELIEVE IN STUFF
- EVEN WHEN - NOBODY ELSE DOES.
- I BELIEVE - IN YOU, SANTA,
- AND YOU HELPED ME - TO BELIEVE IN MYSELF.
- THANK YOU - FOR EVERYTHING.
- YOUR PAL, JEREMY,
- THE BOY WHO - SAVED CHRISTMAS."
-( beeps )
-NOW ON TO SOMETHING -A BIT LIGHTER.
-TODAY IS PUFFY -OUR OWN BENGAL TIGER'S
-THIRD BIRTHDAY.
-( laughs ) -KELLY.
-- HAPPY BIRTHDAY, PUFFY. -- ( laughing )
-NEXT UP, PEARL -GARRETT JOINS US
-WITH HER ANNUAL -HOLIDAY RECIPE.
-THIS YEAR: -FRUITLESS FRUITCAKE.
-FRUITLESS FRUITCAKE? -WHAT IS THAT?
-- CAKE. -- ( laughs )
-- GOOD NIGHT. -- MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYONE.