Cloud forests are one of
Mexico's most bio diverse ecosystems...
...as well as one of the most
threatened rain forests in the world.
Since 1996, in Veracruz,
a small community...
...has devoted itself to the
reforestation of an old cattle ranch.
There is a co-op
in this place today...
...where each partner
plays an important role...
...in the community's
development...
...thereby attempting
to live modestly...
...and harmoniously with
their environment.
Some time ago there were
some lumberjacks felling trees;
...but, one day, not all
of them went to work.
Just one kid went...
...whom they ordered to cut
down a huge tree, a very pretty one.
He sharpened his axe and began
cutting into the trunk.
All of a sudden he heard
a very strange noise...
...and the noise kept
growing louder.
He just stood there, and he wanted
to go find out what it was;
...but, then he saw something
like a mountain lion.
Those animals had never
been seen around here before.
So, when the kid went home,
he told the other lumberjacks
what had happened...
...and the guys made
fun of him, and said:
"We'll go tomorrow and
see what it's all about."
They went back again...
...and saw the tree they
intended to cut down...
...and they heard
new strange sounds...
...unlike the ones made by the animal
that had chased the kid off.
Then they saw like
four or five chaneques.
The kid got spooked and said
he saw them around here,
looking like wood sprites.
The sprites spoke
and told them...
...not to cut down that tree
because it belonged to them...
...and that they should
never come back again...
...because they were the
guardians of that forest.
What is it, baby?
Want a toy?
Easy.
If you can.
Otherwise, leave it.
It's easy.
That one there.
From there.
The branches will break off.
Pull it! Yeah, but
don't drop it all on me!
All done.
- This enough?
- Will this do?
Yes, that's good.
Remember last week when
we discussed permaculture?
- Yes!
- OK
What did we say?
That there were what principles?
-Ethical.
- And design-related.
Celebrate abundance,
share equally.
- Everything has to be equally
- I want examples.
You have your
water tank for a week...
...and, if you use it up
before the week is over...
...you can't have it recharged.
Rationing water.
Do you think it's a good idea?
- It's for Huatusco, for instance?
- Yes.
But first you need to
make an estimate, because...
...maybe one tank is not
enough for you.
Depends on how many liters.
Depends on what?
It depends on how many liters it
holds, our consumption, and?
And how many people
live at home.
- How many people?
- And how much the tank costs...
...because maybe some
people can't afford the tank...
...and, if they don't have a tank,
they won't get any water.
Great. There's the solution,
or a proposal of one...
...but it must be analyzed
from different points of view.
What good is it?
No, it's a good idea.
It's good because it
rations resources...
...and it's intended for them...
...to be shared equally.
Now, what are these
ethical principles for?
The last one.
Did Tejón leave right
away on Saturday?
Yeah, he wanted to
leave even before that;
...but, since we were
going to take him...
...I asked him to wait for me.
He needed to go see his
cows before nightfall.
Tejón had a new female calf,
bull calf, no, female, right?
What a pretty animal that was!
- So he has good animals?
- Yeah.
Yeah. And the other
one's about to calve too...
...the one that refused.
You didn't go to the
carnival yesterday.
- What for? I fell asleep.
- To get a couple of beers!
I've got my Tecate girls on my
calendar, no need to go see them there.
The ecosystems I mentioned
are marked in green, that is...
...low rainforest, high
rainforest, mangrove swamps,
...cloud forest,
pine and oak forests…
This is how the state looked
like before the Conquest.
This is how it looked supposedly...
...and,
this is actual scientific data...
...this is how it looked like in 2002.
What was left in color,
what you see in green...
...is what's left from the
original vegetation.
This is the perimeter of
“Las Cañadas”… 306 hectares.
We're here; we had
180 heads of beef cattle...
...grazing, sort of rotating in very
large pastures, on the hills.
All work was done by hand:
land clearing, then the herbicides.
It all went to the cattle ranch.
We got the cows out...
...we planted 50,000 native
trees in this deforested area...
...and, by 2007, this is how
things looked like.
Later on, we can see
the transformation.
This is last December.
You can still see little
patches of star grass,
but now it's covered with…
The change is quite obvious.
This over here looks open now.
You couldn't see it before,
because it was all cow pastures,
and now it's 6 hectares of
corn, for all the members.
You told me you were gonna
live far away from home...
...very far away from home.
Away from home,
but in “Las Cañadas”.
I would be like a
plant doctor or…
It's like a herb doctor
or something.
Like Concha?
Yeah, like Concha,
but a bit more
It's completely devoted to it.
And what were you
going to be in twenty?
Oh! I was also
going to be a writer.
- A writer?
- I was gonna write, in my free time.
What about you?
- No clue.
- Come on, Rafa!
Will you live in the
country or in the city?
I don't know.
Great prospects for the future.
If I join the army,
I'll be in the city.
- And if you don't?
- The army? Really?
Yes
All boys want the army.
Makes them feel powerful.
Why powerful?
Because you have a gun,
or something.
I wanna be an army doctor,
not a hitman.
Oh! OK!
Being in the army doesn't
mean being a hitman?
Exactly.
I won't kill.
OK, good! You'd better!
In this document,
we find that 1% in Mexico...
...controls 21% of the income.
That's more than in the U.S.,
than in Colombia.
It's the highest ratio
in the entire world regarding
...the countries we have
information about.
There are not many,
but for all the countries...
...we had information about...
...it was the country with the
highest income concentration.
The problem we're looking
at with the INEGI
in this "incident",
as Enrique calls it...
- That's what he calls it,
- What would you call it?
I'd call it I'm less
elegant than Enrique.
I'd call it a mistake.
I'd like to think it's
an honest mistake
Well, worse things
come to minds.
Thank you, Ricardo, both
of you for being here.
So if I give away
“Las Cañadas”, the land...
...and register it as a
nonprofit organization...
...if I donate it to a
...where we're all members
in a co-op, it means you.
I don't get any land.
You don't get any land!
Exactly.
- What do you think of that?
- I think it's great because…
Think about it and
tell me straight. Seriously.
Seriously, seriously, seriously,
I think it's great.
I do want a little piece for me,
for my home...
...my vegetable garden and stuff,
but what would I do with all that land?
Besides, if you
have that, it's like.
Well, the co-op members
wouldn't feel as safe
'cause they'd be building on
your land, so the day you go:
No more co-op", you'd be keeping
all those goods which area.
Yes, collective,
that belong to all of us.
And the idea that
everybody else would be…
Left out in the cold.
Right! I don't like that.
Besides, what would I
do with so much land?
Sell it and travel
around the world.
But, the money wouldn't
last forever, that’s no good.
Yeah, when it's gone, it's gone.
Oh!
Well, that's it, man,
I'm just waiting.
Yes, yes, I'll text you,
if anything happens.
Yes. Theoretically I'm due
this week, but, you know,
Jonás was two
weeks late, so…
Yes, Ani, I'm taking it easy, but you
know you can't take any medicine...
...when you're like this.
Here, take this one.
Yes, for your baby sister!
Shall I hold it, or does
it stay on its own?
It's anchored already.
It's clean. Stop.
Come here, let's
wash your hands.
I don't remember how it goes.
Like this, I think, right?
You don't tighten it?
Or was it?
It's the other way around.
Truth is I don't remember, dear.
-No, no, no, hold on!
-This one's not for you.
I definitely need the
larger screw, but it's lost.
It should be in the bag,
but it's not.
That's weird, because
you put everything in there.
Oh, now you did it!
Give the baby a little kiss.
Wow!
Yes.
Easy, easy, remember?
…remember she's very tiny.
Hey.
Firewood wouldn't catch.
It wouldn't catch?
Time to eat.
- It's the friendly hour.
- Some cheese?
Have a taco.
Remember, Don Adán,
the first time we met?
-Yeah.
-When we met?
Yeah.
It's been so nice.
We've been friends ever since.
How long has it been?
Like five years.
You were sowing corn over there.
I helped you plant
corn and beans.
I worked with you
for two weeks.
Then we went to
work in the barns.
Is it the one that has
stalks this thick?
They told me to use star
grass to fertilize my land.
Oh, and you took
it to Perote?
Yeah.
But I planted it
and watered it
and it died even faster.
Didn’t help much.
No, it didn’t help much.
Well, Don Adán, that was the
reason I stayed here with you.
Yes.
I asked if there was a chance
for me to work here with you.
And, I think yes, it’s fine by me
and I feel good here.
EMERGENCY PREP ROOM
That’s the heart.
-Is that where it hurts? Here?
-Yeah, it feels tight there.
That's where the…
in fact, that's where it starts.
Oh, right!
The contraction. See?
You already have a C-section,
and it could tear the…
…the scar left by Jonás.
In a very long labor,
it could tear…
But if everything goes
normally, does it…?
-We're almost there, aren't we?
-One week, tops.
-No, we're going to…
-No?
So we're going to
wait until I'm in labor.
Yes, right?
If I come back on Thursday and I’m not,
he’s gonna put me in the OR.
Yeah, looks like it.
Yeah, he will.
Let’s take it easy.
-What?
-Let’s take it easy.
It's illegal to perform a
C-section without your consent.
Yeah.
-He can't force you to.
-I wanted to see the dates,
‘cause he didn't even check.
His memory's bad, but
I'm still on time.
Yes.
And I have water, I mean,
everything’s fine. Fine.
-Oh, that man.
-Relax, woman.
Don't get all worked up.
It's not good for you.
Easy for you to say.
It's not you under the knife.
Rufino, could you tell
them where to enter?
Go through the
furrows up ahead.
Yes, but they
don't know how.
Ok, come on!
-Are you taking that spot?
-Yes.
-Take it easy, Karim
-What's wrong?
With your feet it’s
like half a step.
It’s about to rain, so…
-Do you want to switch?
-No, it's too big.
Taxi, guess what!
They're releasing Allegiant,
but in two parts.
Like Twilight!
That's what everybody
does with the last book.
Do you know who did it first?
Harry Potter.
I was reading yesterday
but I fell asleep.
"-What part are you on?
-I don't remember."
Taxi!
I remember only after
I’ve read it twice.
Has anything
happened with Caleb?
Or how do you say it?
I say Caleb.
"-But you say…
-Caleb. "
It gets intense.
That guy does something bad.
That's my favorite.
The cage is missing, man!
We'll unload a
couple of sacks here.
Everyone against Diego!
-Karim, stop it!
-What?
You throw the biggest stones!
-I don’t!
-Watch out!
Sofía! Vargas Pellicer!
Sofi!
Come to eat!
Come here, Güera,
don't eat José’s food!
Yeah, right? It’s Beto’s.
Does it work?
I don’t know.
Where’s Beto from?
From here.
I think so.
It’s no good! You’re done!
Like toast! Hurry!
Let’s see!
Rafa, come here
if you want some.
Pumpkin.
It counts, it counts.
3-2
Thanks.
I almost fell down.
Baby!
There's no point. If you're
full term, that’s it.
You already have a C-section,
there's no point in waiting.
We wouldn't want
anything bad to happen.
If you come in with an emergency,
then we run to the rescue, you know?
But we all have to be there.
-Today is the 28th?
-29th.
I don't know. What's the
right thing to do?
Oh, love, let’s do it.
OR
Where's mom?
I'll be right back. You stay
here with dad and Mónica.
Just for a bit.
"-We have a pair now!
-Yes.
Wow!"
The doctor's so quick, huh?
She needs warmth.
Want us to put something
here to hold her up?
-Yeah, good idea.
-What do you want?
Look at her.
Oh! You want to see,
you want to see.
Look, baby, your
baby sister.
Does it hurt?
Does it?
-What?
-The C-section?
Yes… yes.
I can tell.
And she’s shivering
with cold.
Look at her…
She likes you.
Your little sister's nursing.
Like the little goat, huh, baby?
Yeah, she's your little sister.
Let's go change your diaper.
Are you all here for the goats?
Damn, there's a lot of us!
Well, let's start by putting
one liter of corn in
each bowl, as usual.
The bad thing is you don't
hear it here, Haya.
No, you don't hear it.
You'll hear it as soon
as it gets full.
I'm hearing it.
Shut up, I'm just
getting started.
Bartolo does it better.
Hey! Stand still!
Don't squeeze her
so hard, Zacarías.
-Let's see.
-Haya'll beat you.
See? She knows.
No, Haya. I don’t
hear anything.
There it is!
It was already full!
Looks like Güera is
pregnant too.
Look, this one lets
you do it. Kinda.
Kinda, you're right.
He has a tiny mouth.
Puchus!
Let's go take him.
No, with this rope.
That one's too old; it'll snap.
Here.
Tell Zacarías to lift you up.
-You want up?
-I'll do it.
-You push the goat.
-Move, move!
Look at that, he's walking.
Go, Puchus!
The goat is getting
used to Puchus, but…
As long as he doesn't
sway too much, it's fine.
What is it, baby, what?
What's the matter, baby?
You would've liked a
natural birth, right?
Of course, mom, from
the first pregnancy.
And the goat had two, right?
Two, like a breeze.
She just pushed
and out they went.
What is it you like the
most about the ranch?
Well, mom, uhm…
…Everything.
Everything?
-There's so much to like, right?
-There’s no need to drive.
-No need to what?
-There's no need to drive.
Drive what?
-A car.
-Come on, you’re wrong on that one.
The need…
-No! I mean I like that!
-Huh?
I like that about this place.
Okay, fine, but you can't go
around with two kids,
walking…
It's a five-minute walk
to work, mom.
-Oh, well, here…
-Well, you asked about the ranch.
-Yes, right.
-Yeah.
And do you think your kids
have a good future here, Karla?
-Of course, mom.
-You do?
-Of course.
-Why?
For starters, the love for
the land. That's important.
To love the land, and
to know how to work it.
Whether they want to do it or not
later on, that's another story.
But don't you think they
need schooling, a career?
That's not an issue.
It doesn't have to be a formal
career for them to…
…for them to know things, right?
But, of course they need
school, mom.
But not the kind of schooling
there is now,
where you're disconnected
from everything else
and stuck in a classroom, right?
But, do they learn?
You did.
Yes, but I learned so much
more here, doing things…
-…than in school.
-Of course.
Every mom here,
myself included,
wants their children to
know things and learn.
What's the difference
between your family and his?
They all live there.
Just that?
That his family lives together?
I mean, the mom lives with
her children, right? Sort of.
-Would you like that?
-I would!
You didn't live with me,
though, for a long time.
That's why I'm telling you,
I didn't appreciate
that until I came here.
Oh!
That's why I invited you
to move here, right?
It's the kind of thing…
we want to instill in our children.
Sure, there's no guarantee.
Maybe they'll leave anyway.
The only thing she
wanted was to move here.
She got her certification,
and as soon as she did,
she said: "Mom, I'm leaving".
It made me sad, but…
She left everything
she'd learned behind,
everything she'd accomplished,
to start over,
because she wanted this.
I didn’t expect that.
But when I saw
how happy she was,
I was glad she came.
Because we all have
to be happy, right?
Allow our children
to find happiness.
I was concerned about
the way she lived and all,
because she was used to
another, a different…
…a different life, right?
But, when I saw how happy she was,
I accepted it.
I slept like two hours.
Three and a half,
more or less.
Hey, don't make fun, OK?
I thought you’d already
done something else,
being the principal's
daughter’s birthday and all…
Good morning, Don Goyo!
-Don Goyo!
-Good morning, kids.
I don't know if
you've visited the cities,
but there's a lot of
construction going on there.
That causes an impact on forests,
and you also need
material to build houses.
And where does this
material come from?
-The forests.
-If they need wood, from trees,
and if they need other minerals
or material, they clear them.
We're losing our forests,
what else?
-Fragmentation.
-What is that? Remember?
It's a kind of isolation.
Like Taxi says,
they build houses and
leave a forest on one side,
then houses, and a
forest on the other.
They're separated.
-They split it into pieces.
-And I guess animals,
if they don't have enough
room or space to live in,
they can't go elsewhere, because
there are houses, roads and stuff.
Jocelyn?
-There are several…
-Things.
Yeah, there's also
climate change, right?
With so many natural events,
they're being destroyed.
All right, what do you
recall about cloud forests?
-Cloud forests? Well…
-What caught your attention? Diego.
They don’t… How do you say?
Tree felling is not allowed.
Tree felling is not fully allowed.
What I found interesting is
that supposedly there are
very few cloud
forests in Mexico.
There are cloud forests
in very few areas.
They are nearly nonexistent
in the world actually.
So, what does all this information
make you think about?
We're talking
about our home,
the region of Huatusco, Coscomatepec,
all around Xalapa,
one of the few places where there
are still cloud forests in Mexico,
where there's biodiversity and
where we can still
find Quercus insignis.
So, what do you
think about that?
I think the world is going
to end because of this.
Oh!
But I don't know what to do.
Well, I can do something
to make it better,
but I don't think it'll
work if it's just me.
What can we do so
we won't feel like…
…frustrated, helpless?
Some kind of campaign?
Because rich people
pay to cut down trees,
to do things like that.
We all contribute in
some way or another.
-To the felling, I mean.
-We can…
Felling and climate change,
and everything.
How can we not contribute?
We need to do something to
prevent this from happening.
The question is:
can we do something?
Yes.
"-Stop consuming, I mean…
-Stop buying."
…not exaggerating with what we buy,
because sometimes we depend on it.
Like Toño says,
maybe a campaign
where we teach or show
people the importance of…
-A course.
-…of protecting the forest.
We can't save the
forests of the world,
but we can have an impact
on the place where we live.
Where to?
Where are you going?
Son of your…
grandmother!
Are you done?
You want to go already?
Let's go to class.
Let's go see the children.
So you can see Haya and Tania.
-Karla?
-Yeah.
Come here, you.
I didn’t catch you yesterday.
They already have their…
-…They already have their book.?
-Great.
-May I erase this?
-Yes!
"-We started to miss you, Karla.
-Who’s teaching you chemistry, Tania?"
I missed you, too.
Let's talk about vegetable
garden planning.
We're going to do another one?
No. We're going to make
a plan of what we’ll plant.
-Right.
-The first exercise is
to organize a bed, and see what
we will plant throughout the year.
The next step is for
third-graders to be able to
plan the six beds they have,
so that first- and second-graders
can help their classmates out.
That's the goal: to plan
throughout the year
what you'll grow in your beds.
"-Jicama!
-Jicama, in hot weather. "
That one, down here.
African cucumbers that
are planted in May.
That one here,
under humidity.
Look, kids, let me
tell you a bit about
how we learned about
vegetables here.
Since we only knew the
ones we’ve already mentioned,
we stopped planting
during the rainy season
because nothing thrived.
We planted carrots, beets,
cabbages; but they rotted.
-Every single year, until…
-Did they wilt?
Exactly, they wilted.
In our garden here,
we almost got no broccoli.
Very little.
Also last year, I think, they
planted in “Las Cañadas”…
-… but there was ground frost, so…
-That was two years ago.
-No. Last year, right?
-No, the frost was two years ago.
Two years.
-Well, the frost killed everything.
-All the plants died.
I've been here and it’s
really cold in March.
D'you know how the
mermaid myth was born?
Men were too long at sea
and didn't see any women.
So when they saw a manatee,
they were so desperate to see women
that they actually thought
manatees were women.
That's how mermaids were invented.
I think. Just don't
ask me where I read it.
-So when you spend a long time…
-Wikipedia?
No! When you spend a
long time with a woman…
Well, in this case, if you're a man
and you spend a long time with a woman,
even if she's plain, at a certain
point you'll think she's a mermaid.
Even if you have a
girlfriend, I swear.
And why are you in a
group from Venezuela?
It's not from Venezuela.
The group is from…
Oh! From a webpage where
you read stories.
Called Wattpad.
By the way.
So, this guy got into the group,
and asked me who Ameca was,
the one who said he was cute.
And I was like:
"What did you just say, man?"
And then…
Well, other things happened,
and I said: "Oh, that guy".
So we started getting along,
we started talking.
Then he texted me privately,
in a private chat,
and we became friends.
-Friends, just friends.
-Yeah.
-What?
-Tell me one reason
why a long distance
romance is a good thing.
Because when two people love
each other, it shouldn't matter.
-That's not a good reason.
-It is!
-No!
-I think long-distance love works.
No! It's like putting
yourself to the test.
Get it? If you really
love someone,
even if they're far away,
you don't cheat on them.
Why do you say 'cheat'? We're just
14, 16, 15-year-old pubescent kids.
Okay, if he kisses another girl.
-Pubescent kids…
-If he dates someone else.
I used to be obsessed with
medicine, veterinary medicine.
I'm not sure, but…
I think I'll go
into psychology.
Cool!
‘Cause, I don't know. I'm very
interested in it.
Although people tell me to go for
a career that has more demand.
That psychology doesn't
have much demand.
But I refuse to listen.
Are you going to
finish high school?
Here? I'd like to.
I'd like to stay,
and I'm going to,
but my aunts and uncles are
always on my case saying:
"Go someplace else.
You've been there for six years…”
-‘Cause you’re a bad influence.
-Hold on,
her aunt said she didn't
have any friends.
-What?
-My aunt said:
"Go study someplace else;
you don't have any friends there"
-She must love you.
-I am nothing.
How depressing.
And I'm going to live at
the Casa del Campesino.
-With me?
-Yes, we're gonna live together.
You're not in the club. Sorry, Rafa.
I wanna finish high school first.
-To begin with.
-To begin with,
I need to pass the semester.
Believe me.
With all the things that
happened to me this semester…
Why?
I have five reports.
-Why?
-Rafa!
At “Las Cañadas”, you were
really smart and got straight A’s.
-What happened to you?
-The party life.
-What?
-Nothing.
Do you still want to
become an army doctor?
Yes, I want to
go into medicine.
You've wanted to
ever since we were kids.
I'm hungry.
-You're hungry, Rafa?
-We just had lunch.
-Didn’t you eat anything?
-A bit.
"I just had two
tamales…"
He went to sit with
Oscar instead of us.
With Oscar…
I forgot he was down there.
I was on my own.
You were the ones who left.
No! We didn’t leave, you left, and
we went after you and we thought…
-Is that so?
-Yes, it’s true!
You didn't say anything.
There was no need for words, Rafa.
But the issue nobody talks about
is that of the land.
Have you always thought
about the entire land?
That's not the issue.
That's how most things are.
It's the least to put aside
a lot for Haya, but after Haya
you don't think about your
grandchildren or their children.
So you can go on forever saying:
"I'm not giving anything anymore!"
But, we need to start a process
with the next generation as well,
to make them feel they’re part
of the project, a part of the land.
Well, if you're working here,
if you have no other options,
if your ancestors
are buried here…
You have this space to design and
build your home, or you have…?
-Get it?
-Oh, I don't know.
But if she doesn't have
something that's her own,
and later on…
there's a conflict with the co-op,
or something happens, I mean…
I’m telling you.
That's the least of her worries.
If she has 2, 3 hectares
of her own, that's it.
If there's any conflict, you have your
space on the land where you were born.
That’s more than enough.
No problem.
We just do it. Period.
Fine, but that doesn't solve the…
Yeah, but it's just a possibility.
You just solve the problem
for the next generation.
And the one after that…
-Goes back to square one.
-No, adjustments have to be made.
That's what this is about.
How do we get the other
generations to work for the group?
Like in the
Longo Maï co-ops.
If someone's not
happy, well…
there's the door.
Half the children go,
half stay.
Right.
We need more children.
Are you up for it?
No.
Wow. The funny thing is you
never know what will happen.
-It's like…
-Yes, but you do know
what will happen
if you don't do it.
-Your grandchildren will sell.
-Of course!
-So now you know.
-I don't think Haya will.
I don't know that.
So now you know.
If I'm conscious when I'm dying,
that will be my last thought.
“Maybe Tania will
decide to travel…?”
“Will she auction
the whole thing?”
Would be okay,
right, Richi?
No, I'd come back to
haunt you. At night.
It's late, Mary.
Yeah, it's getting late.
Last time we had to
give the hens some weeds,
and someone told Julia
to give them flemingia,
and there she goes.
She got tons of it!
No kidding, Richi.
I think she took
all you had,
and she laid it
out for the hens.
When I got there, I asked Mauro:
"What is this?"
And he said: "Dunno.
I told Julia the hens wouldn't eat it,
but she gave it to
them anyway."
-When mom arrived…
-They didn't eat it.
Obviously not.
But mom gave us all
a piece of her mind.
Get the gate.
-Well, it was like a test.
-But they don't look alike.
Well, I don't think so.
You think we can get
something out of there?
Yeah.
What I still haven't read is why
it can be done in lemon water.
One day we'll have avocados.
There's a tree at school, but…
It's a Hass.
-That poor tree in the shade?
-Yeah, we always put urine
from the dry toilets, but…
it doesn't work much.
These trees need more
than just nitrogen.
All right, let's go.
Let's go that way.
Are we getting chaya?
This yam is ready.
See its leaves up there?
Yeah, is it that one?
Or that one?
Shall we take a look?
Just with your hand.
Look.
-See that?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
"-Take it out.
-Wait."
Yam, manioc, taro and,
in the end, air potatoes.
Manioc goes on
top of the taro?
Manioc on top of the taro,
that's right.
You're kidding.
Excuse me.
Look, there're others…
This little guy.
-Careful.
-Here.
Let me cut it for you. Hold on.
-It's really big.
-Yeah.
See how much
we got out now?
How much of that taro root do
you think is edible?
Well…
-But it tastes better.
-Look, each one of these…
Well, Haya…
We need leaves.
I think it's eight already.
Did you finally
manage to sew your…?
Yeah, I managed.
I hope the teacher
says they’re all right.
Good technique.
It's a technique,
but it's also…
-Skill?
-No. Practice, man.
I was Puchus’s age when
my dad took me to the harvest.
A bit older, when I
was like five.
Look at those
beauties, Querubín!
The sowing season feast.
We'll be busy.
We kill lambs on the 14th.
Then we skin them
and cut them up.
-You do that?
-Yeah.
Olegario too.
Olegario loves to kill.
I just tell him where,
and he does the dirty work.
"-Right, Romero?
-What?"
Like twenty lambs for
the feast of the corn.
Excuse me…
Move over!
Look, tie them like this
with one end, that end.
"-Together?
-Yes, all together there,"
so they won’t move around.
How do you mean?
Like this?
Yeah, like that.
That’s it.
We can pour it
in the big pot.
-What?
-The blood into the bins, right?
There's the green knife.
They sell them
at the flea market.
There you go.
-We're becoming experts.
-Yeah.
I’m gonna get into the
sheep business now.
Cántaro, don't pull
too much. There you go.
Otherwise, the blood
won’t come out.
Didn't even kick,
nothing.
If you pity it, it won't die.
You're right.
Its life’s passing
before its eyes.
That's why it won't die.
It’s strong!
-It’s quite some blood, huh?
-Yeah! Lots of blood.
It won’t die!
Someone's pitying it.
Gonzalito!
You're pitying it,
aren't you?
"-It refuses to die!
-Really?"
"-You didn’t hit the jugular.
-How many times did you stab it?"
It won't die.
There's no more blood.
There, that’s it.
"-You nailed it. Bled really well.
-Look how much blood!"
It’s dead now.
No, but it's dying.
Let's string it up.
"-This one's mine.
-This one?"
Yeah, that one’s mine.
That one. Where?
Hello?
Hi, sweetheart,
how are you?
We've been well.
How's daddy?
Fine, my dear, he's fine.
He already left for work.
He'll be back in a
while, and then
we'll go up to the dining hall.
Great!
-Yeah.
-All right.
-Yes, it's gonna be nice.
-I'm glad, mommy.
And how have you been?
We've been all right, dear.
I went up to Los Altos.
Saw your brothers.
-Oh, good. How are they?
-They're all fine.
When are you coming
for a visit, to see us?
Let me see if I can get
a few days off work.
All right, dear. Let's hope
you do. We miss you, honey.
Me too, mom.
I miss you a lot, too.
José Adán López Colorado.
Eduardo Antonio Peralta Canseco.
Haya Romero de Alba.
Alonso Sánchez Tepatlán.
José Vargas Pellicer.
Zacarías Villafuerte Colorado.
Congratulations to all our…
…all our graduates.
I chose this phrase because
I think it describes us.
It says:
"Maybe small people…"
Thank you.
"Maybe small people
in small places
doing small things
can change the world."
That's who I think we are.
We're small people doing
things that might seem small,
but we can turn things around.
I'm very proud, and I
feel very grateful to you.
I love each one of
you in a special way.
After everything we've shared,
I feel I grew younger
over these three years,
in spite of the scolds.
I feel younger, more alive,
happy to have shared with you.
Most of all,
I want you to be free.
Don't sell yourself out,
don't give up.
Just do that which makes
you truly happy. I love you.
On behalf of the co-op,
we want to propose a toast
for everything
the soil gives us
to feed us.
And we thank you all for joining us.
-Cheers!
May Mother Earth give us a
more plentiful harvest next year.
Cheers!
…weaving life, yeah,
You are cause and origin,
Seed Universe,
You are cause and origin, Seed!
You are memory, legacy seed,
Traveler seed, boundless seed,
You are memory,
nourishment seed,
Sustenance seed, native seed!
This is a prayer for freedom,
This is a prayer for diversity,
Seed that grows
towards the sun,
Multicolor seed,
You travel freely
spreading your roots,
A seed is not taught to sprout,
Creation’s design of perfection,
A seed is not taught to grow,
A seed is not taught!