Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Hey. Hey!
Can you not lie up in here?
You said on the application
form you don't smoke.
- I don't.
- For fuck's sake,
my wife will think
it's me again.
Are you smoking weed?
Look, I don't care
if you smoke.
But don't do it
in the house, all right?
You burn the place down,
and we get nothing
if the old fella dies.
You wanna smoke,
you go outside and smoke.
And none of that
funny stuff either.
I said I don't smoke.
Look, we don't
normally hire people
if this is their first job
in care, you know.
From the look of you, I wouldn't have
thought care work was your thing.
Especially the night shift,
everybody avoids that.
I need the money.
Don't say much, do you, Emma?
It's Emily.
Mind you, you'd be
in good company with Mr. C.
He's not exactly talkative,
if you know what I mean.
Well, here we are.
Come on in.
Mister...
Well, if he wakes up
you tell him.
Here he is, our best client.
Hello, Mr. Cunningham.
You got a new girl
looking after you tonight.
Name's Emma.
See? Nothing.
Alzheimer's.
Guess some people
are just unlucky.
His wife died 10 years ago.
Brought his daughter up
single-handed.
She left for London
a couple of years ago.
Hasn't been back since.
When this place just
went to wreck and ruin,
he just... closed up
and turned into a hermit.
Shame. He's a lovely fella.
He's a grumpy bastard.
At least when he's
awake, anyway.
Aren't you, Arthur?
Well, you see
what you want to see, don't you?
Commode. He doesn't
have a catheter,
so he might need it.
Camera.
Your workstation
is through here.
It's a bit of a mess,
but what isn't in this place?
Kettle...
Monitor, television...
Telephone.
No personal calls.
We check the bills.
Emergency contact numbers,
including a 24-hour
medical helpline.
My number.
Don't call at night.
He dies at 5:00 a.m.
you make the call at 9:00.
All right, through here...
Cleaning utensils in here,
should you need them.
Uh, through here...
upstairs bedrooms
and the office,
never used now, of course.
And through here...
These shutters...
must be closed at all times.
It keeps the heat in.
Okay.
It's an old house, you know,
there's lots of creaking.
It unsettles some people.
I'll be fine.
Someone'll pick you up
at 6:00.
6:00.
All right,
let's do it then.
I'll drop you
at the station.
Where did you find
that little weirdo?
She applied for the job.
I mean, I did...
Tell her about the house?
There's nothing to tell.
Anyway, you ready?
I'll let her know we're off.
No...
Come on!
Hi.
I'm Emily.
It's cold in here.
Are you warm enough?
That should be better.
Handsome guy.
You must be so lonely here.
Life can be unfair, can't it?
Yeah, I know.
Okay, you're okay. Shh.
It's all right.
Okay?
Is this your daughter?
She's a pretty girl.
Would you like me
to contact her?
Maybe I could talk to her.
See if she would
come and see you.
Yeah?
Would you like that?
So, Arthur...
where would you
keep her number?
Hello?
Oh, God.
Arthur?
What?
Why aren't you in your room?
Uh, um...
- I was cleaning.
- Cleaning?
Yeah. Okay?
Okay, let's get back to bed.
- Back to bed, back to bed.
- Yeah.
Okay? Yeah?
Is it true? Is it true?
Is what true?
- No. Shh. It's okay.
- Jenna's always there.
- Let's get warm.
Okay, okay, um...
- Let's get these round...
- Is it true?
Good girl.
- Okay. No, no, no. Okay.
- Good girl.
Yes, that's it. Okay.
- Yeah.
- I hate that.
Stay in bed now. Okay?
- Stay in bed now?
- Yeah.
Yeah, nice and warm.
Nice and warm.
- Okay. Okay.
- Nice and warm.
What does she want?
What?
Who?
Her.
- There's...
- No, no, no...
No.
There's nobody else here.
It's just me and you.
Who's there?
Oh...
Arthur.
Arthur, wake up.
Wake up, Arthur.
Arthur, can you tell me
what you saw?
Can you tell me
what you saw at the door?
Arthur, please.
A girl? Was it a girl?
Arthur.
Arthur, tell me what you saw.
Who...
are...
you?
Oh!
Arthur?
Arthur.
Arthur, come on.
- No, no, no.
- No, no, no, come on.
What happened?
What happened down here?
Okay. Okay.
No, no, no. Slowly, slowly.
It's okay.
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, slow down. Slow down.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Back into the bed, huh?
All right. Come on.
That's the way.
Okay. Okay.
Lie down.
It's okay.
It's all right.
Breathe, breathe, breathe. Shh.
Arthur.
Listen to me! Arthur!
Arthur, it's okay.
Ugh!
Come on.
Hey!
Arthur? Arthur?
Okay, okay, okay.
It's fine now.
Getting back in.
Let's get you back into bed.
You're okay.
All right. You're okay.
It's okay.
Let's warm you up.
Okay?
Okay, okay. Just relax.
Shh. You're fine now.
Okay?
Arthur.
Arthur, you have to tell me
what's going on.
Arthur?
Huh?
Oh. It's okay. It's okay,
it's okay. It's okay, it's okay.
It's okay. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. It's okay.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, I've got you.
It's okay. It's okay.
Let's go in here.
Hold on to me.
We're just gonna go in here.
We're gonna be safe.
We're gonna go in here
and sit down... And sit down.
Okay. Just like this.
Come on.
Come on. Okay, let's go
and sit over here.
Okay, come on.
It's gonna be okay.
Okay?
Sit down for me.
Just sit down.
Like that. It's okay.
Okay, it's okay now.
Let's put this over you.
Okay. Okay.
Okay? Okay?
Go to sleep now.
Go to sleep.
Okay? I'll make it stop.
I'm sorry.
By this candle...
with this charm...
I banish all that
would cause harm.
By this candle...
with this charm...
I banish all that
would cause harm.
By this candle...
with this charm...
I banish all that
would cause harm.
By this candle...
with this charm...
I banish all that
would cause harm.
Help!
Leave us alone!
Okay, okay, Arthur.
We're gonna go for a walk, okay?
Okay? Just come with me.
Arthur. Arthur?
Arthur, we're just
going outside for a bit.
Get up, Arthur, please.
Come on.
Come on, Arthur, please.
We're just gonna go
for a walk, okay?
Okay. Okay. Well, okay.
Come on.
We're just gonna go...
out front, okay?
Okay. Okay.
All right. Okay.
Okay?
Where are the keys?
- Where are the keys?
- I don't...
Oh.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Arthur, just go...
Okay.
We're coming.
Arthur? Arthur?
The hatch outside,
is that a way out?
No, no, no. No, just wait here.
Just wait here.
I'll be back
in one minute, okay?
I'll be back in one minute.
Oh!
No!
No, no, no!
Arthur!
No! Arthur!
No. No!
Help me!
Hello?
It's all right.
It's all over.
I'll tell everyone
what your dad did to you.
No...
You don't have
to hide here anymore.
It's you.
We see what we want to see.
No.
I'm Emma.
What have you done?
No.
No!
Mom?
It's over.
Mom.
Emma.
I missed you so much.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org