♪♪
[carnival music playing]
[kids shouting]
You okay, Pa?
Just a little
bit tired.
Doing six shows a day
is nothing for a kid like you,
but an old-timer
like me.
Aw, you're not old.
Is he Flame?
What's the matter, Pa?
Ah, nothing.
Are you
sure you're okay?
Sure, I'm sure.
Okay, if you
say so.
I say so.
Now go on, feed
Flame.
It'll take
you a good half-hour
and you still have some
studying to do.
Come on, Flame.
Want some company,
Mike?
Come in, Joe.
Well, I see you've
been packing.
It means you
must have told Shawn.
I only told
him we were quitting.
How'd he take it?
You know how
kids are.
Glad to
do something new.
What's newer than
a long trip?
Then you didn't tell him why
you're quitting?
My heart?
No, there's
plenty of time.
I'll miss
you and the kid.
[groans]
The pills...
suitcase...
pocket.
Thanks, Joe.
That was
nitroglycerin.
Works real fast.
Just slip it under
the tongue.
Mike, Mike, you can't
make this trip.
You're a sick man.
You ought to be
in the hospital right now.
I can't spare
the time.
Well, suppose
you don't make it?
I got to
get Shawn there.
Where's this place you're
taking him?
Angela's School
for Boys in Darwin, Texas.
Darwin?
Why, that's
over a thousand miles.
About 1200 miles.
I'll make it.
You're sure they
have room?
I've already written
them.
They'll take him,
same as they once took me.
They'll do for Shawn
what I can't.
Oh, it'll be good to see
Michael again.
We'll nurse
him back to health.
This trip, Mother...
won't it be
too strenuous for him?
Oh, but I know Michael,
he'll manage.
Now, the boy...
We'll put him with the
ten-year-old boys in Ward Four.
Very good.
And, uh, let's see...
Mrs. Logan's ranch,
just right for Michael
and the horse.
The horse?
Yes, they're a carnival
team.
Michael, known
as Moko the Clown,
and his son, Shawn, rides a
horse in a circus act.
They're very
good, too, I've heard.
Show people.
The last
group we housed
didn't work out too well,
I remember.
Michael was
brought up here.
I'm sure his son will
be well-mannered.
Thank you.
I'll take
care of the details.
Everything will be in order
when they arrive.
♪♪
"Leaving Oklahoma.
Entering Texas, Perryton
58 miles."
Pop, we're in Texas.
Gee, Texas.
The trip will be over in no
time now, huh, Pa?
Mm-hmm.
Something the matter?
Why do you ask?
I don't know.
You've been acting funny
on this trip like,
like maybe
you didn't feel well.
Tell you what...
we'll stop
up ahead here.
Flame can stretch his legs
and nibble on some grass
and you and I
can have some lunch.
Okay?
How bad
sick are you, Pop?
Well, I'll tell you all
about it
as soon
as we're settled.
That looks like a good place
over ahead there.
♪♪
Back, Flame.
Was a good lunch,
Pop.
Thanks for
cleaning up, Shawn.
Aw, it's okay.
You were gonna tell
me how bad sick you are?
And I will.
I'll tell you
the truth
for the truth is most
precious of all blessings.
Always remember that,
Shawn.
When we were
playing Daley's Carnival,
I had a lot of pain
in my chest.
You didn't tell me.
I couldn't tell you until I
knew what it was myself.
And you know now?
Three different doctors told
me the same thing.
I have
a bad heart.
Very bad.
Are you gonna...
Yes, son...
I'm gonna die.
[crying]
Pop.
Now, now.
It's all right,
Shawn.
You mustn't be afraid.
It comes to everyone,
like a long peaceful
sleep.
Now, that's
why I'm not afraid,
and that's why you don't
have to be afraid.
Can you
understand that?
I'm, I'm not sure.
I guess so.
You will...
in time.
Can't you
go to another doctor?
Sorry, son.
I could go to all the doctors
in the world,
it'd still
be the same story.
But, Pop, what's
gonna happen to me and Flame?
How am I gonna take
care of him?
Where will we go?
Now, now, now...
Easy.
It's all settled.
You'll go to live at the Angela
School for Boys in Darwin.
That's where I lived
when I was a boy like you.
You?Sure.
I was an orphan too.
Remember I told you about
that a long time ago
when you asked about
your Grandma and Grandpa.
Will it
be your home too?
Sure, we'll live together
just as we always did
for as
long as possible.
And Flame too?
Of course, Flame too.
They got a big field for him,
a regular Texas ranch.
And say, won't those
other kids have a time
when you and Flame put on
your act for 'em?
Now, Shawn, you got
to promise me you won't cry.
I'll try my best.
The only reason I'm
telling you all this now
is so it won't be too much
of a shock to you
when the time comes.
What do you mean?
It could happen
to me anytime, son.
You mean even before we
get to Darwin?
This is what I want you to
do in case it happens,
you get on Flame
and you ride
to the nearest city
and you ask the policemen
to direct you
to the nuns
in that town
and you tell 'em what
happened.
The good sisters
will take care of everything.
Is that clear?
Yes, Pop.
Now there's, uh,
something else
I want to show you.
♪♪
Here's $200.
It's all
we've got left.
If anything happens
to me,
you give
that to the sisters.
It'll help them send you
and Flame to Darwin.
And...
here's something for
you to keep.
It belonged
to your mother.
I gave it to her the day
you were born.
God took her
from us the next day.
I'm sorry, Pop...
I can't help
it.
I'm gonna cry.
You go
ahead, Shawn.
You go ahead
and cry.
Oh, Pop.
[crying]
♪♪
[crickets chirping]
Okay, that's enough.
It's pretty rough country
from here on.
We keep
pushing on tonight,
first thing you know
we'll be lost.
Yeah, I
suppose you're right.
One thing's for sure,
it's just as rough on Garvin
as it is on us.
He's probably battered
down someplace for the night.
Yeah.
We'll pick up from here
in the morning.
Barker, you've
been after Garvin
since he broke out
of Fort Worth?
No, before that.Before?
Yeah, I arrested him
when he killed
his stepfather in Dallas.
Sounds like
a rough customer.
You have much trouble
taking him?
No, no trouble.
I almost think he wanted
to get caught.
He doesn't sound
like the type of guy
who'd try to break out
of the pen?
I think
he's exactly the kind
that would want
to get out.
You see Garvin
didn't consider himself
guilty of anything.
He claims he killed
his stepfather
to keep the old man
from killing Garvin's mother.
Only once Garvin went to trial,
he couldn't prove it.
You, uh,
think he was guilty?
Well, I only get paid
to bring them in.
[laughs]
You know the difference
between a trapped rat
and a
guy like Garvin?
A rat can't think or
feel very well.
Garvin's feeling plenty.
Mostly he's
hating our guts.
He has to.
He has to keep thinking
every minute
how we're going
to try and box him in.
Barker...
you sound like
a bad case of conscience.
Oh, well, maybe
I shouldn't have been
a cop in the first
place.
Come on,
let's get out of here.
All right, fellas, that's
all tonight.
♪♪
[crickets chirping]
All right, stand up.
Don't turn around, I got
a gun in your back.
You heard
me, on your feet.
I'm not playing games, Mac,
on your feet.
Get up!
[horse neighs]
Hey, what's a matter?
Who are you--
What are you doing here?
You crook, you were trying
to steal our stuff.
Pop!
Pop, wake up!
Wake up-- Pop!
My...
Pop...
is dead.
[crying]
I'm sorry, kid.
Who are you?
Stanton.
Yeah, Peter Stanton.
Stealing our stuff,
I saw you.
I was
just taking some food.
I'm awful hungry.
I haven't eaten
for a couple of days.
You were stealing
our stuff.
My poor father was--Wait a minute, kid,
I had nothing to do
with that.
I know you didn't.
We've been
expecting this all along.
We?
Flame and me.
Oh.
What do you mean we've
been expecting it?
Has he been sick?
Pop's been awful
sick...
in the heart.
Well, what was he doing
dragging a kid
around the country for?
He should have left you
with your mother.
He should
have stayed home too.
My mother's dead and he wasn't
dragging me around.
He was
taking me to Darwin
so that Mother Superior could
raise me like she raised him.
Mother Superior?
Sister Mary Virginia of
the Angela School for Boys.
She must be a good
lady
'cause she sure
did a nice job on my Pop.
I'm sure she did.
Say, I don't want to keep
calling you "kid."
What's your name?
Shawn O'Casey.
Okay, Shawn.
I'm sorry about
your Dad.
We'll figure out
something to do with him.
Say, I, uh,
I guess this is maybe the wrong
time to say this, but...
What do you mean?
Could I have
some of that food?
Like I said before, I haven't
eaten in a couple of days.
I guess so.
Help yourself.
Thanks.
Say...
Shawn, have you got
a blanket?
We use sleeping bags.
But there's an extra blanket
in Flame's trailer.
I'll get it
if you're cold.
It's, uh, not
for me.
Here's the blanket.
Yeah.
It was awful nice
of you.
Thanks a lot.
Forget it.
I guess
I'll go eat.
You and your father, where
were you coming from?
From Kansas City.
We were
at Daly's carnival.
Yeah, you like
the show?
My Pop is--
was Michael O'Casey.
Moko the Clown?
He had
an act at Daly's.
Hmm.
You sure are hungry.
Don't you
have any money?
Not a dime.
What about you?
I got a couple
of bucks.
Nothing much.
How come you're going 'round
to people's camps
stealing food?
You could
get a job someplace.
Well, I, uh, I've been
hitchhiking to, uh...
maybe a job
will come up soon.
You don't even have any
other clothes.
I, uh, sold my good
clothes to get eating money.
Gee...
You could wear my Pop's
best suit.
He won't be
needing it anymore.
Shawn.
Yes, he will...
when we--
when you put him in his
final resting place.
I almost forgot.
I got to ride Flame to
the nearest town.
I guess
that's Perryton.
I got to get his bridle.Oh, you can't go now.
You wouldn't
be gone ten minutes
before you were lost.
But I got
to find help.
Well, I'll help you
all I can.
I got to
find a policeman.
What for?
He'll take me
to the good sisters.
They'll know what to
do about...
about Pop.
And they'll
take me to Darwin,
to the Mother Superior.
Yeah, but you can't go
now, it's dark.
You better
wait until daylight.
Pop said I was to do it,
so I got to do it.
Yeah, but when
he told you that,
there were a couple of things
that he didn't count on.
Like what?
Well, for one thing,
he didn't expect it to be
in the middle of the night.
Another he didn't figure
I'd be here.
You?
Yeah, me--
I can help you.
I'm a pretty good
driver.
I'll drive you
all the way to Darwin.
Get you there
fast too.
You shouldn't
bother the good sisters.
They got a lot
to do.
They got orphans and people
like that to take care of.
If you bother the good
sisters,
that means
that somebody else,
well, maybe they won't get
the same kind of treatment.
You understand?
I guess so.
But what about Pop?
What are we gonna do
about him?
I'll help
you with him too.
How?
I'll figure out something
by morning.
Hey,
speaking of morning,
you better get
some sleep.
I don't think your
father'd want you to be up
this late even
for him.
I guess I
am a little sleepy.
Good night, Pop.
Think you'd
better hop into bed.
Good night, Flame.
Good night, Mr. Stanton.
Good night, Shawn.
Pleasant dreams to
both of us.
Ah, it would take a whole
posse a couple of weeks
to flush Garvin
out of country like this.
Yeah, by the time he
was found,
he'd be
dead of starvation.
I don't think he's anywhere
near here.
What makes
you think so?
Well, we
know he was able to
swipe that outfit that
he's wearing
from a truck driver.
Now he might just have been
as smart enough
to have
hitched another ride.
Mmm.
Well, that warning against
hitchhikers
has been on the radio steady
since yesterday morning.
Yeah, but there are
a lot of farmers
that don't have
radios in their trucks.
Yeah.
Oh, relax.
It's a fine
morning and it's a cinch
we're enjoying it more
than Garvin is.
[sighs]
Surely goodness
and mercy
shall follow me
all of the days of my life
and I shall dwell in the house
of the Lord forever.
Amen.
I guess Flame's saying
goodbye to Pa.
Mr. Stanton?
Must we call
each other "Mister"?
I mean Pete?
What's on your mind?
Are you sure it's better for
Pop to be buried here
than in
a regular cemetery?
I mean, maybe the Mother
Superior wouldn't like it.
No priest or nothing, just
buried in the woods.
Your father would like
this place, Shawn.
He's probably
the kind of man
who was always close
to nature.
You talk
like you knew him.
Pop used to say,
"If you're close to nature,
you're close to God."
He said
the right things.
Yeah, Pop will be
okay here.
Good.
Well, let's get
going.
Darwin's a
long way off.
All night.
[Garvin]Shawn...
come here a minute,
will you?
When I was on
the road I lost my wallet.
Didn't have any money
in it
but it had my
driver's license in it.
It would be kind
of awkward
if a police
officer stopped us.
You can use Pop's.
Where'd you get
this?
It's Pop's savings to pay
our expenses to Darwin.
Shawn, a kid like you with
no mother or father
has to learn how
to handle responsibility.
From now on you're treasurer
of this group.
You handle all
expenses, okay, Mr. O'Casey?
Okay.
Let's hit the road.
Come on, Flame.
♪♪
So we took the act
to Daly's
'cause he
offered the most money.
I see.
Lots of other shows
wanted us.
We were
the best in the business.
Presenting Moko the Clown
with Shawn and Flame,
the Wonder horse.
You, uh, must miss
the show.
Yeah.
Well, the thing to do is to
keep working on your act
while you're
in the Angela School.
When you graduate, you can get
yourself up another act.
Won't be
the same without Pa.
Pa was the greatest clown
there ever was.
I'm sure he was.
What are we
stopping here for?
It's still a couple miles
to Perryton.
If you're
gonna do you part,
you're gonna start
right now.
What do you mean?
I'm gonna
let you go to town,
buy the supplies alone and I'm
gonna stay here.
I can't drive.
You take Flame.
Hey, you got a deal.
Come on, Flame, we're going
shopping.
Back, boy, back!
Look what's coming.
Anything wrong,
Officers?
We're looking for a fella
named Garvin.
You didn't happen to see a
hitchhiker back there, did you?
No.
Where you coming from?
Back down the road about
a mile, on this side.
Uh, well,
you can move on, son.
Let's go, Flame.
[t'sking]
I'm gonna run down to where
the kid's father is
and talk to him.
Maybe he's
seen Garvin on the road.
Want me with you?
No, I can handle it.
♪♪
Hello, Officer.
Something wrong with
your face?
My face?
Oh, the makeup.
No, I'm just practicing
new expressions.
Oh, you an actor?
I'm a clown.
I work in carnivals.
Sign back there says
no parking
except in emergencies.
Oh, I'm sorry,
I didn't notice that.
May I see
your license please?
Yes, sure.
This says
your 37 years old.
You could be 108 with that
stuff on your face,
I wouldn't know.
Oh, clowns aren't supposed
to have any age.
Oh.
Well, all right,
Michael O'Casey,
as soon as you can, move out
of this emergency spot.
I'll be pulling out as soon
as my boy gets back.
I sent him
into town for supplies.
I sent him alone 'cause he
wanted to exercise the horse.
Yeah, I know, I saw him back
at the roadblock.
Roadblock?
We're looking for an escaped
killer named Garvin.
He broke out
of prison in Fort Worth.
Oh, yeah, yeah, I heard about
that on my car radio.
Uh, say, what's
the closest route to Darwin?
You're on it.
No shortcuts?
Mister, there isn't even
a rabbit path
for the next
hundred miles.
Take it easy.
Yeah.
Shawn, I've been
thinking.
Maybe I could
take Moko's place.
What's that mean?
Suppose you taught me how
to be a clown.
We'd have
a regular act together.
We could play towns before
we got to Darwin
and make some money.
Hey, yeah.
I could teach you
all the things that Pop,
I mean, Moko used
to do.
That wouldn't be the same as
taking Pop's place, would it?
Of course not.
Is that
a deal, partner?
A deal.
♪♪
How's it look now?
Just try
one more time.
Do another flip.
♪♪
[horse snorting]Son...
I've been thinking about
myself so much
I never stopped
to realize how much
this could all mean
to you--
wearing your
father's clothes.
That's all right, I said
you could do that.
Now wearing
his costume and makeup.
Well, it's almost like I was
trying to take Moko's place,
but you know
I'd never try and do that.
No one could take Pop's
place, never.
I know...
and I'll never try
and take your Pop's place,
you understand?
Okay, let's get
rolling.
Pete?
Hmm?
Never mind,
it's nothing.
Spill it.
How long before we
get to Darwin?
Mmm,
20 miles or so.
Wish I didn't have
to go to that old school.
If we keep on doing the act
the way we've been doing.
Your father wanted you to
go to that school.
He was right.
Yeah, I guess so.
I can't help wishing,
can I?
No, son,
I guess not.
Won't be much fun
at school.
You'll have Flame
there.
You'll make friends.
Will you come and see me
and Flame at school?
Sure.
Sure, if
things work out.
Well, it looks like a good
place to stop.
You'd, uh,
better get some sleep.
We've got a lot to
do tomorrow.
I can't.
My mind's awful busy.
Now remember what your
father told you.
Go to town and ask for
the Angela School for Boys.
Yeah.
Supposing you were to wake
up in the morning
and something
had happened to me?
Supposing I wasn't here.
You figuring on
pulling out?
No.
No, no,
I was just saying suppose.
Are you sure
you're not pulling out?
Don't worry about it.
Everything will
be fine.
Now go to sleep.
Okay.
I like you, Pete.
I like
you an awful lot.
I like you too,
Shawn.
An awful lot.
Good night, Pete.
Night, Shawn.
Show people.
They're so unreliable.
A most uncharitable attitude,
Sister Grace.
Mother, perhaps they've
stopped on the road.
He could have
even changed his mind
about coming to Darwin.
Michael was quite blunt about
his physical condition
in the letter he wrote.
He said the doctors
gave him very little time.
That's why he was hurrying
to get the boy to us.
Got a plan, that is,
if you'll go along with it.
What is it?
You don't really have to
get to that
Angela School
right away, do you?
No.
There's bound to be some kind
of amusement park
right here in Darwin.
You mean we can keep on
doing the act?
Maybe for
a little while
'til we see how things
work out.
Did you hear what he
said, Flame?
Boy, oh,
boy, oh, boy.
All right,
no time for play.
We've got a lot
to do.
[carnival music playing]
Back, back, back.
The boss around?
Well, I run this
place.
What are you
guys supposed to be anyway?
The best carnival act in
the business.
Presenting
Moko the Clown
with Shawn and Flame,
the Wonder horse.
[laughs]
Business has been
terrible.
I could use some kind of
an attraction.
We're great,
lady, aren't we, Pete?
Well, I can't afford to
pay very much.
The most I could
give you is $75 a week.
That's $75 more than we're
earning right now.
All right, I'll give you
a week's tryout.
Flame, we're working again.[horse snorting]
By the way, my name is
Robin Anderson.
My family's owned
this place for years.
My name is...
Mike--
Michael O'Casey.
Shawn is my boy.
Oh, that's funny.
I thought I heard him
call you Pete?
It's a nickname
he picked up someplace.
Well, Mr. O'Casey,
I, uh--
You can call me Moko,
I'm used to that.
All right, Moko.
I was just wondering where
we can rig up
a dressing
room for you.
Oh, that won't be
necessary.
We'll put our costumes and
makeup on at the house.
Fine, where's the house?
Well, right
now that station wagon.
Could you suggest someplace
for us to stay?
There's a little house
for rent just outside of town.
And there's plenty of ground
around there for Flame.
Anything would be good that
doesn't have wheels on it.
Thanks.
Bring in some business
and I'll thank you.
Next.
Two,
there you go.
All righty.
Next.
[carnival music playing]
[kids laughing]
Pete!
They want an encore.
Let's do it.
You give it
to them solo, Shawn,
I've got to go talk business
with the boss.
Okay.
Well, Boss, a week's trial
period is over today.
I know.
Well, are we fired?
But--
But you're rehired
for as long
as you want to stay,
and with a $25-a-week
raise.
$25 dollars a week!
Hey, thanks, thanks
a lot.
I'll go tell Shawn.Hey, wait a minute!
I mean, I'd be stupid to
let you go...
you and Shawn
and Flame, of course.
You've more than tripled
my business.
I'm glad.
Moko...
you intrigue me.
Do I?Well, what I mean is...
We work together all
day long,
we talk a lot,
we seem to be mutually
interested in many things.
Maybe we
like each other.
Well, that's part of
what I mean.
And yet, I don't
know what you look like.
I mean, you come to work
with your makeup on
and you
go home with it.
I've never seen
the real Moko.
You'd be disappointed if
you saw him.
I'd like to
decide that for myself.
No, I decide.
Maybe someday I'll take
you by surprise.
I hate surprises.
Excuse me.
♪♪
Hello, Flame.
[horse neighs]
[buzzer rings]
Moko, let me in.
Why Michael O'Casey, you're
positively handsome!
I feel cheated your
hiding behind that makeup,
shame on you.
I wish you
hadn't come here.
Well, now that I'm here,
aren't you gonna ask me in?
No.
No, we'll...
we'll talk outside.
Where's Shawn?
He's asleep.
I wish you
hadn't come here.
My, aren't
you hospitable.
May I ask why not?
It doesn't look
right.
You're a single woman
and you really don't know
anything about me.
Perhaps you're
a desperate character.
Perhaps I am.
And I am a natural born
shameless hussy
and a determined
one as you can plainly see.
You were determined to see
what I look like.
I was.
And I like what I see.
I'm sorry, Michael, I've
intruded.
Forget it--
It's done.
You could be a little more
enthusiastic.
It's a lovely evening.
Come on and take a walk
with me...
please?
All right, I guess a walk
would do me good.
You know, you, um,
you look exactly like
I hoped you would.
You know, you and Shawn
don't look anything alike.
Nobody would ever take you
for father and son.
Well, he, uh, looks like
his mother.
Let's talk
about something else.
You, for instance.
Name: Robin Anderson,
age: over 21,
height: 5'2",
weight: 110,
vital statistics:
single.
Is there anything
else you'd like to know?
Yes.
Boyfriends:
scads of them,
but not a one that means
a single thing to me.
I'm sorry, I had
no right to do that.
Shouldn't I be the judge
of that?
No, come on, let's
go back.
Michael...
What is it, what's
wrong?
Let's go back.
Michael, what is wrong?
There is nothing wrong,
nothing that anybody can
do anything about.
Good night, Robin.
Good night.
Well, do you suppose something
happened to him on the road?
Oh, if it has, Mother,
that poor little boy, it's
a terrible thing.
Yes, I've thought
of that.
Such a long
distance from Kansas.
It could've happened
anywhere.
Well, how
can we find out?
What can we do?
There's only one thing
to do.
Police headquarters, please.
[carnival music playing]
You and Flame get
started.
I'll explain to Robin.
Oh, back, now, back.
I'm glad you're here.
I was afraid something
had happened.
Sorry, Boss,
we had a flat tire.
I'm glad that's all
it was.
I thought that
after last night
you might not want to
come back again.
One thing I've learned
in this business,
never quit
without leaving notice.
As far as last night's
concerned,
we better forget it.
I can't forget it.
I don't want to
forget it.
Can you forget
that you kissed me?
No...
but I think we
better try.
Well, if it
isn't Michael O'Casey.
You're the Officer from
up north.
Right.
Barker's the name.
I've been looking
for you.
Is that so?
You've been traveling
pretty fast.
No more than usual.
Mmmm.
Oh, don't you ever get out
of that makeup?
I'm ready to go on.
Oh, Moko and Shawn.
Flame, the Wonder horse.
Where's the kid
and the horse?
In the tent.
How come a guy like you
is working
in your condition?
What's that
supposed to mean?
Look, Moko, we've had
a general search out for you
since yesterday.
What for-- I haven't
done anything.
No, not
much you haven't.
Yesterday.
You fellas go to all
that trouble
just to
settle a traffic ticket?
You carnival people are
all alike.
You've got about as
much sense of responsibility
as a jackrabbit.
Don't you realize you've got
a little kid on your hands?
Well, of
course I do, but--
You write to
the Mother Superior in Darwin
that you're dying and you're
bringing your kid to her.
Then you
don't show up.
Oh...
so that's it.
Now listen, Moko...
you've got
the Mother Superior
half out of
her mind with worry.
She reported you as
a missing person.
We all thought you
died someplace on the road.
I'm sorry about
that.
I didn't
mean to worry anyone.
I guess I wasn't as sick
as I thought.
I've been
feeling pretty well lately.
I should have notified
the Mother Superior.
I'm sorry
about that, I forgot.
Well, at least you're not quite
as dead as reported.
The Mother Superior
will be glad to hear that.
What are you doing this
far south?
Well, I'm
looking for this guy.
You seen anybody that
looks like him?
No, I'll sure
be watching though.
You figure he might be
around... Garvin?
Unless he tries to hit
one of the other border towns.
My guess is he's working
his way to Mexico.
He could have
come this way all right.
It won't make much
difference though.
The border patrol boys are
working double shifts.
We'll get him.
I'm sure of it.
Well, I've
got to go on.
Okay, Moko, see
you around.
Uh, if you see anybody that
looks like this Garvin,
just notify
the nearest police officer.
I'll do that.
And, uh, since you're busy,
I'll radio headquarters.
They'll get
word to Mother Superior.
Thanks.
Fine, thanks a lot.
Okay.
Officer, have
you met Moko before?
Well, yes, on the road,
way back near Perryton.
The Mother Superior
at the Angela School here
had a missing persons alarm
out for them.
I told him about it.
Funny...
he's supposed
to be a sick man, bad heart.
Clowning like that can
be rough work.
Well, he
seems all right.
He's never complained.
That's all?
How long's
he been working here?
A little over a week.
How did you happen to hire
the act?
They just dropped in.
I liked their
work so I hired them.
Drifted in, eh?
You get many such
drifters?
Very often.
But none with
talent like Moko and Shawn.
Huh, but you
do have guys coming by
looking for work.
A couple of times a week.
Maybe you've seen this
one recently?
Who is he?
His name's James Garvin.
He, uh,
wanted for something?
Well, he was serving time for
second-degree murder,
but he broke out
of prison at Fort Worth.
Have you seen him?
No.
Hmm.
Okay.
Thanks, Miss Anderson.
If you
want me for anything,
I might be around
for a while.
Goodbye.Goodbye.
[car door closes]
[car engine starts]
♪♪
Pete-- Pete!
Pete, where you going?
♪♪
You're the only person
I could tell
and I had
to talk to somebody.
You love him very much.
Yes.
I didn't realize
how much until today.
Life isn't always what
we make it, is it?
Shawn loves him as though
he were his own father.
Shawn's father...
what's become of him?
He's dead.
You know that?
Yes.
Just a few minutes before
you got here,
I received a telephone
call from a man named Daly
who owns a carnival
in Kansas City.
That's where
Michael wrote me the letter.
He was worried.
He was relieved to learn that
Shawn was in Darwin
for Moko's grave was found
by some hunters in the woods,
just over the Texas border
from Oklahoma.
How had he died?
Mr. Daly said
the autopsy showed
that he died of a
heart attack.
Ever since that detective said
that Peter was a murderer...
Well, we don't
have time to do much.
We must make up our minds
this minute.
Why?
Shawn's father was identified
less than an hour ago.
It won't be long before
that policeman, Mr. Barker,
finds out about it, if he
doesn't know already.
But what can we do?
We must confront James Garvin
with what we know about him.
Then if he tells us the rest of
the truth about himself,
we'll know
just how much to help him.
What if he's gone?
What if he's tried
to escape?
Oh, that
would be disastrous.
Come quickly, child, we'll see
if he's at his home.
♪♪
I do hope your young man
has the good sense
not to run again.
How could he care for that
boy the way he did
and still be the kind
who can kill somebody?
It's not possible, it
just isn't.
We can
pray that it isn't.
No, nobody's
seen him, Captain.
You have?
At his house?
225 South Lake.
No, I'd like to handle
it myself.
I have my reasons.
Thanks, Captain.
[kids shouting playfully]
How did
you get here?
I rode Flame.
Why didn't you wait
for me?
Why'd you
run out like that?
Look, kid, there are a lot of
things I can't tell you.
Okay, I guess you got a right
to do what you want.
You going someplace?
You mean
you were going away
without even saying goodbye
or anything?
Look, kid,
I'm in an awful hurry.
Maybe I can come back
for you.
Maybe we can do
the act someplace else.
What's wrong with
Darwin?
We were
doing real good here.
Everybody says so.
Yeah, well, maybe there
are better places,
places where
we can make more money.
As soon as I find the right
spot, uh,
we'll team up again.
In the meantime, I'll have
to go to the home.
You're just saying it.
You won't come back.
Look, kid, that's what your
father wanted, wasn't it?
Why you blaming me?
That's what
your father wanted.
That should be all right
with you.
Sure.
Sure, I guess me and Flame will
get along without you.
Oh, kid,
you're lousing me up.
Every minute we gab here,
you're lousing me--
[sighs]
If I had
the brains of a flea,
I'd be on my way.
Does that mean you're
gonna stay?
Look, Shawn...
your father was
a fine man, a good guy.
But every time you look at me,
you're thinking about him.
I know that--
I've known that all along.
Well, I'm not like him.
I never was.
You understand what I'm
trying to tell you?
I don't get you.
Maybe I don't understand
myself.
Remember one thing,
for everyone
there's a day of reckoning.
For everyone in
the world.
I only hope
when mine comes,
it'll be tougher on me than
it is on you.
[car approaching]
Flame will
be getting hungry.
Why don't you go
feed him?
Thanks, Pete.
So now
you know the truth.
That's why I didn't want
you to see me
without my makeup.
Sure, sure,
I'm James Garvin.
I'm a convicted murderer.
The police are looking for me
all over the county.
Pete!
Kid.
You didn't hear--
Pete, you couldn't
kill anybody.
Well, sometimes
you can if you have to.
I wanted to go
to Mexico.
Couldn't even do that right.
I'm going to give myself up
to Barker.
First my
real Pop, now you.
Kid, listen!
I'm not
gonna listen to you.
I'm not gonna listen to
any of you.
Shawn, wait!
I wanted to be gone before
he learned the truth.
Pete, you better leave
him alone!
No, I'm gonna go
see where he's going.
Shawn!
Wait-- Wait!
Wait!
Let go!
I'm not
staying here!
I'm not staying here!
Down, Flame-- down!
[horse snorting]
Kid, you shouldn't have
tried it.
You can't run
away from things, kid.
You can't run away from
things, believe me.
Things would
have worked out.
They--
Hello, Garvin.
You better get
a doctor for the kid.
I can wait.
Hello, Pete.
Hello, son.
I just talked to
the doctor.
You got
a pretty bad bump.
But you're gonna be as good
as new in a couple days.
Did Flame run away?
You think he'd go anywhere
without you?
Pete, don't go away.
Okay.
I'll wait as long
as I can.
Then Garvin's stepfather
grabbed the gun
and was about to shoot
his wife, Garvin's mother.
But Garvin grabbed him, they
struggled for the gun,
it went off
and the stepfather was killed.
That was Garvin's story
but it didn't
sound so good to the jury.
But it did to you.
Well, I guess I was closer
to the whole thing
than anybody else.
You know something,
Mother...
... a policeman is just
another guy but with a badge,
a human being.
He's got eyes,
a nose, a mouth, feet, hands,
and most of the times,
he's got a heart.
He has his own opinions
and feelings about everything
just like everybody else.
Sometimes he
doesn't want to have feelings.
Sometimes it's better if
he doesn't.
Well, you know what I mean.
I know.
Well, seeing
as how I was responsible
for Garvin being in jail
and seeing as how I didn't
think he was guilty of anything,
I knew I had to do something
about it.
It was getting
tough to sleep nights.
So...
I asked my pal in homicide over
in Dallas
to help me run
the case down a little more.
Well, while I was chasing
Garvin all over Texas,
he really
ran down the case.
He sent me all the information
just before I came here.
Now I'm
willing to bet ten bucks
that with this new
evidence,
the Governor will
be convinced that Garvin
should have a full
pardon.
Won't the fact that
he escaped from prison
count against him?
Well, normally it would,
but he's
still an innocent man
and the way he took care
of the boy
proves that
he's a good citizen.
No, I wouldn't be afraid to
go to bat for him
all the way.
Thank you.
He's asleep.
Well, I'm ready.
Well, if you want to say
goodbye to anybody,
it's okay with me.
Mother, shall we
go ahead?
We'll walk forward.
That's always
the best way to go.
I wonder what it would have
been like in Mexico?
♪♪