(footsteps)
- Are you ready?
- What time is it?
- Just past midnight.
- Thank you.
(sigh)
Happy Birthday
Maria Hartmann.
(hooting and clapping)
- Isn't it Maria?
- Shit.
- It's fucking Maria Hartmann, isn't it?
- Like hell it is.
- Who is she?
- She goes to the business school.
In Niels' reading group.
Ah, Niels, you lucky bastard.
Hey, Maria! We will just have a picture
for the school magazine.
- You can't just fucking go.
- Wanna bet?
- They have paid for two shows.
- Then you can make the second. Good luck.
(plays "Happy Birthday")
- Kurt?
- Shut up for just two seconds.
- I have not talked for 20 minutes.
- You just have Kurt.
Why are you antisocial.
You're damn antisocial, man.
What the hell are you doing?
Aren't you going to write on the card?
Congratulations. It's there already.
You need to write who it is for.
"Hello Batman"...
You really take on, huh?
"Batman". It says "Dad"!
It looks as if it's Batman.
I'm sorry, honey.
I should have called, I know.
Something wrong?
- This is not right.
- What?
- Yes, us and our relationship.
- Because I'm late?
No, I can't manage this
lack of commitment.
It's not a lack of commitment.
We see each other often.
We don't at all.
I want something else.
Either you start to work less,
or so...
- I will probably...
- Stop that.
Sorry.
Sorry, I said.
What?
Darling.
I will, darling.
- Then you have to promise it.
- I promise it a hundred percent.
(a telephone number dialed)
- Yes, the truck is here.
- We are coming. - The vehicle is there. Go!
When we finish with the Russians
the niger in Halmstad has a job.
This is my last job.
- I will have to see, to believe it.
- There it is. Go!
Go on!
Stop!
Come here. Get out!
Here! Out!
Here!
In!
Leave me alone.
- Where is it?
- What?
Where is it?
"The Black Madonna"
is in one of the boxes.
Damn it.
- Hey.
- What's happening?
It's just the engine that stopped.
We are checking on it.
In a few minutes we are on the road again.
- Very well. Good luck with your work.
- Yes, thank you.
- What do you have back there?
- Some empty pallets and stuff.
- Can I see?
- Of course.
Hello? Is there anybody in there?
It's the police.
What the hell are you doing?
Stop!
Are you crazy?
Victor, dammit!
"After the motorcycle was hit,
we are searching for a black Iveco-truck."
- Sorry, I have to go.
- "The driver was wearing an orange jacket."
You understand that I'm tired
that your job always comes before me?
- I just wonder if you understand it.
- Yes, I understand that. I'm sorry.
(honking and braking)
- Would you call 1 12?
- What?
- What is happening? What the hell are you doing?
- Have you found it?
Not yet.
Here are all possible kinds of paintings.
- Stop! This is the police!
- What the hell is happening?
- Why didn't you hit him?
- Drop the gun!.
- Do you think you're hunting ducks?
- Kurt!
10 meters from you and you miss it.
- Yes! I have it.
- Are you blind or what?
- Come on, damn it, Kurt!
- Where the hell are you? Kurt!
He's fucking gone!
Get in the car, for God's sake!
That fucking bastard. He has fooled us.
I've never seen anything like that.
That huge, antisocial ass.
Just wait till I get hold
of that damn bastard...
- Shut up and drive.
- It can't be so difficult.
You go shoot and rob.
He ran that way.
Gustav!
(sirens)
Satan in hell. What the hell do I do?
Shut up, man.
Brian, you asshole!
Shit, damn.
Satan in hell.
Kurt! Stop now!
Yes, what is there so?
Kurt, dammit man.
What did you think?
We catch you every time.
It's only the third time,
Pedersen.
- Hi, Kurt.
- Hey, Ole.
- That was really hot last night, huh?
- Yes, that...
Will you please come in and put
your badge and your gun in my room?
- Really?
- You are suspended until the hearing.
Isn't it to overreact?
Think, you can't fire
1 1 shots in a residential area-
-without a hearing.
That's what the Ministry of Justice said.
The perpetrators started shooting.
That says the report.
Fine. So get some more ammunition
and go out and shoot more.
That's too stupid. I have, in addition,
arrested one of the perpetrators.
The prosecutor released him.
Kurt Hartmann had an alibi.
He was with half of Russia
throughout the evening.
And grow a real beard. It looks like,
You have sucked an exhaust.
- You shall just sign here.
- Okay.
Well, Kurt.
- Should I have an excuse?
- I know you know where the picture is.
- I'm a plumber.
- You have not seen a trap for 40 years.
See you again, Kurt.
- Thank you for now, Ole.
- Yes, see you.
(plays "Happy Birthday")
Hey, you forgot your card.
Hey, Kurt.
Where were you yesterday? I was
looking forward to meeting you.
I had a little problem,
but managed on that shit.
Come in here, Kurt.
It's cozy.
(plays "Happy Birthday")
So here we are. Now we certainly need
a small glass and something good to eat.
Have you tasted Golubtsy before?
Russian minced meat in the cabbage.
Very delicate.
Hi, Igor.
Is it him?
- Does he have the Madonna?
- Yes.
Give him the money
and let him go.
Are you sure he's okay?
He looks a little tired.
Mr. Tuschinsky kept his part of the
agreement. Do you have the Black Madonna?
- No.
- You don't.
Just a moment. What is happening?
Is there a problem?
- He hasn't the Madonna.
- He hasn't the Madonna?
What's he for?
Where did you find the idiot?
Now you must pull yourself together.
Get it right and get him out.
- Do you know where it is?
- Yes, I know who has it.
"And the weather. It will be windy
with a fresh breeze to gale."
Ole from show center.
What the hell are you doing?
You never run away from a show.
It will be deducted from your payment, bitch!
Maria it's dad.
Take your phone if you are at home.
Hey, it's dad.
I have sent you a package.
It is important that I get it.
You should get a number...
- "It was the weather, Caroline."
- "And now a new Danish art theft."
"The robbery last night was described
as the largest..."
You called Maria Hartmann.
leave a message.
Maria? I forgot the number.
You get it right here. Hello?
- Do not send gifts.
- It's not a gift.
"The painting is a famous icon,
The Black Madonna."
You called Maria Hartmann.
leave a message.
It's me again.
Forgive me for calling.
But I need to get hold of you.
You called Maria Hartmann.
leave a message.
Maria! It's important
- What are you doing?
- Have you received a letter from me today?
- Yes. There were not enough stamps on it.
- It's important that I get it.
I believe that the police think the same.
How much should you have
for not going to the police?
- 10.000.
- It's okay. Okay.
Okay? I should have said 20.
When do I get the money?
You come and bring the painting
and I give you the money.
- And you?
- What?
Congratulations.
(plays "Happy Birthday")
(breathe in)
- Can't you stop that?
- What?
You do not breathe. You breathe in
and then you don't breathe out.
It's just because I'm concentrated.
It's fucking annoying.
(plays "Happy Birthday")
Gustav.
Could you keep the card closed?
He has just written 'congratulations'.
Why that when it is already there?
It's an unsolved mystery.
You're right, Gustav,
it's a really good tune.
Especially if you hear it
over and over again.
Are you not going home?
- How big was the stolen painting?
- Not very big, but expensive.
- Around this big?
- Approx. See you tomorrow
Can you give me a lift?
I feel a little like
I've eaten too much meat.
I feel a little bloated...
So you might get to be
slightly awake at night.
It's the fucking cops.
It's the damn cops. Go!
Those nosy bastards.
- Maria Hartmann?
- Yes.
My name is Gustav Pedersen.
Have you heard from your father today?
- Do you have the money?
- The money?
- Do you have the money or not?
- I come from the police.
- Absolutely.
- I'm investigating a case.
- Show me your badge.
- My badge?
If you are from the police,
then you have a police badge.
- Technically speaking, I have a badge...
- I'll call the police.
I am from the police.
Let me just explain.
- Where is the gnome?
- In the bath.
Igor! Igor!
It was teeming with cops over there.
There were two cops with his daughter.
- Are you sure?
- 100 percent.
They both had gleaming
water-combed hair.
That son of a bitch. Shoot the jerk with
the cap and throw him into the water.
What is happening?
- The police came first to Maria.
- The police?
Anyway, I'm glad that we
enjoyed ourselves a little.
The police is in the apartment,
so don't bother Igor.
Now he goes home. It was not
what we agreed, was it, Kurt?
You should have come with
the painting yesterday.
It's bad, Kurt.
Shitty day.
Mother fucker-Damned fucking ass. Shitty day.
Satan's ass.
Bastard ass-fucking-shitty day.
Piss-fucking-bollocks.
(phone rings)
Dog's head!
You can't fucking do it there.
You'll make a hole in the boat. Idiot.
You won't make such a mess.
Wrap him up well. He's fat.
Just hold it.
- Hello?
- Are you trying to cheat me?
- He does not have the money.
- Who?
That unpleasant motherfucker with
pubic hair in his face. Gustav...
- The cop?
- So he is really a cop?
That was what I fucking said.
Fucking shit!
I have given him power enough
to illuminate Esbjerg.
- Do you still have the painting?
- Yes.
She has the painting.
We can get it.
- The daughter has the painting.
- Goodbye, goodbye.
- Igor is really indifferent.
- What is it? Go now!
Can she come to Kaliningrad
with the painting? We will be there.
- It's not a good idea.
- It's a really good idea, Kurt.
A really good one.
It's called Landuskin Marina.
In Kaliningrad.
- Maria, take the painting with you to Kaliningrad.
- To where?
You take a ferry to Poland and then
a train to Kaliningrad. It's easy.
- I will not fucking go there.
- It takes at most a day.
- I have tests in a week.
- Have you started to study?
- It's not of your damn business.
- You get 200 kg.
- It's a good day's wage.
- I'll do it for one million.
One million!
Now you must control yourself.
Shall I do it?
- That's how I educated you?
- You have never educated me.
You needed to be there to do it.
Which ferry should I take?
You need to go to Landuskin Marina.
Take the Swinoujscie ferry to Poland.
Then it's just to the east.
Kaliningrad. It's damn easy.
Bye.
Idiot.
"The Black Madonna" is as famous
in Poland as "Mona Lisa" in France.
Painted with gold leaf on oak.
They have smeared the gold leaf on
with eggs. It's fucking disgusting.
I bet that his daughter knows
where that antisocial bastard is.
- He has blown us.
- Hell, he has not.
Maybe you can see the
Madonna somewhere else?
Kurt shouldn't have thought
that he is smarter than me.
- It's violence against an officer on duty.
- One who refused to identify himself.
- And who was trying to get in.
- Maybe. But you are in trouble.
- In trouble?
- Yes.
Where have they found you?
You talk as if you were on the 80's.
It's an invaluable piece of art.
I know exactly
what it's worth to me.
Give me the painting.
You can get four years behind bars.
- Behind bars?
- Yes.
Are you a striptease dancer?
- Striptease dancer?
- "DM strip". What is it about?
Who can take off their clothes quicker?
I can earn 10,000 in one evening
by shaking the ass.
For men like you.
Who is the most ridiculous?
I don't fucking care.
I pay no money for...
I'm engaged.
Oh, how romantic. Does he
also have this framed ass-beard?
There's food in the refrigerator.
Hey, hey, hey!
(sighing)
You go insanely slow.
There she is!
Where is Kurt and the Madonna?
Fucking assholes.
Damn hell. Fucking Hell.
Fucking shitty day.
- Someone could think you were four years old.
- Shh! Piss-shit-bollocks.
- She's not opening. Watch out.
- No, no, no. The body.
Hold them right here.
(roar)
Yes, that was good.
Holy shit, that's the damn cop.
Where is the girl?
And where is Kurt, the antisocial bastard?
I don't know.
You keep an eye on him.
Oh, what a hell. Such a bullshit.
She should be fucking shot,
the bitch.
She is also a bloody
antisocial bastard. Arrgh!
(he gets power)
(something smashed)
Oh, what a hell.
- Where is Kurt?
- I don't know.
Holy shit. Do you think
I'm stupid? Where is he?
I don't know!
- Fuck, he hits hard.
- Oh, what a hell.
Where's the Madonna?
Where is it?
(he gets power)
Hey, hey, hey!
You can't leave me here.
Damn fucking shitty life.
- Hello. Central Alarm.
- Shit! Damn fucking shit.
This is Gustav Pedersen, KA.
Hey! Give me the keys.
Sure, have a good time!
Gustav Pedersen, KA.
Shoot now, man! Shoot now!
It's a hunting rifle.
How the hell do you fail to hit?
Yet he failed, you jerk!
Hell!
Damn psychopaths.
- Do you know what time is it?
- No. Quarter past eight.
The time is 20.15,
and you are under arrest.
Suspicion of complicity in theft
and assaulting a police officer on duty.
I must make you aware
that you have the right to not...
Idiot, man.
It's a tiny museum.
Two guards, nine custodians.
Munch paintings for 920 million.
She is also a fucking
antisocial bastard.
Like her shitty father.
What the hell?
- Victor, come here.
- What is it?
She's on a fucking trip.
- They have cheated on us, bloody hell.
- La-n-duskin.
- You must stop the Poland ferry.
- Good idea.
Do you know what suspended means?
What about we close Kastrup?
"The Black Madonna" is on board.
- Listen now, you're suspended.
- Yes, I know, but...
- What the hell is that?
- I'm looking for...
You must wait for the hearing.
Don't run around alone, right?
No of course not. "The Black
Madonna" is on its way to Poland.
- Are you taking it on the ferry?
- Yes.
- Have you shot someone?
- What have I done? No.
- You go nowhere.
- I promise.
- Get out!
- Give me the picture.
- No, it's mine.
- It's a Polish national treasure.
I don't give a damn.
It's mine, and take off your hand!
You can't go all the way to Poland
in a lifeboat. So do Laurel and Hardy.
Come on, Brian.
You need to get in a better shape.
Fuck!
- Have you looked there?
- She's gone.
She can't just disappear.
We are on a ferry.
That's damn stupid.
Plastic chairs are a stupid choice.
You go that way,
And I look over here.
- Give me the picture and get rid of trouble.
- No thanks.
Piss off.
Two psychopaths looking for you.
You can't stay here.
- Wait and see.
- I think I'll do that.
Thank you.
Then you add some curry,
but Brussels sprouts can get too much...
It must be nice
to have such a helpful daughter.
Maybe. She's lovely.
Her birthday was yesterday.
Congratulations.
What did you give her?
We are not the kind of giving gifts.
I wrote her a long letter .
They are also bad to play.
They just sit and count the money.
How old has she become?
Do you have a picture of her?
Yes.
This is her today.
This is a job she has.
- She is a cute girl.
- Thank you.
Send it to Kuntz.
- Hey, my picture.
- Yes, you will get it back.
She is sexy.
What the hell?
Tell me, are you blind?
The blue piece is heaven.
Do you have silicone in your brain?
Is it almost 10 o'clock?
You said I'm under arrest,
so I won't tell you that.
I just had an agreement
down in the laundry room.
"The ferry will be in port
in a few minutes."
Good morning.
- Are you stalking me?
- No, I'm not.
Fuck!
Shitty asshole.
- Quiet. The police is down the quay.
- Well, say hello from me.
What do you mean?
I contacted the captain
when you fell asleep.
- Do you never let go?
- No, I don't.
Give me the picture.
Gustav it's washing time...
I have a million in Poland.
That's all I have.
I will not be arrested. Not now.
Hey! What the hell are you doing,
you crazy bitch?
She is fucking insane.
Fucking ho! Fuck!
Fuck! Shit!
(screams)
Now, haven't I got too much
Brussels sprouts?
Damn shit fucking bollocks, too,
fucking shitty day...
Fucking disgusting, dammit!
Damn shit!
Shit, damn!
Shut up belly flop!
Was you trained in the police?
- I landed on my legs.
- It must have hurt!
- I actually landed on my feet!
- No.
- I won't bother arguing with you.
- It's so fucking stupid.
- Very cheap.
- Do you know where the train is?
- No, thank you. Do you know where the train is?
- Waterproof. Very cheap.
- The train!
Take and piss off.
Otherwise I'll stick it in.
Hello, nice to meet you.
My name is Adam Kuntz.
- Gustav Pedersen, KA.
- Your shit!
- The time is 8.55, and you are under arrest.
- Do you have the Madonna?
- Top boy, scout snitch!
- She said yes.
Here is my car.
Oh, for hell, man!
- What are you doing, man?
- Let me go!
You've just thrown a saucepan
in the head of the Interpol.
Damn shit, dammit!
What are you doing, you crazy bitch?
- Are you completely insane?
- Do you believe he is from the Interpol?
Polska, Polska, Polska.
Do you have a more modern
and bigger gun?
He doesn't understand a word.
You are so negative. See how nice.
- Kipling and genuine leather.
- Niggers!
Shut up, there she is.
You go that way and I go this way.
Stop now, your anti-social bitch!
- Fuck off with you!
- Victor, I have her!
Maria!
- Come in now!
- Run.
- Give me the painting.
- Nope, it's mine.
- Give me that!
- Don't you touch it!
- Brian, stop them!
- Oh, for hell.
Damn, Brian.
- They could bind books later.
- They run there dammit! Come on!
You should lose weight.
- I think I broke my arm.
- I don't give a damn!
Whatever you have broken,
you will just deliver the Madonna now!
Amateur! Did you get run over by a slut?
Get that picture.
So, here is a dream cake.
Find the Madonna!
What is happening?
You are a fucking sissy!
Just find the bitch!
It's just because your daughter
has smashed Igors best man. Here!
- Have you sent someone after her?
- Yes, sure.
- Will anybody have cake?
- Yes please!
- I can just bloody pay her.
- Why?
- Because we have an arrangement.
- No, no!
- You have an arrangement. We have not.
- It's you who fucking have!
You have not even touched your cake.
You're so fond of sweets.
You get the Madonna with your daughter,
you receive the money.
If we get it,
then you receive nothing.
Try to call and find out
how far she is.
- She's not answering.
- Well.
Shit phone.
- Be careful now. Give it to me.
- It's mine.
- Just like the painting is not yours.
- Shut up!
Moreover, it's nothing without
magazine. Give it to me.
(breathe in)
- Stop that.
- What?
You hold your breath.
It seems you're dead.
- Then I could not drive.
- That you can't almost do either.
You drive very slowly.
(breathe in)
- So you did that again.
- No.
You don't breathe.
I sure do that.
May I say something?
- You run like a girl.
- I don't do that at all.
You do that for sure.
You run with your arms out sideways.
Just as if you were going to fly.
Aha!
May I say one more thing?
Those glasses
are in fact a girl's model.
You don't look at all like
a police officer with them.
Who the hell do you think you are?
You just sit and quibble.
Negative energies all the time.
You are like my ex-girlfriend.
You sit and knock everybody down.
Nothing is good enough.
No movie, no book, people. Nothing!
- Your ex?
- What?
- Is she your ex or your girlfriend?
- What the hell do you care?
You think you're so smart. Everyone can
see that you have had a shitty childhood.
Now you're trying to compensate by stripping,
so that someone cares to look at you.
Maybe I don't resemble all the men
you tend to be abandoned by-
-but I am who I am,
and I don't intend to change that.
If you say so.
Fine.
This sausage is not made of an
animal that has grown up on a farm.
- What do you mean?
- It tastes like cat.
You have obviously tasted it several
times. I think it tastes good.
I have actually tasted cat.
In the military, I applied
for the commando troops.
We had been on exercise
for five days without food.
Then, we found a dead cat.
So we ate it.
- So, didn't you come in that time?
- No, but that was close.
- Can't you try again?
- Too late.
I think otherwise,
You were pretty rough before.
Sorry it was not the intention
that it would be so hard.
It suited you, actually.
- Will you do me a favor?
- I don't think so.
What are you thinking?
Can't you deliver the painting
to the Danish consulate in Gdansk?
Why are you so stubborn?
I can't go home without it.
What should I do?
It's not my problem.
- What is happening?
- Run!
Run it! He comes again.
He will push us off the road.
It's good.
Fuck!
Step on the accelerator.
- Fuck! Turn in!
- I'm trying! Shut up!
Fuck!
Beware of the cow. Haven't you
learnt it at the police academy?
- Run away from him!
- There's no grip.
(car alarm)
Shit!
You don't need a seat belt. Such a
truck is equivalent to 200 cars.
We drive straight over
the little car.
You must be the police's worst driver.
Now, we drive straight over them.
This is equivalent to a speed bump.
- That's it, hold on.
- So run over them!
Stop! We didn't hit them.
(screams)
Fucking shit! Damn shitty day!
(groans)
We'd better get away from here.
You are bleeding.
What is it?
The Madonna, please.
Move away from the car.
Damn fucking shit.
(he runs away)
(yelling)
How much do you think such a cow costs?
When I was 12,
and we still lived in Sweden-
-I got a horse from my father
as a birthday gift.
I was happy.
Imagine what a hero I was at school.
- I had got a horse from my father.
- Yes, it must have been wonderful.
The problem was that the money
came from a robbery at the post office.
So the day after the police came
and picked up my father.
and afterwards fetched the horse.
Well...
How do you tell your friends,
you don't have a horse anymore?
And that your father is in Vridsløse?
- Was he ever at home?
- Yes.
When he was, it was not for long.
There was always some reason to leave.
There is no car.
God dammit! Holy fucking shit.
Would you bother stop cursing,
since you are so bad at it?
We get a lift, catch him up,
and get hold of that painting.
- Awesome plan!
- There we have it again. Irony and talk talk talk.
Honestly. The man is driving a car.
We can't catch up an asthmatic snail.
I'm hurt, and you run as a cheerleader.
What were you thinking?
What about this guy?
He doesn't have a car.
So what a hell will he do
with two gallons of gasoline?
It's put together with adhesive tape.
It must be okay.
Don't be so girly.
I'm not fucking girly.
Just look at him.
Pilots are some of the most
checked people out there.
They are checked in the head and ass.
Excuse me, Mr.
Could we have a lift, please?
You have to speak up. My ears don't work.
Too much noise in plane.
- Can we have a lift in your plane?
- Yeah, no problem!
- Thank you.
- I came for the sausage.
The best sausage of Poland.
- Departure. We now fly. No sleep. Fly.
- It's fucking perfect.
- Do you want some?
- No thanks.
It's very good for your head
when you're tired.
It keeps you awake.
And it's good for stomach too.
- He's also a fucking junkie.
- Relax, you're not at work.
You know what...
Hello?
- Move!
- Hello? Damn!
Take the stick. Can you keep it?
We'll crash! Hello?
Hold it there.
Can you keep it?
Is he dead?
Hello? How can you sleep when
you have sniffed a pound of coke?
What are all those buttons for?
If I pull, we'll go up.
You must not go up.
We call for help.
- We must not go up, we must go down.
- That's what I'm trying to.
We'll crash!
Take it there. Hold it there.
There are pedals. It's like a car.
- Mayday!
- It's like a car.
- Find a field with a haystack.
- A haystack, then we are saved.
Just get it down.
What the hell are you doing? We are plunging!
I turned on purpose. There he is.
He has the damn bag over his shoulder.
Now you no longer go down.
Stay here.
He has the fucking Madonna.
- How much is the green?
- 3,30.
- What if we attack him from behind?
- It's a really good idea.
- So find something else.
- I'll do that! Bring the plane down!
Climb out on the wing.
I mean it.
- Are you completely insane?
- So I do it myself. Hold the steering wheel.
What the hell are you doing?
- Hold the steering wheel still.
- I'll do.
Are you completely insane?
I can't keep it.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Down!
- Completely down. Lower.
- What?
Lower!
Down, dammit!
Use the pedals!
- I'm trying.
- Hold it.
I'm trying.
I can't.
- Hold it.
- I can't keep it quiet!
Now you must not go too far down.
What are you doing?
Straighten Up!
Pull the steering wheel, dammit!
Pull the steering wheel!
Down! There he is.
There on the left. You missed.
Quiet!
- Right there.
- I have him.
"Caution. Caution."
(alarm)
Are you at home in the cave?
Yeah, it's you I'm talking to.
There are crumbs everywhere.
The carpet was expensive.
- Give me the bag.
- Don't be stupid.
- Come with the bag!
- He's fucking brave.
But he stinks of garlic.
(phone rings)
Hello? Adam. How are you?
Has she got hold of the painting again?
A plane?
Have you broken a few fingers?
So beware of the other arm. Hello.
- Maria is not hurt.
- That's a lie.
No, she has just flown over
Igor's best man with an airplane.
Yes, it may sound a little weird,
but she has the Madonna.
- So now you can release Igor.
- I don't believe a damn thing you say anymore.
Kurt, you have always been able to
trust on me. Nothing happens to you.
Just let go.
You go away.
Go away!
Kurt, I understand you well.
I'm here only to help.
- Is he okay?
- He breathes.
- But he's probably not in a good mood.
- So let's just proceed.
- We can't fucking do that.
- Oh, okay. So see you later.
We can't fucking do that, damn.
THANK YOU
- God only knows what's the name of this town.
- Something with 24 consonants.
If you had kept the plane in the air,
we would be on our way home.
I'm sorry I didn't let you
fall out from a mile high.
Hello. Do you know
where we can find a hotel?
- I don't like it.
- No, that's fine.
Hotel? English?
Someone must speak English here.
They all certainly have
a doctorate from Yale.
Otherwise, they can't join the EU.
We have no money.
We are broke,
and we are just travelling.
- Stig. You must be Stig.
- It doesn't sound so nice.
Hey, look who it is.
My mom is a big fan of you.
Just go in.
Mom! Take a break.
See who I have invited.
You are Stig.
- What?
- "Les Miserables".
- What is she saying?
- I didn't understand.
Come here, everybody!
Come and say hello to Stig Rossen.
Stig Rossen!
Yes, I know him well.
- Does she believe that I'm Stig Rossen?
- Yes!
I'm not...
I don't look like Stig Rossen.
But you do. Now let it go.
We need to sleep.
Do you have a place we can sleep?
Can we sleep here?
Stig is sleeping with us.
Welcome, Stig.
Can I... Can I buy some... some clothes?
Can I buy one of these?
It would be very nice, because
my... my... my clothes are very wet.
(plays "We dance rock and roll")
- Can I buy it?
- You are a woman.
This is very nice.
Let him get some rest.
I'll smash you if you say something.
It's beautiful.
You look like the queen,
when she is in Greenland.
My clothes were wet.
I must go to bed now.
Are you not going to sleep?
Stig!
Now you sing for us.
Listen here. Now Stig will sing for us.
Sing. "Les Miserables".
Picasso is not actually worth
much money.
"Flying dog" - 20 million.
"Teacups" - 38.
While Munch's painting "The Scream"
in Oslo is 400 million worth.
- Isn't it strange?
- I don't know.
Many people think that stealing paintings is
the most difficult. But you know what it is?
Shut up now. I have heard of this
paintings shit for the last 256 km.
- Can't you talk about something else?
- What?
I'm thirsty.
(Gustav sings "We dance rock and roll")
What the hell is this cat moaning?
It sounds very good.
It's a good melody.
- It sounds like crap, it's false.
- Hell, it's surely not.
Niggers.
Shut up, you sing badly.
It went fine.
Good night.
That, which hangs down the neck.
Is it some kind of cap?
It looks incredibly real.
It's 100 percent nylon, all this shit.
Yes, if one didn't know
that you were an...
...annoying striptease dancer
from Vesterbro, so...
What then, if one didn't know it?
So one would think,
you are somewhat lovely in that dress.
Well...
If one didn't know
you were a stiff cop from...
- Where are you from?
- Roskilde.
Well...
What then?
What?
If one didn't know I was a
stiff cop from Roskilde, what then?
I don't know yet.
What are you doing?
They say that you are not a real man until
you have kissed someone in a folk costume.
They are right.
Do you really have a crush on folk dancers?
Sick bastard.
What?
- It never happens in stories.
- What never happens in stories?
That the girl doesn't know what
to do with the lower arm.
Have you always wanted to be a cop?
Yes.
I like you better as Stig Rossen.
Not to be an annoying ass,
but the state also offers a reward.
How much?
Enough for you to keep your clothes on,
until you take your exam.
Is it not what you want?
Here you are.
- Really?
- Take it.
(phone rings)
It's working.
Hello?
- Hi, Maria.
- Who is it?
Do you have "The Black Madonna"?
Maybe, why?
- Can I get it?
- No.
It would be good if it was
in Landuskin within two hours.
Otherwise, you can fish up your dad
out of the water in four different places.
Bye, Maria Hartmann.
What's happening?
They'll kill him
if they don't get the painting.
They're just trying to put pressure on you.
We don't know if Kurt is with them.
Maybe I have an asshole shitty father,
but they can't cut him into pieces.
Of course not.
- Give me the painting.
- I'll call the police. Hello?
- Relax. I'm trying to help.
Hello?
Maria, wait a minute.
Maria.
Another thing that people don't know is
worth the money is iron. Scrap iron.
It's worth the cash. There are no guards.
Yes, there are dogs, right?
- So I got ride of the Wunderbaum.
- You can get plenty of wires.
- There are the cop and...
- Shut up, there she is! Brian, come.
Have you seen this tool, Victor?
It runs on pneumatics.
- It is typical Russian to do things like that.
- How the heck does it work?
What a hell,
this is a good thing.
There are the bitch and Kuntz,
the amateur.
The Madonna has to be with them.
Otherwise he's finished.
She looks like the picture.
But she is a little skinny.
- Beware she doesn't beat you, Kuntz.
- She's not so big.
Isn't it quite embarrassing?
Get up, slut.
She's actually quite delicious.
- Good morning, Maria Hartmann.
- Where is my father?
- Do you have something for me?
- Yes, here.
Can I get it?
No, I want to see my dad first.
Take her bag!
Stop!
Or The Madonna goes into the water.
That would be quite stupid.
- I'll do it. I want to see my father.
- Calm down. Let's take it from the beginning.
You give me the Madonna,
then I release Kurt immediately.
No.
Dammit! Fucking shit!
Do you have more complaints?
- No.
- Yes.
Damn hell. Fucking piss bollocks.
Piss-shit-fuck. Damn ass.
What?
- You look like your mother.
- You look like shit.
I haven't always been a real father.
I've been a little "on and off",
inside and outside.
- It's too late to apologize now.
- Yes, it damn is.
This is my last job.
From now on, I have plenty of time.
From now on?
I don't need you now.
I needed you when I was born.
My first day at school,
when I had surgery, when mom died.
But now? Well...
- Good heavens.
- No, but...
What the hell do I need you for?
I have become a very good grandpa.
Grandpa?
- Can you see any small child here?
- No, but I suppose you have a boyfriend.
No.
I have none.
I have no boyfriend.
(footsteps)
Where is the Madonna?
- At my partner. He's a police officer.
- And where is he?
I don't know.
He's coming with all the Interpol.
Have you become girlfriend of a cop?
- Yes.
- Shut up.
Isn't it the one with the beard?
- He comes with the whole force?
- No.
- You just said it.
- Yes, but he doesn't, okay?
Goodbye, Kurt.
As usual you have ruined everything.
- Departure!
- Let us put an end to it.
For your information, this means:
We sail now.
- Be careful now, Kuntz. The staircase are steep.
- Hold tight.
Goodbye, Kurt.
(ship horn)
Tell me, what is this all about?
Now come the two new idiots.
- Give us Kurt Hartmann, or you will die.
- Who?
I said, give us Kurt Hartman now,
and the money.
- Which money?
- Give us Kurt Hartmann you mother fuckers!
It's good, Brian.
- Ouch!
- Fuck...
Piss and shit.
Leave!
Oops, whoops!
Hey. Who comes there?
Are you the police officer?
- Do you have the Madonna?
- Give me Maria, then you get it.
- I'll get it anyway.
- Where is she?
You can't hang here, can you?
No, let go. So we just say that
you gave it to me voluntarily.
Then you get the girl.
Thank you.
If I could now,
say something to you, so...
I don't bloody know, what to say.
Maria!
You should just know that...
Fuck.
Gustav!
Help!
Maria
- Maria!
- Gustav?
He's stuck!
He's stuck.
Under the water.
- Are you okay?
- Hold there. Like that.
Hold here.
Ouch!
It's him, Gustav.
- Well, we know each other well.
- I told you we would meet again.
I had not ever imagined,
I would be so happy about it.
(footsteps)
Give me the Madonna now.
Thank you very much.
Gustav?
I know you know-
-that it's just business.
Yes, yes.
Kurt... I'm sorry
that it has to end like this, but...
The time is 13 something, and you are
under arrest, whatever the hell your name is.
Your fucking bitch!
Is it finished now?
Yes. Now it's finished.
I have read your report,
and I have just one simple question.
When I suspended you,
was it an invitation-
-to go to war with the Russian
mafia, or to stay at home?
- Yes, it was really a little stupid.
- Yes, you just don't do it again.
And don't shoot anymore
with stainless steel nails, right?
It was a shame with Kurt Hartmann.
Yes, it was a pity he got away.
Yes...
- Kurt's daughter will get the reward, right?
- I don't know.
Yes, she certainly will. Yes.
Gustav! I received a bill for a Cessna light
aircraft. Do you know anything about it?
It was reported as a total loss.
Gustav?
(church bells)
(organ music)
They are very good as well.
Well.
I don't really know, you know.
Dad, shouldn't you do something else now?
No, now shall we both
be properly together.
We don't need to be together the
whole time. You can look around.
- We can look at it together. Come.
- No, dad. Will you do me a favor?
Yes, of course.
- Would you bother to go?
- What?
(footsteps)
- Well... Not a problem.
- Good.
(breathe in)
You're doing that again.
You're holding your breath.
- I'm not doing that.
- You are so fucking annoying.
Strange,
you don't get better at cursing.
You're really bad at it.
Just breathe.
- It's because I'm concentrating.
- Don't hold your breath. Breathe out.
Talk, talk, talk, talk...
What are you concentrating on now?
You.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
- Is it good?
- Yes, I think it is.
(alarm)
- What the hell is happening?
- Motherfucker-pissing shit-fucking ass, man.
(alarm)
(speaking over the radio)