THE HOUND OF BASKERVILLE
It's as if this dice shaker
is jinxed in my hand.
Twelve!
I won't catch up with that.
12 eyes?  That's too much.
Twelve eyes are too few for the
man who has a beautiful wife.
To admire her?
-No, to guard her?
What would you do with a man
you knew were stealing from you?
If he were a small man,
I would have him whipped.
And if it concerned a large thief?
Then I would send him on a voyage from
which he would never return.
What's that?  Watch out.  Someone
has already seduced your wife.
Who knows that?  -The medallion that you
guarded like the virtue of your wife.
Sir Bettans is carrying it
under his jacket.
How do you know?
When James, Sir Bettans's servant, is drunk,
he says more than his master would like.
Sir Bettans!
Miserable boy!  I should have had the
dog chase you from the castle long ago.
Now, you'd better believe I will!
Now to you, wife.
You won't drive me away.
I'll see to that.
Kill me.  I'd be thankful
for this one good deed.
You gave up the right
to me a long time ago.
Every hour at your
side was torture.
I only abided it so long because I saw
my duty as more important than love.
I was faithful to you, but you trampled my
love with your feet.  Destroyed my life.
Until Sir Bettans came.
He made life worthwhile again.
Yes, I gave him my heart.
You believe this old
ghost story?
This fairytale about this hound
from Baskerville?
Only because it's written
in your family chronicle?
Besides, the story is
200 years old.
I have to believe in it.
One always hears it, this
howling of the dog
that walks across the moor.
-Nonsense.
I have explained it
to you so often.
The sounds must be coming from
the morass holes.
Caused by sinking mud and
rising water, or from somewhere.
It follows all of us who
are named Baskerville.
Pfft, it follows all of us who
live here on the moor.
I can't fathom it.
A man like you, who is always poised, gets
nervous and overwrought by these noises.
Lord Charles, as a doctor I'm telling you.
It's high time you got away from here.
London would do you good.
There are no dogs
howling there.
There's a flight, where you'll have
the company of pretty women.
Pretty women?  -Lord Charles,
I know what you're missing here, eh?
This time it was only
a young woman.
See, I was right.  A carriage
has pulled up.
A woman has gotten out.
A woman?
Is Lord Baskerville available?
Please report my arrival.  My
name is Beryl Vendeleure.
Vendeleure?
That name is familiar.
A side branch of our family.
I'm sorry.
Milord is sorry.  -Lord Baskerville will
regret it.  I must speak with him.
Tell him I beg of him to
see me tonight.
Milord doesn't wish...
-Listen, announce me again!
Pardon me, Milord, but the
lady won't be dissuaded.
She says she must speak with
the lord today.
A Miss or Mrs. Vendeleure?
-She only said her name.
Beryl Vendeleure.
OK, let her in.
Strange visit, so late at night.
Vendeleure.  I'm not thrilled.  Someone
by that name was in prison.
You will be surprised, Lord Baskerville.
To force my way in at such late an hour.
Surprised yes, but pleased.
Dr. Mortimer.
My butler said you wanted
to speak to me urgently.
Can I help you in some way?
Yes, please.  It concerns...
I was in the area. You might
know that we own land around here.
No.  -Yes, the piece of land
adjacent to yours belong to us.
I thought, what if I offered
to sell it to you?
Maybe you have...  -But that's nothing
more than a worthless moor.
Yes.  Sadly, I had to be
convinced of that.
But because the carriage that was taking
me back to the train station was passing
by here, I remembered that we Vandeleures
are distantly related to the Baskervilles.
Regrettably, yes.
-What do you mean?
I mean, regrettably only distantly.
One would rather be closely
related to a pretty woman.
I only have a few minutes.
-Out of the question.  It's stormy.
You would arrive in London in the middle
of the night.  So stay with us overnight.
Actually, I wanted to be back
by this evening already.
How long have you been here?
-Since noon today.
I only wanted to be away
from London for half a day.
Why are you unpacking the suitcases?
-The lady said she's staying here.
I don't know if I should accept your
invitation to stay overnight.
It's unexpected.
The vanity of women.  Three suitcases
for half a day.
I thought I might find a prospective buyer.
-You have one already.
For my moor property?
-No, for you.
What's that?
It's just the moor.
-It sounds so eerie.
Pardon me, Milord, which
room for the lady?
The room with the bay window.
-Very well, Milord.
You, will see, Miss Vandeleure, in the
light of day the castle isn't eerie.
If only the nights weren't.
Lord Charles is a little high-
strung, nervous.
Mr. Stapleton.
-If I may.
Our dear neighbour.
Beware of him.
He's an embittered woman-hater. He
eats women down to their skin and hair
Miss Beryl Vendeleure.
Look how sharply he glares at her.  -No, no,
that's only because I can't see well.
I have the impression that
the lady is very pretty.
But that must be a
mistake.  I'm mean,
how does a pretty woman
end up in this eerie castle?
Where are my glasses?
-You're holding them.
No, that's the one for distance.
Oh, I see.
Ah, here is the one for close-up.
Yes, she is pretty.
And she's staying!
Get away from here as quickly
as you can, otherwise in short order
you'll be as ugly and unearthly as this
castle, as me, as him, as Lord Charles.
I find Lord Charles neither
unearthly nor ugly.
Then it's high time for you
to acquire glasses.
Forgive me.  The suitcase
slipped out of my hands.
If I am to accept your offer to stay
then I must retreat to my room now.
May I serve dinner in half an hour?
-Please, yes.
A pretty woman, no?  Even you
must admit that, Stapleton.
What are you looking for?
Found it.
Best way to get rid of
a pretty woman.
I'm leaving.
This house was a hospitable one
as long as no women were here.
When a woman is here,
there's hate, discord, etc.
I'll leave this for you.
-What is this?
You'll need this.  An elixir for gall
ailments.  He laughs.
You know why he's laughing?
Because he prescribed this for me and
he knows very well it's useless.
Perfume, a woman in the house.
No, it doesn't suit me.
I'm going.
-I'll accompany you.
Are you going too, Doctor?
-Yes.  You won't need me anymore today.
You have more amusing company.  Come,
Doctor.  Goodnight.  -Goodnight.
Is our guest happy with her room?
The lady didn't have the courtesy
to share her opinion with me.
Set the table for two, but somewhat
friendlier than usual, with flowers.
With flowers?
-Yes, with flowers!
Why are you repeating that?  -I'm not
repeating, Milord.  I just said with flowers.
The woman is good medicine for our Lord.
-I don't like her.
Why not?  She's pretty.
-Yes, she's pretty, but she's a woman.
Why are you a misogynist?
There!  The siren is
from Princetown Prison.
Some poor devil is trying
to escape again.
Won't get far.  The moor
swallows all of them.
But they try again and again.  Run with a
deathly fright and scamper over the wall.
How about the pillow?
Light.
Yes.  Yes, I'm on the phone.
Here?  What?
I don't have time right now.
What?!
No!
That can't be true!
What?  Oh, OK, good.
Come right away.
Hello?  Hello!
Madam, don't interrupt me!
Yes, you interrupted me!
I won't tolerate this tone!
Dumb person!
Lord Charles was just here.
Did he leave the house?
-Milord will surely be right back.
Schmidt, Milord is out here
in the garden!
I'm sorry, I thought
you were alone.
I would suggest the lady
not come into the garden.
Why not?  -There are tripping
hazards and booby traps.
I beg you.  Stay here!
The castle is very secluded.  Lord
Baskerville doesn't abide dogs here.
You see, there's an old story.
-Yes, yes, I know that tale.
Of course, you don't believe it,
but there's something to it.
Yes, yes.
Jack, Jack, you have to help me!
-How did you get here?
I'd best leave you guessing.  But they're
searching for me everywhere!
You have to help me!  -I don't want to
have anything to do with you.
No, Jack, you have to help me!
I have the right to demand it.
You can't leave me in the lurch.
Barrymore, what's with
Lord Charles?
Did you not hear that?
It came from that direction.
No, I didn't hear a thing.
-There was a scream!
You are mistaken.
-It was Lord Baskerville!
OBITUARY
Please fetch Miss Vandeleure.
Yes?
Dr. Mortimer would like to see you.
Well, how are you?  Is it better?
-Thanks, it's better.
May I begin with the reading
of the will?  -Yes, please.
Then let's begin, My Lordship.
...and declare herewith that the rightful
heir of the title and the property of
Baskerville is the son of my late brother,
who currently lives in Paris,
the engineer Henry Rogers.
I leave with my heirs the duty to provide
my old friend, Dr. Mortimer, an annual
pension of 200 Pounds, and to give my loyal
servant, Barrymore, a one-time payment
of 1000 Pounds.
Lord Charles had a nephew.
We didn't know that.
A nephew?  That is very surprising.
The will is properly signed and
confirmed by two witnesses.
Lord Baskerville, an engineer
currently living in Paris!
Are we going to Grimpen right away?
-I'd like to stay one more day in London.
In which hotel?
-Well, what do you suggest?
Maybe Northumberland, Mayfield,
Victoria...  -It doesn't matter to me.
Northumberland is on the way.
I thank you, dear Doctor, that you picked
me up at the train station.  -Oh, gladly.
Did you have a comfortable trip?
-Oh yes.  Exceptional.
It was of course a big shock for me.
-Yes, for us too.
You must know that it is hard to relate to
all the grief.  I hardly knew my uncle.
He died of a heart attack, right?
-Yes, yes.
How, so suddenly?
Well, I always feared it.
He died from fright.
From fright?  Of what?
-He feared a ghost.
The hound of Baskerville.  -He
believed in that?  -Yes.
And I believe in it too.
Wait, don't laugh, Lord Henry.
There's something strange going on
in this castle.
That's why I sought a man today who might
be able to shine a light on the situation.
And who is he?
-A certain Sherlock Holmes.
Oh, the famous detective?
Well, he probably laughed at you.
I haven't met him yet.  I'm supposed
to go back this morning.
Then he'll laugh at you
this morning.
Do you want to stay here too?
-No, thank you.  I live with my sister.
I'd like a room.
-Certainly.
OK, then I guess I can leave.
Or should I wait?  Don't you want to
come with me, Lord Henry?
Oh, no no no.  -All right, then, goodbye,
Mr. Baskerville.  -Goodbye.
Pardon me, Lord Baskerville?  -Yes?
-A letter was left here for you.
For me?  Impossible.
-"To Lord Henry Baskerville"
Nobody knew you were
coming here.
"Charing Cross"
-That's about two hours from Baskerville.
Charing Cross, Charing Cross...
"If you value your life,
you'll stay away from the moor."
Somebody doesn't put much
worth on my presence.
Who could have sent this letter?
Probably the Hound of
Baskerville personally.
Room 47.
-Thank you.
Are you sure you don't want to come with
me, Lord Henry?  -No, no, no, my dear
Doctor.  I can deal
with ghosts myself.
Your Sherlock Holmes can
busy himself with that.
Mr. Holmes?
He still hasn't come.  I've been waiting
for two nights.  That makes me very nervous.
Mr. Watson!  What am I supposed
to think?  Mr.  Watson!
Oh, for goodness sake!
-Close the door!  The ash will fly away.
Is it that tragic?  You don't have to sweep
it up.  You're not ordinarily neat anyway.
What do you say, Mr. Watson?
Mr. Holmes still isn't back.  5...8
containers you have in this room, and
the ashes are all
over the place!
Have you gone crazy?
I have to examine these ashes!
117 different types.
What kind of crazy things you do!
For what?  You smoked all this yourself.
Whatever you do, don't get sick.
Do you have any idea how sick
I am already?  -Me too.
What, you smoked?
-Brazilian.
-It's a disgrace that you're
ruining the young man.
Quite the opposite.  He
will never smoke again.
By the way, don't stand around.  Help me
a bit.  Have a smoke and study the ash.
You must have lost your mind!
Mr. Holmes is here!
Good that you're here.  I was so worried.
-But I knew it right away.
Mrs. Garben, tea, sandwich, and
a hot bath, please.
Good that you're finally here.
We were all very worried.
Those were two awful days.
But the gems that were stolen from the
Vatican are now on their way to Rome.
But you said it was a hopeless case.
-Yes, but my first suspicion was right.
What's this cane?
-A certain Dr. Mortimer forgot it here.
Godright said he wanted to talk
to you.  He's come back later.
So, my first suspicions led me
to George Baynor.
He's a country doctor.
-Who, George Baynor?
No, this Dr. Mortimer.
A country doctor.  How
did you conclude that?
Because in the city one doesn't use
a cane with an iron tip.
Holmes, this Dr. Mortimer
could also be a judge.
No.  People go to a judge.
A country doctor goes to the people.
You can tell by the
timeworn iron tip.
See what you can find out about Dr.
Mortimer in the doctors' registry.
As I said, I went to George Baynor.
He has a dog.  A big,
powerful dog.
Who, George Baynor?
-No, this Mortimer fellow.
How did you conclude that?
-The cane has big notches in the middle
from a big dog's teeth.
Hey, there are two Dr. Charles Mortimers.
One in London, and one in Grimpen.
Dr. Charles Mortimer.
-What's new in Grimpen?
Good day.
My friend and colleague, Dr. Watson.
Feel free to speak in his presence.
Before I speak with you,
I would like you to read a part of
the Baskerville family chronicle.
No.  Mr. Holmes is much too tired.  Can
you not tell us the matter in brief.
Can it really be explained?  The unnerving,
the unexplainable story gets lost.
It concerns an old legend
from the 16th century,
about a huge dog that tore apart the
lord of the castle.
And why should I read this story?
Because events have been happening
recently at the Baskerville Castle
that frighteningly remind
one of the old legend.
The ghost of the dog is roaming.
-Have you seen it?
Seen?  No.  But one often hears an odd
howling on the moor at night.
And the howling is
from the ghost dog?
You believe.  -Me?  No, but Lord
Baskerville believed in it.
And the fear sent him to his death.
He died of a heart attack.
His corpse lay in the garden.
And, gentlemen, I saw
that myself.  It was raining.
Next to the corpse I found the
tracks of an enormous dog.
This is your cane, right?
-Yes, thank you.  I forgot it here.
If this is your cane, then you have a
large...roster of patients.
You make a lot of house calls, walk across
the land.  The iron tip is all worn out.
You are a country doctor, right?  We saw
it right away.  -Astonishing!
Who, in ancient times, could have
had a motive to kill Lord Baskerville?
No one.  -Really?  Didn't the lord
have heirs?  -No.
That is, to our surprise, it turns out
he had a nephew, who worked for years
in Paris as an engineer, and who is, as the
next of kin, the next Lord Baskerville.
I picked him up from
the train station today.
At the hotel, something
strange happened.
The desk clerk handed Lord Baskerville a
letter that had been dropped off for him.
What's unusual about that?
No one knew in which hotel
Lord Baskerville would be staying.
"If you value your life, you'll
stay away from the moor."
The words and letters have been cut
out of a newspaper.
Probably, judging by the letters.
Surely from The Times.
-Mrs. Garben!
10 to 1 they are from The Times.
-We know that!  -Well, OK then!
Sunshine.
Was the room in the Northumberland
reserved for Lord Baskerville beforehand?
No.  He decided to stay there on
the way from the train station.
Corporal, here.  -Look up the hotels
I will write down for you right away.
And ask everywhere if a letter for Lord
Henry Baskerville was dropped off.
So, a letter for Lord
Henry Baskerville.  OK.
And what did the lord say when the clerk
gave him this bizarre letter?
Well, nothing.  He
laughed about it.
He leaves the impression of a level,
easy-going, very calm person.
Well, that's great!  That a single shoe
vanishes.  A brand new shoe.
I'm sorry, but I unpacked the shoes and
put them there.  -Yeah, right!
I swear.
-I saw it too.
Did the shoe vanish into thin air?
Pardon.  You called.  How can I help?
A pair of shoes were unpacked.
Brand new shoes.  And one is gone.
What can I do with one shoe?
Am I a stork?
Why, that's not possible.
-Maybe someone stole it.
Don't talk nonsense!  What's a
person to do with one shoe?
The shoe must by
all means be found.
You have 20 minutes.  Otherwise
this'll be my last time in your hotel.
Excuse me, sir, I found your other
shoe.  It was on the staircase.
Well then!
Then everything is in order.
Excuse me, please.
Please.
Miss Henry would have come into
consideration as an heir.
Probably so, if the direct heir
hadn't surfaced.
How did the lady behave
when the will was read?
She was shocked, shaken,
and stayed at the castle even though
she had planned to leave that night.
And for what reason did she stay?
-She claimed
she had hurt her foot
and couldn't walk well.
Ah!  -What could I have done?
-But you could have quickly examined it.
I did, but I didn't
find anything.
Who, of all these people, was given a
bequest in the will?
The servant, Barrymore.  1000 pounds.
-See, that's important.  Everyone
who was endowed a bequest in the
will is suspicious.
Lord Charles left me an annual
pension of 200 pounds.  I wouldn't...
No, no, I didn't mean to say that,
for God's sake.
Mr. Holmes, there was a letter for Lord Henry
Baskerville in all the hotels you gave me.
But they didn't give them to me.
-I can imagine.  You don't look like a lord.
Why not?
-Look in the mirror.
Well, how does a lord look?
-Like me.  -Aha.
Yes, hello?  What's that.  Yes,
Dr. Mortimer is here.  Doctor, for you.
Yes, this is Dr. Mortimer.  Oh, it's
you, Lord Henry.
Yes, what can I do for you?
A shoe?  That is peculiar.
And for that reason you're changing hotels?
-That's the second in a very short period.
The first were brand new.
One was found, after all.
And now a used tennis shoe.
Excuse me.  The shoe is nowhere
to be found.
As if it disappeared from
the face of the earth.
Nowhere to be found.  No, no, no, dear
Doctor.  This is laughable.  I'm moving out!
Say, Doctor, do you know another good hotel?
-Yes, of course.  Hotel Victoria is excellent.
Yes, then I'll see you again
in Hotel Victoria.
The new shoe was brought back,
but the old one was stolen?
Watson, I think this case is beginning
to get interesting.
Are you going to drive there?
-No, I have no time.  You'll drive there.
What am I to do there?
-Yes, what's he going to do?
He shall see to it that the Hound of
Baskerville gets the right collar.
Over there is the moor.  It
goes for 15 miles.
I didn't know it was that pretty.
Yes, it's nice.  But dangerous.
Very dangerous.
The moor!  Come help me!
Something seems to have
happened again over there.
You were lucky.
-It was a close call.  I almost drowned.
It's not worth the risk to find
the guy we're after.
Who is it?
-Someone broke out of Princetown Prison.
I'm sure he's dead.  The moor swallowed
him.  -Yes, I think so too.
Yes, yes, the area is dangerous.  As
you see, I didn't overstate it.
The Moor...Hello, Stapleton.  You're
about to meet a funny guy.
He catches butterflies?
-He's a naturalist.
Ah, Stapleton!  Lord Henry, this
is our friend Stapleton.
In nice weather you won't see
me without a butterfly net.
It would be a sin to be without a net.
I caught a lovely zyclopedus (?).
Show us the creature later.
Come on, get in.
Greetings to you, Mr. Watson.
-How do you know me?
Firstly, I saw your picture
recently in a newspaper.
And secondly, your right should is
somewhat scuffed.
That indicates that you always fight
shoulder-to-shoulder with Sherlock Holmes.
And thirdly, your name
is on your suitcase.
This is Barrymore.
You won't hold it against me if I
go home.  My wife is awaiting me.
Well, then I don't want to hold you
up.  Goodbye, dear Doctor.
Many thanks.
Let's go.
For sure not a merry house.
I can understand that one believes
in ghosts if one lives here.
Right, Doctor?  Well, some things
are going to change here.
Milord, my wife and I would be happy to stay
here until you have decided on changes.
Are you saying that
you want to leave?
We were heartbroken by
Lord Charles's death,
and we will not be happy as long as
we are living at Baskerville Castle.
Well, what do you
want to do?
Lord Charles's generosity gave us the
means to open a store.
But if you insist on us staying here...
-We'll talk about it another time.
I find it strange that the man wants to go.
-It almost looks like flight.
I know the real reason.
There's a woman in the house.
But this woman will not be
here much longer.
I only awaited your
arrival, Lord Henry.
Tomorrow I'm leaving.
-I would be saddened.
Let me introduce.  Dr. Wat...
-My name is Parker.
I will now play the housewife
a bit and show
the master of the house and Mr... -Joe,
er... P-Parker.  -...Mr. Parker the rooms.
Very friendly.
Since I have been in the house you
haven't shown your face, Mr. Stapleton.
But hopefully you haven't forgotten
where the whiskey bottle is.
No.
But you have forgotten something.
-What's that?
You have forgotten to limp.
-I'm doing much better today.
You see, I hurt my foot.
-Yes, Dr. Mortimer told me of that.
Will you take the room with the bay
window, Lord Henry?  -Gladly, thanks.
And for you, the room next door
is possible, Mr...  -Peinter.
Earlier you said Parker.  -Yes, Parker-
Peinter or Peinter-Parker.  However you like.
May I set a place for Mr. Stapleton?
-Absolutely.
Can't leave that boy...can't leave that
boy alone with that woman.
If I understand it right, Mr. Stapleton
believes...  -Yes, I believe that.
Sadly, that is also my opinion.
And, um, what's the basis
of your suspicion?
On the night of the reading of the will, Mrs.
Vandeleure cried for hours in her room.
Why was she crying?  What do you think?
-Disappointment.  A poor relative.
Nobody thought Lord Charles
had any remaining next of kin.
And how was it that you heard
Mrs. Vandeleure crying?
I was eavesdropping at the door.
-Ugh, disgusting.  -Excuse me.
Ugh, disgusting...
Just leave it, Barrymore.  I'll unpack
the suitcase myself.  -Very well.
It must be unpacked right away.  Otherwise
everything will be squashed  -Let me do it.
Please leave it to me.  I'm happy
to be occupied.
It's so boring for me here.
-Why did you you stay here then?
Well, I'm looking for an opportunity.
I thought maybe I could
be useful at this time.
May I ask what you have been
doing with your life heretofore?
Model, but I have no talent
or enthusiasm for it.
But who asks for that?
I have no other choice.  Tomorrow
I'm leaving.  -Why that?
Because you haven't
invited me to stay.
Of course.  It would be my pleasure to have
such a charming, pretty lady as a guest...
if she wants to.  -I'll accept the
compliment and the invitation, Lord Henry.
And thank you.
-I thank you!
Well, what is that?  Ink?  -Nice.
Aha, the ink pen!
Too bad about the suit.  I don't
think it can be saved.
I'll try anyway.
-It's an old suit.  Throw it away.
It's not all that bad.  Barrymore
will be happy.  But it's a pity.
Do you have any other
requests of your housemaid?
No.  -If it's OK with you, I'll have
dinner served in one hour.
Please do.  -Be punctual.
-Absolutely.
You, too, Mr. Parker.
That's astounding!  -Isn't she nice?  I've
just hired her as a housemaid.
Oh, that's wise of you.
-But she's really very nice.
Nice, but dangerous.
-To the contrary.  dangerous but nice.
By the way, do you
have any suspicions?
For the moment, everything lies in
front of me as if in a deep fog.
Mr. Holmes, we found nothing
about these moors.
In Grimpener Moor, there are well-
preserved caves, in which our stone-age
antecedents dwelled.  The Neolithic
period doesn't interest you, right?
Let me see.
Lord Henry.
It's you?  What's the deal with
the light signal?
I...I gave a light sig...
Ah, Barrymore gave some and
someone on the moor answered him,
and...
You really gave me a bad blow.
-I'm sorry, but someone knocked on my door.
That was me.
-When I came out, no one was there.
That was me, too.  I went after
Barrymore to see what he...
We have to go outside to the moor right
away.  -Now, in the middle of the night?
We'll have time in the morning.
-No, something must be happening.
But no, come on and go to sleep.
May I serve breakfast?
Tell me, Barrymore, why do you prowl
around at night with a lantern?
Mr. Parker, I do a security check
of the house every night.
To make sure everything
is in order.
Good of you to be so
diligent.  That's good.
Good morning.  The newspaper.
Hey, young friend, come in.  Does that
boy bring the newspaper every day?
Yes, he picks it up at the train station.
By mail it would come much later.
Good morning.  A weekly paper.
-Thanks.  Here.
Well, boy, how's business going?
-Business isn't going, but I go a lot.
How long do you think it takes me to
deliver my 46 Timeses every day?
46 papers?  You don't sell more?
-No.
Well, the lady here in the house bought
10 newspapers at once the other day.
She at least has a sense
for business stimulation.
Wait!  Which lady?
-There is only one lady in the house.
10 Timeses, and all from the same day?
-Maybe she wants to wallpaper her room.
How did you get that idea?
-I'm supposed to bring her glue.
Well, goodbye.
-Goodbye.  10 Timeses?
Miss Beryl seems to be
writing threatening letters.
Ah, Barrymore.  When does
Miss Beryl get up?
Very early.
-Is she up already?
She went riding with Lord Henry an hour
ago to view the estate.
Lord Henry is out of the house?
Without telling me?
And what does Mr. Parker think?
-Why does that interest you?
Because I find him very nice, this
Mr. Parker.  Nice, but dangerous.
Yes, he spoke very admiringly of you.
-Really?
He thinks you have especially good hearing.
-That must be a holdover from my career.
As model?
-No, as a telephone operator.
Oh, you were also a telephone operator?
-Yes, but this is my first time as a maid.
I think you love the variety.  -No, the
variety loves me, and never lets me rest.
Even though I love a calm life, and
have never had it.
I have always had it, and I crave
change, adventure, and excitement.
Stop.  Who are you?
-I'm Dr. Watson.
I live in Baskerville Castle.
Perhaps you are looking for a
man and woman on horseback.
I am worried...
-You don't have to be scared of horses.
If he stopped on the moor
he is no longer alive.
We have searched the whole thing.  -We're
withdrawing.  No sense hanging around.
Excuse me.
You think he shot at us?  -At us?  At you,
Lord Baskerville.  You have to leave here.
You are in danger.  That's why I sent you
the letters.  In London, all the hotels.
That was you?
-I wanted to warn you.
Yes, but what made you do that?
-I was scared.
No Baskerville is safe here.
-What should I make of that?
Don't ask.  Leave right away.
Ah, Lord Henry!  Miss Vandeleure!
Did my dog bark at you?
Anyway, what are you doing here?
-Staying busy.  I have to visit a patient.
Well, I'd better be going.  Otherwise
I'll scare the horses.
Goodbye.
The fishie swam in the little stream,
and was so big and fat.
In a moment it'll swim in the pan,
and then it becomes a fish cutlet.
Mr. Stapleton!  Mr. Stapleton!
Mr. Watson.  -Hello.
-To what do I owe this pleasure?
Have you seen Lord Henry or
Miss Vandeleure?  -No, why?
Because I'm worried about them.
There was a gunshot in the woods.
A shot rang out, hey, hey!  Who shot out
there?  Is my little rabbit scared?
Don't make jokes.  Come with me.
-And the leprechauns will fry my fish, huh?
So, what's wrong with the Lord and his
Lady?  Did they disappear together?
You think the worst right away  -Cut the
jokes.  Show me the way to the woods.
Go up onto the roof and you'll see the
forest.  All the way to the moor.
Now come with me.  I don't
know my way around here.
Please.  There are the stairs.
Do you see them?  -Of course I do.
-Go up them.
17 steps.  You can handle that, can't you?
Climb to the roof.  I'll be right there.
Here's to our rescue.
To your rescue, Lord Henry.
I have the feeling that I'm safe
as long as you're around.
Well, who knows?
-Yes, nothing nasty.
You have that much trust in me?
-Unconditional trust.
You must stay with me Beryl, OK?
What is that?
The shot.  Are you hurt?
Boy, it was a close call.
-Are you really okay?
No, not the slightest trace.
But please don't tell Watson of this.
-Watson?  Who's that?
Well, I mean, Mr. Parker, Peinter.
-Parker?  Peinter?  Watson?
What is it, then?
-OK, Watson.
He's a colleague of Sherlock Holmes.
Sherlock Holmes?
Watson had to promise Holmes not
to let me out of his sight.
If he saw this, he'd be very upset.
Come.  The fish is done.
-Yes, just a minute.
A man who stands in
front of the telescope,
spurns a good fish.
Deserves , whether it's
summer or winter, 25...
Well, are you coming?
-There...there's somebody on the moor.
There's somebody on the moor?
-Yeah.
Yes, got him.  What's
he doing there?
He blowing away smoke.
-He probably has a reason.
To not reveal his hideout.
Now he's gone again.
-Can you show me on
this map where he was
when he disappeared?
A general's staff map?  -Yes, we
are to some extent in a war.
Yes, yes, a war with ghosts.
So, here.  There it is.
The circle seems to
be slowly closing.
It isn't without danger to cross
the moor at night.
However, this one path
is completely safe.
Am I bothering the gentlemen?
No, absolutely not.
Mr. Stapleton is only showing Lord Henry
the property that belongs to the castle.
Just don't let his poker face fool you.
Mr. Stapleton is a dangerous game rat.
Goodnight, gentlemen.
-Goodnight.
Why the secretiveness
with Miss Beryl?
It's not necessary for her to find
out about our nightly excursions.
It could worry her.
-Above all, it would worry us.
Are you still of the mind that Miss
Beryl is not quite trustworthy?
In brief, yes.
And you, Doctor?
Do you know who sent me the warning
letters in London?  -Yes.
Miss Beryl.
-How do you know that?
It's my duty to know a lot
and speak of it very little.
Warning letters?
"If you value your life..."  It's cut
out of newspapers.  -Yes.
A dangerous woman.
Why?
I have learned something from
you, Mr. Waston.
Know a lot and speak little.
-What do you know?
Nothing specific.  But Miss Beryl belongs
professionally to that sort of woman who
entices men to make
senseless purchases.
How do you mean?
-Well, she was a mannequin.
Off and on.  A model.
I am aware of that.
What of it?
But please, I certainly didn't want to
besmirch this very honourable profession.
And I would request that you do not.
-Gentlemen, let the models go up and down.
We have more important
things to discuss.
So, this was the spot where we saw the
man disappear into the caves.
As I said, the path there is totally
safe, but for the return trip
one will have to descend.
I will look after that.
Now, this way across the moor, if one knows
it, is passable.  He could flee this way.
A very perilous route, but I know every
step.  Ah, I caught a longhorn moth there.
A wonderful exemplar.
I must show it to you sometime.
-If it's not dangerous I'll go with you.
That's out of the question.
You're staying with me.
I am at least somewhat
responsible for you.
Where are you going?  -With the men.
They're going out onto the moor.
No, you're staying here!  -No, they
can't go there alone.  Leave me!
Let happen what will happen!
There will be a disaster and we
are at fault.  There will be a disaster!
You must leave the castle
right away!  I wish you would.
No, I won't let you talk me into
anything.  I won't be forced.
I will only go when I know I
have nothing more to lose.
I knew you loved him, but do you
realize it could cost you your life?
Wait a second.  There's something
flickering in the castle.
That's Barrymore.
-Light in the fog?
Night after night of this howling
sent her uncle to his death.
What are you doing here, Barrymore?
I made my security check
of the house.
Don't lie!  You made light signals.
What did they mean?
Nothing.  You are mistaken.
Talk!  What kind of witchcraft is going
on?  To whom did you signal?
That's my business and not
yours, Miss Vandeleure.
Then I'll tell Lord Henry what's
happening behind his back.
And he'll chase you off.
This is the end, Eliza.
We can pack our things.
-No, it's my fault!  Mine alone!
I asked him for so long, and refused him
my love, until he did me the favour.
Barrymore, whom did you signal?
-Go out onto the moor.
Who is out there?
A poor person.  He's followed by
everyone.  He's from Princetown Prison.
He has been hiding
out there for days.
What are you doing
abetting a convict?
He is...
-He is my brother.
And why did you give him light signals?
-To warn him.  The men went onto the moor.
Who's on the moor?
-Lord Henry and Mr. Parker.
The caves must be very near here.
Oh?  Well, take a look at the map.
Lord Charles, a light!
Come, come!
Hands up!
What are you doing there?
Light.
I'll go down.
Today's Times.
The inhabitant is very modern.
Hands up!
Hands up, I said.
-I have them up.
What do you want, Watson?
-That's Holmes!
Of course.  It's me.
Lord Henry, I presume.  In London you
were reluctant to come to me.
And now you even sneak
into my digs at night.
This is your place?
-Yes.
Totally modern.
Running water.  -That's astounding!
Your boots were damned dirty.
Thank you.
What are you doing
here, anyway?
In case there's a criminal in the
Baskerville case, there's no better hideout
for him than these caves.
Why didn't you contact us?
Because I only found out this evening that
the man on the moor is an escaped prisoner.
An escaped prisoner?  But
how do you know that?
I found his hideout.
And I searched his clothes.  Prisoner
#113, Princetown Prison.
Last night he got new clothing
from someone in the castle,
with whom he communicated
with light signals.
Barrymore?
-An escaped convict?
And you're not going after him?
First he has to help me solve
the Baskerville case.
And I think, gentlemen...
I think...
Hello!  Mr. Watson, over here!  -What,
Stapleton?  -He went down over here.
Who?
-Lord Henry.
Henry?
-I warned him so sternly.
How did this happen?
-A dog chased him.  A huge dog.
Lord Henry ran out of fear, and
didn't watch where he was going.
That's where he fell.
That's not Lord Henry.
It's the convict.
A convict?
-Poor devil.
Are you sure you're
not mistaken?
It was really a dog
that chased him?
It's possible that I'm mistaken.
An ink stain?  -This my jacket!  The
one I gave to Barrymore.
Mr. Holmes, do you have an
explanation for that?
Can you see to it, Lord Henry, that the
poor man gets a decent burial?
What happened to him
was meant for you.
I thank you for your
sympathy, Milord.
When will this criminal
finally be caught?
Is it clear to you, Lord Henry, that it is
too dangerous for you to leave the house?
What do you mean?  -The poor devil in there
died because he was wearing your clothes.
A shoe of yours was stolen in London.
-Two, in fact.  A new one, which was
returned, and later a used one.
-What's the reason behind all that?
Because the dog could only find
a scent on the used shoe.
Who could be interested in
siccing the beast on me?
The next of kin.  Who would inherit Lord
Charles's estate if you were gone?
The Vandeleures.
Beryl.
-In case there's no male Vandeleure.
I don't know of one.
Who is that in the picture?
-Lord Baskerville.
He's actually only missing a butterfly
net.  He looks like...  -Shhhh
Lord Henry.  -Do you really think Beryl
is suspicious?  -Yes, I believe that.
Where is the lady?
-She's sleeping.
Then we'll wake her.
Where's Miss Vandeleure's room?
-Follow me.
But Holmes, in the middle of the night.
This looks like an interrogation.
-It will be an interrogation.
When did you last see Miss Beryl?
-Before midnight.
And where?
-Upstairs in the bay window room.
Why did she go up there?
-She surprised me.
Doing what?  -I was...I was
giving light signals again.
What did Miss Beryl think about that?
She was very angry.
But we told her the truth right away.
Miss Vandeleure said that she didn't
think we had any intent to harm the lord.
But she ran away, and later
I saw her leaving the house.
And where did she go?
-I don't know.
Maybe out onto the moor.
-Hello!  What's this?
But Mr. Holmes.  What will Miss Beryl say?
-Who cares what Miss Beryl says?
Lord Charles died on the 18th, right?
-Yes.
At what time?
-11 p.m.
With whom did he talk on the
telephone at 10 minutes before 11?
I don't know.
-Think about it!
What do you say, Watson?  At 10:50, he was
so agitated that he insults the postal clerk.
Because of this grievance?  There's
nothing suspicious about this.
I gave it to Miss Beryl myself
to take care of these things.
This complaint, Lord Henry, will break
the neck of Lord Baskerville's murderer.
You come, too.  We'll
need the whole team.
And I?  -Hold down the fort with Beryl's
help.  You two stay here.
-Why?  -Because she'll bring us into
peril.  Think about them!
But Holmes, you expect me to
stay here passively?
If you promise not to leave the house, I
give you my word that you will know all
the secrets in a few hours.
How far is it to the post office?
-20 minutes on the country road.
Please take the shortest route.
To call in the middle of the night!
Such lack of consideration!
Yes, yes!  I'm coming.
Of course, it Baskerville
Castle again.
Hello?  Yes?  Yes, Grimpen Post Office.
Night calls cost double taxes.
You know that, right?
Yes, yes, I know!  Please
give me Mr. Stapleton.
No, I don't know the number.  Please
look it up.  -Number 17.  I'll connect.
Such shenanigans, these night calls!
I'm sure I won't be able to sleep again.
Hello, Mr. Stapleton.  Miss Beryl
left in the middle of the night!
Where did she go?
-I don't know.  Maybe on the moor.
Holmes and Watson are looking for her.  You
know all the paths.  Don't you want to help?
But of course.
Naturally.
-Help!
Hello?  Hello!
Are you still speaking?
What's wrong now?
Who's there at this time of night?
-It's me, Barrymore.
Two gentlemen would like
to talk to you.
Eight hours, between nine and five.  Not
at midnight.  I'm not available now.
Especially not concerning
Baskerville Castle.
I beg of you...
-It doesn't even concern Baskerville Castle.
Well, what then?
-It concerns you, my good lady.
You were offended on the 18th,
at ten minutes to 11.
We came on behalf of Lord Baskerville
to ask for your forgiveness.
Where are the flowers, Holmes?
-Why, I gave them to you.
Darn, I left them behind.  We'll
have them delivered tomorrow.
It's actually unfathomable to offend
such a charming young lady.
"Dumb person" is what he called me.
-"Dumb person".  That too!
I can't be expected to accept that.
-No way.  Forget about accepting it.
Uh, with whom did he telephone?
With a nervous, unfriendly subscriber.
Number 17.  Mr. Stapleton.
Was it a common occurrence that the castle
asked to be connected to #17 at night?
I can't remember.  Only on the
18th and today.
Today?  -Five minutes ago I was awoken.
The castle demanded number 17.
Maybe Miss Beryl has been found.
Connect me with the castle.
It'll cost you night taxes.
-Yes, yes, yes.
Do you think Lord Henry is very attached
to Miss Beryl?  -I think so, yes.
Why do you ask?
But that's Stapleton arm-in-arm
with Miss Beryl.
Even though they behaved as if
they didn't know each other.
A pair of crooks?
-What's taking so long with the phone?
Baskerville Castle is not answering.
No one is answering?  Then
Lord Henry isn't in the castle.
If he went to Stapleton's, he's gone.
Come!
Wait!  Wait!
Who's paying the phone charge?
Who's paying the night taxes?
Stapleton!
A dog!
Beryl is in the house!
Help!  Help!
Henry.
-Beryl.
Save yourself.  My brother will sic the dog
on you.  He'll kill you like he killed
Lord Charles; to inherit everything.
Your brother?
Stapleton is your brother?  -Yes, he only
calls himself Stapleton.  He's a Vandeleure.
Why did you come here?  -I was scared
that something awful would happen.
You scoundrel!  You sicced the
dog on him.
Help!
So, what do we learn from the
Baskerville case?
That all assumptions can be proven false
whenever a pretty woman is in play.
True.
A letter for Mr. Holmes.
A letter from Baskerville Castle?
Aren't you curious what's in it?
I know the latest news
from there.
A letter from Lord Baskerville with
Miss Vandeleure's perfume.
Oh, you mean...
-The same old song.
As an engaged couple,
we'll miss you.
Only one truth has existed
since the beginning of time.
One cannot understand women.
The first showing of "The Hound of
Baskerville" occurred on January 27, 1937,
in a double premiere in Berlin's Ufa
Theatre on Kurfuerstendamm and in
Primus Palace.  Following two silent-film
adaptations from the years 1914 (direction:
Rudolf Meinert) and 1929 (direction:
Richard Oswald), this is the third film
version of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's "The
Hound of the Baskervilles" to have been
filmed in a German studio.