[tense music]
[heavy breathing]
[sheets rustling]
♪
[heavy breathing]
[metal lid clinks]
♪
[clanging]
[light switch clicks]
♪
[click]
[light switch clicks]
♪
- Shit.
[lighter clicking]
You piece of...
♪
[sighs]
[clink]
♪
[smack]
[jarring music]
[smack smack smack]
[sharp exhale]
♪
[sighs]
Hey.
Coffee's still hot.
- How long have you been up.
- Uh...
I'm not sure.
[Lucy scoffs]
- Why is the fridge warm?
[Jose] Oh, power was out
most of the night.
- No bottled water?
[Jose] I think there's
a case in my trunk.
I think there's some
construction on VP,
so we should probably leave
by 11 just to be safe.
[Lucy] Oh, that's fine.
O'Leary case still?
- Uh huh.
[Lucy] Did you get any sleep?
- Um...
A little, maybe.
- It doesn't look like it.
- That's nice.
[Lucy] I could feel you
tossing and turning all night.
- By-product.
- Look, honey, are you sure
this isn't too much for you?
- What are you talking about?
Come on, you know how long
I've been waiting for Diane
to give me something
like this, right?
It took her three years
to learn my name.
- Okay, but you
haven't been sleeping.
Your blood pressure's
gotta be like--
- Okay, look, Tom Bodner
worked 18 hour days
when he started.
All right?
Nights, weekends.
Guy was a machine.
And Diane saw that,
and she made him partner at 31.
Now he just plays golf all day
while we do all the grunt work.
[tense piano music]
Hey.
I promise,
this weekend...
You get me all to yourself.
[rock music]
♪
- What?
- You know I'm ticklish there.
Wait, that doesn't mean
I want you to stop.
- What about there?
Are you ticklish there?
- Okay, okay, okay.
[Vicky chuckles]
I didn't even hear you come in.
- I told you, I'm as
quiet as a mouse.
- How late was it?
- I don't know, like 1, 1:30.
- Oh.
[Kelly yawns]
♪
- Oh, you okay?
- Just parched.
- What do I always say?
One beer, one water.
I can't have any
sympathy for you-
- I know, I know.
I'm doing it to myself.
[Lisa chuckles]
[dog barks]
[water drips]
[calm rock music]
[Vicky] How was the show?
- I don't know, it was okay.
- Yeah?
Good turnout?
- Yeah, we had like
50 people there.
- That's not bad!
[Vicky chuckles]
Anyone I know?
- Just Sarah J,
and that guy Dom.
- They stayed for
the whole thing?
- No, I don't think so.
But Dom was really
pissy last night.
- Right?
He was like that
when I met him too.
- I'm gonna go shower, okay?
I'm still sticky
from last night.
- Oh.
- Will you make me some coffee?
- Gross!
- Please?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
[phone dings]
[rock music quietly playing]
[whistle of syringe]
[heavy breathing]
[pump airing]
[knocking]
[clears throat]
[Doctor] All right, guys.
How are we feeling today?
- Uh.
Pretty good, I think.
[Doctor] Getting to enjoy
the last of the good
summer weather, I hope?
- Trying to.
[Jose chuckles]
- Okay, well...
Gonna be a few days till we
get the test results back,
but I think we should probably
be in a pretty good spot.
Lucy, everything looked
and felt really good
in your physical exam.
Have you been taking the
klonophine as directed?
- Um, I think I missed
a dose, maybe two.
- That should be fine.
Your follicles look like
they're in decent shape.
We just need a little extra
boost the klonophine gives.
You two been sexually active?
- I...
I wouldn't mind
a bit more.
- Of course you wouldn't.
- Right, um...
Okay, well, how
long do you think
it'll take before I'm ready?
- It all depends.
We'll know for sure when
we get the blood work back,
but there's no reason you
shouldn't keep trying.
Especially considering the
treatments we've already done.
- Well, you heard her, Luce.
- And you'll let us know
when the labs come in?
- Absolutely.
- All right, great.
Thank you, Dr. Penn.
- Sorry, one more thing.
I know this isn't my business,
'cause I'm not your GP,
but your blood pressure is--
- Ah, yeah.
- It was 153 over 98.
- I know.
- Oh my God.
- You've had this
issue before, correct?
- Yep, yep.
Yeah.
- When he gets stressed out,
he gets bad tinnitus,
and he can't sleep.
- Have you tried
things to mitigate it?
Breathing exercises,
medications?
I could prescribe you something.
- I've already got
amlodipine, some benzos.
You know.
- Those should definitely help.
Be sure not to mix those with
any other drugs or alcohol.
Okay?
- Yep.
Thanks, Doc.
- Thank you.
Sorry about that.
- No problem.
[Jose] I don't want to.
- Why not?
- Because I don't want to.
- Your mom's stroke
wasn't enough
for you to take this seriously?
- I take it seriously,
believe me.
I just, I don't...
I don't want to have
to take pills every day
for the rest of my life.
- Hey, I'm just saying,
if your blood
pressure's this bad now,
just think about how
much worse it's gonna get
as you get older.
If we're ever gonna
have this baby,
I would really like you
to be around for it.
- Oh, come on, that's
a little bit dramatic,
don't you think?
Besides, they say your
blood pressure goes up
like 20 points in
a doctor's office.
[unnerving music]
- I'm thirsty.
I think there's a
convenience store in Vanwood.
[unnerving music]
[tense music]
[birds cawing]
♪
[jarring music]
- This pill...
See, as I was
trying to make mine.
I don't like to do it that way.
- Okay, man.
[tense music]
[Reporter] For O'Leary
Pharmaceuticals
said the issue still
isn't resolved.
Meanwhile, the Matthews
Water Treatment Plant
says its operations are
almost back to normal
after last night's outage.
Boy, it sure is a hot one.
[knocking]
- Don't you live on
the Rustywood?
- What? Why?
- I'm your neighbor, Trent.
- Okay.
- That orange cat
you always pet?
- Diego?
- He's mine.
- Oh.
Oh, hi.
- We love Diego, he's-
- Sorry to scare you, I just...
- It's okay.
- No, I just wanted
to introduce myself.
- It's nice to meet you.
- Yeah.
Oh, your husband's
the guy that's always
out running, right?
- Right.
Yep. Speak of the devil.
- Hey.
[Trent] Hey.
- Everything okay, Luce?
- Yeah, this is our
neighbor, Trent.
- Oh, hey.
Hey, Trent.
- Diego's his.
- Diego? Oh, no kidding.
Yeah, he always runs up
when he hears us coming.
I'm Jose, nice to meet you.
- Oh, I did...
[Trent grunts]
I just wanted to say hi.
Well, hi.
Hi, hi.
[Trent laughs]
- Yo, listen.
I'm making a bunch
of soup this weekend.
If you guys wanted to
stop by for a bowl.
- Um...
That's cool.
Like, not this weekend,
but maybe in the future.
It'd be cool.
Nice to meet you, man.
- Hey, you too.
[Jose] Yeah.
- Sorry.
It was nice to meet you.
[eerie music]
- There's time if you
wanna get some more,
it's gonna be available for you.
More inventory or
more of the same?
[eerie music]
- Let's finish what I
have at my house first.
♪
- You want the pasta?
- Yeah, whatever.
[Lucy] Jose.
- What?
- Why are you being like this?
- I didn't say anything.
[ominous music]
[pills rattling]
[water running]
- Here.
Please.
It's just a blood pressure pill.
- Fine.
[heavy inhale and exhale]
- Like, you know, I'm just,
I'm worried about you, okay?
It's not, it's just,
the last time that--
- This is nothing like
last time. You know that.
- Okay, well, I can't
go through that again.
- Have I slipped up
even once since then?
- No.
- Exactly.
Look...
I'm gonna go for a run.
Okay?
Just to clear my head.
- Okay.
[mysterious music]
♪
[car door slams repeatedly]
[drill whirs]
♪
[water running]
[gulps]
- Ahhhhhh.
♪
[sighs]
[music beat]
[plate shatters]
- Jose?
- Hey.
Oh, don't worry, it's
not your grandmother's,
'cause hers are the
blue ones, right?
- Yep.
Oh my God, there's blood-
- No, I got it, I got it, I
got it, I got it, it's fine.
Don't worry about it.
Oh, shit.
No, it's like...
Yeah, you know, look at
that, it's a little cut.
- Hey, are you okay?
- Yeah.
It looked a lot worse
than it actually is.
[hands bang]
Okay.
All right. Oops, sorry.
Ooh!
- Babe, did you get
any sleep last night?
[Jose] I tried,
I tried, I tried.
[tense frantic music]
- Honey, maybe you should
call in sick today.
- Why would I do that?
- Because you haven't
slept in three days.
- I got the O'Leary case.
It's fine, I feel fine.
[tense frantic music]
[Jose spits]
[water running]
[Jose grunts]
[Jose coughs]
Okay, see you later.
[tense frantic music]
- Your half sister's coming
over tonight for dinner.
- You say sister?
Wait, what?
That's tonight?
- Yes, that's tonight.
She texted you in the group
chat to ask what to bring.
- Well, no, she doesn't
need to bring anything,
I'll just take
care of everything.
I'll just go by after work.
- You know what?
I can go get it.
- Lisa's pescatarian, so that
means fish, right?
So, salmon?
Or that's too boring.
Grouper?
- I'm sure whatever you get,
it's gonna be great.
- Chilean sea bass!
Chilean sea bass.
With the little foil packets
with some coconut rice, right?
And then a nice salad?
What do you think of that?
Great. Oh...
I've taken the amlodipine.
[pills rattling]
Are you proud of me?
- Yup.
[tense frantic music]
- So, it looks like we've been
thrown a little curve ball.
Looks like this power outage
caused a big issue at the plant.
I haven't been there
myself to see it,
but apparently the
place is a disaster.
Their system's
completely collapsed.
So now, it looks like
the FDA inspectors
won't be able to get in there
until they get it
all cleaned up,
which could take days,
even weeks.
Martinez, what are you doing?
[window squeaks]
Can you sit down, please?
Jose!
- Sorry.
- Where was I?
- You were-
- Power outage...
- Talking about the
cleanups and inspections.
- That's right.
[tense music]
So, there've been some
rumblings about drainage issues.
- Did the power failure
make the leak worse?
[tense music]
[Diane chuckles]
- He's kidding, everyone.
Trust me, there's no leak.
One of the drain pipes
for the by-product
was affected by
the power outage,
but O'Leary herself
has assured me
that the damage was minor,
and shouldn't cause
any further issues.
[tense erratic music]
[knife chops]
Ahh.
- Hey.
Are you focused?
Did you get my text?
- About the gas bill?
- Mhm.
No, not the gas bill.
I invited Dom and
Sarah J for dinner.
- What?
- Sorry.
Sarah and I were on
the phone earlier,
and it just kind of came up, so.
- That's okay.
I got way too much food
for four people anyway.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Besides, it's been way too
long since we've seen her.
- Yeah, I know.
You and Dom just don't
get along though.
- Well, come on, Luce,
the guy's a prick.
You should see
how he treats her.
- Well, she's our friend, so,
if that's who she chooses
to be with, then...
Honey, I think you've
chopped that enough.
[knife chops]
- Bisexual fish?
Are you serious?
- Yes!
It is here for you to read.
They're putting
hormones in the water.
- No, they're not.
- They are.
The male fish have
too much estrogen,
that's why their
populations are dying out.
- She's just joking.
- No, I'm not.
Will you just look for yourself?
- Babe, no one wants to read
your True Secret
conspiracy theories.
- No, wait a minute.
Didn't somebody on True Secret
recently expose
the school board scandal
in Oregon though?
- Exactly.
- One time.
They were right one time.
You see some of the
others shit on there?
They have this
whole sub dedicated
to the benefits of
drinking goat semen.
[Sarah] No!
- She is exaggerating.
That is not true.
But...
Sort of.
[Sarah laughs]
Okay, well, what about
the big pharma cover ups?
I mean, do you know how much
of that gets in the soil
that we grow our food in?
- Wait a second.
They talk about
that stuff on there?
- Okay, does anybody
want more wine?
- I'll have another glass.
- Whoa, whoa, what
are you doing?
- What?
I told you, I don't like
it when you drink wine.
- Maybe just some water.
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah, I'll have water.
I'll have some water too.
Good for the vocal chords.
[Jose] Oh, yeah? You got a
show tonight, Lisa?
- Yes, sir.
- I thought it was tomorrow?
[Lucy] Where is it?
- No, it's tonight.
And it's down at Sage Brush.
[Sarah] Mm.
I haven't been there in forever,
what time do you play?
- Midnight.
[Sarah] Maybe we'll
catch the next one?
- No, there's no shortage.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Nothing.
- Do you ever go, Vicky?
- No.
She's gotta get
up early for work.
- I'll be in the car.
- Thanks for dinner, Dom!
- What was that?
- I'm sorry, he's just cranky.
- I'll say.
- We haven't been
getting very much sleep.
Um.
Thank you so much for dinner.
Maybe we can host the next one?
[Lucy] Of course.
[Jose] Sure.
You can just leave it,
you're fine.
[Jose laughs]
- Don't forget your phone.
- Goodnight.
- Told you.
- Is he always like that?
[Jose chuckles]
[Lucy] Kind of.
- Okay, well, did you see
the bruise on her wrist?
- What?
- What bruise?
[Jose] Are you serious?
You don't think...
- You know him better than I do.
- She was always such a badass.
I can't see her putting up
with anything like that.
Jose?
Yo!
- Huh?
Oh.
Man, Dom's a dick.
He always has been.
[mellow music playing]
I'm sorry.
- He okay?
- I think he's just tired too.
- Are you sure that's all it is?
- You think I haven't
thought of that?
[Vicky] Okay, sorry I asked.
[Lucy] I'm sorry.
Just, this feels different.
I've never seen him
like this before.
[intense frantic music]
[heavy breathing]
[ominous music]
♪
[heavy breathing]
Mm.
[Jose screams]
- What? What?
What? What is it?
Jesus Christ, Jose, I
thought someone was in here.
[heavy breathing]
- So did I.
[deep inhale]
[deep exhale]
[ominous music]
[door squeaks]
♪
- Is that where you were?
That's what I said last time.
But it's gotta be a perfect
line because...
If you do it right,
you get a prize.
Ooh, maybe even two.
Hopefully a new hat.
I could really use a new hat,
it's really cold out.
[woman chatters]
[ominous music]
♪
[engine humming]
[phone dings]
[tense music]
♪
[knocking]
[Kelly] Hold on.
I'm coming!
♪
- Where is she?
- Who are you?
Hey, what the fuck is this?
- I saw her come in.
I knew it.
- Just wait.
- I fucking knew it!
- Just listen to me, please-
- Don't you fucking touch me.
[tense music]
- So...
I'm guessing that was her?
[tense music]
[Lisa sobs]
♪
[sobs]
- Fuck!
[Jose yells]
[tinnitus rings]
[heavy breathing]
[tense music]
[jarring music]
♪
[exhales]
[jarring music]
[Lucy] Hey.
Did you get my message?
[Vicky] Yeah.
[Lucy] It's worse
than I thought.
It's gotta be tonight.
[ominous music]
- Do you want me
to tell Sarah J?
Well, she orchestrated
the first one.
Fine, fine.
Look, I gotta go.
What are you doing here?
- I need to explain.
- No, get out.
- Please, I swear-
- Oh, you swear
nothing happened.
- Yes.
- Well, I saw it.
- Please, I promise you.
- I saw it.
- Vicky, wait, listen to me.
- Okay, you're right.
I went to Kelly's house,
and we kissed,
but that's it.
[Vicky] Your shirt
was unbuttoned.
- I know!
But I stopped it right
before you walked in.
I swear to God.
- Bullshit.
I know how late you stay out.
Come on, you think I'm stupid?
- She is the only person
I've done anything
remotely like that with.
[Vicky sighs]
- Why should I believe you?
- Because...
I love you.
Because we have a
life together, Vicky.
- Then why would
you do this to me?
- Please, just wait!
Just let explain to you,
I'm trying to tell you.
[erratic music]
[sharp exhale]
I know you hate me,
but it's not near as
much as I hate myself.
It's just...
- Just what?
- You have to get up so
early every day for work,
and I'm out late every night.
We don't see each other,
we don't hang out.
- And this is what you do?
Get out.
I can't stay in the
same house as you.
Not right now.
- Fine.
But I do love you.
- Go!
- Fine.
[intense music]
[phone rings]
[knocking]
- What?
- I got that copy of the
affidavit that you asked for.
- Just leave it, man.
[intense music]
Shit.
Anthony!
Fuck.
Sorry, that was rude, man.
Anthony!
[phone rings]
[intense music]
Diane, what are you doing?
- Oh, I can't seem
to get this printer
to print fast enough, right?
You know, how it
always takes so long.
- Yeah, do you
know how to fix it?
- Well, I felt this
loose piece, you see,
and then sure enough,
when I opened it up,
they're all loose,
and then I finally get 'em
nice and tight, and now look.
- Listen, did you
ever see that memo
that I sent you about
about O'Leary's drainage?
- Where the fuck
does this piece go?
I mean, it looks
like to just screw it
in the back here like this,
but then when I
look at the manual,
it says it needs part 10A and...
Fuck it!
- I think there's
a real potential
that some of the
climate pharmaceutical-
- Oh, just order a new one!
[phone rings]
[intense music]
[jarring music]
[water running]
[intense music]
- I told you, I'll get
to it when I get home.
I don't know, an hour?
Maybe more?
What does it matter?
No, I'm hanging up.
I'm hanging up.
[sharp exhale]
- Are you okay?
Oh, here, come, sit down.
Come.
- I'm sorry, I know this is
supposed to be about Jose.
- No.
- No, no, no, no,
don't worry about it.
What happened?
- He said I didn't tell him
I was gonna be here,
but I know I did.
It's just, we've been
fighting so much,
and neither of us can
seem to get any sleep.
- Hey, what do you mean
you haven't been sleeping?
- I just toss and turn and
can't turn my brain off.
[door squeaks]
- Hey.
- Hey, Vic, Sarah J, what's up?
- Hey, babe.
You think you can sit
down for a second?
- Sure.
What's happening?
[Lucy] Sarah J, you
wanna start us off?
- Um...
Jose, we all are here
because we love you,
and because we know how hard
it was the last time and we-
- Are you...
Are you fucking kidding me?
- Babe.
- I'm not using.
That's what this is?
[Lucy] Honey.
- We're just worried
about you, Jose.
Lucy says that
you've been up night,
and you've been acting erratic.
- Well, maybe I'm acting erratic
because I can't remember
the last time I slept.
Okay?
- Okay.
- Using, Jesus.
I haven't touched that
shit in five years.
Never crossed my mind.
You know what, while
we're confronting people,
why don't we start
with you, Sarah?
- Me?
- Yeah.
Dom, he's terrible.
- Don't say that now.
- Why?
We all know it.
We see how he treats her, we
see the bruise on our arm.
- Wait!
Seriously?
[Vicky] It wasn't the
time or place.
- Oh, really?
Then when?
Unbelievable.
- I guess I'll go too.
- Yeah.
We didn't resolve anything.
- Call me if anything changes.
- Okay, thanks.
[ominous music]
[shower running]
[eerie music]
[jarring music]
[ominous music]
♪
[Jose] What are you watching?
- I was watching that.
[deep breath and exhale]
- Will you look at me,
please?
[sighs]
I don't know what's going on.
But I swear to you,
these are the only
drugs I've taken.
- Then why are you
acting like this?
Up all night and
these mood swings.
- Something's not right.
And I can feel it...
but I don't know what it is.
And I don't know
how to make it stop.
I'm scared, honey.
I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
[ominous music]
[phone buzzing]
Hey.
Wait, wait, wait.
Slow down.
He did what?
[ominous music]
[door squeaks]
[Jose] Shit, Sarah.
- Jose, go get her some water.
Oh my God, sit down.
It's okay.
[Sarah] I've never
seen him like this.
[Jose sighs]
- Sorry.
- Fuckin' asshole!
[Sarah sobs]
Here, take one of these.
You can't let him
get away with this.
- I know.
I'll report it in the morning.
I'm so tired.
- It's all right.
You're safe, okay?
You can stay here
as long as you want.
[Sarah sobs]
Okay?
[ominous music]
♪
[pills rattling]
[Sarah coughs]
♪
[wind blowing]
[water running]
- Sarah.
[yawns]
Hey, it's too hot out here.
Sarah.
[jarring music]
Oh, what the fuck?
Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh, shit!
[Lucy] Hey.
Hey, what's going...
[Lucy gasping]
[Lucy sobbing]
[tense music]
♪
- Come on, Vicky.
[cell phone buzzes]
- Hey.
[Lucy] Where'd you go?
- I just gotta pop into
the office real quick.
- You're joking, right?
- No, I just got
something I gotta wrap up.
[Lucy] Promise me you're
not going over there.
- Over where?
[Lucy] You know where.
- Uh, yeah, sure.
But I just got here,
so I'm going to...
I'll just be home soon,
all right?
[Lucy] Jose, don't do...
[tense music]
[knocking]
[door creaking]
- Who the fuck are you?
- Where's Dom?
- Is he expecting you?
- Where is he?
- He's out.
Fuck off.
[door slams shut]
[distant buzzing]
[ominous music]
[drill whirs]
♪
[whack]
- Hey!
- Jesus.
- Hey.
I just wanted to see if
you needed your lawn cut.
See?
- Not right now.
- It's me, Trent, from the gas
station, with the orange cat.
You know, the one that...
[snarls]
[Lucy] I know.
- Oh, what junk mail, huh?
Oh boy, they really load it up
at the end of the month,
don't they?
Huh?
- Hey, what did you say?
- Flyers, coupons, magazines.
- Nevermind, Trent.
I gotta go.
- The pet stores.
Oh, this...
Hey.
[tense music]
[Trent grunts]
[ominous music]
[Lucy exhales sharply]
♪
[cell phone timer rings]
[door squeaks]
[Vicky] I know,
I can't believe it.
I just saw her.
- Hey.
[Vicky] Can I call you back?
[Lisa] Where have you been?
- Long line for gas at Habsta,
but they ran out.
What are you doing here anyway?
- Well, you weren't
picking up my calls
or looking at my texts, so...
[Vicky] Didn't you
hear about Sarah J?
- No.
- She fucking died last night.
- What?
[Vicky] At my brother's house.
- Oh my God.
Are you okay?
- Wha-what do you want?
- Right.
This is gonna sound crazy--
- Don't you have a show
you have to be at?
- I need to tell you something.
[Vicky] Some floozy
to make out with?
- Stop! Will you just
listen to me, please?
- What's with the water?
The water supply has
been contaminated.
[Vicky] Contaminated?
- With meth.
[Vicky laughs]
- Wow.
That's the best one
I've heard yet.
- Okay.
[Vicky laughs]
You're mad at me,
and that's fine.
I just need you to promise me
that you're not gonna
drink the tap water.
- You're serious, aren't you?
[Lisa] Yeah.
- Who told you about this?
- It's everywhere.
You know how the O'Leary
plant makes ADHD medication?
- Who?
I knew it.
When was the last time your
little conspiracy theory trolls
actually got something right?
- Why is it that you think
you couldn't get gas?
Whenever a disaster
like this happens,
what's the first thing
people go out and do?
They go out, and they buy
up all the bottled water,
and all the gas.
Look...
Even if there's just a slight
chance that this is true,
wouldn't you rather be prepared?
I mean, if everyone else is?
Please?
We need to go out,
and we need to buy
bottled water right now.
I mean it, like right now.
- Fine.
- Okay. Let's go.
[tense music]
- Luce?
[jarring music]
[Lucy] Hey.
- Hey.
- Where'd you go?
- I'm sorry that I left,
I just couldn't--
I couldn't stay here, okay?
I kept seeing the
image of her body.
[sobs]
[Lucy shushes]
[sobbing]
What is that?
- Oh, there's a construction
zone near the office,
and they're always leaving
trash and their junk there.
- Can't believe you.
- What?
- You promised that you
weren't gonna go over there.
- I didn't do anything, Luce.
I didn't do anything.
[heavy nervous breathing]
- Who are you?
- What do you mean?
[heavy nervous breathing]
What do you mean?
What are you talking
about, honey?
It's me.
This is me.
What are you talking about?
- What if Dom comes
after you, huh?
What if you go to jail?
Is that how you wanna
spend the first...
- First what?
[tense music]
[Lucy sniffs]
♪
It worked?
Are you serious?
This worked?
It worked?
[tense music]
That's, that's amazing.
Oh my gosh.
What's wrong?
What is it? What?
- Just, Sarah's gone and...
Jose, you're really, really
starting to scare me.
- Baby.
No, baby.
Listen.
Look at me.
You know all I ever wanted
was to have kids, right?
Okay?
Now when that happens, I swear,
everything's gonna
be like fuckin'
"Leave It to Beaver"
in here, okay?
I promise.
All right?
Okay?
[Lucy sniffles]
[sobbing and sniffling]
[Jose laughs]
I can't...
I can't believe this.
[tense music]
You know who would've been
really happy about this?
- Yeah.
Sarah?
[tense music]
- Stay here, I'll
get you some water.
Okay?
- Yeah.
[kiss smack]
[Jose chuckles]
♪
- We're outta bottles.
[Jose] Oh, it's not
gonna kill you.
- I cannot believe
they were out of water.
- I still think
we're overreacting.
[Reporter] This just in
from the mayor's office.
Residents of Knox County
are being advised
to not drink tap water.
I repeat, do not drink
tap water in Knox County.
There's been an
unspecified contamination
that scientists are
saying may have been...
[click]
- Now do you believe me?
Who are you calling?
- My brother.
[cell phone buzzes]
[ominous music]
♪
[Lucy grunts]
- What is it?
- I'm so fucking tired.
I don't know if I'm
gonna go to work today.
[ominous music]
[cell phone buzzes]
- Hey,
nine missed calls?
You must've heard.
What?
Why?
Who told you that?
Shit.
Okay.
Shit, okay.
All right, bye.
Lucy!
Luce!
Hey.
No, no, no!
[glass shatters]
[Lucy gasps]
Here.
- What the...
- Look.
We gotta go, okay?
- What?
[Jose] Come on.
[tense music]
♪
- I'm so sorry about Sarah.
Are you guys okay?
- Not really.
[Vicky] Has anybody
talked to her mom?
- [yawns] Um,
they're supposed to have
the service next week,
but I don't know.
It's pretty crazy out there.
- Did you guys
hit up the stores?
- Yeah.
[Vicky] Any luck?
[Lisa] Well, we have this
water here if you want some.
[ominous music]
- You need anything else?
- Go home, Trent.
- Oh, last time I
checked the chairs,
they were real rickety.
Mm, oh, but sometimes
I put too much oil.
Oh, and it gets messy.
- Just go home!
- I, uh, I'll come back later
for the lawn money.
- Fuck.
- How would he know
about the chairs?
- Wait, is that all you have?
- Afraid so.
- Maybe we should
think about rationing.
- With food, you ration.
With water, you're supposed
to drink it if you have it.
Once dehydration sets in...
- She's right.
- Well, did you guys hit up all
the stores on the west side?
- Haven't you heard?
I mean, the whole
city's tapped out.
[Jose] Shit.
Well, what about
filters or Gatorade?
- Gone.
- What about Briar Creek?
The water doesn't go
to the treatment plant.
Maybe we can use
those filter straws
that we use when we go camping.
- Yeah, we could boil
it if we have to.
Do you guys have gas?
- Probably enough to
get there and back.
[Jose] Let's take your car,
and hopefully ours will
still have some left.
- Sure.
- Lisa, will you stay with Lucy?
Vicky, come with me.
[Lisa] Why can't I go?
- I just...
It would just mean a lot if
you'd stay and look after her.
- Why? What's wrong?
She looks fine to me.
- Should we tell them?
- Yeah, sure, um.
[clears throat]
I'm pregnant.
- What?
[Lucy] Yeah.
[Vicky] Are you serious?
- Congratulations.
- Oh, big brother!
[Vicky laughs]
- Okay, all right.
We should go before
it gets dark, um.
Yeah.
You guys just take
it easy, all right?
Fuck.
[ominous music]
♪
[footsteps]
[Jose sighs]
[leaves rattling]
- Wait, wait.
What was that?
I heard something.
- I don't hear anything.
Come on.
[sighs]
Okay, yeah.
It's just up here.
[Lisa] Over there?
[jarring music]
[gun cocks]
[Jose yelps]
[Man] Private property.
- It's a public park.
Ah!
[Man] Not anymore.
- Okay, okay.
[Reporter] Officials are
warning that there are
no remedies that can block
methamphetamine ingestion.
This after numerous residents
have been admitted to hospital
after drinking a combination
of canola oil and mouthwash,
a remedy that has
been making the rounds
on Controversial
Conspiracy Network.
- So?
[Jose] No.
- What? Are you okay?
- What happened?
[Jose] Somebody
else got there first.
Thanks.
- Any word on how
long this will last?
- They said it could take a week
to fully clean out the system.
Maybe longer.
[Jose] What about more
bottled water or filters?
- We just saw a truck on
the news being hijacked.
It's literally chaos out there.
- Okay, so, we stay put
until this whole
thing blows over.
If we're not gonna ration this,
let's at least take it easy
so we don't drink more water
than we normally would.
- Okay, what about food?
- Well...
We should probably minimize
our food intake too.
- He's right.
Digestion requires
a lot of water.
- So, this is it then?
[Jose] Yeah.
[ominous music]
[Reporter] Consult a doctor
if your medication...
[ominous music]
[jarring music]
- Hey, where's Vic?
- She's in the office.
Did you get any sleep?
- [sighs] Nah.
- Did someone put this
in another container?
- What's that?
- Oh, shit.
[Jose] This you?
- No.
I only had the one glass
you gave us last night.
[mysterious music]
- Jesus.
[Jose] Did you drink this?
- Do you see a
glass anywhere here?
[Jose] It was you?
- What was me?
[Jose] You drank
this whole jug?
- No, I didn't.
[Jose] I know you need
more water for the baby,
but you couldn't have
just saved a little bit?
- What the hell are
you talking about?
- Thanks for sharing.
[door slams]
[Lucy] Jose!
[Reporter] Declared a state
of emergency in Knox County.
Citing the dire need
for drinkable water
that has led to rioting
in distribution centers
and blockades.
[Jose] What the fuck
are you doing?
- Oh, it's getting there.
It's getting there.
Ah!
You know, there's all these
little screws in there.
[Jose] Get out, Trent!
- Okay, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Heard some of them...
Need bolts, you see?
[Trent laughs]
[Jose] Get out!
- Fine, fine.
Uh...
That's 300.
[Jose] 300?
Well, first there was the lawn.
And if you had a
handyman back here...
[grunts]
We would definitely
charge you more.
My mom used to have
this guy come around
that would fix the sink,
and he used have these little
teeny, tiny little cars,
and I used to just...
[mock car revs]
- I'm not paying you $300,
I didn't ask for
any of this shit.
Get out!
- No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
- Get out!
Come on, let's go.
[Trent] You lied to me!
You owe me!
- Go, Trent, go!
- You owe me!
Hey, hey, hey!
I want my money!
- Go, go!
[tense music]
[sighs]
Here.
- Don't you want it?
[Jose] No,
I was wrong.
You need a lot more than I do.
- You haven't had anything
to drink since last night.
- That's okay, I'll
figure something out.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
[single piano key plays]
[pee trickles]
[exhales]
[single piano key plays]
[grunts]
[heavy breaths]
[gags]
[grunts]
[coughs]
[ominous music]
[Reporter] The governor
is contemplating
sending in the National Guard
to assist in the deployment
of bottled water and gasoline.
[ominous chaotic music]
♪
[sharp inhale]
[water trickling]
[knocking]
[Jose] Luce, you
almost done in there?
- Yeah, I'll be right out.
[Jose] You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Luce?
Why is there a wet
glass in there?
[Lucy] Look...
[Jose] You wouldn't.
- I had to.
I'm so thirsty.
- Are you...
Jesus!
What about the baby?
[Vicky] Don't yell at her.
- This doesn't concern you!
- I'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry.
- I'm not gonna be
treated like this!
You hear me?
[glass shatters]
[women screaming]
- What the fuck?
[Trent yells]
Stop it!
[intense music]
[Trent groans]
[punches smacking]
[tense music]
♪
[Jose yells]
[wind blowing]
[computer keys clacking]
- Oh shit.
Yes.
Guys...
Guys, pack everything.
I got it. I got it!
- Got what?
- Look.
Luce!
Come check this out.
So that's a standalone pond on
a rental property, all right?
The owners are in Colorado,
they're not even there.
It's only 40 minutes away,
I think we got enough
gas to make it.
Just pack everything
you can, okay?
Lucy! Hey.
I found a lake.
We're gonna go, okay?
- What? No.
I don't think I can make it.
- What are you talking about?
- I don't think I
can do the car ride
with all those bumps and plus,
I don't wanna be around
you when you're like this.
- What is "this"?
What are you talking about?
Luce, look at me.
I don't know how much
longer we can go without
you and the baby
having clean water.
All right.
And besides, Trent.
You think he's gonna
let last night slide?
Trust me, we gotta go.
Okay?
I'm gonna get some stuff,
you do the same.
All right?
It's gonna be all right.
[ominous music]
[car beeps]
[Vicky] Should we have
brought more food?
- I don't know, I...
[Jose yells]
Oh my...
God!
- Just go!
Would you just go?
Drive!
Go! Drive!
Just go!
[tires screeching]
[intense music]
[ominous music]
♪
- I'm gonna grab something
from the car, okay?
- Okay.
[ominous music]
[water boils]
[Jose] There's a
little more soup, Luce.
- I'm good.
- I'll have some.
Thanks.
[Jose] Yeah.
- Doesn't this look
like Uncle Jorge's spot?
- I never went to Jorge's.
- No?
- No, you must have gone
when I was up here with mom.
- Oh, yeah.
- Think I'm gonna turn in.
- Yeah.
Yeah, me too.
[Lucy] How do you
open this thing?
- Remember when you showed
me where all the
constellations are?
I still can't even find
Cassiopeia on my own
without somebody
showing it to me.
You're gonna be an aunt.
- I know.
- I know you've
always wanted that.
I know you love kids.
Is this how it's gonna be?
Look...
I know that you hate me,
and I don't expect
you to forgive me.
I don't.
I just...
Can we just put this on hold
till we get through
whatever this is?
Please.
[wind whooshing]
[crickets chirp]
[ominous music]
♪
- Hey.
- Good morning.
How'd you sleep?
- Like a rock.
- Is my brother still down?
- Yeah.
- Thank God.
He needs it.
- Want some?
- Yes, please.
[tense music]
- Hey, um...
Do you think, um...
Nevermind.
- No, what?
Come on.
- Do you think
he'll be a good dad?
[Vicky] What do you mean?
Of course he would.
Why would you say that?
- I don't know.
You saw what he
did the other day.
I didn't think he was
still capable of that.
- I mean, to be fair,
it wasn't for no reason.
The guy barged into his house
with his pregnant wife
right there.
I think he just
wants to protect you.
- I don't need protecting.
- I know.
Look, this will all pass.
We'll go back to our boring,
normal lives,
and you guys will be fine.
Trust me.
- Right.
[tense music]
[catydids chirping]
[women chattering]
[women laughing and chattering]
[women laughing]
- Oh my gosh.
[Vicky] Good morning.
- Hey.
What time is it?
[Lisa] Like a quarter to six.
[Vicky] You almost
did a whole 24 hours.
[Jose grunts]
- I feel like I
could do 24 more.
[Lisa chuckles]
- You want some chili?
- Oh, yeah, absolutely.
- Have you guys thought
of any baby names?
- Oh, yeah.
I got a ton of 'em.
Like if it's a boy-
- I don't think we should get
so far ahead of ourselves.
- Why not?
- I don't know.
I mean, we just found out.
I haven't even
seen a doctor yet.
- Well, we could still
get their input, right?
- Well, what about Strum?
[Vicky laughs]
What? It's totally
gender neutral.
- Strum?
[Vicky laughs]
- You mean like a guitar?
Like Strum?
- Kinda.
I was thinking more
as like a tribute
to Joe Strummer, but...
- [scoffs] Who?
- Look, I'm not
naming my baby Strum.
[Lucy laughs]
- Oh, yeah.
No, yeah, you're right.
Yeah, maybe.
[Vicky chuckles]
- Let's just wait until we
get to the 12-week mark
to have this conversation,
please.
[Vicky] Oh, come on.
- No, she's right.
We can, we can wait.
Wait, shh.
Do you guys hear that?
- What?
I don't hear anything.
- Exactly.
- Jesus.
- You scared the shit outta me.
- He always does that.
[Jose laughs]
- Okay.
[Jose chuckles]
Please go back to the tent now.
[girls laughing]
- If you want.
- Make your exit, please.
- Strum though, right?
I'm gonna write that down.
[Lucy] Don't, please...
[Jose] Strum, Twang.
[tinnitus rings]
[ominous music]
[tempo quickens]
♪
[gun fires]
- Listen up!
- Hope y'all got some free
water in while you can.
From here on out,
you want some of this water?
You come see us for payment.
- And don't worry,
we ain't gonna shoot no one.
Not unless you make us.
- No credit cards, no checks.
This is cash only.
- Well, if you ain't
got no cash,
don't worry.
I'm sure we can
figure something out.
- Carry on.
Oh, look who it is.
What, no 2x4 this time?
- You son of a...
[gun cocks]
- Yeah, go on!
Give me another reason!
No friends and family
discounts, I'm afraid.
[tense music]
Unless...
Pretty sister of yours here?
Well, how about your wife?
Maybe we can give
her the discount too.
[tense music]
[Tom laughs]
Yes, sir.
You wanna fill that jug up?
[Man] Yeah.
[Dom] $30.
- We gotta get the fuck
outta here.
- How are we gonna go?
We don't even have any gas.
- Where are we going?
- I don't know,
but I think it's about
to get real fucked up.
[tense music]
[water trickling]
♪
[Dom] Mm, hey, Vic.
- Get off of me.
- Oh, come on,
don't be like that.
- Let me go!
- Whoa.
- You don't gotta
make a scene about it.
- I know what you did.
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
- My brother told me about
the bruises on Sarah's face.
You're a piece of shit,
you know that?
- Come on, Vic.
You don't gotta be like that.
If you get thirsty,
just come to me.
I can hook you up.
If you, you know...
Help me quench my thirst.
- Get your fuckin'
hands off her.
- Hey!
Hey, hey!
[tense music]
[smack]
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
[tense music]
- What's going on over there?
[Vicky] He has a can of gas.
- Who does?
[Vicky] Dom, under the table.
[Lisa] A lot of
good it does us.
- I think I know how
we can distract them
so that Jose can grab
the can, fill the tank,
and put it back
before they notice.
[Lucy] You think
that'll be enough gas
to get us out of the county?
- No, probably not.
We need another can or two
to get us to Haliburton.
- The Paige River?
- Yeah.
- Okay, so then, how
do we get the rest?
[tense music]
[zipper sliding]
[ominous music]
♪
[spits]
[coughs]
- Fuck.
[puking]
Hope this works.
Are you ready?
- It's worth a shot.
Hey, Dom.
Can I have some water for us?
- Do you have a change of heart?
- Well...
[Jose coughs]
- That's fair.
- All right.
- You're on watch.
[ominous music]
- I can't let you do this.
- Honey, the girls
are in the tent.
We don't have any other
options right now.
[Jose gags]
- Just gimme the knife.
- Okay.
[Jose grunts]
- Why, hello, beautiful.
What can I do for you?
- I'm thirsty.
- Oh, yeah?
[tense ominous music]
On your knees.
Don't worry, I'll get to them.
[Tom yells]
[gun fires]
[gasping]
[thud]
[Dom] What the fuck?
[gun cocks]
- Let's go.
- Come on! Let's go!
[tense music]
- Come on!
- Get up! Come on!
Go, go, go!
Fuck!
What the fuck happened?
- I don't know!
[Lisa] Oh my God.
[Jose] Go, go, go, go, go!
Did you shoot him?
What the fuck!
[Lucy] I don't know.
[Jose] You don't know?
[Lucy] Well, yeah,
I fucking shot him
in the fucking neck.
[haunting vocal music]
♪
[heavy breathing]
[jarring music]
[haunting music]
♪
[Jose screams]
[water trickling]
[ominous music]
♪