Get down here!
Why are you shouting at me?!
I am not deaf!
There you go. All fixed!
Don't go too far, okay? Take care.
- Okay. Thank you.
- I'll just fix the lights.
Put this in place. Take care, okay?
Go ahead.
You're not deaf?! I've been calling you!
What is it, my king?
What do you need, my grace?
- Are you hungry?
- Belen, watch your mouth!
Do I need to wash your ass?!
Do you want me to feed you?!
Stop it!
Are you trying to fool me around?!
Ouch! Let me go!
- Let go of me!
- What are you trying to prove here?!
Mama! Mama!
Mama! Look!
- I can do it!
- Oh yes.
But I told you to go slow.
You might get scratched.
- Where's your dad?
- He's inside.
Fixing the lights.
Good.
Mr. Waldo and Ms. Belen are fighting again.
- Enough!
- I will kill you!
Go ahead. Hurry up.
You look filthy.
*voices fighting'
He'll me!
Help!
Help me! Help!
- Mama! Mama!
- Please!
What's happening?!
It's Ms. Belen!
Stay there! Don't go down! Stay there!
What is it?!
- It's Belen and Waldo!
- What's happening?!
Belen! Oh My! Belen.
What happened to you?!
Don't worry. We'll take care of you.
- We'll ask for help.
- Belen!
Somebody help! Help us! Neighbors!
No please!
Please. Don't do this to Belen!
No!
Have pity!
Please! No!
Ms. Belen?
Papa?
Mama?
Mama...
Papa...
I'
'Mylene!
- Mylene! Mylene!
- Grandma!
- Mylene, what's happening?!
- Papa! Papa!
- Mylene.
Stop. Stop. Stop crying-
You're just having a nightmare.
You're just dreaming.
I should've helped her.
I should've let her in!
It wouldn't have happened to mom and dad!
Don't cry. Don't cry. Don't cry.
Mama!
Papa!
Mylene.
Close your eyes.
Our Father, who art in heaven
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. Amen.
Mylene, open your eyes.
Do you see nothing now?
They're gone!
I don't see them anymore!
You may not see them now, Mylene,
but there will come a time,
especially when you're
going through tough times,
your eyes will open once again.
And you will see more.
Not only ghosts, not only spirits.
The world will not always be as you see it.
And sometimes,
sometimes, you will get hurt.
But when those times come,
I want you to be strong,
be brave!
And always remember,
you should always do what is right.
Mylene...
Are you okay?
I just miss her.
I never told you
I see ghosts when I was a kid.
Really?
But grandma closed my “third eye...
Right now,
I wish, even for just a while,
I could see them again.
I might see her again.
Maybe you're already late.
Old people say
the spirit of the dead goes to
heaven after forty days.
I feel so alone right now.
Hey.
I'm here.
You're all I have now, Jimmy.
Please promise me, you won't ever leave me.
Oh My. Ervic is so stubborn.
He let himself suffer of not seeing anything.
Ask your husband when does
he like to visit the clinic?
When he's already blind?
Wait. It's Jimmy. He's already outside.
- Thanks, doc.
- Thanks, Linda, bye.
Hello, Jimmy, where are you now?
Sorry, I won't be able to pick you up.
What?
I didn't bring a car today.
You said you're going to fetch me.
I'm really sorry. Boss just called me up.
I'm not sure what time will I finish.
Never mind, never mind.
I'll just take a cab. I'll see you at home.
Bye.
I just don't want you calling me!
Especially at this time!
Fine. Tomorrow.
I'll take care of it.
Come on!
I'll see you tomorrow.
I said yes.
Okay. Okay.
You're naughty!
I promise myself I won't attend to that reunion
'til I lose thirty pounds!
I thought you already moved on?
I thought you're so over Lloyd.
I want him to choke on regretting
when he sees how sexy I am!
All these hassles for a cheater like him?!
Let me do my thing, girl.
Oh My. That guy is so slow!
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm okay.
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Have you asked Randy?
About Aunt Agnes' birthday.
Yes.
Do you want to buy gift
after dinner tomorrow?
Okay-
Okay, good night.
Mister!
Can you open this?
- Is Mylene here?
- She's inside.
Are you sure you really don't want coffee?
No, thanks. My heart might palpitate.
I thought you're going straight to aunt Agnes.
We finished early at the seminar
that's why I went straight here instead and
I really need to tell you something.
Where's Jimmy?
He's upstairs. Why do you ask?
You said you really wanted
to talk to me about something.
I need you to hear this sitting down.
Mylene, I don't know what I saw but
I was in Quezon City last week,
Please don't put me into this situation!
It'll look like it's my fault!
I'll call you back.
- Are you hungry?
- Yes.
I'm not sure what I saw.
She could be a friend,
a relative or a long lost friend.
But I feel like it's my duty
to tell you as my friend.
These past few weeks,
he's been out with somebody I don't know.
Sometimes, I see him talking to his phone.
And he doesn't want me to hear it.
He's been hiding a lot of things from me lately.
Do you think Jimmy is cheating on you?
You said the woman's pregnant?
Yes.
Look, Mylene,
It's not a reason that you can't give him
a child for him to cheat on you.
You can adopt. There are lots of ways.
But Mylene, you have to set things straight.
Hey, Ryza.
Are you guys going somewhere?
Yes, later.
You want coffee?
No, thanks. I need to go.
Wait. You said you're coming to
aunt Agnes' birthday dinner.
I forgot to tell you.
There's an emergency with our project in Rizal.
I have to go check it.
And I have to stay overnight.
Just greet aunt Agnes for me, okay?
EmergenEY?
What kind of an emergency?
Our contractor has a problem
with the subdivision.
What exactly is the problem
with your contractor?
Since when did you get interested with
my real estate problems?
You're my husband.
I believe it's pan of my job to know.
What's your problem?!
Excuse me. I'll just go to the powder room.
Look.
I know I promised to go to aunt Agnes.
If that's why you're upset.
Are you having an affair?
What?!
Hey, Mylene. What is this all about?!
I asked you a straight question.
Are you having an affair?
Is that what Ryza told you?!
What did she tell you?!
This is not about her! So answer me!
Mylene, you are being paranoid!
Why is that?
Because you can't tell me the truth!
Because you know you're cheating on me?!
I have to go.
Boy! Open the gate!
Where's Mylene?
She went rushing out. She used your car.
What?!
Mylene! Mylene!
Oh no!
What's her problem, man?!
I'm already here outside.
Doc, do you believe that the eyes
are the windows to the soul?
Look straight please.
Well, Mr. Trinidad. All your tests show that
there's really nothing wrong with your eyes.
Really?
How many consultations have you had already?
Three, four times?
If you want me to refer you
to another specialist, I can.
Okay-
I have a confession to make.
Mr. Trinidad, I am not a priest.
I have other patients waiting.
And they have real eye problems.
Sorry.
- I'll go.
- Don't bother paying for the consultation.
No. I insist.
Instead of coming over
and over again in my clinic,
you would save money,
if you invite me out, Mr. Trinidad.
Let's do it together.
Delicious!
Your tum.
Thank you.
- Thank you, doc.
- You're welcome.
Promise, doc, we'll take care
of our new eyeglasses.
Okay. But not only the eyeglasses,
you should also take care of your eyesight.
- You should all eat...
-vegetables, carrots, squash.
Very good!
Jimmy, I know it's you.
Where have you been?
Why are you all dressed up?
Oh no. Wrong! You're mixed up!
I've never thought of the day
I'd be ready to do this
But I don't know what to do
for the rest of my life
without you.
I will take care of you.
You and our future child.
I want to start a family with you.
Hey, the kids have been
waiting for you outside.
I was able to talk to Dr. Santiago.
I won't be able to give you a child.
I'm so sorry, Jimmy.
I'm so sorry.
They said the paint still smells upstairs.
We can stay downstairs for the mean time.
You've been quiet.
Is there a problem?
Nothing.
Tum left, sir.
You will see a sign. It'll lead you to the highway.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Are you mad?
Did I say anything wrong?
You're not - You're not the only one
who has a problem!
People are asking me about my situation!
I don't want to explain anymore!
I'm done lying, Jimmy!
Janet!
I'm going back to Manila when it's my due.
Mylene, confronted me.
She asked me if I'm having an affair.
What did you tell her?
Are we still on the right way?
I don't know. Have you seen any sign?
I didn't see one.
Shm
We shouldn't have gone out today.
Fine!
This is all my fault!
Janet, please!
We're lost!
Don't make this about yourself!
That's the problem!
It's never about myself to you!
I don't want to go back to Manila!
I don't want to go back!
Finally, you admit it!
You didn't even think about the baby?!
Janet, your doctor is there!
What if complications occur
when you give birth?!
Even for once,
could you be a little bit concern about me?
And not all about the baby?!
We talked clearly about this.
You said before, we were just having fun.
Nothing serious.
Janet, I didn't want you to get pregnant!
But what am I suppose to do?!
It's already there!
As if I'll abandon my baby!
Stop the car!
Janet!
Stop! Stop!
Are you okay?
Miss. Good afternoon!
Good afternoon.
We'd just like to ask
for a direction to the highway?
Looks like you're lost.
Who's that with you?
My wife.
She looks like she's going to give birth soon.
Miss. How are we going out of here?
You're too far.
If you want, I could go with you
back to where you're from.
No, thank you.
We'll just go back instead.
Sorry for bothering you.
Jimmy! Jimmy!
Jimmy!
Hello?
Someone there?!
Somebody home?
Somebody home?!
Wait!
Boy?
I'm Mylene. I need help.
Don't be afraid of me please.
I won't hurt you.
What's your name?
Who lives with you here?
Are your parents here?
Will they come back home soon?
I wanted to call the police but
I don't know how to get out of here.
Ram Ram!
Who are you?
Ma'am, sorry for bothering you. I just need your help.
It's my husband. I need to call the -
She's looking for the police.
Get inside.
You wanted to call the police?
I don't know the way out.
- That's why I asked for help.
- Where are you from?
They closed the main highway.
Then I got lost.
He'll me!
Help!
Where do you think you're going?!
Let me go!
Help!
What did you do to Jimmy!
Come here!
Help!
Jimmy?!
Susan!
Where are you going?
I just found a good offering for Cenon.
But someone got in.
She saw what I did.
Come on. Hurry.
What are you doing here?
I followed you when you left.
We have to get out of here!
Janet?
- Where's Janet?
- Jimmy, you're hurt. I have to get you out of here!
They've taken Janet with them.
That woman took Janet with her!
I need your wife and your child.
She's pregnant with your child?
I'm so sorry, Mylene.
I didn't know how to tell you.
I didn't want to hurt you.
I'm sorry.
Mylene, I love you.
I made a mistake.
You really want me to believe that you
didn't intend to get her pregnant?!
You shouldn't have come here.
Well, it's too late for that now!
We have to get out of here.
What about Janet?
Jimmy, you need to go to the hospital.
You lost a lot of blood!
I can't leave her alone.
I can't leave her and my child alone.
We'll call the police when we get out of here!
We'll ask for their help!
They can do something about this!
She took the guy with her!
They'll have a hard time getting out of here.
Go now! Go after them!
I have to get home. I have to
start offering the pregnant one!
Remember this.
The woman should die first.
When her heartbeat stops,
that's when you take the child
for the thanksgiving offering!
We have to find the way back to my car.
Your car's networking.
You go, Mylene. I'll go after that woman!
Jimmy! Obviously, they're killers!
You're hurt! What can you do?!
Didn't you hear?! They're going to kill them!
Forgive me, Mylene. You have to go.
I have to do this! Save yourself.
Call the police.
Jimmy!
I'll go with you!
You don't have to do this!
I have to! You don't know
what you're getting into!
I was able to get inside their house.
I already saw the couple and their son!
Wait!
Are you sure this is the way back?
This is the only way to the house.
You said you saw a guy.
Yes.
He was there
when you guys were taken.
- The guy?
- What is it?
I didn't see a guy.
I saw them earlier.
Who?
Is somebody there?
I saw them at the car accident.
Mylene?
Myleneg
Mylene, what is it?
Let's go, Jimmy.
That's the house.
Are you okay?
Mylene --
Be careful.
He'll me!
Jimmy, wait! Jimmy!
I have to help Janet!
I'll go inside.
What?!
Wait for me here.
Take care of yourself.
Please. Don't hurt my baby. Please!
Please! My baby!
'Prayer offering*
*woman shrieking*
You're just a spirit!
You can't do anything to me!
Leave me alone!
Blood of two souls, I offer to you.
Blood of two souls...
Come with me. Give me a hand.
Get the goat.
Soon, Cenon.
You will soon come back.
One life's blood with two souls,
with two beating hearts.
Come. Follow me.
You're Jimmy's wife.
This isn't the time to introduce each other.
We need to get out of here.
Where's Jimmy?
He's badly hurt.
I have no choice but to help him save you.
But I don't intend to die saving you.
We have to move now!
*Prayer offering'
Bring back our beloved Cenon.
To our powerful ancestors,
who gives life in return for our offer.
Bring back our beloved Cenon!
Bring him back to us!
Bring him back to us.
Soul, blood and life.
Soul, blood and life!
Ram Ram, Ram Ram...
Do you still remember me?
I told you I need help.
You have the nerve!
Go ahead! Come near!
Let's see if your husband's going to
live if I smash his head with this!
Hurry!
Jimmy!
- Jimmy!
- Jimmy.
Mylene...
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I love you.
I...
Jimmy, don't do this to me please.
For our child...
Janet.
- I'm so sorry.
- No!
Jimmy!
- Jimmy!
-Jimmy!
Jimmy!
Once the mother of the child dies,
you will be whole again.
You will have your soul back
to your body.
Follow them.
They can't leave.
I've been wanting to tell you.
I want to blame you!
I want to yell at you!
I want to hurt you!
We're in this nightmare because of you!
My husband's dead because of you!
I'm sorry.
I saw a woman earlier.
She was peeking inside your house.
She's probably the one
Susan was talking about.
What if that woman
comes back with the police?
I've been worrying about that.
That's the only way
I know back to the car.
You take care of the charcoals.
Okay-
I have to go get Lydia
from the riverside.
Please.
Please don't hurt me.
Help us escape. Please.
Please. Please.
Please.
Don't worry.
Your father will bring me back.
Just like what we did to both of you.
We will see each other again.
Someone might be there.
Let's ask for help!
I have this bad feeling about this place.
I won't make it, Mylene!
Let's go there.
Come. Looks like no one's home
Mylene.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want this to happen.
Is he planning to leave me?
I know he loves you.
He's not leaving you.
I didn't know what he felt about me.
What I know is he loves our child.
I can't take it anymore, Mylene!
I can't!
You can do it!
You can do it, Janet! Push!
We have to go to Susan
to witness the offering.
Louder!
We just came from Susan.
She's gone. She's dead!
The pregnant woman's inside.
She was taken by that woman
I was telling you about.
Call the others.
There are people outside.
They're with the woman who took you.
You're almost done! Push!
One, two, three, push!
It's coming!
The three of you!
Guard the back!
You! Stay around the house!
Hurry! Here!
Break the door!
Hurry!
Tear it down!
Mylene.
Please. Save my baby.
Go.
Janet, I need your help.
Where's the other one?!
Don't open the door!
Where's the baby?
Don't come near me!
Stay away!
Don't open the door!
She got out!
She's here! Hurry!
Follow me!
Run after her! Hurry!
Hurry! Hurry!
You can't do anything to me.
You're just a spirit.
Stop this!
Leave me alone!
I'm not afraid of you.
Please don't!
Canon!
- Cenon's alive!
- Cenon's finally alive!
It's him!
He's alive!
Hurry!
Hurry! Hurry! Go!
Go! Hurry! Get her!
Come in, come in, HQ.
This is HQ, where are you?
We're at the town of Sungayan.
We're here with the complainant.
I think what they're saying about
the cannibal tribe is actually true.
Okay. We'll be there.
Over and out.
Ma'am, they're gone.
Is this what you're talking about?
Okay, we'll take this as an evidence.
Now, where are we going
to find a place to stay?
In Quezon, Alodia's daughter is there.
This is so heavy.
I'm hungry.
Are we still travelling far?
I think so.
Are you hungry?
Put it at the back.
- Here.
- Thank you so much.
- That's already big. Are you due this month?
- Yes, actually.
My child, I'm really thirsty.
Can I have something to drink?
Sure. Come inside.
- Let's go.
- Hurry! Go!
You know what?
You have your daddy's eyes.
Stay away from us!
There's nothing you can do!
Leave me alone!