- Flowers!
- Yay!
Thank you. They're
beautiful, baby. Thank you.
- Yeah, you like it?
- Yeah.
Did you pack?
- Mm...
- Oh, come on, I left a note.
Oh, yeah, yeah,
I saw the note, Carl.
Uh...
"Pack the cooler, pick out
a cute outfit for the road,
and, hey, sneak in a winter jog
if you feel like it."
The last part pissed me off,
so I didn't do anything.
It was a josh!
I'm really excited about
this weekend.
Oh, God, don't.
You have bad breath.
Disgusting.
Super excited.
Gonna give it to her this
weekend at a bed & breakfast.
- Congratulations, by the way.
- Thanks. Actually, we're
We just were so broke back then
we couldn't afford the rings.
I see. So, you had a cash bar
at the wedding and shit?
Are you crazy?
After 10, yeah.
- Yeah.
Dad! Fuck, please,
I'm with a client here.
It looks very bad.
Get in the back, please.
I'm sorry.
- No...
- When they get older,
He's like a little vegetable
with glasses.
Ugh!
Unh! Hey, have you guys heard
anything about
the design position?
Yes! You didn't get it.
They read
the part on your resume
that says you're retarded.
- Ah.
- But I did hear that
- at E Arts in Vancouver.
- Here we go.
Robyn Leffurn, yes.
How is that boner machine?
- What?
You know what
a boner machine is, right?
- No.
- Oh. It's a machine that makes
So, five years later and we're
still hearing about your ex.
- Yeah, I'm aware.
- So, you excited
Yes, I'm so excited.
I'm... beyond.
Ah, I'm jealous.
My weekend plans consist of
trying to stop Doug
from eating wheat and sugar.
- Diet?
- It's a yeast infection.
We've been passing one back
and forth like a hot potato.
That's nice.
It's nice to share.
And with that,
I bid you adieu.
- Bye.
- You have fun.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I don't know.
Uh. Oh, now you're in for it.
Fabulous conducting.
- Why, thank you.
So, Ryan's
emailed me the ski route
to Sainte-Adle for the
It looks like it's gonna be
an awesome workout.
Oh, cool, 'cause all I wanna
do this weekend is exercise.
That he gave us the best room
in the B&B, the Lovers' Suite?
- That's what it's called?
- That's what it's called.
So, still no word yet
on the promotion.
Can you believe that?
- When are they gonna decide?
- They can't keep me
on the floor
forever. It's like...
on local cheeses
while we're here.
Local cheeses!
Let's get some cheese
up in this bitch.
Is there where you murder me
and stuff me in the trunk?
This is where we tear
each other's clothes off
and make passionate love
to each other.
- Oooh.
- Yeah.
All right, let me
just pee first.
Ah!
Hey!
Do we have any Kleenex?
Uh...
there's a paper bag
back here.
Ew!
I think I have a receipt
in my wallet.
- Hilarious.
- Ha! Ha! Ha! Hurry up!
How'd you know
this place was here?
Uh... all these vin...
these little vineyards have
hideaways like this.
Drip dry.
Ah!
Don't slam the door.
Why do you always slam the door?
That's a woman thing.
Oh, is the car gonna break,
Carl? Is it gonna break?
Here, take one of these.
Can you put the pumps on?
- Oh!
- I'm sorry.
Put 'em on, put 'em on,
put 'em on.
Mmm. Watch the seats. Here.
No, no, no.
I wanna keep it on.
No, I just got a really
not so great bikini wax.
Yeah, I don't care, I don't
care about the little bumps.
From behind.
- Ow!
- Ooh, uh, sorry. OK, ready?
Yeah.
Oh, God.
- 'K, let's come fast, OK?
Please don't take
like half an hour again.
OK.
Oh, God.
Oh, fuck. Shit, Sue.
Ah.
Oh, does it feel good?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, you fuckin' like that?
- Carl, shut up. Yes.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
You can do it, Carl.
Tell me how you were
waiting for me.
Uh, OK. Um...
So, you're on a skidoo,
and, uh, you come across me
in the forest,
a little ski bunny that needs
a big lollipop to suck.
Oh, hello.
Can I give you a ride?
Yeah, OK.
Um, I'm your wife's dumber
and hornier cousin from Italy.
Uh, me no speak-a no English.
- Oh, don't do that.
- Me no speak-a English.
- Why are you doing that?
Sorry. You wanna spray
my snowsuit?
Oh, yeah,
spray your face.
And, uh, luckily,
you put my hand on a language
everybody understands:
A big, hard, throbbing
American cock.
I'm sorry,
I just couldn't...
It's OK.
It's nice to get the feeling
back in my legs.
This is adorable!
- Yeah, you like it?
- Yeah. Eee!
- Head on in,
I'll get the bags.
- Thank God for my sweater.
Yeah, bitch.
The one thing I won't renovate
is the Lovers' Suite.
I mean, you'll see.
It has so much charm,
- it's like going back in time.
- Cool, cool.
So, should I take the stairs,
or my DeLorean to get there?
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
What the hell are you
doing here?
What's the deal?
You guys know each other?
Yeah, uh... Yeah, uh,
Robyn used to be my boss.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Wait. Robyn?
I thought... Robyn?
I thought your name was Ryan.
Whoa. You're Ryan?
You're the Ryan I've
I can't believe
that you're the Carl.
I mean, you are an excellent
speller, by the way.
Well, jeez, come here.
I mean, it's
amazing to see you. It's, uh...
- Yeah.
Hi, I'm Sue,
this man's wife.
- Yes, wife, her.
Yeah.
Hi.
- You are stunning.
- Oh.
- I mean, really.
You walked through the door,
and I was like,
"Wow. Am I working
at a supermodel agency?"
Oh, my God. Thank you.
Can we rewind
real quick?
Why are you
calling yourself Ryan?
That's really embarrassing.
Um, I guess that it's
just all part of the new me,
along with simple problems
like fixing broken
drainage pipes and making beds.
I don't...
I don't get it.
I bought this place.
You what?
What about Vancouver?
Your job? Did I hear you quit?
- Ah, I just needed a break.
I mean, the plan is
to give this lodge a facelift
and then give it to my parents
as a retirement gift.
- Wow, that's amazing of you.
- I have no idea
what I'm doing.
Like, I am learning,
one hammered thumb at a time.
- So, what,
it's been like five years
last October?
I think, I think.
- Oh, uh,
or something like that.
- Yeah. You look great.
Oh, my God.
I'm totally breaking out.
I mean, flashback to grade 10
yearbook photo. Mortified.
Let me get the room key.
Shit. This is work.
It's a file error.
- Sounds interesting.
- I'll help Susan with the bags.
It's Sue. Sue.
Haven't changed my name yet.
Hmm.
Hey.
Is here, at the fucking lodge
we're staying at!
What the fuck?!
Oh, my God, what?!
Excuse me, lady,
what occurred here?
Is this turning you on? Should
I call the wet police? What?
Carl, where are you?
I'm in the Laurentians.
I don't know. I'm at, uh,
just some area here.
Oh, my God, Carl.
- Stacey, just... just stop.
- No. No!
No, no, no, no, no.
I can explain this, OK?
Consider this your cold
shower, Your Horniness.
What is she
doing there anyway?
With the owner, and the owner
turns out to be her.
She bought a ski lodge? What?
- I mean, of all the ski lodges,
why the fuck
would she buy this one?
Ask you the same question.
Why? Why, out of the all the ski
- Take Sue where?
- Doug, you gotta shut up.
No, you better
shut your fuckin' mouth.
Perfect lately, and...
and I just thought
that this might spark something
for us, you know?
Apply this.
- Aha, OK.
But so we're clear,
it was your oven
that leavened my bread.
- Carl?
- Yeah, what was I saying?
- [Um, something about
to a ski lodge that was
your romantic getaway
with another woman.
- What?!
We should leave. I should
cancel the trip, shouldn't I?
What are you gonna tell her?
You get back in there,
you have the weekend
you planned, because that is
all you can do, Carl.
Just answer your phone.
: Hi.
Hey. What do you think?
- I love it.
- Yeah, it's great, right?
- Is everything good at work?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I sorted out the, uh,
file error.
The reception sucks
up here, though.
Isn't this place cute,
Carlito's Way?
Answer: Yes.
Hey, uh, you're not gonna
believe this. I forgot my boots.
- You're kidding me.
- It's all these heels
you made me bring,
you fuckin' perv.
Shit. We'll just go into town
tomorrow and we'll get you
Um, hey, do you want to go
into town tonight maybe?
And get dinner?
Really? You've been talking
about this place's
confit de canard all week.
Well, I don't know.
I don't wanna get
back in the car, babe.
It's dark and we don't know
where we're going.
Hey, uh, what...
what... what was your deal
down there?
Why were you acting so weird?
- Is this shirt...
is this too urban?
What do you think?
Would you just stand still
for a second? What's your deal
with Ryan - Robyn?
What is that?
- Oh. Uh... yeah.
Well, full disclosure:
We used to date.
...inanimate
objects. I...
Robyn dated you?
The tone seems
like you're shocked.
Well, how long
did you guys go out for?
I don't know. Honestly, I don't
really remember.
I was mostly just shocked
at how much she's aged.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
She's beautiful.
I... I can't imagine
what she looked like before
if she's aged.
She's OK. She's not, uh...
ho-ho-ho!
So, why have I never heard
of this person before?
Oh, no, I have definitely
mentioned her before. You
No. No, no.
You never mentioned her.
Well, it just never came up.
You know.
Younger people talk
about their exes. That's
So, I'm assuming
that you slept with her?
We were adults
at the time,
so yeah.
- Amazing.
But it was
totally forgettable.
I mean, she's just...
she's one of those pretty women
who doesn't know
how to be sexy.
And for the record, I had no
idea that I was emailing
She was signing her emails
"Ryan," which is just bizarre.
Who does that?
I don't know. Ryan.
All right, well...
- Well, hold on.
I mean, she must have known
that she was emailing
No, I used
my Hotmail account.
I use my Hotmail account
when I book to avoid spam.
This is weird.
We should... we should
change lodges.
No, it's nobody's fault.
I understand.
It must be
super weird running into her.
- I want you to be comfortable.
- No, I... Yeah.
- I want you to be comfortable,
and I want this weekend
to be awesome.
- I'm fine if you are.
- Really?
- Yeah, yeah.
- You're amazing.
I know I am.
I am soooo cool.
You're not cool.
You're amazing. This sweater
does not make you cool.
All right, all right.
Get the door.
Just watch your head.
- Seriously, stop it.
- Feel the rhythm.
Stop making me laugh.
I will drop you, I swear to God.
- Bonjour.
- Bonsoir.
Bonsoir.
: What the fuck?
- What's up? Are you OK?
- Yeah, yeah.
No, no, no, no.
Are you staying here?
Oh, bonjour. Je suis Sue.
- Lise Winters. Enchantée.
- Enchantée.
- Hi!
Hi! Mwah, mwah!
I'm Carl.
- Carl. This is Carl.
- Hey, how's it going?
Hey. Oh, hey. You too.
- Please, sit, sit. It would
- Really? Yeah?
- Ah, yes, join us.
OK. All right. Uh...
Carl's American,
hence the perfect accent.
Well, I wish I could
play music, but...
Babe, Anatolii is
an actor.
He's amazing.
I just saw that, uh,
that French film you did.
You were...
- Naked for most of it.
- That too.
- Ah, he was naked.
- I'll take the credit.
- Well done. Good body.
- Ha, ha. Well,
well, I'm already a fan
of your turtleneck,
so I'm sure... so I'm sure
I'd be a fan
of your work.
Do you guys have any, uh,
any plan for the weekend, or?
Oh, yes. We are
going on a vineyard tour.
A hard look at what activities
we both enjoy...
Sounds good.
Shut up. I love her.
- Oh, I adore her.
- I love her.
- Who is she?
Wow.
Well, it sounds compelling.
- Yeah, excellent.
- I like your pumps. I have
I have to pee! Sorry, I have
to get the pee out of my body.
Preferably in a toilet.
Um, upstairs, first door
on the left.
Fantastic.
All right, I'll be back.
: I'll
be back.
Let me clear
your plates.
- Hi. Tell me everything.
- She seems like she's doing
really great. She's still
the most annoying person
Is she still a boner machine?
But it's funny, I can
see why it didn't work out.
No... Babe, I can't
hear anything. What should I do?
I think you should shut the
fuck up while I'm doing yoga.
Carl?
I need you, OK? I need...
Wait a second, what?
...emergency.
- Huh? What do you mean
I gotta go.
Oh. Sorry.
Don't say you're sorry, man.
It's a sign of weakness.
Thanks for the tip.
Hello?
I call that
a perfect dismount,
no thanks to you
and your mouth.
What the fuck?
Oh, my God.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Ryan's gonna eat with us.
- Oh.
I... I don't want
to spoil your dinner.
No, you're not, you're not.
She's was gonna eat alone
I've run out of conversation
topics with the fridge
- Ah.
- Relax, Carl. Sit.
Yeah, yes.
Let's relax.
Mm, so, this is
a local cabernet,
and it goes best
with the entire bottle.
Would you like some?
- Oh, no thanks. I don't drink.
- OK.
- No, I'm good,
a question. Why does Anatolii
have a different accent
He's been working in France
since he was a teenager.
He's still a teenager.
- Jailbait.
- Word.
Gross. Both of you.
Very gross.
So... can you believe
that I'm sitting here with you
and your drop-dead-gorgeous
wife?
It's pretty surreal.
So, tell me,
how are things at work?
- Yeah, good.
- I mean,
you must be...
one of the top dogs
by now, no?
Well, you know,
there's a lot of, uh...
politics there, and we're not
really developing anything new.
Why... am I defending myself?
You're doing great, baby.
So, uh, so,
riddle me this:
What's your deal?
Are you single? Divorced?
Are you, uh...
Is there a Mr. Ryan
back in, uh, BC,
or what?
I am...
comically single.
So, you never settled down?
Well,
I recently made the mistake
of dating someone from work,
and when it started
to fizzle,
he started talking
about our private life
in front of everyone,
and completely humiliated me,
and ejaculated
all over my office.
- Are you serious?
- He masturbated
into a picture frame
and left it on my desk.
: Oh!
Romantic. Wow. I'm sorry.
That's terrible.
- Awful.
- Yeah.
I was never cut out
for a husband and kids.
I'm a loner.
Yeah, you're
like Julian Assange,
living out of a backpack
and changing the world, right?
- Who's Julian Assange again?
- Ah.
Twenty-four-year-olds get their
news from Perez Hilton, so...
Julian Assange is WikiLeaks.
He's the guy who...
Yeah, I know what it is, Carl.
I just forgot his name.
- You're cute.
- Fuck you.
Did you notice
that she didn't ask us
one single question
at that meal?
It was completely 100%
about her, like the whole time.
- I know.
- Yeah, yeah.
Unbelievable.
It seems like she has
a very interesting life.
Nobody's ever jacked off
into one of my picture frames.
I'll jack off
in your picture frame.
: Carl, get off.
I'll hit you.
- Uh, also,
what right does she have
to criticize me about my work?
It's like, I'm sorry, Ryan,
if I'm not as successful
- She's so skinny.
- Yeah.
Are you still
attracted to me?
Am I still
attracted to you?
Are you kidding me?
You're like perfect.
- I need to work out more.
- No, you don't.
What are you talking about?
I'm so attracted to you.
Look at me,
look at that.
We could camp under it.
Yeah.
- It's a cool cock, babe.
- Thanks.
- Cool.
- Well...
- Cool stuff.
Honk.
- Mm.
Honking a boner.
Doesn't quite work.
Yeah.
Hey, hey,
did you see this?
Have you seen this?
No, what am I looking at?
What is that?
We should
carve our names into it.
- No.
- Look, Sailor
- No, I don't like it.
- Why not? Come on.
It's like... it's like
defacing the place.
- Are you joking?
- No, I'm not joking.
You're such a wiener.
Who are you?
- I didn't bring a knife, hon.
- I'm sure we can find a knife.
No, it's cheesy. Mmm.
I'm tired. I'm just tired.
We haven't even christened
the room yet.
OK, I know, but I just feel
like one failed attempt
in one day is enough for me,
you know what I mean?
Is that OK?
- That was bitchy.
- Babe.
No, I didn't realize I was
vacationing with a cold fish.
Wow. Really?
I'm sorry,
I'm just disappointed.
You know what, if it was gonna
be fast, I'd be down,
but lately sex has become
such a production with you.
It's annoying that I always have
to recite that fantasy
in this baby porno voice.
- You don't have to dissect
our sex lives. OK, you like
specific shit too.
- Yeah, sure, I do, but...
- Yeah, I know you do!
- Yeah!
- Your tastes are very
repetitive. I feel
like I'm in a Broadway play
that's been running for 3 years.
- Bravo, babe.
Sometimes a woman just needs
to be fucked by her man,
so she feels
like he can't help it.
Preferably in under an hour.
I'm sorry
I'm so inadequate.
This is a good look.
Let's just watch some Conan
and go to bed.
Ha!
- Hey.
- Hi. Hey.
Hey.
Aw, geez Louise,
you look beautiful.
- I missed you.
- I missed you too.
And you lost
your dead grandma's sweater.
Thank you so much.
You're so sweet. I love them.
What do you love?
* Da-da-da ding, da-da-da-da
ding, ding ding-ding-a-ding *
Where'd you get those?
Am I interrupting
a make-out session?
No, no making out,
as far as I'm aware.
Tell me they fit.
Wait a sec,
you got these for me?
I mean, I had to go
into town anyway, so...
Wow.
How did you know
that she needed boots?
Oh, the rooms are bugged.
: I'm just kidding.
Sue told me last night.
- I can't believe
you did that. That's, like,
the sweetest thing ever.
Prego, grazie, it's not-a
big-a deal.
- Uh, what's with the pails?
- Oh, I'm going to the maple
syrup factory. I mean, the barn
with a couple of pots in it.
- You make your own maple syrup?
- Well,
it's a dream my dad had,
so I'm trying to figure it out.
You do, like,
everything.
Yeah, that's, like...
that's wild.
- Is it a complicated process?
- If you
help me out, I'll teach you
everything I know.
We'll be
two and a half minutes, Carl.
- Very funny.
- Yeah, I mean, I could...
You should go, yeah.
I'll wax the skis up.
- OK.
- Yeah. Have fun. Don't fall in.
- Bye.
OK, then.
No.
- Bon matin.
- Yeah, hi.
- We are here!
- What the fuck
- We are... here!
- What do you think we're
- Seriously, what the fuck?!
- You said it was an emergency.
I didn't ask you to come
the fuck up here!
Yes, you did, you did.
You said, "Stace, I need
- We came.
- I didn't say that.
- Oh, my God.
- I didn't say that. But
OK. Fuck, fuck, fuck.
OK, Doug, let's go, let's go.
OK, yeah, yeah, I'll just get
my chauffeur hat.
You know, I really...
Can I please pee? 'Cause
I'd prefer it if you get
in the fucking Jeep and go.
Guess how many times
we stopped on the way here.
- I don't give a shit!
- Five times.
OK, you've got the bladder
of an 80-year-old man.
Is that her?
She's a fuckin' babe.
- My God.
That megalomaniac hasn't aged
a day.
- Hi.
: Hey, hey, hey.
Did you guys make some syrup?
- Yeah.
How was the, uh, the sugar -
with the maples? The...
- Hey.
- What are you guys doing here?
Oh, nothing.
Yeah, they, uh...
drove up here...
And they're here,
at the lodge we're staying at.
Wait a second.
Stacey Humes?
- Heeey!
- Wow,
you look terrific.
- Oh, thanks.
- Mwah.
Exactly the same.
- Actually I just
- Oh, nice.
- Douglas Reginald.
Your acquaintance.
- Ah, the man who made
- Yeah.
- The reservation?
Going on here.
What's going on here?
Could you escort me to a john?
I need to do a bladder drainage
Let me get my surgical gloves.
Follow me.
Oh, my God, I am so sorry.
This is just so ridiculous.
They're insisting on tweaks
for the distributor meeting
on Monday, and I've been
trying to reach you,
but I couldn't get you, so...
- The cell reception's terrible.
And also we're on our getaway.
That's 'cause we wanted to get
- Get away!
- What kind of tweaks?
The dark prince's underbite.
He's like...
- Yeah.
- They said, "He'd be able
to afford orthodontic work -
he's a prince," and I was said,
"OK, why don't you eat
each other's assholes instead?"
- That's a good comeback.
- I wouldn't
have bugged you if it weren't
for the promotion, right?
'Cause I know how much
that means to you.
Yeah, it means a lot.
And you decided
to stay the night?
No! No, of course not.
- That's fun, that's fun.
- No. No.
We're gonna do the work,
Doug's gonna piss a few times,
and we're gonna leave.
- Good morning.
- Oh, great.
- I didn't know
- you had friends coming up.
- Neither did we.
Yeah. Stacey, je presente
Lise et Anatalie.
- It's Anatolii.
I know who you are
and I love you.
Are you guys still going
on that vineyard tour?
On a ski route that links
all the wineries.
Please come. It will be
so chill if we're all together.
Uh, no, no, no, they have
their own plans, dear.
- We do.
- You know what? Plans recently
changed, so I'm in.
- Babe, you don't even drink.
- I can try
the local cheeses.
You're obsessed
with cheese.
Hey, hey. I'm... I'm sorry.
I thought we were going
Right. See, I don't give
a shit about rocks, though.
I am so sorry about all...
about this. It's crazy.
How could you forget to take
the dark prince's
socioeconomic background
into consideration, Carl?
You don't take
my work seriously.
You don't. You barely asked me
about my promotion. It was a...
You said
you didn't get it yet.
Yeah, I know!
What do you want me
to do here? I'm...
Oh, I want you to go hang out
with your BFF who can't leave
I'll be wine tasting
with your ex.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Well, I guess we can put off
the work and tag along.
I mean, I heard there's
some really good cabernets...
- What work, Stacey?!
- The... fake work.
Well, excuse me for trying
to make the most of the trip.
* Everywhere
* That we go
* Seein' warm
* People
* Feel the positive pole
* Yes oh yes, but so...
Sue, give me your skis;
I'll lock 'em together.
Oh, yeah, thanks, Carl.
It's a rough neighborhood.
Hey, Sue, wait up.
We'll start with whites.
We are
suspending Doug's diet in light
the situation. Thank you.
The plan is to have dirty,
infected sex tonight,
right, my pet?
- There isn't anything
not disgusting about that last
sentence. Please don't call
What's lodged
up your ass, man?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe it's that my wife is
with the love of my life.
- Do you get how messed up that
the love of your life in
the same sentence as your wife?
That's not
what I meant, Stace.
Well, what did you mean?
I don't know, Doug!
OK, listen. I know, I know.
You're looking at Robyn,
you're remembering how she would
boss you around in a meeting,
and then you'd be the one
in control when you'd be
of her car, OK?
- Respect.
How is that supposed
to help me?
She's just
the one that got away, Carl.
Everyone has one.
She's your white buffalo.
- Mine was an ex-con.
- What?
- Yeah. Louise.
- Louise.
- She was a mugger.
What I mean by that is she used
to... mug everybody.
It was a real problem.
- And then she... she got away.
Besides, dude, Robyn is so
weird. She's buying her parents
a ski lodge that she used
as a fuck den.
OK, we did a little bit more
than just...
Yeah, it's kinda weird. I didn't
think about that until just now.
Yeah, and I'm gonna
tell you something.
I didn't like you
when you were with Robyn.
Yeah, I said it. You were
suddenly above everything.
'Cause I remember being happy.
- Oh, really?
Well, when you were happy,
everyone hated you, so...
- Dude, you have a great wife.
- Yeah, I know I have a great
who married her.
- So then what the fuck?
So then nothing, OK?
Everything's gonna be fine.
Everything's fine,
everything's great,
except for the fact that
you guys decided to show up.
Kidding. Come on,
bring it in.
I love you.
Shouldn't have come.
So, it's nice that, uh,
you get to spend so much time
with Anatolii.
We haven't seen each other
in months.
I don't know if he stays
in France to avoid me,
or the women he's entered
in Montreal,
many of whom are my peers.
- Excuse me?
- One doesn't prepare
for dinner parties with friends
that have fucked your son.
That's an interesting problem
to encounter.
: Bonjour.
** Toi qui me quitte
avec la levée du jour *
* Et qui me laisse dans I'espoir
d'un retour *
* Pourquoi ne pas faire durer
ce matin *
* Jusqu' demain *
* Je t'offrirai
* Des croissants de soleil
pour déjeuner *
* la saveur de miel
et de rosée *
* Sur un plateau de drap
et d'oreiller *
* Qui fait rver *
* Puis nous dînerons
de paroles de rve *
* Nous goutterons I'amour
et I'eau fraîche *
* Et puis quand viendra
le nouveau matin *
* On sera si bien
* J'inventerai
* Des recettes de bonheur
volonté *
* Sur une musique venue
d'un ciel de mai *
* Que tu ne voudras
plus jamais quitter *
* Sans regretter
* La la la la
* La la la la la la
la la la la *
* La la la la *
Oh, my God!
Formidable!
Formi-fuckin'- dable!
That was beautiful, babe.
- Thanks.
- You're so talented.
Thank you. OK.
Come on, let's eat.
Anatolii and I are gonna
smoke a pinner.
- We're in the middle of a meal.
- Yeah, I'm not so hungry.
Ate a lot of cheese.
I'm kind of obsessed with it.
- Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Could you just leave him alone
for like two seconds?
How much wine
have you had?
- Hardly any.
- Would you let go?
You're pinching me.
What is wrong with you?!
Mine tastes like
Dr. Crapperstein
compared to this.
Where is everybody?
Well, Stacey and Doug went
to pee.
He's a highly hydrated
individual.
And, um, the rest left.
How nice of them.
You wanna walk?
Mm-hmm.
So, I used to have
this fantasy/nightmare
about the guy you end up with.
- Hm.
Yeah. So, you're
in a limo,
and you're, uh, you're
on the way to, um,
the premiere of a game
he designed.
Oh, here we go.
And, uh, and I...
pop into your head,
just like this...
momentary thought.
And then you look
at the guy, the new guy...
...and you think
to yourself, "Wow...
...this guy inspires me
so much more."
And then
you guys just fuck.
Does he have a bigger dick
than you?
- Oh, yeah. Balls too.
- Oh, my God.
You love
to torture yourself.
- Fuck you.
- OK.
Fuck me.
You remember when we did it
in the floor of your office
With the door open.
Do you remember when you used
to whisper in my ear...
That I wanted
to go down on my knees
so the entire staff would know
I was yours?
The world was our canvas,
and we used
every color imaginable
to paint it.
Well, if you ever quit
game design, you could
get into the greeting card
business.
He became obsessed
with the animals he painted.
- These are terrifying.
- Yeah, that's his intention.
Fear of that
which infatuates us.
Apparently
he married this owl.
- What the fuck?
- For tax reasons, I'm assuming.
Yeah!
I just found my new tattoo.
: He has your eyes.
I'd be lying if I said that
I haven't fantasized
about being back here.
Was the helmet part of it?
Can I ask you
something?
Why do you like me
so much?
Like you?
I'm only good
in the beginning,
the exciting part.
I can't do the rest.
I think you're addicted to men
falling in love with you.
Don't reduce me to that
because it didn't work
Work out?
How could it have possibly
worked out? You left!
You never flew to Vancouver
to tell me.
You never fought for me.
But why here?
Why did you buy
this fucking place?
Because there is a part
of me that was hoping
this was more
a than memory too.
I loved you, Carl,
no matter what you think.
That guy's going
really fast.
Hey, slow down!
Slow down!
Oh, fuck, what? Come on!
Are you kidding me?
Oh, my God!
What are you doing here?
Currently I'm
trying to keep warm.
- Wait, you know this guy?
- Who are you?
- He's nobody.
- Oh, thanks a lot. Yeah.
Would you mind telling me what
the hell is going on right now?
Please, I'd love to hear it.
I'm as curious as shit-face
- Carl, this is Aaron...
- OK.
...my, um...
husband.
You're... you're married?
To this guy?
- Separated.
- Yeah, thanks for
- How did you know I was here?
- Your parents told me.
Oh, and want to pass
this message along. They think
you're wonderful and amazing and
have never done anything wrong
This is the guy
from your office?
You're Aaron Berg, aren't you?
I recognize you. You're
Oh, and you must be
Sherlock Holmes, is that right?
I'll take Watson, thank you.
She's got a better body.
OK, Carl, can you
take the skidoo back?
And Aaron and I, we'll walk.
- Yeah, could you get the fuck
out of here, ski patrol?
- Hey, you know what?
You destroyed the skis!
You destroyed my skis, pal!
Yeah, they're fucked!
- I can see that!
What are you doing
in the middle of the woods
with this piece of dog shit?
He's a friend, trust me.
He's married.
You can't do this. You can't fly
here and expect anything.
I just want to talk.
- So talk.
I love you, and I want you to
come home so that we can
It was never my home.
I was always a visitor there.
Don't say that, OK?
I hate when you say that shit!
- Don't get "angy."
- I'm not... I'm not
I'm just saying, you're buying
a fucking ski lodge in Quebec.
A psychotic
episode or something?
- Oh, it wasn't that bad.
- Oh, oh, really?
Ejaculating all over my desk?
I'd call that pretty bad.
That seemed like the right
thing to do at the time.
Oscar misses you.
- Right.
- He does. It's like a wake
at our house. We can't
watch any of our shows.
I have all
the Rookie Blu PVR'd.
Watch 'em.
I'm caught up.
Crazy stuff happens.
- What?
- Hey, I can't get
this fucking thing started.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
I'm really sorry.
- Why the fuck
are you still here, huh?!
- Hey, you know what, pal?
I think she's making
her feelings pretty clear, OK?
Oh, is that right?
Excuse me, just one second.
- Fake head butt?
- Stop!
What are you gonna do,
motherfucking bitch?
- Mr. Slap My Face?
- OK, OK, OK, Carl,
Yeah, go.
Oh, that's right,
I can't get it started.
Love to get out of here. I'd
love to get out of your hair.
I'd love it.
Get it started.
A little turn of the key.
It's really nice to meet you,
man. That was sarcasm.
Yeah, nice to meet you.
Ride this back to the lodge,
you fuckin'...
I can't believe she's married
to Aaron Berg.
You should have seen the guy;
he was a fuckin' maniac.
Hey, I'm really sorry
about this, about all this -
Stacey, and everything...
I'm sorry I was...
jealous of Anatolii.
He seems like a perfectly
nice, very handsome young man.
Babe.
There's something I want
to tell you about Robyn and I.
What?
Our relationship was
a little more intense
than I originally led on.
We actually dated
for like a year.
Hm.
Yeah, but it was...
everything that's wrong
in a relationship.
It was toxic, passionate...
- Sounds awful.
- The whole thing
consisted of just fighting
and fucking...
- Stop!
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I just thought I owed you
the truth.
Are you OK?
I think so.
It's so odd that you've
never mentioned this person.
I love you
so much.
I want to be buried
next to you.
And you can wear your... your
disgusting sweater for eternity.
I've got a surprise
for you.
I have something for you.
- Hang on, hang on, hang on.
If you guys went out
for a year...
Yeah.
Well... it's kind of amazing
that she happened
to buy the lodge
that you brought me to.
- No, no, I had no idea...
- It's just a big coincidence.
Depends on how
you look at it.
Have you been here with her?
I thought you would think
it was weird, so I didn't...
- You have?
- Now, hold on, I haven't...
It is weird, Carl.
It's extremely fucking weird.
Clearly you knew that
or you wouldn't have
kept it a secret.
- Yeah, I did keep it
a secret because I knew that
you would think it was weird.
I just said that.
Oh, OK, uh, Greece is romantic.
If I'd taken her to Greece,
does that mean we could
Probably not;
that's just how it works.
And this isn't a fucking
country, Carl; it's a ski lodge.
How many times
have you been up here?
- Does that matter?
- More than once?
- I don't know, a few times.
- Did you stay
in this room? Did you stay
in the fucking Lovers' Suite?
It's a small inn. We probably
stayed in all the rooms.
You probably fought and fucked
all over this place.
I feel sick to my stomach.
I feel sick.
No, listen, I picked
this place because I knew
it was nice, and I thought
you would like it.
That's it, that's the whole...
Where are you going?
It's freezing outside!
Hey.
What are you doing?
I'm not allowed to bring
my iPad, but you can fucking...
I'm so fucking sick
of your rules, Carl.
What are you doing?
It's her, isn't it?
It looks like you.
I designed her to look like you.
I don't have a fucking
rose tattoo on my forearm.
You're obsessed with her.
- No, I'm not obsessed with her.
What happened on that
ski trail? What happened?
You were completely flushed
when you came in.
Yeah, he slapped me
in the face!
Well, why the fuck would he
slap you if you hadn't
The clothes you get me to wear.
The heels. You've been trying
to mold me into
your ex-girlfriend for years!
- That's insane!
- No shit! I have changed
so much for you.
- I've changed everything!
I've changed tons of things
for you.
- I quit drinking for you.
- No, you quit drinking for you.
You were drunk every
fucking night! You were dr...
I was a kid! Sorry I wasn't
inspiring the world
with a fucking ski lodge!
- I don't want that.
You don't know
what the fuck you want.
I just want you.
Please, please.
- Give me the keys.
- Please, please! I'm not gonna
- Give me your keys, Carl!
- Please...
Stop it!
Sue, where are you gonna go?
Where are you gonna go?
Door... slam!
Oh, my God!
Sue, Sue, are you OK?
Honey.
You know, it's pretty
incredible that you've held
Look, hey, maybe
there's something to be said
about that, you know?
On the other hand,
you could have, like,
an obsessive disorder,
in which case we should...
we should talk to a physician.
You want me to be quiet?
Yeah.
OK.
- Sue, are you all right, baby?
- Get the fuck out of here,
Get the fuck away from me.
Get out!
I want to take
her to the hospital.
50km away, so I would
advise against it.
Oh, oh, you would?
You'd advise against it?
He'd advise against it.
- How is she?
Well, we think
she's had a concussion.
Shit. Well,
how do you know?
He's some kind of life coach.
- You're a life coach?
- I'm a trained lifeguard.
Like in real life?
This isn't some erotica film?
- Hey, man, I passed bronze med.
- Oh, that's no joke.
- Well, she asked that you don't
sleep in her room tonight,
asshole - her words.
She'll see you
tomorrow, asshole.
Is that second "asshole"
from you, or her?
Listen, you gotta wake her up
intermittently throughout the
you slap her in the face,
you punch her in the teeth.
- Seriously, man?
- She has a concussion.
So you punch my wife
in the teeth?
Basically he's saying his mom
is gonna sleep with Sue,
and it hasn't happened yet,
but that is going to happen,
and that... I'm getting
that Anatolii...
I'm just getting that Anatolii
is not happy about that.
Trouble in paradise?
Look, Carl, I'm...
sorry about your skis.
And also for slapping you
in the face.
The skis were
a limited edition.
Find them on the internet.
- Probably not.
It'll be challenging.
- Have a beer with me.
- Honestly, I just
want to get some sleep.
- I will have a beer.
Me too.
My day buzz is wearing off.
Oh-ho-ho, quick, inject
the female with some alcohol
before she turns into
a fucking monster.
There you go, you got
some drinking buddies.
Well, I wouldn't want
to make you "angy."
What's your,
uh, tattoo?
That is a panther,
those are lightning bolts
shooting out of its eyes;
therefore
it's a lightning panther.
- I love it.
- It's impossible
not to.
So,
you're the Carl
that went out with my wife.
Hm. And you're the husband
we never knew existed.
She didn't mention me?
- I probably wasn't listening.
- Yeah, I tend to tune her out
myself.
- Mm-hmm.
- Well, most do.
- You know,
frankly, I just... expected
someone a little...
Yeah, well,
the feeling's mutual.
I guess we know
she has a type.
- I'm too hot for her.
- You know, it's crazy.
You're the guy whose career
I wish I had.
Yeah, well, I had a kid
really young,
so it made me grow up fast.
- Oh, how old is
your little twerp?
- He's not a twerp anymore.
He's got pubic hair.
Oscar is 13, so...
- Ah, 13.
- Yeah.
- Were you 13 when you had him?
- Ha, ha. No.
Holly and I were seniors
in high school.
Holly's my first wife.
Wow. Well, maybe
third time will be the charm.
Stacey.
No, um, this is
gonna work out.
I mean, it...
it has to.
Robyn is, uh...
everything to me, so...
Honestly, I respect that.
I do. I mean, you chased
- Yeah.
- And it didn't work out.
I mean, sometimes I wish
I had done the same.
What do...
what do you mean by that?
Oh, come on, Doug.
When I was a little girl,
I didn't exactly dream of being
with a man with a supernatural
and a yeast infection.
- Serious?
It's very serious.
To you and not settling.
- My body, my rules!
- Oh! I'm sorry.
Sue?
Oh, um...
Oh, my God.
- Oh.
- Oh, my God.
I'm sorry, I...
This room is not part
of the B&B experience.
I am still renovating.
- I'm sorry, I'm gone.
I'm so sorry.
- No, wait, wait. It's fine,
it's fine. This pigeon pose -
everything just comes
gushing out, you know?
I'm so mortified.
There. Better?
Yeah.
Nice tights. Heh. Not.
Remember when Borat brought
the "not" back?
Comedy works in cycles.
Yeah, yeah.
No, that's very funny.
You knew you were emailing
with me,
right? I haven't changed
my work email
in 10 years.
A little strange
you didn't mention it.
you brought your wife here.
It's a mistake to over-
intellectualize paintings.
Picasso said it's
like the sound of birds -
it fills you with emotion,
yet you can't make sense of it.
- Mm, that's cool.
- Mm.
: Morning.
What about you, Sue?
Did you get much rest
with my mother molesting you?
Hey.
- Am I interrupting something?
- Yes.
Tough. Shared table.
Are you OK?
Is your head all right?
It's never been
more clear.
Do you ever take those
heels off? It's 9am.
My nana sent them from Italy.
Good morning, everyone.
'Tis a beautiful one.
- 'Tis, Ryan,
'tis. You know
what I think it is?
It's all this history.
- Good morning.
- Good morning!
- Hey.
- I got morning hugs.
Come on.
- No.
- Don't touch me.
- Whoa, you can't catch
Ooh, ahh!
What's on the grill?
- Oh, fuck.
- Aaron, uh,
- You're pretty.
- And this is Lise and Anatolii.
- Mmm.
- As you may have gathered, I do
that is, when she
makes it home for dinner.
If you look up "mortified"
in the dictionary, you'll
That's cute. The only place
she can bear to lose control
what I'm talking about, right?
- Are you kidding me?
Can you help me
in the kitchen?
Jeez. My turn on the chore wheel
again, I guess.
Do you know what it's like
to have walked through your
look of disappointment on their
faces that I'm not Holly?
Who gives a shit what they
think? They're fucking senile!
Who cares if Oscar doesn't
like you? This is about us.
- He said that?
- No.
He's a teenager -
he hates everything.
Don't take is personally.
- I'm a horrible stepmother.
- No, you're not.
- Just come home.
Look, I know
that this has been hard, pickle.
How did you get out of your jar
and all the way here?
I took a pickle plane.
The seating was cramped.
Hot beans?
- Coffee?
- I will take half a cup.
Great. No problem.
Anybody else?
- Thank you.
- Do you want
- What's sailor?
- Shh.
They went
snowshoeing.
Who's "they?"
Your wife and the cougar.
I feel you, man.
I have a flight to Paris
in six hours.
I've done an amazing thing
coming here.
Yeah, yeah,
you're such a great son,
you see your mom twice a year
Well, she's the one
getting action now.
Sue?
What's going on?
We were snowshoeing.
No, you weren't.
The snowshoes are behind you,
stuck in the fucking snow.
- I'll wait by the trail.
There's no need to wait.
You can just leave.
You don't deserve her.
We shared a moment.
You know what that's like.
So, now you're...
cheating on me
with a woman
that you just met.
Don't you think that you're
overreacting a little bit?
Uh... I look at it as
making up for lost
What the fuck
does that mean?
When you get sad, is it
because you're thinking of her?
No.
You know, for months
you've been
implying that this weekend was
gonna be some big answer
and I think I was in denial
about what needed fixing.
- We don't need fixing.
- Stop lying for two seconds!
I haven't been attracted
to you for two years.
So, that's my thing.
You gross me out.
I do?
I'm glad
this weekend happened.
I think it had to happen.
So you can go fuck yourself,
sailor.
Ah.
Hey, Sherlock.
I see you've solved the mystery
of starting the skidoo.
- I did.
- I'm sorry I called you sailor.
No, it's all right.
It wasn't your fault.
Want to get on?
I was looking forward
to the arm workout.
Get on the skidoo, Robyn.
Mmm.
Right here.
This is good.
- Oh... wait, wait, wait.
- No, no, no, I'm falling.
- OK, right here.
- What are...
- Oh. Oh, are you OK?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
Can you... are you, uh...
- Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- Do you want my... I can...
- They make it really hard to
OK, I'm not on the pill,
so pull out, OK?
Yeah, yeah, of course.
Holy shit.
Fuck.
Oh, yeah.
Oh!
Oh! Oh!
Yeah. Ah!
- Ah.
- Yeah.
- Shit. I'm sorry.
- Oh.
I'm sorry. Let me just...
I can go... here.
Did you... did you?
- No.
No, you go ahead.
Are you close?
Not really, no.
Um... uh...
OK.
Just, uh...
can you
tell me how you were waiting
for me on the trail
like a little slu...
like, uh,
in your snowsuit?
Uh, yeah. Um...
I was getting, uh,
maple syrup
at the tree,
and, uh...
and I was waiting for the sap...
- Yeah.
...'cause it takes a while.
- Yeah, sap will take
And, um...
Shit.
- Robyn, are you crying?
Oh, my God.
Oh, shit, no.
I'm so sorry.
Are you all right?
I think so. You?
We should get going.
You go ahead.
No, I'm not gonna leave
without you.
No, please go.
She's gone - with the hottie
and his hot mother.
See you in the city.
Well, I'm on the 8 o'clock
home tonight.
Yeah, I think she might have
completely lost her mind.
Yeah. Can I call you back?
* I'll follow
* I'm yours, so...
Oh, of course
that's what's happening.
Hey.
Sue.
Go home, Carl.
What the hell
are you doing here, Carl?
You broke into my house?
Are you kidding me?!
Now Anatolii's joined
the party.
All right, all right, buddy,
just... just cool your jets, OK?
- Please, guys...
- OK, all right, I'm...
He knows Krav Maga.
- Hey!
- Oh! Fuck! Stop it!
Stop it! Stop. Enough.
We need to speak.
- Your husband's a pussy.
What are you even doing here?
Aren't you supposed to be
on some movie set in Paris
getting your... getting
And then they get
the fuck out of this house.
Copy that.
Sorry to interrupt
your dance party.
I think the best
discovery I made this weekend
was how much I miss wine.
I love you so much.
Not enough.
We don't
love each other enough.
I disagree.
How do you know?
I slept with her.
I was... confused.
You said
that it was over.
I was gonna give you this
over the weekend.
I finally got
our wedding rings.
Sue.
Wait.
How could you look
into my father's eyes
and ask to marry me if you had
all this shit in your heart?
How could you make me
walk down the aisle?
How can you do that
to somebody?
What was I supposed to do?
Just bow out of life
because I have
a little baggage?
Everyone's got exes, Sue;
everyone's got little pieces
of their heart that belong
to other people.
It just becomes a part
of who you are.
But you let it ruin us.
** What is this
* Got me feelin' so good
right now *
* What is this
* Make me wanna run home
anyhow *
* Whatever it is, yeah
* Oh, I cannot, cannot hold
* My peace
* Mmm *
- Hi.
- Mmm.
All dressed up
for the opera?
How's it been going...
generally?
Be sure
you chew that, now.
Is there anything in there
he can cut himself with?
Later, dick nipples.
That's nipples on dicks.
That makes absolutely
no sense.
I'll call you later.
OK. I'll be sure
to screen the call.
It's Sue, right? Hmm?
It's good to see you back
on stage, Carlos Santana.
You're in town
for the Mexican parade?
Is there a...
Mexican parade in town?
- I don't know.
- No?
You look amazing.
- Oh.
I agree.
I do look fantastic.
So, I've had some time
to do some thinking.
Uh, yeah, I've been doing
a lot of thinking. Um...
- Before you say anything,
I just want to...
put something out there.
I'm seeing somebody.
That...
Oh, that's cool.
Who is he?
He's just a guy.
We shouldn't have done this.
- No, we had to do it.
We had to.
If it didn't hurt, something
would be wrong with me.
There's a lot
wrong with you.
The fact is, I...
I lost...
someone that I could have spent
the rest of my life with.
It wouldn't have been
right, though.
I acted more like a sister
than a wife.
You were perfect.
No. No, no. No.
I knew that it was over
long before that weekend.
And I was just too scared
to do anything about it.
I miss you.
Just promise me you won't make
your next girlfriend wear
I don't...
think I can do that.
- Mmm.
- You're doing great, baby.
You gross me out.
Fuck you.
** I don't want nobody
to leave me *
* I don't need nobody
to want me *
* I know this may sound strange
right from the start *
* 'Cause when I wanted somebody
to need me *
* When I needed somebody
to want me *
* All I ever got was
a broken heart *
* I felt no taller
than the ground *
* True love had
let me down *
* But I had to be a man
and stand up tall *
* And this heart of mine
was pure *
* But I know
now for sure *
* That love,
you didn't love me *
* You didn't need me,
you didn't want me *
* Don't want nobody
to change me *
* Or try
to rearrange me *
* Just take away the pain
that's tearing up my mind *
* 'Cause love has been
my total destruction *
* Like a volcano
eruption *
* To me, love and pain
just seem to rhyme *
* I felt no taller
than the ground *
* True love had
let me down *
* I had to be a man
and stand up tall *
* This heart of mine
was pure *
* But I know
now for sure *
* That love,
you didn't love me *
* You didn't need me,
you didn't want me *
* I don't want nobody
to change me *
* Or try
to rearrange me *
* Take away the pain
that's tearing up my mind *
* Love has been
my total destruction *
* Like a volcano
eruption *
* To me, love and pain
just seem to rhyme *
* Love don't love me
* No, no, no, no
* Love, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no... **