Kim Hee-ae
Ko Asung
Kim You-jeong, Kim Hyang-gi
Yu Ah-in, Sung Dong-il
It's not ironed
It'll wrinkle after an hour anyway
But it's nice to wear
a neatly pressed shirt
Give me three minutes
This is just fine
There's no soup?
Don't complain
or we'll switch to cereal
The eggs look perfect
Aren't you a sweetheart?
Man-ji, learn from your sister
I take after you, mom
Directed by Lee Han
You're not gonna have that, then?
No
Yay
Mom
Yeah?
Can you buy me an MP3 player?
What for?
Just that... everyone else
has one and I don't
What kind of a silly reason is that?
Everyone has one
so, you must have one too?
Make it an early birthday present
Months in advance?
Just get one for her
Who said I wouldn't?
How about next month?
We have to renew the lease
this month
Just listen from your phone
Who uses MP3 player these days?
Wait up, Man-ji
I'm late
Sorry, honey...
can you put the dishes
in the sink?
Man-ji
Come and have a taste
Tofu is buy one get one free
Would you like to sample
some tofu, ma'am?
Dumplings!
Hey, Cheon-ji
What's up?
Can you knit a hat for me
with my yarn?
First an MP3 player
and now, a woolly hat?
One for stew, please
Honey, I'm busy
Can we talk later?
How about some dumplings, ma'am?
Sorry about that
It's organic and
buy one get one free today
- Thank you
- Have a good day
Dumplings, ma'am?
Roll up your skirt
It's really bothering me
Your's looks as if
it's about to explode
Dress like a dork
if you like getting picked on
Just shut up and decide
which snack parlor
Of course your diet
was going to last
Look at the middle-schoolers
So sweet...
That teacher loves making
the girls hug each... pervert!
Yeah, that'll help them make up
She's Mi-ra and Cheon-ji's
home room teacher
Mi-ra...?
Oh, your sister!
She and Cheon-ji
are in the same class?
Didn't Cheon-ji tell you?
Mi-ra talks about her sometimes
What does she say?
I don't think they're that close
So, have we decided?
Attal
Okay
What?
Was it MP3 player
that Cheon-ji wanted?
There are so many different kinds
You said you needed to
save up for security deposit
It's an MP3 player
It's not gonna make us homeless
Can you ask her
which model she wants?
There was something about her tone
She never asks for anything
I don't know... I gotta go
Cheon-ji died
My baby sister who was pressing
her shirt to perfection all morning
took her own life
without leaving a note
Cheon-ji's dad
Don't ask her why
if you see her
Just give her a hug
Bitch...
Good bye, baby
Nine years after burying dad
mom had to bury her little girl
ELEGANT LIES
I've only just buried my baby
How dare you talk about
my daughter that way
when you could've just
asked me to move out
Have a good life,
you rotten hag!
Get us out of here
as fast as you can
Why didn't you leave behind
the things we don't want?
The hag tells me to
take everything
It feels so weird
to be just you and me
Thank you
Hello!
We're moving into 103
No room for privacy
Doesn't it smell like
old public toilet in here?
Didn't you check the apartment
when you signed the contract?
I signed when I heard
it was Chowon Apartment
Where do I sleep?
We can sleep here together
I don't think so
Then, you take the living room
We'll have to get rid of your desk
There's no room
You don't want me to study?
I'll get a small foldable table
I'll just use Cheon-ji's
It's okay
Alright
I'll put this in the balcony
Let's clean it up first
What is this smell?
Look out for a hidden
secret toilet
Can you get the garbage bag?
- Oh my God!
- What?
What?
- What is it, mom?
- Rats
- Oh, no... catch them
- You do it
No, you do it, mom
Who the hell are you?
I live next door
Are you a rocker?
No, I'm studying for
the civil service exams
That is one precise middle parting
I appreciate the beauty of balance
Freak...
So, you're a man?
What's going on inside?
Rats...
Yeah, it's a big problem
in this building
They're swarming in the box
in the balcony
Can I call 911 for this?
Why don't you let me handle this?
There is a dust pan
in the balcony
Which box is it?
The moldy one
in the furnace closet
I'll close this first
in case they try to escape
He's kind of dependable
What's wrong?
It's too big... I'm sorry
Gives me the creeps
So much for his big words
Next time I see him,
I'll give him pigtails
He almost broke that door
Dependable?
Did I say that?
Shall we call the security?
He won't lift a finger for free
I couldn't find the big one
- Argh
- Hey!
You can't just catch the small one
We'll see if it comes back
I gave you 10 dollars
for that tiny little one?
So, there might still be
a rat in there?
Shall I get some bug spray?
Like that's gonna kill a rat
It'll kill the ticks
on rat's skin
I have a feeling that
I'll run away soon
I have a feeling I'll be
taking more shifts at work
- Let me help you with other things
- No, thank you
That one
We need to throw that out
You can't let a stranger
in our house
There's nothing for him to take
What's your name?
Lee Man-ji
It's an easy name to make fun of
I'm Chu Sang-bak
Chusang Park or Chu Sangbak?
It's Chu Sang-bak
No charge for the glass
The board is three dollars
The dresser, also three dollars
So, six dollars in total
The board and the dresser are a set
You can't charge them separately
It's the size that matters
Even as a set, it's six dollars
Hey
You charged me five dollars
for a dresser similar to this one
You see?
I don't decide this as I want
There are guidelines to follow
Five dollars
Oh, come on
Isn't that Cheon-ji's friend?
It's Hwa-yeon
Bosingak owner's daughter
So, that's that
I'm hungry
Let's get something to eat, Man-ji
Can we have a word?
What about?
You can't charge people differently
as you please
The economy isn't
what it used to me
It was two weeks ago
Okay
Then, let's just settle for this
I'm only doing this because
you're like a son to me
Hello
We just moved here. I guess
we'll be seeing each other around
Right...
I'm back
We'll have two black bean noodles
with a sweet and sour pork
- Two black noodles and one pork
- We can't eat all that
We're not three people
Of course, we can
We're gonna need that much energy
- Can we cancel the pork?
- No, we'll have it
You gotta eat black bean noodles
when you move
I'm sick of moving
How come you never bought a house?
By the time I save some money
the house price soars out of reach
and you want to go to cram schools
to get good grades
What choice do I have?
Alright, I take it back
New to the neighborhood?
We also deliver
We'll pop around
We live next door
How kind of you!
Enjoy your noodles
Study hard for mom, okay?
They say 'unlucky in marriage,
poor luck with children too'
Prove them wrong
With what luck
could I possibly achieve that?
You talk back constantly
It's good. We are the ones
that talk... I like that
Mom, stop being so dramatic
You're making me uncomfortable
Let's just stay the way
we used to be
My daughter's nagging
gives me energy. It's good
Let's get this straight, moron
I didn't end it because you're a bum
Don't make the unemployment
problem your excuse
You just hate working
Don't wait for my call, you damn...
Bastard... Why would I
tell you about moving?
What?
No, don't wait for me there
Stop being pathetic
You've got kids to look after
What?
Cheon-ji's mom?
Don't you dare mention
my daughter's name
Good night
Night
Why did she do it?
Do you know anything about it?
What are you doing?
I had borrowed it from Cheon-ji
When?
Three months ago maybe
Three months?
She never asked for it back
So, you didn't bother returning it?
I thought she'd come get it
if she needed it back
So, she has to come to you
to kindly ask for it back
It was only a gym uniform
Of course
What about Cheon-ji
who would've been terrified
what you might do if she say no?
Why the fuck did
she have to kill herself?
What?
What did you say?
Hwa-yeon gave it to me
saying it would fit me
Are you friends with Hwa-yeon?
We got close after she invited me
to her birthday party
- What about Cheon-ji?
- She's not my style
She was best friends with Hwa-yeon
But I only know Hwa-yeon
not Cheon-ji
I'm Cheon-ji's sister
The scent is so thick
Hi
Can we have a word after school?
Cheonji
Hey
Are you her sister?
Yeah
Hi!
I'm Cheon-ji's friend, Hwa-yeon
Hwa-yeon
It's so great to finally meet you
Why don't you buy me a pork cutlet?
You don't have to
You two are so different
They say opposites attract
I don't have enough
for pork cutlet but...
Can we get two rice cakes
in chili sauce?
Thank you
Excuse me for a moment?
I'm going
I'm on my way
- Here's your rice cake
- Thank you
Hwa-yeon
What are you doing?
I met Cheon-ji's sister
I asked her to get pork cutlet
but she's buying me rice cake instead
So, what do you think?
She's cute
I felt bad about not buying you
that pork cutlet
Thank you
I heard you and Cheon-ji were best friends
You must be upset
I've known her since elementary school
but we weren't best friends
I don't know what the girls
said about the day she died
but Cheon-ji seemed quite upset
during the presentation
What are the evils of prejudice?
Especially when it is
maliciously disseminated
Let's look at some common ways
in which prejudice can be fostered
One, slander disguised
as a compliment
People react more sensitively
to smaller points than the basis
Example:
'She always gets good grades
but she's actually quite dumb'
Basis, good grades,
point, dumb
Your cruel words can kill
Are you a murderer in the making?
Thank you
What an interesting presentation!
But 'a murdererin the making'?
Don't you think you took too far?
Should I have said
a 'confirmed murderer' instead?
I'm sorry, Cheon-ji
I'm really sorry, okay?
Let me go
Cheon-ji, I'm sorry
Why do you always apologize to her?
What's the matter with her?
It's not like you ever
did anything to her
- What a self-absorbed bitch!
- Totally
She was going through something
terrible and I never knew it
So, I told myself that
I'll be a better friend for her
I only asked you if you were upset
and that's a pretty long answer
I thought you might want to know
Does everyone have MP3 players?
Probably, although I can't
be bother to carry mine around
Why?
Cheon-ji was asking for
an MP3 player before she died
I wondered if you knew
anything about it
We were going to exchange gifts
for our birthdays
Was it your birthday?
Among close friends,
we pick out the presents
and give each other before the birthdays
An early present...
an MP3 player
that you rarely use, no less?
That doesn't seem right
There are cheap ones, too
For 20 dollars or less
Stupid girl... troubled over an MP3
when there are cheaper ones, too
Why aren't you eating?
I am
Are you close with Soo-gyeong?
She's a delinquent
She's a friend of a friend's
but she seemed close with Cheon-ji
They lend each other gym uniforms
They used to lend each other
gym uniforms?
Well, yeah...
I didn't know you moved
to my neighborhood
I saw you yesterday
I thought you saw me, too
I would've said hi
if I did
These apartments are so old,
aren't they?
I lived here all my life
I'm so sick of this place
but my parents won't go anywhere
unless the restaurant shuts down
Well, our black bean noodle
is quite famous in this area
You
You can't stand the silence,
can you?
It makes you nervous
So, this is what she meant
I just didn't want to be rude
since you treated me
Cheon-ji said that you were cool
You really are
I think she once said that
it's hard to talk to you
Then again, I'm not sure
There's nothing cool about
being cool-headed about your sister's death
But I guess it's okay
to talk about it now
I think I'll look for
her suicide note
I thought she didn't leave
any note
Why wouldn't she?
I just haven't looked yet
Maybe I'll start soon
or not
Declaration of Friendship
Cheonji
Are you still mad at me?
I already told everyone
that it was a joke
Didn't I correct myself about
Cheon-ji being bullied
in elementary school?
Are you still mad about that?
No, I never heard that
It's not about that
Alright!
I'm sorry anyway, okay?
Come here
Let's sign a
Declaration of Friendship
Sign here
This certified that Lee Cheon-ji
and Kim Hwa-yeon are best friends
Hey, that MP3 player you're
getting me for my birthday
Give it to me to commemorate
becoming best friends
I'll give you the digital camera
Mi-ran, tell me what your sister
told you about Cheon-ji
About Cheon-ji and Hwa-yeon
Come and have a taste
It's specially cooked in
low temperature for extra flavor
It's really good
There's no additives
or preservatives...
Noodle, quickly
With sauce?
- No, in soup
- Coming right up
Give me a large one
- A large one
- Double portion
The noodle's cooked just right
What's the matter, 'Tofu'?
I just buried my baby
and I'm sitting here stuffing
myself with an extra large noodle
trying to live
She's watching you from above
Go on, eat
This is Cheon-ji's stuff
You live in the same building
as her family?
Her sister asked you to
bring this over for her
Okay
It's true that we were best friends
but she made me feel suffocating
She would nitpick over
every little thing
Put the box in there
I was the only friend she had
Wasn't it because of you
that she only had you?
Look, I just felt bad about denying
she was my best friend, that's all
Don't try to provoke me
You won't get anywhere
Thanks for bringing it over
- Your youngest got over cold?
- Yes
Hey, I know these are
promotional give aways
- Thanks
- Sure
What's he doing here?
He's enjoying the free buffet
I think he came to see you
That pathetic asshole
If I saved up every penny
I spent on him...
Who can I blame, but myself?
Hello
Oh, sorry
Your hair...
Can I get three blocks of tofu?
Are you throwing a party?
I'm making dumplings
And, you need three blocks?
I make a fridge load at a time
and have them for meals
If you're making dumplings
get the cheaper ones over there
These are pricy
Oh... thank you
Do you know him?
He lives next door
A man who makes
his own dumplings
Do you know what shampoo he uses?
How would I know that?
He has a beautiful silky hair
Can you ask him for me?
Should I get a transplant?
Dear me... I'm sorry
Can we have a word?
Piss off
before I call the security
You want me to?
I just want to talk
Or I'll come everyday
It'll only be a second
I'm sorry for everything
Let's start over
You've done nothing wrong
I just don't like you anymore
No, come on
Forgive me
- Let me go
- I won't
For crying out loud!
Jeez...
I miss you so much
that I can't do anything
Get off of me
What the heck?
Have you lost your mind?
Leave her alone
What the hell?
You crazy bastard...
You crazy bitch!
What's your problem, bitch?
Stop it
Bitch
Here
Come on
Over here
Don't ignore my calls, okay?
I was about to strike back
You were letting him
beat you down all he wants
I used to be bullied back
in high school
so, I learned boxing
If you cover your face and torso,
it really doesn't hurt
Are you sure you're okay?
Absolutely
Can I touch your hair
for a second?
No? Oh, thank you
That's her
That girl in Class III
died because of her
Switching seats
I can't believe we're doing this
in middle school
You said Cheon-ji's father
killed himself
When did say that?
At your birthday party
Did I?
My sister is friends with Man-ji
She asked me about
you and Cheon-ji
She hit the ceiling when
I told her about the father's suicide
She said he was
killed in an accident
I don't remember saying that...
But it's true
You said that
You said that Cheon-ji is
somber because of that
Fine!
Tell Man-ji everything
I see so much of her everyday
that I'm growing fond of her
You moved to my school
in fifth grade
I always wanted
to be friends with you
Picking out your next target?
That hurts
I heard that your specialty
was the new girls
They warned me to be careful
or I'll end up like Cheon-ji
What nonsense!
Cheon-ji and I were best friends
Do friends do exactly
as they're told?
I asked her favors and
she did them for me
You call them favors?
They were orders and coercion
I'm the only one that
actually hung out with her
Did any of you even look at her?
How convenient for you is it
that she never fought back?
How could you be so relentless
about bullying her?
I would've killed myself, too
Wow, you're playing a hero?
Whether you like it or not,
I was her only friend
Alright,
so I didn't hang out with her
but at least,
I didn't manipulate her
Do you have a conscience?
To tell you the truth,
Cheon-ji was hard to get close to
but do you know
what your nickname is?
'Free wallet'
You always buy things for us
and pay for karaoke
Popcorn's always on you
when we go to the movies
You didn't say a word
when she was around
Now I'm the only bitch?
I'm gonna tell Man-ji that
Cheon-ji was an outcast
I have the conversation history
of our group chat room as proof
You're all accomplices
That's mine
Get out of here
- Cheon-ji is coming, too?
- Yeah
Why do you care about her?
I feel sorry for her
Her father died when she was little
Suicide, you know?
Really?
That's why she is so somber
I think I heard
that somewhere, too
Let's refer to her as
'my sister'
We don't want to upset
her father's ghost
Okay
My mom doesn't like Cheon...
I mean 'my sister' either
She's smart and pretty
but her family
must be quite gloomy
Let's all be nice to
'my sister,' okay?
We don't pick on people for no reason
I hate that
You're right
There you are
Take a seat
You're late
Wasn't it three o'clock?
I must have written '3'
instead of '2' by mistake
Sorry
'My sister' must be upset
Didn't she come at three last year, too?
- 'My sister' showed up late
- No more talks  about 'my sister,' okay?
- No more talks about 'my sister,' okay?
We're just talking about
our sisters
You have a sister, too
What's she like?
She's cool
Order a black bean noodles for her
Mom, can we get
a black bean noodles?
Where's my present?
What did say you wanted?
MP3 player
I'm sorry I forgot
I'm kidding!
Who cares about presents?
I was gonna get your present
but this is just
an early birthday party, right?
I'll give it to you
on your real birthday
Thanks
Here
Thank you, Mrs. Kim
We're all going to karaoke
after this. Are you coming?
I have to study
You have to study
I did invite you, okay?
You can't say I left you out later
Look at her gobbling up
that noodle
How is Man-ji?
What about her?
It was Hwa-yeon
Did something happen between
you and Hwa-yeon?
She picked on Cheon-ji
all the time
You didn't like Cheon-ji
very much either
She pretended not to know
that she was being bullied
I hated that more
Don't say that about her
Be honest. You didn't want to be
friends with Cheon-ji but then, she died
You feel guilty. So, you're
blaming Hwa-yeon for everything
Did you bully her, too?
I was one of the nicer ones
Everyone in your class
just ignored her
And you were one of them
Only the wrong people
end up dying!
People like dad live
while mom had to die
The smell's killing me
Bring me my ramen
The fucking loser
can't kick the ball
It's right in front of you, idiot
Stop smacking your mouth
You're disgusting
I can hear you, bitch
Mi-ra needs to go to cram school
They don't have teachers
in middle school?
Did you get the certificate?
It's my goddamn business
It's me
Of course, I'm in
The dumb ass loses every time
and still wants in?
Sorry I yelled at you
It's okay
I'm going
Thanks for the ramen
Pick up the damn phone, woman
You wanna kill yourself, too?
I know that woman
What?
The woman that dad is seeing
- Shall I pay a visit to your school?
- It's okay, uncle
Don't tell mom, though
I swear if it happens again...
This is good
What a handsome boy!
Thank you
These bullies pick on him
during lunch hours
and the ten-minute breaks
And the school's solution is
to install more surveillance cameras
Have some fried tofu
Thank you
How polite you are!
Here's some pocket money for you
50 dollars?
That's too much
It's okay
You can take it
Can I ask you a favor instead?
Tell your mom about it
Or I'll tell to her
Are you going to
cram school tonight?
No
Come round my place for dinner
Your eyes have sunken
We're both busy with housework
Let's not bother with dinner invitations
I'll pretend I had it
We need to talk
It's about our parents
Supper's ready
Come on, Mi-ra
I can deal with no eggs
inglass noodles
but no fish cake in spicy rice cakes
is just unacceptable
It's good... try it
I only eat fish cakes
inspicy rice cakes
It's good
Never been treated as a guest before
This feels great
Now talk to me
Isn't your mom seeing someone?
She did
He turns out to be a jerk
I think she ended it
That jerk was my dad
I wasn't really curious
but it was your dad, huh?
You're not surprised?
You gave all the hints
My mom never knew about your mom
He told her that he was widowed
So, don't hate her so much
Bastard...
Why are you looking at me
like that?
You're so different from Cheon-ji
How?
Just... a lot
Didn't Cheon-ji say anything
about me?
I didn't know she had a sister
And I didn't know you were
friends with my sister
It's worse that hearing
she said shit about me
Did she know
about our mom and dad?
Hey! You alright?
Cheon-ji doesn't know about my dad
was too ashamed
to tell her about him
You okay?
I wasted good food
It's okay
There's plenty
I'm sorry
in the middle of eating
and it tastes really good
without the fish cakes...
but I gotta go
- Let me see you out
- No, it's okay
There's this girl in my class
who gets bullied
I don't understand why
There's always a reason
You're so prickly and yet,
you have so many friends
I don't have many friends
Don't you have a friend
who talks behind your back?
Don't be friends with
someone like that
What if she is
the only friend you've got?
Then, just stick to yourself
Who would I hang out with then?
Mom,
I think I was a terrible sister
I was a terrible mom
She reached out to me
loud and clear
But I just...
Listen
This is not
what Cheon-ji wants
But I have to know
what tormented her
I can't move on
without the answer
Lift your feet
You're not going to school?
Can I skip school?
I have a stomachache
Don't be silly
Come on
I forgot it was my friend's birthday
Can I get 20 dollars?
Oh, sure...
You forgot!
So, here's your money
I wish I was my daughter, too
I give you money for friends' birthdays
and because you have to go somewhere
It's just 20 dollars
We need to talk about that girl
What's her name...
I heard she died
I had a phone call
from your cram school
They said they can't keep you
because you were bullying people
Cram schools are business, too
When they ask
a paying customer to leave,
it must be for a serious reason
How come you're always
on others' side?
Aren't I your daughter?
I'm on the side of
whoever is right
How can I take the side of a daughter
who burns a hole in someone's heart?
Hey
Ungrateful brat
5:30pm, Queen's Karaoke
I'm treating
Shall we get this one together?
Yeah, for the two of us
For the first three to arrive!
What are you doing here?
I was asked to sit in
for a few hours... hi!
Can you hang out with me?
Doing what?
Just talk
I don't see you
with Cheon-ji these days
She died...
she killed herself
What?
How do you know her?
So, it was true
She's dead
Cheon-ji...
I'm asking you
How do you know her name?
I used to run into her
from time to time at the library
She liked to talk
So, we talked about stuff
or grabbed a bite to eat
She hated to talk
I guess she
was different around you
She said her sister's name
was Man-ji
And the girl who moved next door
is called Man-ji
They seemed very different
yet, looked so much alike
So, I wondered where Cheon-ji was
Why did she do it?
When was the last time
you saw her?
At the library. She was preparing
for her presentation assignment
I forgot something
I gotta go
I wish there was a air freshener
for the mind
Cheer up, Lee Cheon-ji!
- Hello?
- It's Hwa-yeon
There a guy next door
with a long hair? Be careful
He used to know Cheon-ji
So what?
I saw her with him when
she came by my house
I just said hello and
didn't think much of it
but apparently, they used to
meet secretly at the library
Is that another one of your plots?
If that's how you want to see it
I'm just telling you
what happened
Why are you telling me this now?
I saw him today
and he said 'Man-ji and
Cheon-ji are sister, right?'
I thought he was just a freak
but there's something about him
And I wasn't gonna say this but...
They met the day before
Cheon-ji killed herself
May be she had a secret
that she couldn't tell anyone
Hello?
Chu Sangbak
Mom, do you think...
What?
We don't know if something
horrible happened to Cheon-ji
like assault...
Are you talking about
sexual crime?
It didn't happen
How can you be sure?
What if she couldn't tell us?
What if she was pregnant?
She didn't even have period
Oh... you're right but what if...
What kind of supposition is that?
Did you hear something?
No, I just wondered
If there was a man, I would know
Mothers know
It didn't happen to her
Not to Cheon-ji
What if something like that
happened to me...
What's wrong with
your goddamn 'what if's'?
If anything like that happened,
I would
shred that bastard to pieces
Loan record?
I'm doing this for my sister and
want to make sure there's no overlap
I see...
Please give me that
Depression can be treated
Psychology of depression...
Sick child
Overcoming depression...
- What are you doing here?
- Huh?
Hi, Man-ji
Did I scare you?
Did you do something wrong?
I was thinking about something
So, you knew Cheon-ji?
I heard... I'm sorry
Why are you looking at me
like that?
You think my hair's funny, too?
Are you crazy?
I just uh...
Cheon-ji used to nag at me
to cut my hair
but I never showed her this
You can take a look for her
What happened?
There was a fire when I was little
Goes all the way down the back
My nickname was a monster
I left school and
started growing my hair
I'm sorry
So, you used to hang out with her
What did you talk about?
She hated studying
She loved studying
No, she hated it
Why do you work so hard
if you hate studying?
People don't believe you
unless you have good grades
Otherwise, your words just
get disintegrated in the air
Maybe I talked too much
No, please
Anything else?
What are you reading?
Hi
Overcoming depression?
There's this girl in my class
I'll give her the list of symptoms
If she acts opposite to the list,
no one will suspect her
Why would she do that?
Her friends will leave her
if they find out she's depressed
She hid her depression...
for some lousy friends?
People who have friends naturally
don't understand
At her age, friends make up
half of their entire world
How close were you
with my sister?
How can you know the things
that even a family didn't know?
Sometimes, you speak
your heart out to strangers
Stranger don't dwell
on your secrets
I was that stranger to her
Where was I all that time...?
Don't be hard on yourself
Families aren't supposed to know
Not knowing everything
helps you stick together for life
What kind of will is no will?
Is it 'don't ask'?
Or 'please hear me out...'
It kills me
because I don't know
Didn't I make the perfect
eggs this morning?
I hated uncooked yolk
- Just have it, will you?
- I said no
God... where did you get
that coldness from?
Cheon-ji was always lovely
She always knew how I felt
Why didn't you be nice to her
while she was around?
What?
We didn't pay attention
when she was struggling
They say you bury your child
in your heart
but I think you just
put it all behind you
What could I do?
You can pour cement and
smelting iron over it
You still can't put it
behind you
You can never bury them
because you feel sorry
and because you can't forget
Don't eat the damn eggs
How can I help you?
- How can I help you?
Yes, ma'am... sir
- Yes, ma'am... sir
Enjoy Shopping with us
- Enjoy shopping with us
Smile, everyone
- Smile
Ma'am, have a taste of fresh tofu
What are you doing here?
I was just passing
Why were passing here?
Why not?
Hey, 'Dumpling'! Boil some
dumplings for my daughter?
I just put everything away
Can't you just fry some tofu?
I want dumplings
Just do it
Oh, come on
How do I look?
Pretty
It's little too big
Man-ji said I have to wear it
until I graduate
What if you don't grow big?
I hope I will
Shall we call Man-ji and
get dinner together? Sushi?
- What?
- Where are you?
I'm busy. Gotta go
I would've frozen to death
if it wasn't for you
How pretty you are!
I heard you're top of the class
Your mom can't stop
bragging about you
- Here you go, princess
- Thank you
Your mom's in a good mood
You can tell her anything you want
I want her to stop being lonely
Maybe I should start dating again
I'm totally supportive of that
Aren't you the sweetest
Come on, there's gotta
be something you want?
What I want?
A chair for her
Let's get some tampons
I know you've been stealing from me
That's fine
Just come home early
I'll stay up
Man-ji...
you touch my heart
when I didn't expect
I don't know
It happens outside my door
Only our plates are stolen
Are you accusing me?
I ordered from you
because we're neighbors
It's just that... for some reason,
our plates have been going missing
We get tons of complaints
about our food, too
What would I do with
your delivery plates?
They make great flowerpot holders
I don't keep any plant
in my apartment
I'm sorry
I'm worried about customers
dropping out by the dozens
Who's stealing the delivery plates?
That's the least of our concern
There is a rumor that we use
rotten ingredients
Who's been saying such things?
I think I might know
I love eating dumplings
and feeding them to others
Oh dear
- Really?
- Why won't people buy more dumplings?
It's really good
It makes a perfect
healthy snack for everyone
Mom, I don't feel well
Where?
My stomach hurts
Can I skip school today?
You have to go to school anyway
If it gets really bad,
go to the nurse's office
How come you always
lose your gym uniforms?
Yes, speaking
I don't know if this is appropriate
but there's a girl called Hwa-yeon
who seems to pick on Cheon-ji
Maybe it's best to pull them apart
I see
Let the kids sort it out
between themselves
You should raise your child
to be clever, not cunning
What?
It's your fault that
you raised yours meek
Please leave, I'm busy
Shall we order black bean noodles
for dinner?
I hate black bean noodles
more than anything in the world
Okay...
let's boil some ramen then
I'll die because of
black bean noodles
Mom
What's wrong?
Mom?
God, you're boiling!
Wait for me, okay?
Hello?
Hello, is anyone there?
Are you alright?
I'm okay
You sure?
Yeah
What are you doing here?
Why couldn't you
find this yourself?
Look in there
What?
There is a note
that Cheon-ji left
My dearest sister
who I've always envied
Don't forget me even if
I go to a faraway place
I love you, sis
Second of five sealed yarns
Why didn't you tell me?
I'm telling you now
It's the second one of five
It means there are more
Because I didn't have this...
Thank you, Cheon-ji
Cheonji
Can I get a black bean noodle?
One black noodle for here
It's pretty quiet
Maybe because it's a weekday
With this economy,
it's no different in the weekend
I just moved and I didn't
come around to say hello properly
Have a drink?
Why not
I heard about what happened
I sit here all day but
news carries itself here
You must be devastated
but maybe it wasn't her fate
to have a long life
I think her destined life
was average
until someone shortened it for her
I came to give you this
My daughter wanted to
give this to Hwa-yeon
It would've been nice
if she could give it herself
I hope your daughter likes it
The noodle's on the house
- No, thank you
- Cheon-ji's mom...
Don't!
If you're going to apologize
An apology in words
is acceptable only
when you can forgive
If you get an apology
you can't accept
it'll only stab you in the heart
Especially when I have
no intention of hearing
It's just a convenient excuse
for you to hide behind
'I apologized but
she didn't accept it'
That's what you're gonna say
I'm sorry but I can't
pass this to my daughter
Now you know
why I moved here
I want you to look at my face
for the rest of your lives
Chinese restaurant
Oh, hello... sorry?
Hwa-yeon fell ill
So, she's taking a rest at home
I'll send her as soon
ass he feels betters
Please understand
if she acts strangely
The dead girl's mother
moved here on purpose
Of course, she can't have
Okay... thank you
Was that her teacher?
She skipped school?
How can you be so uninterested?
She's so full of silly thoughts
in her head
I'm gonna teach her a lesson
Will you just shut up?
Oh, God!
You used to knit
This is for you
How are you feeling?
Better
Shall we start?
It's still break time
Alright...
I'll just leave the books here
I wanted to spend more
time with you, that's all
Miss Lee
Yes'?
I'm not feeling well
Can I sit in the front?
Who wants to switch seats
for Hwa-yeon?
I will
Okay, I'll see you
when the break is over
Thanks...
This is for you
What are you making?
A sitting mat
Will you make one for me?
Are you crazy?
- Where are you going?
- She's upset because of you
What did I do?
Oh, forget it
Did we have homework
for this class?
Why come all the way here
to ask that?
Wanna go to the restroom with me?
No, Mi-so had to move
because of you
I'm sorry but
I couldn't see the board
It's always the dumb ones
that complain about the board
I can't take it anymore
I should go home
- Talk to her for me?
- Yes, miss
Okay
That's my yarn, miss
Don't knit during the class
I wasn't
I just had it out on the desk
Is it a scarf?
Just a wide plane
Alright, you can go now
So, you're just knitting
a square shape?
Did Miss Lee ask you
to talk to me?
No... to Miso
I guess it's something
the teachers can see
But I don't want to
She'll just snap at me
So, your this class'
Miss Congeniality?
Only because I'm average
in every aspect
Not pretty, not bright,
not rich...
I liked your answer
'Just a square'?
I keep knitting a wide plane
until I feel it's enough
Then I undo it
Is this wide enough
More or less
Then, let's undo it
Can I?
What's this place?
Just where the red wool led us
You didn't know you had a smile
I smile a lot
Alright
I love this place
Can I come everyday?
Of course
Like this?
Like this
I'm telling the truth
This time, she's really dead
Go to hell
No, you just had your punishment
now that your wife's gone
That's what I keep telling you
She's really dead
You're a lot bigger jerk
than I thought
Get out of my sight
Hey
I'm serious...
You tormented mom
until the day she died
because of someone like this?
Watch it
This is what I deserve
for dating a jerk?
I'll let this one pass because
I sympathize with how you feel
Hey!
How dare you?
Don't be rude
She'll be your step mom
Wait! Cheon-ji's mom!
Cheon-ji's... mom?
Did you say that your mom
worked in GS Mart?
Yeah... why?
Nothing
I don't feel well from
all the potato chips
I think you're mom
is dating someone
I'm supportive
Yeah, life must rosy for her
when the daughter's like this
What do you mean by that?
Stop pretending you don't know
What are talking about?
Why ask me when
you know damn well?
By the way, it was
Miss Lee's favor
to talk to you, the biggest
pathetic outcast of this class
But I'm tired of it
Is this the library?
I was wondering
if you had a ball of red yarn
in lost and found
I'll hold
Were you out?
It's heavy
Give me a hand
You don't?
I see... thank you
Cheon-ji's mom
Get out of here
before I call the police
Who is he?
Go inside
You must be Man-ji
What's going on?
- He's nobody. Go inside
- Hi. I'm the...
I'm your mom's...
Your mom's what?
You obviously haven't seen
my temper yet
Stop talking to me like that
Or what?
You'll hit me?
You wanna serve time
for beating your wife, too?
Don't try my temper
Who the hell are you?
I see you a lot, bitch...
What are you a man
or a woman?
A man
Walk away
It's not your business
Bring it on
Don't
Show me what you got
What's wrong with you?
Whoa!
He's down
Hit him some more
Mom!
I'm sorry...
Are you okay?
You bastard!
Please, stop
Mi-ran's father!
What?
Think about Mi-ran and Mi-ra
if you have the energy for this
How do you know
Mi-ran and Mi-ra?
Mi-ran's my best friend
and Mi-ra was Cheon-ji's
And I hate the idea of you
becoming my stepdad
She sure can speak her mind
Man...
I'm bleeding
Your dad just stirred up trouble
in my house
It's not like that
It's over between them
Maybe that's a good idea
Pack your bag and
get out of there fast
Tell them to come here
bring their schoolbags
and uniforms
They say shit happens in life
What you saw what that shit
Are you okay?
As you can see, I'm fine
How did you end up seeing
someone like that?
You must have pretty low standards
Just kidding
This coffee's really good
Is it Maxim?
Shall I give you a trim?
Maybe like this?
What's the matter?
Time for shampoo
Here
Thank you
You haven't had a proper
homemade meal in a while
It's not much but
it'll taste alright
Does your dad
come home often?
He doesn't seem like
the type to care
You used to come to
the store I work in
I could tell you're used
to grocery shopping
You know, I faltered briefly
thinking about you girls
Shall I bite the bullet
for the sake of the girls?
But after Cheon-ji passed,
I realized how silly I was
I couldn't even
look after my child
They say all the wrong doings of the parents
are passed down to their children
I don't know how he treats you
but he shouldn't have done that
to me or to your mother
He doesn't know
what he's doing wrong
We're doing fine on our own
I know, I can see that now
Your mother did a good job
raising you
Come on, eat up
Mi-ra, don't take the trouble
to go to other grocery store
Ours is the best in this area
You can't avoid or block out
someone forever by trying
And there is no need to
forgive or love everyone
Just let yourself feel
what you feel
What's wrong, sweetie?
You seem like a lot better person
than I thought, but my dad...
She must be over whelmed
by a proper home cooking
Eat up
Clean out your plate
Mom
Didn't you say you look
at the face in a man?
Yeah
My dad's not exactly...
You guys don't know
That's the look that ruled the 80's
What's this?
Hwa-yeon, that crazy bitch
Did Hwa-yeon give it to you?
Yeah
Can I have it?
Whatever!
This is so annoying
Hey, what brings you here?
Do you have the ball of yarn
that I gave you earlier?
It's probably still in my locker
Why?
This note was in the yarn ball
that Cheon-ji gave Hwa-yeon
You really can't be separated
Where did you get this?
It was in the yarn ball
that Cheon-ji gave Hwa-yeon
Do you know about this?
Why do you have it, not Hwa-yeon?
Where is she?
She hasn't been
coming to school much
So, the yarn ball you gave me...
Cheon-ji gave it to you?
'A murderer in the making'
That's a warning, isn't it?
Hwa-yeon won't lift an eyebrow
Wasn't it fun for all of you?
Are you coming, too?
Yeah
Is there nothing
you want to ask me?
If I asked you why you bully me,
you'll say you've never done that
Did you bother to ask?
For years, she wrote three o'clock
on your invitation,
but you always show up at three
You play along when you know
that 'my sister' is you
You just pretended not to know
That's what scares me
You and Hwa-yeon both think
that you can only keep friends
by picking on someone
Do it all you want
I won't wince
I'm different from Hwa-yeon
I have reasons
But Hwa-yeon, she won't realize
until someone ends up dead
Why do you always carry
that color of yarn?
You...
What is it that you want to see?
No. Mi-ra should read it
It was meant for her
I'll just read it later
I didn't know
I really didn't know
Open it
Couldn't you keep some of the thing
you said to yourself?
Sometimes the words
from your mouth
cut deep into my heart
but I'll forgive you
because I remember
the first time I saw you smile
What did you do to her?
Why'd you hit me?
I've been good to her all along
while everyone pretended
as if she didn't exist
But after I saw dad with her mom
I couldn't forgive her
Who does she think she is
to forgive me?
Are you crazy?
- Why drag dad into this?
- Shut up!
Did you play her?
It's not like that...
I'm sorry
Did you play her like a goddamn toy?
Stop it, Man-ji
Mi-ra was one of few
who were nice to her
Then, she got mad after
seeing our parent together
It was one fight
How can anyone...
die over it?
I'm sorry...
I know how you feel
but if you have something
to say to my sister
talk to me
Don't yell at her
Let's go, Mi-ra
You're so good, I hate you
She's not going to college?
She gave up college and
wanted to move to a vocational class
but after what happened to her sister,
she changed her mind
She says she wants to
go to a good college
With her grades, she can apply
to any college of her choice
I see
If you look here...
AAC
AAB
How beautiful you are
Please don't die early
You know the Chinese restaurant
outside Chowon Apartments
They got busted for using
out of date flour
I had food poisoning
from eating there earlier
Bosingak!
The one right outside the building
You came far
What have you got there?
It's ours
Yours?
Never mind
It's from my parent's restaurant
Yes. So, these are
from your restaurant
Harassing your parent won't
helps you release your anger
You can only live
by torturing someone?
This is the only way we'll move
After the restaurant shuts down
Why are you doing this to me?
Why?
Why? Everyone else except you
will know why, bitch!
Why did you do it to Cheon-ji?
Why did you all do it to her?
You can kill yourself over nothing
She was a freak all along
Everyone says that about her
Where could she go?
How is she supposed to say
how much she suffered
how broken and torn she was
I hate going to school
I hate it so much
that I'm gonna go crazy
And Cheon-ji's not there anymore
No one believe me
when I say this
No one!
But I miss her, too
I really miss her
You, crazy bitch
Let's go
Man-ji
Come on. It's dangerous
to be by yourself here
I'm so sorry
Forgive me
Cheon-ji left this for you
I'll forgive you before I go
Because you'll still be here
after I'm gone
I wish you won't do it again
I wish you won't suffer no more
Don't manipulate people
from now
No matter what glittery things
you have in your hands
It's nothing to those who
doesn't care about them
And I will make sure
that you don't wear out
and follow my sister's path
Not because I like you
but because I can't let my sister
take blames even after she died
I start now
until I find her
last ball of yarn
Let's go home
I'm sorry for leaving early
I'll eat well wherever I go
So, promise me that
you'll be strong
or I'll be very sad
I love you, mom
I love you, too, Cheon-ji
Were you waiting for me?
I'm so tired
Give me a piggyback ride?
You will?
Oh, I am so happy!
You come to me
You cold-hearted brat
Wait! Stop
Only because you're
embarrassing me
Don't push it, mom
Come on
It's awkward
As you like
Mom
Cheon-ji was in my dream
Was she smiling?
The widest smile...
We gave her a big hug
She must be doing well
My dear little sister,
you've always been
the sweetest sister
I won't forget you
no matter how far away you are
I love you, sis
I hope you're well and happy
It was nothing after a while,
isn't it?
Thank you for pulling through it