Tigers in lipstick
THE ARAB
Hey, who are you trying to fool...?
You're not an Arab.
What a piece...
Hey, come here.
Stop it baby...
There you are.
eight
Climb the stairs.
- With all the merchandise?
- Don't be ridiculous, leave everything there.
I'm here, on your right.
Do you have matches?
No.
You know, it's horrible.
As soon as I wake up
I immediately want to smoke.
Well, how do you put up with all those
clothes, dear.
I see a man in a dress
and I get even hotter.
Then get undressed... Like this...
Good boy... get undressed...
And don't you dare go up to bed
bed dressed like that.
Better yes, but...
I'm sure it would be much
cooler...
But don't say that, in spite of
everything, you feel excited.
- Excitement, yes... yes.
- Ah, I don't believe it.
How can you wear such things
at this hour... in this heat?
Isn't it too much...?
Where are you from? Morocco?
No, from Sicily.
Please, over there.
Yes, yes, that's exactly what the...
what the doctor... prescribed.
- What are you doing?
- What am I doing?
Yeah. Be smart...
Well, come on, put me down, come on.
thirty
- Yes, right now, just don't move.
- How nice...
Oh yes...
Oh yes, just wonderful.
- Can I ask you something?
- Yes, just don't stop.
Yes, yes, sorry...
I wanted to ask you about that photo.
How did you manage to put it down there
down there on the beach?
- The boy did it.
- What boy?
Yes, the one who sells liquor on the beach.
I asked him to leave the photo
somewhere in plain sight...
... was looking for a partner.
- Like a hook, right?
- Exactly.
- And they caught me like a fish.
- I hate those comparisons.
I didn't mean to offend you.
- Don't you have anything better to do?
- I wouldn't say that...
I hope you don't regret...
Damn heat.
No, no, if after this
something else will follow.
- So, do you want to continue?
- Yes, I do.
Don't stop, fan...
Well, let's see if I can make you happy....
Oh yes, oh yes, oh yes, oh yes...
Harder, harder...
Don't stop...
Oh yes, oh yes...
Louder.
You are a beauty...
Did I do something wrong?
- You are overflowing with joy.
- And what else do I have left?
A knife could help...
A knife to open envelopes?
Yes, that's not a bad idea...
Put it on my forehead.
- Like this?
- Oh, yes... And here...
Oh yes...
And here too... I am very sorry that
this knife is not bigger.
- You are absolutely right.
- Please appal me again.
Yes, yes... now.
Oh yes.
Is it okay...?
Please don't be afraid if I...
But listen, in this heat
I'm not capable of anything.
Don't worry.
No, don't do it like that, you'll ruin all the fun.
all the fun.
No, I'm not going to mess it up...
Come on, think about the envelope opener...
After all, it's what you wanted....
Just think how... this
nice breeze... refreshes you.
Are there no paintings in this house
depicting a winter landscape?
None...?
Christmas... North Pole... Ice.
How can they make love in that cold.
Imagine his hands, they are completely
freezing cold... And yet... her feet are cold...
And it's 50 degrees below zero outside...
And they... bury themselves in the snow...
Howling wolves... Frozen in
cold places... really cold.
It's unconvincing... You're all sweaty...
Now look, it's 40 degrees...
And stop telling me all those lies.
We almost made it.
Well, okay... just because
you seem like a nice person, I'll try.
A cold shower might help...
And then we'll see if I can make
you happy with me.
Great idea.
Thank you, you are very kind.
Thank you, because any
idiot could come...
You always take a risk,
leaving a photo on the beach.
Yeah, I didn't even think about it...
Even the crabs could come.
- How old are you?
Well, let's say thirty.
Yes, it's a good age...
Listen dear while I'm taking a shower...
I'm taking a shower...
...don't just stand there...
Look at this mess...
I get even hotter.
Yes, and please remove the pillows
so we have more room.
Who is it?
- Madam.
- Yes, what is it?
- There is a man sleeping in his room.
- It's impossible, look again.
- But I saw it.
- Look again.
All right then.
Mr....
Hey, uh... Mister...
Come on, wake up...
Let's go...
Oh shit, he's dead...
Ma'am, there's a dead man in your room.
But ma'am...
Don't touch me you monster...
I didn't do anything to him.
Don't move, or I'll shoot you.
No... I found a photo on the
beach... I'm not to blame for anything.
Of course he is not to blame.
You can tell everything in the section.
Just terrible...
I called them on the phone...
I sit in the street, and I see a suspicious
a suspicious Arab into the house...
Did he also kill the lady?
No, the lady, she just
lost consciousness.
Maybe it will be better if I take her downstairs
to get some fresh air...
...away from the body of
her unfortunate husband.
What is going to happen to him?
He will get 10 years.
He's not facing the death penalty....
For him, this is an opportunity
to get an education...
I knew one, before he went to prison he couldn't read or write...
prison he couldn't even read or write....
He is now a teacher...
Well, what did you see in this woman...?
Nothing, 10 years for that...
It would have been better if
stayed at home.
For a woman like that, I would agree
to do it again, even 20 years more.
Yes, he says, only because his
10 years are over.
You wanderers are jealous of me.
jealous of me.
In this prison no one dares
to dream of such a girl.
- All women are whores.
- Relax.
Since I've been locked up,
my head has been spinning.
I want to get out of here and I will get out....
That's just what the doctor ordered.
- I'll choose who I'm with...
- Stop doing that...
Soon at your service will be all
the whores of the city, if you want it.
I didn't understand anything,
others do not interest me.
I will not rest until I have her in my arms.
Gigio is a true friend,
he managed to find the lady's address...
Really great...
I got your phone number...
Once I get out of this hole...
Watch out bitch...
Why should you be careful?
Is he going to kill her?
Excuse me, does Mrs. Martucci
live here?
- Are you Fieroni?
- Yes, I am.
But how do you know?
The lady has been waiting for you
for quite some time.
- Which floor?
- 5th floor, apartment 12.
Second door to the right of the elevator.
May I come in?
Yes, come in, dear.
- Where are you?
- I'm upstairs.
Finally.
What's stopping you?
Come on in, honey...
I have been waiting for you for ten years.
- How long did it take you to get here?
- Don't you know, I was locked up for murder.
- Are you very angry?
- Angry? Honestly, yes.
Oh, my God.
Why do you always have so many
clothes in this heat.
Just look at you and immediately
it's hot.
Yes? And I've been roasting
for 10 years, ma'am.
Are you going to take revenge on me?
Maybe you're going to kill me?
Come on, you have the right.
But on the other hand, my dear, what difference does it make.
Do you want to rape me...?
To defeat me?
Maybe I'm wrong, but
you should pay my bill.
What a dramatic statement.
Now I am constantly crazy...
...when I remember how you treated me...
Which is true... But I am
completely exhausted in this heat...
- I am dead.
- Don't talk about death.
Yes, I'm sorry, honey...
But there are no dead people at home today.
Do you see it?
Whether it was released in Oct,
winter... or spring...
...yes, in any month more suitable.
There is always a reason,
it's cold, even in August.
All right then... Get undressed.
We have to do something in this heat...
Then get naked...
I like you better naked.
Of course, of course.
But this time, we will address
what went wrong last time.
- I will do everything that depends on me.
- No tricks, okay?
Like this... and like this...
This is where you will stay.
This piece of iron is so cold.
But she'll help you freshen up.
Honey, I'll be ready now.
Oh, come, undress...
Oh, I'm your slave, I'm your prisoner.
- I'm coming.
- Hit me hard... Love me.
Now... I'm coming...
Great... Relax...
Leave everything to me honey and you'll see....
I've been waiting for this for 10 years...
I went crazy dreaming about you...
Enough talk, let's make love.
What did you say?
I always speak Dutch
when I make love.
I am thirsty.
If you are thirsty, stop,
if you're hungry, dig in.
What?
An old Chinese proverb.
If you are thirsty, then loving
is not good for you...
...but if you're hungry...
I'm thirsty but I won't stop for anything.
I have left in the fridge,
some champagne.
- French champagne? May I?
- You must...
You know... You were right:
the game was worth it.
In what way?
After such an act of love,
he could go back to jail...
...for another 10 years.
Thanks for the compliment...
But isn't this a joke?
No, I was only speaking figuratively.
Hurry up dear, I'm starting
to get excited again.
Wait.
So that I fall in love again...?.
I'm not going to defend myself...
The body is in the fridge...
Take me away guys.
He killed him and then raped me....
Poor Aran died protecting me.
It is terrible, terrible.
Bitch...
Looks like you had a lot of fun.
Shut up you idiot or do you also want to
to relax in jail in his company?
Let's go.
I touched the gun...
My fingerprints are everywhere.
everywhere. Even on the fridge...
It seems useless to deny it.
Dirty bastard... I saw it coming...
He acted a little strange...
That's why I called the police...
Poor lady, how much has fallen on her.
- Well, this is too much.
- What does it mean?
I swear, no one in the world,
no idiot would agree...
...to wait in jail
for sleeping with a woman.
The guy looks like he's gone crazy.
Well, unless I go crazy
in 10 years, I'll come back to you...
...my lovely whore.
MOTHER OF MY MOTHER
- Hello ma'am... I'm late for school.
- Why are you late?
I had to take my brother to day care,
my mother is sick again.
- Oh, you poor thing.
- I'm late for the first time in my life.
So the teachers don't scold me,
someone has to come in with me.
Could I do it?
- Me?... To school?.
- Yes. Why not?
No... Get out of here...
No, I'm not properly dressed...
And no one will believe that I am your mother.
My teacher says I am the
first student in the class.
- The first student?
- Yes.
But I don't even look like
your aunt, or your father.
No. I want you to say
you're my mom, not my dad.
If you were my dad...
Would you beat me up?
- A beating?
Yes, but I don't know how...
...I never knew how to lie.
My lies are like Pinocchio's lies
I always come out...
...that's my Achilles heel.
I start to move...
Look, let's forget it...
I won't be able to do anything.
- No, he'll do fine, I know it...
- Why do you want to fool me?
You are a great actress, even
better than Wooster's mother...
Well, please, or I'll get scolded later.
All right, I hope my ass
doesn't let you down... Where are we going?
- There.
- Let's go.
Hey, come on.
And I'd better button up my coat,
otherwise you'll really be scolded...
That's... Well...?
Let's go.
Do not scold the child. Keep in mind
that this is his first tardy.
- First, he says.
- He is the best student.
- Stop it... Is he the best?
Yes, he told me so himself.
Little scoundrel... This semester
your child has only come to school twice.
Two?
Exactly... I'm even surprised
that he came today.
We would prefer never to see him again.
He's joking, at least
exaggerating... Poor guy.
- You should have read my letter.
- Letter?
Yes... The boy was seriously
sick, he had the flu.
Right?
Look how pale he is.
He lost so much weight that...
I didn't even recognize him this morning.
Well, isn't that sad.
The mother does not recognize her son.
And yet, every morning, she has to take her brother to daycare...
to take her brother to kindergarten...
...because children must also
be more independent.
You know, your family... No, our
family... It's not easy for us.
We have to walk many
streets in the rain and cold.
It must be very exhausting, but
having a husband like yours...
...the world-famous Giorgio
Salveri, I can understand that...
- Did you hear?...Giorgio Salveri?.
- Do you remember him?... Your husband.
A madman climbing the Eiffel Tower.
Oh, of course.
I appreciate his tact, for the fact
that it does not take advantage...
...your family's position.
But I have to tell you that this...
Silly, to put it mildly...
...is far behind in the classroom.
Really?
For the past 2 years, your child has
been sitting in fourth grade or...
...or sits for 4 years
in second grade.
Just don't tell me, last year he's been in first grade for 5 years.
been in first grade for 5 years.
No, wait... Unbelievable...
Maybe you're confusing him with someone else?.
If he is incompetent, why was he named valedictorian?
named valedictorian?
- The best student?
- Of course.
So he told me.
- Are you talking about "our misfortune"?
- About him...
Yes, I named him valedictorian
of the class...
...because the boy deserves it.
Right?
It burned our theater, flooded the showers.
When toilets clog, it's your fault...
toilets, it's your fault...
He blew up the lab, broke the kitchen wall and interrupted
the kitchen and interrupted Mother's Day.
Did you hear what the teacher said?
- Director, if you don't mind.
He heard nothing about it.
The last exam required
to write 82 lines...
...and he only wrote 32 or 33 lines,
I don't remember...
...and there is not a single word
without error, not a single one.
Your mommy is exhausted...
trying to teach you.
You understand that I don't want
to be too strict...
...but put yourself in my place
and judge for yourself...
Yes...
How to evaluate it.
More or less like this...
- Four... Just something like that?
- That's a lot...
- Well, yes, six... Six?
- No way...
- Maybe five?
- Four.
- Little boy, what is your name?
- Filippo.
You're not lying...?
Come here for a moment.
Here's this for you little guy.
I'm going to kick your ass.
- I'm sorry... Yes, Director?
But doesn't your husband care?
No absolutely not...
How are you doing with history?
I really want to know.
- History...
- History.
- Story.
- Shut up.
I don't know... there is nothing in "history".
Don't tell me "I don't know..."
Be more specific.
- Maybe we shouldn't talk about this?
- No.
He has always been, how shall I put it
to put it mildly, completely incapable.
- Totally incapable?
- Yes, minus another 3 points.
Three? You're useless...
What about arithmetic?
I told him that the boy is a
complete layman in arithmetic.
He... Let's not talk about it, okay.
No, it is your responsibility
to give knowledge.
I want to know absolutely everything.
No, it's actually not that bad.
His grades in arithmetic have always
have always been quite high.
What does it mean?
I dreamt that my son became
an excellent student...
And now I suddenly know, that
this guy is a complete idiot...
But why then did he name him
the best student in the class?
So, he is not the best student?
And I make sacrifices so that he gets
the best education, and he's dumb?
Well, I shouldn't say that.
A better word would fit here...
"Failed."
No, he's an imbecile, if he doesn't know how to
how to write correctly... And in history?
Only God knows what their qualifications are.
No, it is well developed
for a three-year-old.
What?
Let the baby try, look
you can count on... Don't mess it up.
- Let's go.
- 6 times 11?
Six times eleven?
I see everything, don't tell him...
The child must count.
Answer...
6 times 11...?
Don't you know... Then...?.
Poor fool... fool.
- Fuck you.
- So you talk to your mom like that.
Yes, like this.
Did you hear what he said to his
mom...? This is my son.
No mother in the world can stand it.
Take it easy. Please.
We should treat the boy better.
Your husband is a good man.
We will give the boy a history test.
Yes, he's crazy...
Do you think you'll calm me down with this deception?
Son, you're breaking Mom's heart.
She is not my mother...
I am telling the truth.
What are you doing...?
Is this the education you give him?
This semester he has never
come to school.
I'm your mother, right?
I don't know her...
My dad will put her in jail.
Wait a minute... What's the
the story?
She gave me candy and told me
to come with her.
- Did I do that?
- This is too much... Who is it?
- I am his mother and he is my son.
- She sells herself.
For sale? So your mother is a whore?
How dare you.
Show me your passport...
I want to make sure it's your mother.
- Yours first.
- Mine...?
- And hurry up... Show me your passport.
- Are you kidding me?
I am serious,
I will expose it.
Turned the boy against his mother.
his mother... I will withdraw him from school.
Come on, Filippo.
No. You can't go.
I have to look at your ID.
Suddenly he is kidnapping
a child.
Take your hands off me, you depraved animal.
He mistreats my boy and now
is insulting his mother.
- Let's get out of here, I'll take care of you.
- Wait.
And now you will obey...
Bibelo, bring back that mother and
mother and child.
We will start a new life.
You will not pass me by, ma'am.
Yes, I've passed, you idiot.
THE WIDOW
Yes?
I'm sorry, I'm ashamed to
bothering you, but, in the cemetery...
...I didn't dare to approach...
In that environment, it would be impolite.
Oh no, I've had enough... No
seem to be embarrassed at all.
- But listen...
- Leave me alone.
But his spouse never refused.
to journalists.
For the past 10 years he has been
voluntarily talking to us...
But I am not a public figure. I have
nothing to say to the nation, I am nobody.
I disagree, ma'am...
I know you've had a hard day.
But it's not just their pain.
The death of her husband is a great loss
for everyone, even for his enemies.
Everyone respected him...
Everyone is suffering.
Okay, between...
Well... Hurry up.
In a hurry... Yes.
Well, I'll tell you...
Could you wear black again?
With veil and hat, but only for....
For what?
I want to take pictures... You must
dress the same as in the cemetery.
But I have been photographed at the
funeral... Why more pictures?
There are so many people around in these
pictures that you can't see their face.
What?
You can't see it... All the time
something was covering her... Do you understand?
So you have to do it all over again.
Yes, I'm afraid I have to.
It's like this...
Let me hold it...
It's perfect, perfect...
Beautiful.
- Well... I'm ready.
- Turn around a little.
Fabulous...
I'm afraid it won't work.
- Why?
- We need a window in the background.
For what?
The sky in the background... And from here you can see
only a building... I need a background.
This must be in harmony with the view.
We need a piece of sky...
If I photograph here everyone will know
will know it's a fake.
Yes, the view from these windows is terrible.
But in general from other windows
the view from the house is no better.
Hmm yes... I see.
However, there is something similar...
I told my husband many times that
I should make a window there...
...where the horse painting hangs.
This is how you could see the sky.
Hmm... and why is this
the living room?
My husband never cared about
home furnishings.
He could fight to the death for a cause,
his party in parliament... But the house...
He was not interested.
Don't tell me you don't have a window?
Which one has a slightly better view?
Maybe the one in the bathroom?
Maybe...
However... you understand, I can not
take the pictures in the mourning bath...
- Well, in the light of the afternoon...
- The design of the house is very inconvenient.
Instead of that bathroom window
I should use the bedroom window...
Yes, you could see it in the sky
just dawning from the bed...
How well I would sleep... wouldn't he?
Okay, let's go...
I'll show you.
Great... Don't move...
Just relax.
Now add some excitement...
Show that you are excited...
Focus on that....
Like this...? Relaxed... focused...
Yes, yes...
Oh no, that's better.
Yes, that's right....
Perfect!
Please continue with the
sadness on your face...
More feeling...
The funeral... If possible...
At least a tear...
I can't...
It's not easy.
I'm sure you can
handle it... don't move...
I can't, I could never cry...
Everything happens for the first time.
Don't worry.
Look, you understand, I almost got it.
At least a couple of tears, well,
please try again.
- But I can't.
- Let's stop taking pictures then.
Photography without emotion is useless
will only ruin your image.
But it's ridiculous...
After all, I'm sad, though I don't cry.
- Here you are wrong...
- And what is it if not sadness?
To be frank, this is something of a
a sense of relief.
I'm sorry, if you don't understand me,
I will throw you out of the house.
Forgive me but I said something
about what I see.
I know it is a misleading impression.
I didn't mean to hurt your feelings.
You misunderstood me, it's my fault...
Maybe I expressed myself badly.
I understand how you feel, but you know
you know, we photographers...
...we often need to model the
emotions of the subject's subconscious.
Fabulous...
Thank you.
No, I was wrong, it looks better
with her hair down...
No, please...
There is no need.
She's an amazing woman
there's no need to hide it...
A bit of savagery...
And then, the makeup....
I should use warm colors,
maybe orange...
...maybe peach, apricot,
that suits you...
What? It's too bright...
I can't even think about it...
I'm sorry...
Don't get mad... okay?
Don't take this as an insult.
have your permission to put your name.
For what?
You know, I know a lot of people
in the film world...
And to be honest, I thought...
Don't worry, this is just a thought, just an idea.
a thought, just an idea.
But it happens to me when a woman
from the upper world...
Like that lady on the cover of the magazine.
I know her...
For me it is unthinkable...
Why? Such a woman, like
this one here, young, beautiful...
with your name...
Everyone would be delighted...
He would be a superstar.
And what should I do?
Ah!... Yes, mere trifles!...
Trust me, I'll fix everything.
- Contracts, views, photos.
- What photos?
I would do it myself.
I'd be happy to do this for you....
I will help you find your style.
the hairstyles, the clothes.
Let's go shopping tomorrow....
It's very nice, but it's not that simple....
There is one big obstacle...
My husband's name... and my reputation.
I can't assure you anything...
Don't tell me, I know.
What is morality in the world of cinema?
Actresses, after all, have to make
have to make concessions all the time.
What is there to...?
I ask you to...
You misunderstood me, but if
it bothers you, for example...
Yes, the photos in any magazine...
Here, see for yourself...
...half-naked girl on the grass,
she is wearing a bathing suit...
...and he a bathing suit...
I can't imagine myself with him,
in the same place.
Me too...
You are absolutely right.
If it is done this way... the quality...
...this can lead to opposite
opposite results.
Actresses do it because
not getting roles...
...but for a woman like you,
you need something more mysterious.
Woman in her thirties surrounded by
secrets, sexy, mysterious.
I swear I'll show you your body
and all your soul...
...and you don't have to...
you don't have to show anything...
Nothing?
Listen, could you sit on the
the horse just for a minute?
Don't move... Great...
That's it... Just relax...
Listen, do you have a separate
separate bathing suit?
No...
Just a déshabillé...
- What color?
- Beige with flowers.
Amazing...
Please put it on.
I already wore it.
God, it's fantastic...
All this...
Turn around...
Turn around again.
Yes...
We are missing something...
Ah, yes... turning on the music?
- Good.
- Lift your head a little.
Come here.
Move as usual...
I need a bright light,
soft, sensual... magnificent.
Beautiful...
Now please relax.
I have an idea...
Come on.
And now a little more independence
independence in sight.
Good.
Here.
This has to be let go...
Like this... Like this.
- Not too much.
- No, not too much.
Incredible, incredible...
Stay free...
That's it, that's it, good.
Oh, let me... And now
please turn to me.
- Didn't we overdo it?
- No, no, it's unbelievable.
Yes, we go this way.
I want you to sit down...
make yourself comfortable.
Relax... Unbelievable...
It's fantastic.
So... mouth slightly ajar...
Yes, perfect.
He doesn't even know it's
a miracle... I'll come closer...
Beautiful.
More feeling, okay...
That's it, that's it.
Wonderful...
Don't drop your shoe...
There, hold it, hold it in your hand.
Beautiful... Raise your head...
Amazing... Just like this.
Yes, that's what I need...
It is fantastic.
Lean back, relax...
You are an incredible woman.
Trust your feelings...
Good, good.
Imagine you have a lover,
who slowly undresses you...
...he starts caressing her...
She is going crazy.
It's on fire, it can't wait
wait...
And it's the same for him.
AN AFTERNOON
A BIT BORING
Do you undress?
Or don't you undress?
No. I want to rest today.
And who told you that we are going to rest?
- Well, then I'll stay like this.
- What's wrong with you today?
Nothing is wrong with me.
- Who is he?
- I don't know.
Of course...
Do you confess it?
Come on, take a walk down the street,
in front of him, do you understand?
I want to see what your reaction is.
- Did you hear what I said?
- Let's get some rest, okay.
Do what I told you,
or I'll paint your face.
All right, I'm coming.
You always talk to me about it, and
I am a faithful woman.
Yes, it seems the same to me...
I knew it...
I will fix it.
- Well, are you happy now.
Are you taking me for an idiot?
This is your lover...
Confess him.
What? I don't know that person,
and you're just ridiculous.
Dirty whore.
Oh god don't start with all
this all over again, okay?
So you cheated on me?
Did you have a thing with that guy?
No wonder when you're with me,
you're so cold, you have a lover...
How you bore me...
So you are concerned?
A YOUNG WIFE
- Can I choose the ones I want?
- Of course, Professor.
These pears are ripe...
- How is your wife?
- Not bad, not bad.
It's been a long time since I've seen her.
Yes, she's so busy with the kids....
She also takes care of the apartment.
Besides, she is still so young and inexperienced.
young and inexperienced.
She must learn everything.
And I help her when I have time.
I consider her very lucky,
to meet a man like you.
You exaggerate.
Oh, no professor, I really believe it.
Such men are hard to find.
hard to find.
Yes, most men before marriage treat you
treat you with affection and kindness...
...but then, above all,
the more they don't lift a finger...
...as if they get themselves a
slave, who is supposed to serve them.
Do you agree with me?
These are our Italian women.
They are to blame for everything.
Do you think so...?
Well, I don't know, maybe you're right.
Everyone complains all the time.
But no one is trying to fight it.
Ah, professor, this is a
gift from me to your children.
It is good that at least one woman
has fallen into good hands.
When a person plants a rose,
it only speaks of his good taste...
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
- It's a funny thing.
- Don't you like it?
I don't want to offend you, but the taste
of this cake is a little weird.
Here's the thing... Why did you put
cloves in the apple pie.
The French do.
People in other countries,
do a lot of strange things.
I wanted to surprise you.
And you succeeded quite well my dear...
I do everything wrong. I am good for nothing.
Learning to cook well is not easy,
it takes practice...
...patience, skill.
So you think that I
am incapable? So...
Soon you will hate me.
Joanna, this is just ridiculous...
Well, who do I hate, you.
Imagine you are a student.
and in the history exam...
...to some questions,
you answered incorrectly.
And I, as your kind teacher,
underline your mistakes with a pencil.
Oh, if I started to hate students who make mistakes...
students who make mistakes...
But I am your wife.
I know... that's why I work
a lot with you.
We could have gone together to
choose the dress...
It was not necessary...
I went to the center.
Why would it be necessary
to take you so far?
And to be honest, I understand better
what clothes look good on you.
Well, I don't know...
But maybe this color...
- Yes, yellow is probably better.
- I like it.
Joanna, do you think I'm going to let you go out of the house
leave the house underdressed?
No... of course not.
But sometimes a woman's point of view...
You have to forget about everything
what you read in the magazines...
what your friends say about what they saw on TV.
what they saw on TV.
You have a husband who...
wants to help you...
...a husband who can
teach you how to fix yourself.
And frankly, your husband has
good taste... Lucky us.
- I let you down, didn't I?
- No, sweetie.
- I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.
- What is it, my dear?
Yes, I understand, in bed.
I don't suit you either.
When you make love
you have to concentrate...
...you need to know the technique.
I try, but I'm always so excited.
I'm losing control of myself.
Yes, there is a big difference
between us and the animals.
The brain was given to us to
control over emotions.
- You do it well.
- I have...
A man is a completely different
completely different.
Why do you keep repeating this.
Are you starting to oppose me?
Joanna, sometimes you are annoying,
more than all my students.
- Now let's go to sleep.
- Let's not be unfair.
If you want, we can
try again.
Repeating all this? You're
turning into a real whore.
Are you going to punish me, Professor?
Don't bother me, you awaken
the beast in me...
Shh... Come on.
But Joanna...
We will play cowboys and Indians.
No, let's do it again... You sit
here in the very center of the room.
Let me read this article first, okay?
article first, okay?
No, let's play.
You got him, Mom, you got him.
One more knot and that's enough.
I saw this on TV...
...she tied up her husband,
and then mocked him.
When and in which program?
I saw it too.
No, you didn't see it... Otherwise
otherwise, it wouldn't be a surprise.
Yes, you are right.
You didn't expect this, did you? But
the joke's not over yet. No...
You'll see what a joker your little
little woman... and what she's going to do...
Now stand still and don't move
until I let you... okay?
What a strange mix: she is
great mother and housewife...
...and suddenly...
And just 5 years ago she was
equestrian and performing in Paris.
No, you can't just hate her.
No. In fact, in these 5 years
she has changed completely.
Let him have fun.
Mom, where are we going?
To visit grandma?
- Yes, my dear, on a wonderful trip.
- And daddy?
And Dad can't go now, but we'll tell him about our trip.
we'll tell him about our trip.
- Good morning, madam... Are you leaving?
- Yes, I'm leaving.
- And how long will it be out?
- Yes, for a long time.
It's been a long time since I've seen my mom....
I want to show my kids.
We are going to Venezuela.
I understand... it's wonderful...
If you only knew how much I envy you.
Yes, just put the mail in the
box, my husband can't move....
...is bound by circumstances.
THE OYSTER GAME
Casino robbery.
One million dollars.
Good evening...
I'm sorry, please forgive me.
What a wonderful night, isn't it.
Goodbye.
- How can I help you?
- My God, you scared me.
I am the princess's secretary...
Why are you trying to enter my room?
Wait a minute, this is my room...
This is my room...
If you want to be sure,
look, I have the key.
Let me see the key.
You are wrong, you have room 89,
turn the key over, and you have room 68.
So it's my room...
- You're wrong.
What a joke... Don't you think it's funny?
Whose room is this?
Look at this.
This is your room, young man.
Thank you, thank you...
Thank you very much.
- My key.
- Excuse me, please.
Good evening...
68... So I was wrong.
Take my advice, put it in the black,
it wins all the time.
No, no, I want to bet on red.
But you will lose.
No, wait a minute, you're betting
on what you want.
Let me play the way I like.
Okay?
I apologize, you are absolutely right.
But if you listen to me,
you will definitely win.
Place your bets, gentlemen.
Let me...
Madam, you can't.
No, this is the number.
You cannot bet.
Don't tell me I don't know what I should do.
I want to bet my chips on a number
above 6 and 9. Nothing works.
Thirty-six red.
This is my bet.
I didn't think about it. Why don't I win.
Bravo, bravo, you are a very intelligent woman.
Good, good.
What a thing...
How are you, sweetheart?
Oh, my poor, my good,
you missed your mother.
How many cookies did you give to my treasure?
Three.
- I asked him to give you 4.
- Yes ma'am, but...
Go up to the room,
and give him another cookie.
Does he have lovely eyes?
Let's see if we can...
My necklace...
My dear, mine is also worth a thousand,
but it's with me.
Come to your daddy, my love...
Intelligent dog.
- Well?
- It is not here.
- What does it mean?
- I'm telling you, it's gone.
It should be there...
I couldn't take him anywhere...
It was dark in there, it must be
around his neck...
Maybe it slipped on the belly,
look... Well?
There is nothing.
- I can't believe it.
- Look for yourself, it's not here.
Hi, I booked a ticket to Zurich...
Yes, on a four-hour flight...
I want to confirm the order...
First class.
No, no, I'll go straight to the airport...
Please prepare my invoice,
in 45 minutes...
Thank you.
Help, help.
Come out, come out, I don't want
to see you anymore... Don't you understand me?
You hurt me...
Don't touch me... Let me go...
I want to be alone...
Sal.
I am finally alone.
- Good evening.
- Good morning, ma'am.
- You can't sleep either.
- No, I tried.
I can't close my eyes... Sleeping late
on a night as wonderful as tonight...
...it is even sinful.
Deep down I feel...
all alone.
- What a beautiful speech.
- I know, but...
I once studied acting.
- Wait, don't go.
- But I have to go... good night.
Don't you think that a meeting on a
terrace is the destination?
Oh, you're a lyricist.
Juliet and Romeo...
And I like it here.
I want to give you this flower...
God, I'll have to give you another one.
Thank you...
But I already have one.
Please, take it...
Your presence will help me
to survive this night...
- Do you know what this flower is?
- No.
- Her name is Queen of the Night.
- "Queen of the night"?
Or "Bride of the Night", I don't remember exactly.
It all depends on the season...
They are so called because...
because they only bloom at night.
But it's a sad story,
at dawn they die.
Too bad, but thanks anyway.
Do not mention it.
You know, you are very beautiful at night.
- Only at night?
- At night and during the day too...
It is always.
I want to see you in profile...
Oh, my God...
Let me touch it.
My God, you have a face like...
a plumber's.
- Plumbing?
- Yes.
When I saw you I imagined
you were a writer...
Between writer and plumber
the difference is small, I confuse them.
Hey, please don't be angry.
Be generous.
In your arms I feel so weak.
I add wheat germ to the spaghetti.
Really? I was so sad...
I'm not always like this.
You probably think that about me...
- Are you kidding me? Quite the opposite.
I think, you have to suffer a lot.
If they see us, no one will think anything,
it's just a friendly embrace...
We are two lonely people.
I never lost the ability to dream.
Yes.
- Do you agree with me?
- Well, of course, I agree.
Yeah, I think we would...
we would be... a great couple.
Tell me, do you know how to dance?
- Yes, but why did you turn off the radio?.
- Turn it on.
It's much better without it.
It's more romantic.
Let's dance as we want...
Take me.
Strongly.
Imagine that you and I are dancing
to the soothing melody of Alice Cooper.
- God, it's wonderful.
- I feel very young.
What surprises us sometimes,
that gives us life.
How good it feels to be with you.
- And I don't love you.
- Do you really?
- But what does it change?
- It's OK.
But I have to tell you...
No, don't say it, because you don't love me....
...and I don't want you as a friend
friend, but that doesn't change anything.
The music is about to end.
let's go to my room...
No.
Look what you're doing, you're out of rhythm
out of rhythm, you stepped on my foot.
Let's stay here a little longer.
But in the room we will get to know each other better.
I beg you, do not rush our
emerging love.
- Let's go...
- No, wait. We've been discovered...
- Hide me. Could he be my husband?.
- Oh, no.
- He looks like a monk.
- We'd better get going.
Do you know him?
No... But he might think I'm a prostitute, curse me...
am a prostitute, curse me...
...or excommunicate me.
Don't be dramatic, he's just a monk.
- He was offended and left.
- Take it easy.
No... please don't.
Get a grip.
The charm is gone...
You think I'm nervous. I'm scared.
- Well, let's dance.
- No, I'm about to lose my mind...
Let's not ruin it and let's remember
tonight, these stars...
- Did you touch my ass?
- It seems so, what were you waiting for...?
Why does it always end up like this?
I'm talking about the stars,
about love and you only think about one thing.
I had the best of intentions.
I didn't mean to offend you.
No, please don't, please.
Good evening...
I don't want to see you anymore.
- Let me explain.
- Goodbye.
Bitch, I was entertained.
Don't you dare touch me, I'm a monk
and I wear a cassock, mind you.
Well... And now speak, my friend,
where is your accomplice? I am listening to you...
I don't have much time.
- Son, are there any empty seats here?.
- No.
Excuse me sister, we are on a
long road, and we are tired.
Patience is a virtue.
Do you want a sweet?
- I'll give you a blow...
- Mom, I need to go to the bathroom.
Ma'am, ma'am, the boy is calling you...
He says he needs a
bathroom, he wants to pee.
Father... Wake up...
Father.
Where is the necklace? Where is the...?
Where is it? Tell me where is it?
I don't have it, I swear.
And here you are, my treasure....
Come to your Father.
Thank God someone came...
I need your help.
What is going on?
This woman screamed, she lost consciousness.
why, I don't know.
Open the window, she needs air.
It's okay, we church servants are very sensitive...
of the church are very sensitive...
- Maybe he is hungry.
- Maybe you need a doctor?
Great idea, but it's better that
I'd better find him myself, stay with Sister.
No, Father, don't go, stay.
Sister, are you better now?
I will be well, if the Father
stays with me.
- You seem to have hurt your jaw.
- Yes, you are right, I did hurt myself.
Feeling better, Sister?
Oh, much better, much better...
Father will stay here,
and I will be fine.
In 5 minutes we arrived at Alasio.
It was just a fainting spell. God saves
and take care of this good Samaritan...
Sorry to bother you.
Hey, what are you doing, hitting me,
you knock me down... you hit me?.
What were you waiting for?
Terrible answer...
How can you behave like that, to beat...
...to a lonely girl, who thought
that you can be her husband?
Stop it... What are you saying...?
Have you lost your mind?
Whether you like it or not, now we'll part...
I'll take the necklace.
Someone is in for a surprise.
Our Brother...
He has left me.
I am in ecstasy.
And you know what you're doing, honey.
Champagne?
- Let's drink to us.
- To our first meeting.
When I saw you on the terrace,
I ended up losing my mind...
- I'm not lying.
- That's what I was looking for.
- Really?
- When I want to, I can...
Make me love you...?.
It's time.
- Get to work.
- Good.
Let's take a look.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes...
Yes, yes, yes, yes...
Okay...
Now from this end to this end...
I will buy 10 elegant fur coats, because with this job
my rheumatism has broken out with this job.
Fur coats are expensive.
Let's add a couple more.
- Yes.
- They are still the same.
You say so because it is my share.
With these I will buy a car instead of the one
of the one stolen by a bastard.
- And about these we...
- Wait a minute...
And these, I thought with these
we could buy a house.
Buying a house...?.
Are you thinking about our future?
- We will be together.
- Beautiful... Caribbean Sea?
What's so good about it?
I prefer the mountains...
A secluded place.
Let's see what we can buy...
Wait a minute...
House in the mountains.
Another one in Cortigny, it is a villa.
This one with a view from the window...
40 thousand is silly...
We can afford it... 40 thousand.
Calm down...
We'll buy furniture with this.
- How about these?
- How much is left?
What will we spend them on?
- I'll buy you a necklace, do you like the idea.
- Let's buy everything.
"The necklace stolen from the princess
in the casino - a forgery".
Well...
Listen...
The necklace, what do we do with it?
It costs nothing.
I understand, but I don't care.
It's very expensive, even if it's fake.
Why?
Yes, because it helped us to get to know each other,
you understand...
...to spend time together.
Even if we were to agree for a minute,
like two approaching trains...
...that somehow sweep through the night
in different directions, and keep on walking.
No. I was acting...
But it's enough for me...
I would like to have the
necklace as a souvenir.
- Okay.
- Let me have it.
No, I have a friend who
could pay something for it.
I can try to ask you for more.
Stop doing this...
By saying that, you ruin everything...
I don't need it anymore, I leave it to you.
Hey wait, I was kidding.
I already put it in your bag.
You are a wonderful person.
I regret having started
to doubt... What is your name?
- Angelo... What about you?
- Maria.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Let me see your paper please.
Please.
Sorry, I played a little joke on a friend
a little joke... Here.
I love a good joke.
Stop the bus.
I need to get out.
- And so am I.
- Don't let it out.
- Hey, thief, come back.
- Don't let her near me.
I'll show you some jokes,
you'll die laughing.
A WOMAN IN THE STREET
- Let's discuss it.
- Yes, next time.
Just look at that.
Hey, hello.
Guys, what are you waiting for?
Get out there with the tow vehicles.
So, Alfa Romeo - tank and wing...
Fiat 131 - front fender and tank...
BMW - hood, radiator, headlights,
pump, steering...
Motorboat, Peugeot, Ford and two Volvos,
well broken...
You did a very professional job...
So... 10 percent...
- No, no, no, no, no, 15.
Well, I agree...
I agree with fifteen...
So your share will be 1973....
Make it 1970, I round the amount.
- No, round up to two thousand.
- You are killing the dying.
But I know you, and you know me.
Is everything covered?
Well, of course, have I ever
cheated on you, my dear?
At least in business...
Take a look at it.
- Thank you.
- Please.
See you?
Good. But only in 3 or 4 weeks...
I have a lot of work to do.
In a month...?
Let's see...
That week on Friday I have
Joe's garage in Naples...
A week later in Milan...
I will call you from Monte Carlo.
Don't forget.
Well, of course... But not here...
not too often...
What about your brother's garage?
You are a genius... Tomorrow I will
I'll call you in the morning, beautiful.
- Goodbye, thank you.
- Goodbye.
I'll take care of the crashes
and you take care of the breaks, dear.
THE BUSINESSWOMAN
- I can't help it.
- Are you going to start again?
This is the woman of my dreams.
I have to stop her.
Stop, she will send you flying.
It is worth a try.
Excuse me. Don't think anything bad,
but I need to talk to you.
I would like to...
But unfortunately,
I have a meeting and I'm late.
Maybe you could make an appointment for me.
- Better leave me your name and address.
- Yes, yes, I have a card.
Here.
- Is 4 o'clock okay?
- Where do we meet?
Of course you have to be at home today.
be at home today.
Are you kidding me?
- Are you a chauffeur or a train driver?
- Musician, I am a conductor.
So you have an audience...
Pop or classical music?
None...
Please, tell me what is your name.
- Giovanna.
- So I'll be there at 4:00.
okay? - Of course I will.
Yes.
- And well...?
- It worked.
Yes?
Yes, I was just about to leave...
I'll be there in 10 minutes.
So you're coming?
Something always happens.
The oboe did not arrive, it has to be replaced.
It's just awful... Well, find
someone, you can't work like that.
See you soon.
- Perfect... Telepathy.
- Go ahead.
I'm sorry I'm late,
but there are so many cars on the street.
Don't apologize, don't worry.
What a nice apartment...
This is exactly how I imagined everything.
And this is for you...
I hope you like roses.
For me?
Flowers and music always go together...
They look good in singles' rooms.
That's what I should do...
buy you flowers.
- Do you have a vase?
- A vase...? Of course I have a vase.
While you are placing the flowers,
can I make a phone call?
There's everything here. Everything but...
...the telephone, which is
bedside.
But that's the right place...
so convenient...
I'll show you where it is.
Make yourself comfortable.
I may be needed urgently,
can I give out your number just in case.
Of course you can,
make yourself at home.
You are an angel.
No, that's what we're talking about.
It was not in the agreement...
I know...
Yes.
Yes, I remember that it wasn't like that at all....
I'm sure I'm not wrong...
No, no, my dear Macketty,
that's no way to do business...
No, no, sorry...
If you change your mind, just say so
I will understand everything...
But this... if you claim that
my terms do not suit you...
...you consider that there is no contract.
I'm sorry, but I
should have called...
Everything has to fit...
Come on, get undressed quickly.
No, no, I think we'd better
forget our contract...
No, I refuse to change anything about it....
Then we'd better forget about him...
forget about him... Listen...
No, listen to me...
I called you to sign a contract,
not to modify it...
I don't want to talk about it anymore...
This land is worth more than a million.
I know your position, but it will not
affect your plans in any way.
I'm sorry, but I can't do that.
It's just not practical...
If you want to do business, do it the
the right way... I'm out of patience...
But listen, I don't want to discuss
this any more in any way...
Goodbye.
I'm sorry, I think I burned your shoulder.
Just a little bit, it doesn't hurt at all.
I hate to do at the same time
love and works at the same time, but...
... you have to take care of
absolutely everything...
But I like you even more like this.
Sorry, I will answer the phone.
Of course...
If it's for me, then I'm not.
Hello?
We have already spoken...
No contracts with such an idiot.
We'll find someone better...
He is unable to do it...
He's going to overcharge me...
He understands perfectly well that this
land is getting more expensive... No...
There are 3 other people
who want to buy it...
He called you back, because he agrees, but now I don't agree...
agreed, but now I don't agree...
Honey, in a second I'll be ready
and you'll forget all my conversations...
No, no... What...
Yeah, you look like you're kidding...
But... Are you out of your mind?
I'll fire you...
I'm tired of all this...
I'll be there in 10 minutes...
Now I'm going to negotiate it, this will be
a good lesson for him...
Of course I will, yes....
No, no, of course there is no
deal with this amateur idiot...
It's just plain dumb...
No, so I decided that I will finally do it.
I realized what the real deal is....
Call my lawyer...
I know we're going to lose on this,
but I want you to understand...
See you in 15 minutes.
Hello.
Look what happens when you relax
you relax a little.
Why aren't you dressed yet?
We haven't finished yet, have we.
No.
- Do you have a car?
- Of course I do.
Then you come with me...
Okay?
I'll take care of this and we'll get back
back together...
- Oh, of course.
- My hero.
For God's sake, hurry up, otherwise I'll be late...
otherwise I'll be late... Move to that lane.
But you ordered me to shift to the left.
That was 5 minutes ago...
Let's be more aggressive, shall we.
Honey, don't be angry...
Since we left the apartment
you never hugged me.
- But I'm driving.
- So you don't love me anymore.
Oh, boy.
Then why don't you caress me?
Won't you hold me?
Make me light up.
Look at the road...
do you want us to crash?.
How stupid is this...
Do you know the 18th position of the
Chinese rhythm?
No.
Come back, I'll show you...
Stop.
Are we there?
No, I want to buy a
lighter and cigarettes.
You can't stop here.
I'm leaving for a minute... And while I'm
I'm gone, you see that tent?
Yes.
Buy me 3 pairs of lace panties.
I don't know what...
I'll tell you. The same as these,
same style...
You saw them today, didn't you.
Thank you.
Panties.
Excuse me. Please excuse me...
Excuse me... Let me pass.
- Hello.
- Good afternoon, sir.
What do you want?
- I need 3 pairs of underwear.
- We do not sell men's underwear here.
I need lingerie for my wife....
She asked me for french lace.
Ah, French...
Yes, we do.
- Can I make a phone call?
- Of course you can.
Hi, this is Sabinny... Connect me,
please connect me to Roberti...
Thank you.
- What color?
- White or black...?
Armando...?
Well...
Listen, I have an emergency...
A problem...
No, listen to me, Armando...
I'm calling from a pharmacy...
Can we move the recording
until 6:00 a.m..
At six o'clock...? What's the matter?
Is it serious?
No, no, I wanted to tell you that...
I'll explain everything later...
Yeah, and give the kids something to drink... sorry...
drink... sorry...
Tell them that I pay for everything...
So I'll see you at 6:00.
Yes. Bye.
So small?
Tell me something indecent... exciting.
Not bad, not bad...
But I think it is very difficult...
Only you support me...
and then nothing happens...
This is just a little intrigue.
Listen, Macketty, since you
are against this contract...
Mr. Spadini is here with me,
he agrees to enter into a contract with me.
- Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
Have a seat.
I didn't want to back out of the contract.
I just wanted to add some...
No, listen, I'm already tired
of statements like this...
Mr. Macketty, are you not satisfied?
If you don't mind...
Too late...
That's why I brought Maestro Spadini...
- You want to conclude this contract.
- Do I?
Tell him you offered me 50 thousand
to get this contract.
I...
Don't worry, no one but us
and Mr. Macketty will find out.
I...
- Well, Spadini, we are waiting.
- But...
This is a new, permanent contract,
just sign... Now...
No, I'm sorry, wait a minute...
Wait a minute.
Signature, Spadini.
Wait...
Oh, I sign?
- What's wrong?
- Do not sign.
Do not be afraid, because I suggested
to sign the contract.
- I am signing.
- What are you waiting for?
Give me back my contract.
- Ardini, was the surveyor there?
- Yes, he is already there.
- What are we waiting for? Let's go.
- Well, of course.
Let's go.
Ardini, I can't go.
But you made the appointment yourself.
But I can't give up.
Master Spadini is here.
We are far behind.
Wait, I'll deal with him,
about the next meeting.
McKetty signed a contract...?.
Spadini, you're a sweetheart...
You see, everything is simple.
There's a problem: I have an appointment...
Let's go together, we'll do a couple of
minutes to be together...
I can't wait as long as we're alone...
I'm waiting for you in the car.
Madam is here...
Good to see you, ma'am...
The surveyor went to town...
to a bar...
He said he would find it there...
He has been waiting for it for a long time.
- What do we do, Ardini?
- I'll bring him in.
Thank you... And hurry up.
- Here you can find a strong man.
- Yes.
My son is strong,
now he is in the stable.
My friend is not feeling well
needs something to drink...
And besides, could you lie down
somewhere?
We have a bed.
Could you call his son?
We'll help you get into bed.
I am fine.
You have to lie down,
and I'll take care of you.
You are crazy.
He is dying, could you take him.
Let me go, let me go...
It's all right.
He needs to be put to bed.
Don't worry, Mr. Spadini,
You'll get better...
Get some rest first.
- Wait, where are we?
- In the bedroom.
You will soon come to your senses...
That's all... Don't worry...
Peace and tranquility
work wonders. Thank you...
You'd better leave us in peace...
Maybe it's contagious, and I'm talking about him.
I'll take care of it... Thanks for everything...
Thank you.
Take off your pants quickly.
- What? Here?
- Yes, here.
Here, now?
The country air doesn't hurt,
Do you want to do it with me?
What air...?
How to smell it.
Understand...
I want to make love to you.
But anyone can come in
and catch us.
Relax. Don't worry.
- Wait, I'll get undressed.
- You can do it like this.
No, no, I have to get undressed...
it's quick.
Really, why don't you untie
the tie.
Please... For the love of God,
hurry up... We have little time.
The hand is stuck.
Mrs. Giovanna.
I told you we were short on time
time, and you didn't listen to me.
- Mrs. Giovanna.
- Wait... Giovanna.
No.
What happened to Master Spadini?
Overheated by the sun...
It's better now.
I am pleased to hear it.
We have now advanced
from quota 103 to 107...
We need to have an average of 105.
We are required by law here.
What about expenses?
You will need 20 days.
About 600 thousand cubic meters of land,
gives a total of about $ 3,000.
This can be done in 2 weeks.
I will not pay more than 2000...
Do you understand me?
- Where is he?
- Upstairs...
Follow me...
It probably got worse.
When I left, everything was in order.
Did anyone call an ambulance?
My son... Because of him, animals
can become infected.
Don't touch me, I'm fine...
I don't need an ambulance.
I'll go with him to the hospital, otherwise
we won't get to the ministry at 6 o'clock.
This is a great opportunity...
Take care of things.
- But what about earthworks?
- You decide for me.
- But what if they don't agree?
- They will.
No, no, wait, I'll take care of it myself.
- My head.
- What's going on?
The road is closed.
- What are you talking about? There's a sick
a sick man. - You can't come in.
- I am late for the ministry.
- Are you leaving?
I'm going with you... I need
make an urgent call.
How do we explain at the
hospital, that he left?
I will pay you for your concern.
What happens if he dies?
He's going to get me in trouble.
We've been stuck
here for a long time...
I have to go, otherwise I'll be late for the
ministry... See you at 8:00 am.
But what am I going to say at the hospital?
Don't worry, it's just in case
you have something, they will test you.
Hey, come in, don't waste your time.
They took me to a hospital,
they said I was sick.
Don't be afraid, I will have x-rays,
blood tests, etc.
Why didn't you say that
from the beginning.
I didn't want you to worry.
Why should I be worried...?.
Here the situation is dramatic...
30 musicians are idle...
It is 4 or 5 thousand dollars.
I said I'm going to pay... After all,
I'm in a hospital. What can I do.
- Do you want to talk to the doctor?
- Why should I talk to him?
What time will you arrive at the studio?
Don't hang up, wait...
At 9:00 a.m.
I promise to be there at 9:00 am.
We will record at 9:00 am.
Will you forgive me?
We have to hurry,
we only have 20 minutes.
So?
Our train leaves in 20 minutes.
- Are we going somewhere?
- I have a meeting tomorrow in Milan.
- What will you do in Milan?
What a silly question...
Trying to fix everything.
Take it easy...
I have an appointment at 9:00 p.m. tonight.
Cancel it... There is a phone in
the station... Have you already paid?
No... Do you want something?
I'll have a drink on the train... It's ok...
Let's run, otherwise we'll be late.
Yes...
Yes.
I bought you a toothbrush, pajamas,
bathing suit and electric shaver...
Don't worry, you'll feel better
in bed, immediately.
Oh, yes, yes.
- Did you make love on a train?.
- No.
It's great, everything oscillates there.
Armando...? Armando, cancel
the session. I can't today...
No, I'm sorry, I can't...
The only way out is for you
to conduct the orchestra...
I will pay you... It could be
the beginning of your career.
You're crazy...
I can't do it...
I know the notes, but there is a complex
piece with piano and trumpets.
It's simple: you need to start slow,
and then a crescendo... Got it...?
Don't worry, everything will be fine...
Great... Thanks my friend...
Goodbye Armando.
Come on, get undressed.
I was starting to worry...
How can you take so long
talking on the phone?
- But I had to make a phone call.
- Don't you want to have fun now.
We are at the station, you can see us.
Let's drop the curtains,
no one will see us.
Ah, the curtains, yes...
Wait a second.
It's crazy...
He looks like General Busardi...
Hey, General, General Buzardi...
I'm here, General.
What's happening now...?
What are you doing?
I'm getting dressed... I need to talk
to someone... I'll be right back.
In the meantime, I will brush
my teeth.
General Busardi. General Busardi, we have
an appointment in Milan tomorrow night.
I decided to come here and told
my secretary to let you know.
My secretary didn't tell me anything
about it in the office today...
He probably couldn't find me...
Good thing I looked out the window.
Wait a minute.
- I'll be here in a minute.
- Okay.
Maestro... Spadini...
Open the window...
- I can't go... Come out soon.
- I'm in my pajamas.
- Were you too impatient?
- What will I do in Milan?
- That's what I'm thinking too.
- Maybe it's better to get off in Florence?
Better go to Milan... There is a plane
in the morning from there at 8:00 am.
- Airplane?
- So you come back.
- And don't forget my luggage.
- Yes, your suitcases.
Maybe you don't have any money with you?
Here, give it back to me later.
As soon as you arrive
call me on the phone...
We'll spend the weekend together.
Agreed? We can't do anything else.
Don't forget to call...
Goodbye...
Why is this happening to me?
Why this punishment for me?
Why don't I go to Denmark!