Sarah, run away.
Beautiful.
Leave that.
Good morning.
How can I help you?
You are here for the first time
and do not know where to begin.
Something like that.
Allow me here to start.
How long are you off?
A few days until Sunday.
With a reasonable pace,
you get the top tomorrow.
Is there a recommended path?
- Do you experience?
Yes, we have ...
- No, something like this never.
For novices,
I recommend Willow Creek to
or Donner path.
We monitor those routes.
If you lost another route,
it may take
we find for you.
You can find a few people ...
- Many people live here?
A few generations of families as
these mountains their home.
Most of them are friendly.
Respect their country
and they will respect you.
Do you have a first aid kit?
- Yes, we do.
Do not mind him, I am a nurse.
- Super.
Good for you, the question was
if you have a first aid kit?
Yes, we do.
- Great.
See how easy that was?
Thank you
Are you receiving?
We let them in the car.
I love him with me.
- Why?
From habit.
- Are you serious?
If we have a problem, I prefer
a phone to me, that does not work,
than no phone.
Are you ready?
Then we go.
Hey, Einstein,
we will leave the tent here,
or will we take him?
I just wanted to check
or you attention.
I wear this.
It will go well.
- No chance.
School Reunions should
but for two things ...
Oh yeah?
The so-called glorious
days of popularity revive
or find out,
you're a cow,
because your ex has become a super model.
What were you?
- A 'stoner'.
And what does that mean?
How should I know?
I was always stoned. "
What do you think?
Donner The path ...
or others?
The guide indicates that the
paths have beautiful views.
Well, we are no Lewis and Clark.
Let us choose one of these paths,
the Ranger recommended.
Good morning.
Have you people help?
We consider our network
route options.
Never mind,
you can not choose wrong.
The Ranger advised the Donner trail ...
- Or at Willow Creek.
I think Sam
only those two know.
If I had to choose,
Donner path I would take.
Willow Creek brings you quickly to the top
but there is not much to see.
The path winds Donner
to Peddler's Peak.
The view there is very beautiful.
What do you think?
That's a very nice ring.
Thank you
It is certainly not a traditional wedding,
but God has the same meaning.
How long have you been married?
- We are not married.
Sorry.
- Not yet anyway.
I got the ring of my father,
then graduated.
I am a stupid man.
I gotta deal with my own affairs.
Does not, it's okay.
Which of the two,
has the most open spots?
Open spaces?
None of these two
has many open spaces.
But that path,
Timber Falls ...
has many open spaces
and beautiful vistas.
And the most beautiful waterfalls,
you've ever seen.
That sounds perfect.
But I'll let you decide.
You have no one like me need
you time.
Thank you
Yes, thank you
Thanks for your help.
'Not yet'?
You use your chances, right?
If I see an opportunity ...
That way they spoke,
with waterfalls.
What do you think?
I think you will be eaten by a bear
and that no Ranger in the neighborhood is
I and the rest of you,
the mountain down to bear.
We go to Timber Falls.
Who are Lewis and Clark actually?
You were really stoned at school.
I unwind here.
That's funny.
I am not affected,
since you omdeed me.
You know no more,
when you gave me.
February 27, 2006.
What are you good.
Hey Lonnie, Brody,
look at this.
It seems ...
whether a party is.
No, man, no party.
We ...
on the road to the mountain.
You are more on the way,
or not then?
If a peach.
You must be careful
what you are doing here.
You never know who is meekijkt.
We have learned our lesson,
Thank you.
You guys are city people, huh?
From Charleston for sure.
You will see how the others live?
We are not from Charleston.
We are from Virginia.
We are the weekend here.
And you, you live here?
It is always easy,
for city people to recognize.
They try to be nice,
but if they do not.
I think ...
You made us the scare,
that's all.
We want to go.
Can I return?
What you found, you may keep.
Not so rough.
Where are you going?
We just know each other.
We want no problems, okay?
We just want to again.
How do you think we
make problems?
I tell you what ...
Keep you from the 'spirit'?
The what?
- The 'spirit'.
Drink.
- Do you like the 'spirit'?
Sure.
- You know what we do.
You ...
Try this out, city boy.
Come on, test again.
Something you have never tasted, huh.
$ 50.
- What?
He is open, now you must buy it.
$ 50 per pot.
Or maybe we can ...
do a barter.
And?
Okay, I grab my wallet.
That's a good idea.
$ 50 seems a bargain.
Pay the man.
This is yours.
It was nice doing business with you.
Take care.
Is everything okay?
- Yes, fine.
Excuse me.
Do you know how many people they die?
I mean children?
I stopped counting.
I thought ...
I do not know what I thought
what do you want me to do?
Put the gun away.
- Disposal ...
Here?
I can not throw away.
One child, someone can find it.
Throw the ball away and when we come home,
you throw that gun away.
Please.
Are they all?
- Yes, everyone.
Thank you.
You are welcome.
Sorry, I wish you not to scare,
I wanted ...
I wanted to hack a path Friday.
The previous week,
we had heavy rain showers
and there are trees
and branches broken off.
One of the newcomers
This was yesterday, but ...
you know how that goes, if you make good
want, you can do better.
It is okay, but we thought
that this route was not patrolled.
Right, that normally happens, but
this is one of my favorite places.
I even think of excuses to come here.
Yes, it is beautiful.
There are other waterfalls,
but ...
no one calls like this like this.
You need me
to believe
look for yourself.
How long do you?
This is a short trip
We wanted a few days out of town.
What city, Charleston?
If Charleston is, I understand you.
The smell there feet.
I must go there once a year,
for my health check.
Because for one or the other
reason, my doctor here do not.
That place is not for me,
you do?
We are not from Charleston.
- But it seems so similar.
We live in Alexandria,
lying in DC.
Alexandria, I have ever been.
That's a few years ago.
I found that city fun.
There are many beautiful churches,
I remember.
What church are you?
I am not sure. Sheryl ...
what church are we?
At this moment no one.
The sun sets and the path
He was not free, so ...
Excuse me, sir.
My name is Clyde.
Clyde, you know a place where we are tonight
can camp?
Yes, tell me that you like.
I think Five Corners
will be perfect.
Just follow this path,
It is a beautiful lake.
That sounds good.
- Yes, that sounds good, thank you.
That is part of the work.
Have a nice time and care to.
Good evening.
- Thank you.
Unbelievable.
- Yes, beautiful.
The Ranger said,
that close to one more.
I would have to commit a murder.
- Wait, it's so dark.
Let's wait until tomorrow.
You know what you're doing?
No, you still see it.
That was the worst food ever.
You've cooked.
- That's right.
You know what this evening
would make perfect?
'Moonshine'.
We have a pot full of.
In fact ...
I have enough
for all the church people.
Of Charleston?
- Yes, our new residence.
I begin with you.
You want what?
What do you want?
I want sex with you.
That's not really Christian.
- I am for the Old Testament.
And ...
what does that mean?
I have no idea
but I think that the worst is
of the two books.
I liked it,
what that woman said about us.
What they said about us?
They thought that we were married.
You are stubborn.
I would not really his girlfriend,
I do not occasionally would tease.
Yes, every time you do,
I feel the bad.
I feel than balls.
Sorry, that was not me.
Where are you going?
The fire part.
Damn.
Why is he so angry.
What is it?
Where is she?
Calm down, man.
- Who? What are you talking about?
What did you do to her?
- I have done nothing.
Where is she?
- Are you deaf, I do not know.
You killed her towel
Where is she?
I have found a towel.
- What?
- You found him?
Is that your story?
Stop lying, or I make you.
I can just as well finish.
Kill me, I swear.
I found the towel on the path.
I swear.
I thought that you had in you,
city kid.
Too bad you lost your piece.
That is not every day along.
Especially when comrades like you.
- Keep your mouth.
You hope that you find her,
before I find her,
I will continue its
pleased to address to
and if I'm ready,
cutting her eyes out
and fuck her skull.
Asshole.
Where are you?
Help.
Michael, can you hear me?
Look who's awake.
Where am I?
In my house, Michael.
You scared me.
I thought that I had lost you.
This clip has fortunately not broken your bone.
You have a severe bruising.
This will not comfort you now,
but believe me, that's a good thing.
Excuse me.
This old terminal is a source of infection,
so we have to wound cleaning, right?
We will use the evening primrose.
It used the Indians
once.
To ... for everything to heal.
I use it so well.
Try to relax.
Thank you.
Thank you for your help.
You do not thank me.
We are here for each other,
the only way we can survive.
Sorry, but I know your name.
Earth,
what am I a bad score geefster,
my name is lda.
lda Forester.
I need your help.
I work as fast as I can, sweetheart.
It is not about me,
but my girlfriend, Sheryl.
You've met her yesterday.
I think it is something.
I woke up and she was gone.
I've searched but I could not find her.
We need someone to call the Rangers,
we must find her.
Did you phone?
No, excuse me.
I did not need.
I have a transmitter,
we can inform the central.
Once we are ready with you.
- I 'm fine, please.
Wil you lose your leg?
Because that is the question.
If we are ready, okay?
Bite it.
I do not lie.
You'll feel the pain, honey.
It is good.
It is almost ready.
It is over.
Look.
We will primulas to do
then you again as good as new.
Ida, please, that station.
The transmitter would transmit a message?
Of course, I care for it.
Ida, are you there?
He searches me.
Why?
- I do not know.
It has something to do with the missing
Sheryl of it.
I normally do.
Ida.
- I'll al
What took so long?
What do you, Brody?
I am looking for a tourist.
Is he alone?
He had a girlfriend with him.
I am looking for him now.
Excuse me,
I have seen no one for days.
Why are you looking for him?
He worked Darryl's face with a rifle.
He left him bleeding behind.
My God.
- He almost killed him.
If you see someone, you do not know
light in me.
Of course.
Well.
He is gone.
Brody and his boys suits.
This cousin of his, it had earned.
What did the Ranger?
Does he talk to me?
Excuse me,
I could reach anyone.
Goddamn.
Please ...
abuse the name of God
in this house.
Excuse me.
Drink this.
They are on patrol
and so will be back.
We try again to reach
and then we find Sheryl.
I swear.
She is determined to go up
and do not know where she is.
That happens a lot more.
Drink this, Michael.
You will feel better.
Good?
How do you know my name?
Pardon?
You called me Michael.
You said the net.
And earlier al
Nobody calls me Michael.
They will have your mistakes.
You should have told me.
I said that I called Mike.
Only my grandmother,
who is dead,
called me Michael.
How would I need to know your name?
On my license and credit card,
the name Michael.
If you my wallet
have stolen from the campsite,
would you know.
Accuse me of the steal
your wallet?
I saved your life twice.
Why would I steal your wallet?
Drink your primulas.
Where are you going?
- I own the Ranger calls.
I go in that room.
I can not let you.
Where is Sheryl?
She is in there, huh?
You are all sinners right.
I saw your last night,
you spuugden God in the face
and its laws,
indulgent to the sins
of meat.
You and your whore girlfriend
will pay for your sins.
Hello?
Is everything okay?
I untie you.
Ok.
Is everything okay?
I must get something
release it to you, okay.
He will come back.
Who, dear?
Fast.
- Okay.
Is it?
Sheryl, run away.
Help!
What's happening with you?
It haunts me ...
- Calm down.
He haunts me.
I can not rope to tie.
Who follows you?
There is no one, check it out.
Behind you is none
see you.
You see, there is none.
Calm down.
Everything is good.
What is wrong?
How can you let her escape,
Deacon?
If you want something
well done,
you must do.
So.
Perfect.
So beautiful as a summer day.
It's almost time.
In his letter to the Korintiлrs
Apostle Paul writes,
'Because there is so much immorality,
every man,
his wife have
and every woman,
her own husband.
The man will be marital obligations
meet women
and other women in the male. "
In the presence of our Lord
Jesus Christ
I ask you, Mike and Sheryl,
you accept the holy band
of marriage?
I ask again.
You accept the sacred band,
of marriage?
By the power entrusted to me,
I declare you husband and wife.
Why are you doing this?
We have you done nothing.
You may now kiss the bride.
You bastards are sick.
Skip never another language,
in this house.
Now kiss the bride,
he cut her lips off.
I love you.
Let her go.
Let her go, damn it.
lda, wait.
Please, do not.
Whatever you want
I will give you.
I know.
Okay, mister.
There is a chair behind you.
Sit down.
I get the mustache out of your mouth
and then we talk
of man to man.
Please, let us go.
It's not too late.
We will tell it to anyone.
How well do you know the Bible, Michael?
- Jesus, God damn it.
I said you had
careful with that language.
Get the clothes.
Have you enough?
Okay.
I ask again.
How well do you know the Bible?
Not very good.
I want you, Deacon.
I want you to fuck me,
hard.
I will tell you a story,
about Judas.
Judas was one of Jesus's disciples.
But he led the Romans
to the particular prison and death,
of our Lord Jesus Christ.
Supposedly he
now next to the Devil,
with forever in hell burning soul,
because of this sin.
But I have my own theory.
The death of Jesus was predicted,
thousands of years,
Judas before even existed.
And to the prediction
to emerge,
Jesus had to die.
I can not believe
that Judas wanted,
you do?
Not me.
Someone had to do it.
And Judas helped Jesus.
He helped him to die for us,
our souls to save.
And I believe,
that Judas is in heaven,
despite his sin.
Because he did what God wanted.
Deacon, go to her.
Forward, out of here, go.
That I'm sorry, honey.
My brother is not healthy.
This is not only his fault.
My father was a good
Christ in him.
And when that terrible accident
and all those scars.
The loss of his voice.
I have spoken with him
and others is over,
will not happen to you.
He promised me.
Son,
you're in trouble.
You and Sheryl are sinners,
in the eyes of the Lord.
Relationships, marriage,
are sinful.
And you are damned souls,
to forever burn in hell.
But me and Ida,
give you an opportunity,
to save your souls
and correct life.
But you will need to maintain
and the strength and determination
your character must show
but that you will succeed.
Because that that is what must be done.
I get it from your mouth
and we will give you some tea.
There is in primulas.
This helps you relax
and rest, okay?
Please, do not.
Let us go,
let us go home.
Drink the tea.
That's better.
Good girl.
I almost forgot
to call
how does it feel to be married?
Why are you doing this?
I thought that you would be happy.
Everything I wanted in my life,
was married and a baby.
The Lord blessed me with Clyde,
but the children is a problem.
She soon becomes pregnant,
but they do not get the end.
Timothy was the hardest.
He took the eighth Monday
This city had some strange doctor
ideas about his condition.
It always breaks my heart.
That woman is a born mother.
What exactly do you want from us?
Listen.
You are young and strong.
Unlike me.
For you will be easier.
- What?
What would be easier?
You'll get a baby.
My baby.
Honey?
What did you do to her?
They will have a few hours sleep,
but she is okay.
Here you have some water.
lda is in a few hours back
and checks to see whether you have done.
If that is not the case,
will your little girl, if you see her,
part missing
set us on the test.
View it.
We know that something is not.
Try not to feel pressure.
We are ready to go
as long as it lasts.
Just do your best every time
and the miracle take place.
Are you really crazy?
What was I talking about that language?
Deacon will be outside,
for the door.
This is the only door
there are no windows.
This room is
six feet under the ground.
You can scream so hoarse,
but nobody will hear you.
Well, we'll let you come alone.
I was almost forgotten.
Will this time be?
- Yes.
Promise me that, Clyde?
Promise.
- I promise.
Sheryl, honey, wake up.
Sheryl, come.
I was not clear yesterday?
No, I ...
Did you know what you expected?
Yes, but how do you expect ...
You have clearly not understood.
You have not even tried.
What you ask us, is insane.
You guys are sick.
Yes, when sex was a sin,
it was okay,
but now she is your wife,
it is sick?
Unbelievable.
I had warned you.
Where is Mike?
What do you do with him?
Make sure you prefer,
about what will happen to you.
What are you doing?
You do not have to do.
Please.
Wait.
You think a lot smarter than me to be, huh?
No.
- It is true.
With your excellent schools
and nice jobs and stuff.
I see it in your eyes, honey.
You will be surprised
but I was an excellent student.
Always tienen.
Except for science
and all that nonsense about Darwin.
I had a teacher, Mr. Billings.
He told us that in the future,
people will be born,
without the influence of evolution.
I ontstak in anger,
explanation on how they gave,
the creations of God.
"No, sir," I said to him.
"I am a descendant
of Heavenly Father
and not some dirty ape. "
I think Mr. Billings
and Mr. Darwin will be welcomed,
because you girl, will evolve.
Wait, wait.
You need not to do this.
Stop please.
Okay, enough.
lda, please, do not.
Do you think that I great job as you,
pain would like to do?
However, if you and your husband
not obey,
my hands are tied.
I get it, Ida.
You can not do.
There are many women that a baby
can not express.
I understand your pain.
You know nothing of me,
or what I witnessed.
Wait.
I am on your side.
Let me help you.
Please, let me help you.
You are helped by the rules.
Clyde.
- Good morning, Brody.
I was last in your house.
Ida said that al
Have you seen or heard something,
about those tourists?
Yes, now you say,
I saw him and his girlfriend go.
And when was that?
Yesterday evening,
at dusk, I thought.
Nonsense.
You may believe what you want.
I saw their car still in the parking lot,
last night.
They left not just before dusk.
Maybe this morning then
the car is now no more.
We feel something not good.
With you and lda ...
I have no time.
Let my arm loose, Brody.
What do you know that tourists,
you tell me?
I said a moment ago, I saw them leave.
Let it go.
How do you think I should do?
Wil you some extra motivation for us?
You do not want to, you have lovely bride
suffering through a day like today?
You will not get away.
We have friends, family,
they will come looking for us,
they know where we are, they find us.
Perhaps ...
but your car will not be found.
Are they gone?
What?
Yes, they are gone.
This mess is
me huge bang.
Everything is good.
- My God, Mike.
What have they to you?
- I'm okay.
You're not okay,
we are not okay.
What should we do?
I do not know.
Maybe we should do
what they want.
What?
If they stop,
you things to do ...
No certainly not.
Remember, once you are pregnant,
they murder me.
And if you like, you
they will murder you too.
Reasons enough for them
no child to give.
I do not talk about sin,
I am so sinful as pie.
I get us here,
I promise you.
Well.
Goei Demo gene, Sam.
Today is no different as different,
So, wipe that smile off your face.
Sam, do you remember that couple in Virginia still,
that arrived here Friday?
Friday?
Yes, when there was a set to
but they told not
where they came from.
The mother of that girl
this morning has been three times,
she says that she no longer
her daughter has heard.
She is yesterday and today
nor her work published.
They certainly knew that she wanted to park?
- Yes, she has a reward be offered.
Damn.
Make sure what photos get faxed,
I lies in the patrols.
It is time.
You do not have to look.
There is nothing happening.
Michael, I appreciate your honesty,
I understand you
particular situation.
But this punishment will have to follow.
Clyde, Evelyn here, please reply.
Say it ...
- Help.
Get him outta here.
We sit down here.
Make sure he keeps his mouth.
... photos received.
If you can, get there a few
and check the environment, okay?
Clyde, did you hear that?
I've heard.
Stop the drugs away.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Evelyn, dear.
When you start something with me?
With such a remark,
will never be.
You are nothing,
than a cold forceps.
I was wondering whether you guys a few walkers
have seen the last days?
What is this about?
Is that missing?
- That seems to be the case.
Why, have you seen them?
Have you already talked about Clyde?
- All Rangers are searching.
The family praises a reward.
How much?
I do not know exactly
I think a reasonable amount.
Lonnie and I will look at them.
We do what we can,
to help.
Hey, if you change your mind,
I will give you a rough ride.
Get out, pervert.
Lonnie in the car.
We are not violent people.
It gives us pain, to hurt you.
I know it yet, which Deacon,
there seems to kick.
Look, I mean it now.
The disobedience,
the curse.
The sooner you give us
what we want
the less you will
and your wife something.
So if I see it,
did you find us alive.
You need us, point.
The park staff
and the police looking for us,
you panicked.
Your whole plan is in tatters.
So stop with that
sucks rod in fire prod,
to make me afraid,
because it does you.
You are just a bunch
fucking sick freaks.
What was that?
Get off her.
Go there.
- What have you done?
What did you do to her?
Okay, it starts from the hand.
The longer your business slows down,
the more risk
that something happens.
Deacon I just turned away.
He knows,
that he has done something wrong.
Everything you need to do
your marital obligations to fulfill
than I love him from the neighborhood.
Do you think God wants
you have children?
Kill them so maybe hell,
for their birth?
Because you a couple fucking monsters,
not baby deserve?
Take that back.
Torture me,
do what you fucking want.
I will you never give a child.
What brave.
Well.
I will not torture you.
I torture her.
Deacon I can recall.
Him going to go.
There are more holes,
where you do not baby it is.
Or perhaps we shall trimming.
Everything we need is the brains,
the heart and uterus.
She has no fingers needed.
She has toes not required.
She has no need nose.
Whether the ears.
I can cut her eye.
So, you give me my baby?
My child?
Born from the marriage?
Saved from his sinful income parents.
Raised in the fear of God
and his name panegyrical.
So there you have us for?
For a baby to get
born from a marriage?
I'll tell a damn joke,
I'm already pregnant.
Eight weeks, since yesterday.
I tried a good time to find
to tell.
No, it can not.
Gently.
It's locked, we disappear.
I turn in a window.
- Save you a window in?
We can not go inside.
If you do not want to go
then not.
Then not.
Go to the lookout.
Lijster shit.
What are you doing?
He lult from his neck.
I turn him on his beak.
Asshole.
What the hell?
Help, we are here.
Help.
Ida, you know, what needs to be done.
Clyde no, I get her an abortion.
We can do her pregnant
leave and everything is good.
Abortion?
No, we do not.
It is no sin,
a devil to abort.
There is a poster on the wall, Ida.
Michael is right.
Now that a reward is awarded, believe you,
that Lonnie and Brody are the only ones?
There will be many people searching.
We must do so,
that they never found.
We find another pair.
- Not again, no.
Excuse me.
It's too dangerous.
We find a different pair.
A better pair.
It is not fair
lda ...
I go inside
and do what needs to be done.
Mike, you're right.
They search you.
But they will not find you.
Believe me, Clyde, I understand the
particular situation,
but there is a criminal
be distributed.
One down.
What is it?
There is no ammo.
No, God.
Burn in hell, Michael.
I tried to save your soul,
I tried to save you.
And what do I thank?
You kill my Clyde.
I send hand to hell.
Damn, I save it.
The walkietalkie of Clyde,
search him
and call the Rangers Post.
Go.
Go ahead.
Hello, please reply.
I need help.
Is anyone there?
is there someone who can help?
Please, please answer.
Is there someone who can help us?
Rangers Post.
If you say that again.
Are you still there?
Honey.
Have we talked?
Wait.
You did it,
you saved me.
Hang on.
Hang on, Mike.
I love you.
If you love me, fight it.
Okay? Vecht.
I'm back.
Stay here press, okay.
Bunch of idiots.
Come on, Mike, are fighting.
ONE YEAR LATER ...