(CLOCK TICKING)
(BRUSH TAPPING)
- (POUNDING)
- MAN: Dude!
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
Yeah, don't get up.
I got it, bro.
(DOOR SLAMS)
Wow.
Damn, Finn.
This must be your best one yet.
How long you been workin' on this?
Like two, three weeks?
Fuck off. I don't go to
the bar and complain
when it takes you 10
minutes to make a martini.
(PHONE RINGS)
I'm perfectly happy
with where I'm at.
I just hit a little
creative block. That's all.
(BEEPS) Hello?
Oh, hi,
Mrs. Anderson.
Why, yes. The building
manager's right here.
Oh, I'm sure he'd be delighted to
come over and fix your toilet.
He's givin' me the thumbs up right now.
He'll be over in a second.
(BEEPS) You were saying
something, right?
About you being perfectly happy
with where you're at in life?
Hello.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, he said he was thinking
of going to art school.
And I said, “Oh,
what a coincidence!
Our building manager
used to be a painter.”
(CHUCKLES)
When you're 18, everybody
wants to be an artist.
- Shh!
- FINN: Where did you get that?
Garage sale.
So weird.
I'm seeing-
I'm seeing...
seashells.
Outlaw,
Rambling Rose, Crab Apple.
Crabs live in the fucking ocean, right?
Yes, they do.
Crab Apple.
I'm betting on Crab Apple.
Hello, my lost boys.
- New sweater.
- New for me.
It's a thrift store find.
You like it?
Oh, uh, I had a little left over,
so I got these for you, babe.
It's the right kind.
Camel hair, right?
Thank you.
Did you get a new journal?
Oh, I knew how much you wanted
them, so I couldn't resist.
(KISSES)
Okay, uh, I'm going to
go start dinner.
Do you guys want
your favorite, lasagna?
(VIDEO GAMES)
(EXPLOSIONS)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(GRUNTS)
Need some help?
Hey, Big Joe.
Yes, I do.
Thank you.
(PANTING)
(BELL RINGS)
(MAN SPEAKING RAPIDLY)
MAN: Eight is really gettin'
taken-Come on. Come on.
Come on.
That's it.
You got this. Keep fuckin' running.
Let's go.
Come on.
What's up?
Uh, hey, Big Ben.
Come on.
Uh, it's Joe.
Crab Apple. Crab Apple. Come
on, you little bastard! Run!
Ah, come on!
Run!
Come on!
Fuck, man!
Chill out.
WOMAN: Hey, Finn, the landlord called.
Mr. Bezzerides's rent is late.
M-Maybe he fell,
and he can't get up.
Eh, he's been late before.
Oh, the man across the way?
Yeah.
I noticed a couple of
parking tickets on his car.
I guess he's got a couple
parking tickets on
his car, so maybe we
should check on him.
And I also invited Big Joe
to stop by the party.
Okay, but I hope he doesn't wear
that tacky rent-a-cop uniform.
I thought we were just
inviting close friends.
Yeah, uh, well,
Big Joe's really cool.
And he's helping me with the chairs.
He's standing here right now.
Don't worry.
I own other outfits.
I'm sorry.
I'm just gonna...
go check on Mr. Bezzerides.
Okay then.
Hey, Mr. Bezzerides,
are you home?
Everyone's kinda
worried about you,
so I'm going to go ahead
and come inside, okay?
Mr. Bezzerides?
(GROWLING)
(LOUD CLANKING)
It was a sure thing.
No, it obviously wasn't a sure thing.
He lost, Jasper.
No, he was a sure thing
up until the moment he lost.
That makes zero sense.
(DOOR OPENS)
What the fuck?
These are shots
of our living room.
(CHUCKLES)
Mr. “Bitch-arabies” is a peeping tom.
Yeah, I though that, too, but why
take photos of our empty living room?
Looks like he saved the best
ones for his private collection.
What is this thing?
I-I think it's a camera.
See?
Cripes.
You think he got enough film?
Hmm.
WOMAN: What? Do I even want to know?
When did we knock over
the coat rack?
Maybe it was that night we played
drunk charades. You remember.
No, he doesn't remember 'cause
he passed out on the couch.
Well, I guess this explains the green
light we see over here sometimes.
Yeah, but why is this thing
bolted to the ﬂoor?
I don't know,
but I don't like it.
I don't like the sound
it's making either.
Uh, or how about the half-naked
photos of me on the wall?
That's the one thing I do like
about this situation.
(SIGHS)
I knew something wasn't right
about that old man.
Hi, Mr. Kendall, this is Finn
from Sycamore Apartments.
I'm calling you back
about Mr. Bezzerides.
If you can please ring me when you
get a chance, that would be great.
Thank you.
What did the landlord say?
I just left a voice mail.
Okay.
I'm off to work.
I counted the cookies,
so if any go missing,
there will be murder
in this apartment.
I'll guard 'em. Well, who's
going to guard 'em from you?
(GASPS)
(SCOFFS)
it's a perfect match.
It's got to be a coincidence.
FINN: Maybe. Or-
Or what? The camera took
a picture ahead of time?
(SCOFFS) Give me a break.
I mean, just look at it.
The placement of everything,
my canvass.
Your canvass has looked
like that for months.
(WHIRRING)
Uh, hey, guys.
(CAMERA CLICKS, WHIRRINGS)
(BULB POPS)
(WINDS DOWN)
No way.
WOMAN: Oh, my God.
This was last Wednesday. Remember you
broke the mug with your four-iron?
Oh, yeah, right.
Thursday.
Friday we went to the movies.
Saturday we lost power,
used candles.
Sunday.
Monday.
That's tonight, Tuesday.
Tomorrow.
Bullshit.
Mr. “B” invented a camera that
takes pictures of the future,
and he only used it
to look in our apartment?
Doesn't make any sense. Well,
maybe he's testing it.
Yeah, and this thing
isn't exactly portable.
Well, he's a scientist,
so there's got to be some sort of
logs or documentation somewhere.
Just start looking. Will you
guys listen to yourselves?
All right.
Come on out, Mr.
I know you're fucking in here in the walls
or something, laughing your ass off!
The jig's up!
Come on out, asshole!
WOMAN: I don't think
he's going to answer.
Why?
“November 27.
Results today:
Positive function.
The machine continues
to work perfectly.
However, I've seen something in the
future that is disturbing to my core.
I believe I've seen my death.
I know the cardinal rule
of time and causality...
is that one should not attempt
to change the future.
But under these circumstances, it
seems to be a risk worth taking.
If I believed in God,
I would pray today that no greater harm
will come from what I'm about to do.”
Then what?
Nothing. That's the last
entry, a week ago today.
A week ago.
Seven photos. That means it was
kicking it out after he disappeared.
So it must be on a timer.
8200 PM.
Then why are there
so many daytime ones?
Maybe it's only been taking ones
at night for the last week.
All right.
Even I have to admit this photo
is a little fucking unsettling.
FINN: I think I know
where he might be.
(KEYS JINGLING)
JASPER: Christ. What's
he keeping in here?
FINN: I don't know.
Him and the previous manager
added this door years ago.
God, please, oh, please,
don't let him be in there.
There's no way. If there was a dead body
in there, we'd be able to smell it.
(GASPS)
Oh, God. What?
Is he in there?
Oh, my God.
Close it, close it.
What happened to him?
It looked like he was burned.
Yeah, I don't know about that.
Did you see his suit? It was fine.
It wasn't even touched.
Isn't it obvious? I mean,
you read his journal.
He broke the cardinal rule.
You don't fuck with time.
Jasper,
please take his hat off.
It's my thinking cap.
What the hell is there to think about?
We need to call the police, guys.
Hang on.
That could be a big mistake.
What do you mean?
I mean, we just discovered
a fucking time-traveling camera!
We need to consider
the possibilities.
Well, one possibility is we've all been
dosed with lethal amounts of radiation...
that, you know,
could've killed Mr.
Okay, Negative Nancy, but what
if we could use this thing?
How?
Remember how Mr. “B” took a photo
of himself holding that sign?
What if we put up, like,
the newspaper?
We would know what happens
in the future.
Yeah, the newspaper, Jasper?
What are you thinking?
Arts and Entertainment?
- Or are you thinking the race results?
- Oh.
Well, what if?
Think about how much money
we could make.
Callie, I foretell that tonight is
your last night waiting tables.
And instead, you can
pursue writing full time.
Callie?
No! Absolutely not!
We're calling the police.
Finn, I foretell that you live the rest
of your life in pathetic obscurity...
and die penniless and insane.
- I'm serious, Jasper.
- So am I.
Does it look like
the cops are here?
That people are buzzing about the
charred corpse in the storage unit?
Everything looks fine.
If we reported it, we probably
wouldn't have had the party anyway.
We'd have canceled it
altogether.
Uh, we can't cancel it. It's Dave
and Sharon's engagement party.
That's what I'm saying.
Obviously,
we don't report it tonight.
There is a dead fucking st-rotting
corpse in the storage unit.
You can't smell anything as long
as we keep the door closed.
Wow.
It's been down there a week.
What's one more day?
Uh-uh.
Look.
We let the party happen,
we look at tomorrow's photo...
and if it shows the cops taking our
testimony and shit, I'll call 'em myself.
I have to admit. I am kind of
curious to see one more photo.
All right. Fine.
One day. But... one day.
(MUSIC)
- What time is it?
- Twenty till.
Well, just in case tomorrow's
photo shows the end of the world-
(INHALES)
I'm going to enjoy myself.
Do you want to dance?
And he adopts his classic
glazed-over look.
What?
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MUSIC)
(LARGE CAMERA WHIRRS)
(BULB POPS, WINDS DOWN)
Hmm.
You son of a bitch.
(MUSIC)
Guys! Guys!
I'm a fucking genius. I know,
but look at that painting.
Holy shit!
I know. I mean, the camera
sees my work before I do it.
It's just incredible. I don't
have to be blocked anymore!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
I'm in.
(CHUCKLES)
Yes!
Yes.
(CHUCKLES)
(HOWLS)
(SIGHS)
(GLASS CLINKS)
You're up early.
What time is it?
How about we start with
what year is it?
Oh, so you can write
in a dead man's journal,
but I'm not allowed
to wear his hat?
This isn't poetry, Jasper,
I'm making
our to-do list.
If we're really
going through with this,
we need to start making it look
like Mr. B's still around.
I mean, this is
actually happening?
What are you talking about, bro?
It already happened. It's done.
Well, I mean, we could just
not go through with it.
Actually, I think we have to.
If I understand this correctly,
this is how it works.
The camera spits out a
photo of us in the future.
Then we go about our day making a series of
decisions that lead up until that moment.
But if we deviate
from those decisions,
then this photo never happened.
Which means “us,” the people who saw
the original photo, can't go forward.
Because our futures
don't exist anymore.
Um, what do you mean
“can't go forward”?
I mean, are we 100% sure
that's how he died?
No, but do you really want
to test it and find out?
So it's agreed then.
We got to do
what's in the photo.
(SIGHS)
Okay, all right, fine.
We have to do this tonight.
But we're talking about
not reporting a dead body.
I'm pretty sure if anybody found
out, Jasper, that's jail time.
Okay, but nobody's
going to find out.
I-I was over there this
morning to make a list.
All we have to do is bring in his
newspapers, water the plants.
We should probably move his car so
it doesn't get any more tickets.
Um, I found
a couple pieces of mail.
Maybe a couple bills,
so I should probably post them.
(SIGHS)
Well, you seem to have
everything figured out. Dude.
Just relax, man.
- The risk is so minimal, it's almost nonexistent.
- (SCOFFS)
All we have to do is make sure that
storage unit door stays closed,
and... we become rich.
And you get your paintings.
Yeah.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Bobcat!
Fuck, yes! Fuck, yes!
(GRUNTS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(CLOCK TICKING)
FINN: All right, let's go.
It's almost 8:00.
CALLIE: Do we have to
be exactly as we were?
I don't want to change anything.
(EXHALES) I don't know.
Is this right? Just smile and say
good-bye to your day jobs, guys.
I mean, we can check the photo.
It's right there.
(PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
(ANSWERING MACHINE CLICKS, BEEPS)
WOMAN: Henry?
Henry, are you there?
It's Joyce.
I received your letter.
C-Could you check in please
when you have time?
I truly hope you're okay.
(CLICKS)
Hey, Finn!
Hey, Joe.
How's it going?
Hey, what's going on
with the old man?
I see Callie coming around here
in the mornings.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Uh, he's sick in the hospital.
We just come by to water his plants
and look after the place for him.
Hospital?
Is it serious?
Uh, yeah, it's pretty serious.
They're still trying to
figure out what he has.
Damn.
(SIGHS)
It's good you guys
are looking after the place.
Yeah. I mean,
we don't mind, so-
(CLEARS THROAT)
But I better get back to it.
No, dude. We're over here tonight because
we're not in the photo from last night.
It's that simple. Well, it's
not like fate decided it.
Presumably, we made decisions yesterday
that made us end up here today.
All right, my brain
just kinda melted a bit.
What was the original question?
The question is, if you
could choose something
to show up in the
next photo, anything,
what would you choose to see?
I'm a little ashamed at how
good it felt to buy this dress.
Back to the question.
Easy.
I want a pile of money so big
that I'm fuckin' buried in it.
You are so predictable.
Me?
What about you?
We all know
what you wanna see most.
A rock.
(SCOFFS)
So you and Finn don't have
to keep living in sin.
Whatever.
- You hear that, Finn?
- What?
You're off the hook.
Oh, he's just daydreaming about two
paintings a day instead of one.
Well, I don't know. Just give a guy
a second here. I need to think.
(WHIRRING, CLICKING)
Ah, I never get tired
of that sound.
(BULB POPS, WHIRRS)
Finn.
All right, come on, guys.
It's not like I want to do this.
Okay, then let's not do it!
Uh, do I need to remind you about the
roasted dead guy in our basement?
We got to do what's in
the photo, right, bro?
How the hell did this happen?
I don't know.
Maybe it's a fucking dare.
- Maybe we're drunk.
- Maybe it was an accident.
It's a fucking lip lock. We
didn't just bump into each other.
Say something, Finn.
We should destroy that machine.
What?
We can't do that.
I know.
It's too late.
It doesn't matter
why we do this.
For all intents and purposes,
it already happened.
(INHALES)
I mean...
I'm in the room.
I don't look mad or pissed.
(CLEARS THROAT)
The painting's
coming out great.
Yeah. The painting's
You probably asked us to do it
for inspiration or something.
We're all friends.
And we just need to trust
that it's going to be okay.
Fuck! What the
fuck was that for?
(SIGHS) That's for kissing
my girlfriend tomorrow.
T-minus one hour,
in case you were wondering.
Please, stop counting down like
it's a fucking shuttle launch.
- Sorry.
- JASPER: Yeah, yeah.
I told you Crab Apple was a sure thing.
He just needed a few more races.
Let's roll half the
winnings into tomorrow's
bets, and I'll come
pick up the rest.
Uh-huh.
Okay, yeah. Um, let me just
get something to write on.
I thought there wasn't
a bottle in the photo.
That's because
it was down here.
What time is it, babe?
Finn, you okay?
Yeah, uh, no. It's this part of
the painting-it's unfinished.
I'm clearly about to paint it.
I just have no idea
what element goes there.
Okay, Michelangelo, but we have to
close our eyes to match the photo.
So you're the timekeeper.
Well-
(SCOFFS)
Yeah, dude, it's 7:59.
Just go ahead.
Well, how long do we do it for?
10, 15 seconds?
I'll tell you when to stop.
Just go.
(EXHALES)
I'll be thinking
about my boyfriend.
Sweet.
Threesome.
(SCOFFS)
Come here, asshole.
(GASPS)
Oh! Of course.
Oh, geez,
did you guys-
Hey!
(GASPS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
Shit.
- Finn.
- Go get Jasper.
I just wanted to-
Go get Jasper!
- Finn, I'm sorry.
- Who is this?
That's my bookie.
Ivan.
The guy you're always
talking on the phone to?
What is he doing
in the apartment?
- I don't know.
- Is that normal?
Have you ever seen him
in our apartment before?
No.
It's not fucking normal.
Did you tell him
about the camera?
No.
- Were you planning on it?
- No, never!
Then what the fuck is he
doing in the apartment?
I said I don't know!
Okay, is he dangerous?
Well, he takes bets from
shady assholes like me.
So, yeah, he's dangerous.
But...
I don't see Marcus here.
That's his goon.
If I were in trouble,
he'd be in this photo.
Well, what if he's sitting over here?
Out of view?
(CHEWING)
I was up early this morning, and I
heard him moving around in his room.
He came out about an hour ago.
Hasn't said a word.
I don't know what those red pills are, but
he's taken at least two of them already.
(SIGHS)
Can you guys shut up for a sec?
(DIALS)
(BEEPS)
MAN: Yeah?
Hey, Ivan, it's Jasper.
I know.
How's it going?
What?
Uh, is everything okay today?
Why wouldn't it be?
No reason.
So, what do you want
to lay down today?
Uh, no. No bets.
I'm just going to cool it today.
Thanks.
So why did you call me?
Uh, shit. I got to go, Ivan.
I'll talk to you later.
So what does that mean?
It means we wait 10 hours, figure
out what the hell's happening.
Babe, can we talk?
(SIGHS)
MAN: ♪ Spider ♪
"♪I am a sniper."
♪ Waiting to spring ♪
Hey, Ivan.
What a surprise.
I was wondering why you showed up
tonight, and then it occurred to me.
It's probably 'cause I called you
like a paranoid fucking idiot.
(HITS WALL)
Hey, Ivan.
What a surprise.
What are you doing?
He's going to be here soon.
You can't leave me alone.
Well, I'm not in the picture, so, send
me a text message when it's done?
Well, I-
I'm not in the photo
either, so...
maybe I should leave too?
Where are you going?
I don't know yet.
Can I come?
You guys are unbelievable.
Real friends
you turned out to be.
Well, we got to do what's in the photo.
Right, bro?
Where we going?
Nowhere.
I don't want to abandon Jasper
in case something goes wrong.
Are we okay?
I got jealous.
This is a-
it's a very complicated
situation.
You're doing your best.
And I, obviously, am-
I'm not handling it well.
(SIGHS)
You got jealous?
(EXHALES)
Tell me more.
So, Ivan,
I mean, what a surprise.
You said that already.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, can I get you
something to drink?
You know what I like
about you, Jasper?
You never welched on a bet.
I have never had to send Marcus
over here to collect.
And I can appreciate that.
I can.
Is that yours?
You mind if I see it?
(CHUCKLES)
Come on.
Let me see it.
That's a nice one.
Yeah.
That takes me back.
Believe it or not,
I used to have Marcus's job.
I wasn't a bad enforcer.
I had my own style.
You know,
I used warm-up bats.
They gave me
a little extra “pop.”
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
There was this one time-
God Almighty-
I was supposed to
“kneecap” a guy.
Standard boilerplate stuff. I'd
done it a hundred times, right?
Only this time, I take a
swing, I hit him-Bam!
And the bat breaks.
It sends a sliver of wood
right into the guy's junk.
Oh!
(CHUCKLES)
You should have heard him.
He was screaming like a cat.
I swear to God, as I heard the
paramedics take him away-
They said that one of his testicles had
swollen to the size of a grapefruit.
You imagine that?
That pain?
(SCOFFS)
(SIGHS) Messy.
Messy, unfortunate work.
In my position,
there's only one thing worse than a
guy who can't make good on bets.
And that's a guy
who never loses bets.
(CLOCK TICKING)
I-I'm just finally
getting lucky, I guess.
Just lucky.
You guess.
Listen!
There's no fix, okay?
Is it an owner? Huh?
No!
I swear! Fuck,
it was just a streak, okay?
Look, okay, okay! I have a source!
I have a source.
It's reliable.
I can't explain it.
It could cause
some serious problems.
Was it a doctor? Tell me what
they're doing to bring in the fix!
No, it-
it's nothing like that.
Look, you wouldn't believe me
if I told you.
Bullshit.
(GRUNTING)
Can't you just ride my bets?
Yeah. Just make the same bets I
do and-I know what “ride” means.
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
You are such a piece of shit.
I hope you enjoyed
the peep show, Jasper!
I'll... take that.
- Finn, this is-
- IVAN: I was just leaving.
So... are we good?
So-
(SIGHS) He basically knows.
He doesn't know jack shit.
FINN: Well, he knows that you
have some kind of information.
How long is he going to be content
just piggybacking your bets?
I don't know.
Forever?
I got it under control.
You look like hell, Jasper.
Are you even sleeping?
You know what, man?
Get off my dick!
You and Callie both get all
this money for doing nothing.
- You should be happy.
- We're all in this.
Callie and I
are sharing the risk.
I hope you have a back-up plan in case
this thing with your bookie falls through.
I seem to remember you wearing something
a little different in tonight's photo.
Screw you, Jasper.
I'm not going to start
as long as he's here.
Yeah, no, Jasper was just about
to take a walk. Aren't you?
I am?
Yeah.
Yes, don't forget to
come spy on me at 8:00.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SIGHS)
So I don't really know
what I'm doing here.
You're going to have to
walk me through it.
Sure.
Um, we just need to get you
in the same pose in the photo.
And then I-
I do the rest.
You know, I'd really like to
know how you got me to do this.
You and I both.
What are you thinking?
You're just-
You're really-
You're very beautiful.
Don't sound so surprised.
(SCOFFS) No.
No, I guess it takes a moment
like this to wake a guy up,
so he can actually see what's
right in front of him.
That's our cue.
(GASPS)
(LIGHTER FLICKS)
IVAN: it's amazing.
Even hazy and out of focus,
you can still recognize
your own silhouette.
I wondered all day-
How?
How is this possible?
So, Marcus here
is going to babysit.
And you-
You're going to take me
to see what's over there.
(IVAN CHUCKLES)
I would not have believed you
if you'd told me.
Kicks them out
every night at 8:00.
Yeah.
What about the daytime ones?
I don't know.
Since we found it, it's only
been doing 'em at night.
What's this?
Uh, it's-
it's the newest one.
Okay-
Here's the deal.
Every day you're going to
take this photo.
And you're going to write down the
stats that go on the window tomorrow.
Marcus is gonna come by and pick
up the photo for safekeeping.
Wait-Wait a second. I am
not going to repeat myself!
The three of you are going
to sit right there,
just like that on the couch
so I know you're behaving.
And you tell no one about this.
We wouldn't want anyone messing with
our little golden goose here, huh?
Now, would we?
I want 50%.
(CHUCKLES)
You take a zero
off that number.
That still makes you
a very lucky man.
Yeah, I feel real lucky.
We didn't agree to this.
(SIGHS) You should have
talked to us, man.
I did my best, okay?
We're still
going to get some money.
He's going to be making
a lot of bets. It'll be fine.
What happens when the guy above
him gets wise to what's going on?
How many more scary motherfuckers
are gonna show up here...
looking for a piece of this?
Ivan's smart.
He's not going to fuck this up.
Oh, that's very reassuring.
(SIGHS) it's unbelievable.
Where's the photo
from yesterday?
Wait, you're not seriously going to
paint at a time like this, are you?
Yeah. I mean, what else
am I supposed to do?
We obviously have no control
over what's happening.
He's keeping the photos.
For safekeeping.
No! That is totally
unacceptable.
Call him right now.
Call him.
Tell him we'll put up
the results on the
window, but we're keeping
the goddamn photo.
Are you a fucking child?
You're aware of who's on the
other end of this phone, right?
I'm gonna make some tea, babe.
Do you want anything?
(SIGHS) You know, you were
always doing the paintings.
You were just seeing
what you'd already done.
(BANGS) I-I know. I'm
aware of that, Callie.
That's what's so maddening.
I painted them in the future.
Now I can't see the photograph,
I end up not painting.
Jasper?
What?
Can't you just, like, sneak a photo
of the Polaroid when it pops up?
Just grab one on the phone?
Since you don't see
the picture today,
there won't be a painting
for me to photograph tomorrow.
There will be, if you agree to
take the fuckin' photograph.
Look, man, I mean-
(SCOFFS)
If your decisions are gonna
continue to dictate my future,
can you at least make one
that benefits me?
And risk my neck being broken just
'cause you can't find your mojo?
Fuck that.
Can't you just be happy
with the money?
No. I can't, Jasper. I don't
give a shit about the money.
At this point,
I'd rather call the police,
or fill a bucket of water...
and spill it all over
your precious machine.
Is that a fuckin' threat?
No, it's not.
But you can't ignore the fact that...
some of us aren't making out
on this deal very well.
I'll see what I can do.
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(CLICKS)
(KNOCKING)
(PHONE BUZZING)
There's a painting.
Thank the Lord.
How about thank the Jasper?
Hmm.
What now? Oh, it's just
it's kind of strange.
Doesn't look like something
I would normally paint.
It looks like
you did it in a hurry.
See? That paint's still dripping.
Hmm.
Maybe it's a warning.
About what?
Maybe something bad's
about to happen.
You're sending us
a warning. Look.
We look scared, right? And I'm
staring up at that painting.
I'm trying to
tell myself something.
I mean, we don't look happy,
but the situation
isn't exactly ideal.
No.
You said it yourself, Finn. That's
not something you'd normally paint.
Yeah, but art's weird, man.
I'm just-
I'm glad that there's
something on the canvas.
CALLIE: Just relax, Jasper.
What if Jasper is right?
What if something terrible
is gonna happen tomorrow?
Then we wouldn't be
in the photo, right?
We'd have left.
Okay. Why don't we?
What, leave?
Yeah.
We can pack our bags
and just go.
Well, and what?
Just... leave Jasper to deal
with everything on his own?
Oh. He wouldn't care.
He'd be fine.
That machine over there,
I mean-
We can't just walk away from it when
there's still hope for things to work out.
I don't see why we'd do that.
Okay. I trust you.
Besides, you have to admit, this
machine, it's working magic on you.
What can I say?
I like being a muse.
(GIGGLING)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
Bye.
Hey, Joe.
Uh, you on duty tonight?
Actually, yesterday
was my last shift,
so I'm just
dropping off the keys.
Last shift?
Yeah, man.
Movin' up to the big time.
Oh, shit. Congratulations.
That's great.
Awesome.
Everything all right?
Yeah. Yep.
Oh, oh, hey.
Let me give you
one of my cards.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Let's have a drink sometime.
Yeah.
Stay in touch, man.
You too, Joe.
Yeah.
(PHONE BEEPS)
What's wrong?
Um, Marcus just caught me
talking to Big Joe.
- What the fuck happened?
- Well, nothing happened.
It's just-it's Big Joe's last
night, so he gives me his card.
What did Marcus do? He-He made
a phone call. He drove off.
Motherfucking shit fuck!
Well, wait. Can't we just
tell them it wasn't anything?
No, 'cause he's not
gonna believe us.
All right. It's okay. It's okay
because I fucking planned for this.
- I hid weapons around the house.
- Wait, what?
Only because you made that
fucking skull painting, okay?
You have to make that painting
before the camera goes off.
- Make the fucking painting!
- Uh
Okay. I'm sorry.
You hid weapons in our house?
Yes, I hid weapons
in our fucking house.
Why did you hide weapons? Do you
know who the fuck these people are?
What exactly did you hide?
JASPER: Just sit
still and calm down.
CALLIE: No, I-I'm
very worried about this.
Just sit still and calm down!
What happens after
the picture gets taken?
- We wait.
- We just sit here and wait?
They'll come in,
ask us some questions.
And if it goes well,
that'll be that.
What if it doesn't go well?
Finn?
There's a hammer
under the couch.
He was just the
building's rent-a-cop.
Then why is this
a police officer's card?
Well, he just became one.
He was dropping off his keys.
It was his last shift.
I didn't tell him anything
about you or the machine, so-
I would love to believe that.
(WHISPERING)
Unfortunately,
I... can't afford
to trust you.
(CLATTERING)
What-
What's he looking for?
Uh-Maybe I can help?
She's your girlfriend, yes?
Yes, maybe you can help.
Okay-
Now let's see if we can
remember anything new.
Uh, I see you.
Boyfriend.
Adrenaline.
Mind racing.
Trust me.
You're not fast enough.
There is an easy way
out of this,
and that's just to answer
my fuckin' questions.
- Please don't!
- You're gonna die.
Why do I feel
a total lack of concern?
Because you haven't seen
tomorrow's photo yet.
It shows your murder.
(CHUCKLES)
And who kills me, huh?
You?
He does.
Maybe it's for the money.
You must have a fortune
in winnings already.
Oh.
Keys.
You should slide your chair
over this way.
I'm serious.
Once he sees that photo,
he's gonna aim through that
window and shoot you in the back.
Smart move.
Where's Jasper?
Marcus, where's Jasp-
Where is he?
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
Jasper, fuckin' stop!
(PHONE RINGS)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
Hello?
Hi, Mrs. Anderson.
No, it was Callie.
She, uh-
She burned her hand
on the stove.
Yeah, everything's fine.
Thank you.
Bye now.
Okay-
Oh, God.
Okay.
Okay. Got it.
We can't leave them in here
forever, you know.
No shit.
It's just for now.
- All right. What's next?
- Next?
Next I go get my money
from Ivan's.
Thank you for cleaning up
the living room.
You mean the blood?
Thank you for cleaning up the
blood that could have been mine?
You're welcome.
Babe-
Don't!
I'm just trying to make sure you're okay.
Do I look okay?
(MUTTERING)
What can I do?
Why don't you go paint?
Holy hell.
I know, right?
And this is just the start.
Jasper,
I think, uh-
I think we should leave.
Split the money,
get out of the country,
get on the other side of it,
get away from the machine.
Are you out
of your fucking mind?
The safest place on Earth
is right here.
As long as we see ourselves
in that photo every day,
we know we're alive tomorrow.
- Callie and I, we, uh-
- We what?
You know.
All I know is that Jasper
saved my life tonight.
I'm going to bed.
Jasper, can you give me
something to sleep?
Thank you.
Callie.
Callie. Callie!
(SLAMS)
(HINGES SQUEAKS, DOOR CLOSES)
(KNOCKING)
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
(EXHALES)
Hello.
Um, I'm Dr. Heidecker.
F-Forgive the hour
and my appearance.
No, uh-
how can I help you?
Henry Bezzerides
is a colleague of mine.
Does he live in the apartment
across the way?
Yeah. Yes, he does.
(SIGHS)
I knocked.
There was no answer.
What's going on?
A Dr. Heidecker
is here.
She's looking
for Mr. Bezzerides.
Did you tell her that he moved
out a couple months ago?
Did he give you his hat
before he left?
FINN: So we, uh-
we found his journal,
and from what we've read,
I guess he saw something bad.
I know. He sent me a letter.
He tried to change it.
After Henry retired, he kept
me up on his experiments.
To be honest, I didn't think
they'd amount to much.
- Poor Henry.
- JASPER: Yep.
Don't fuck with time.
Well-
You think time did this?
That he was somehow punished
for trying to change the future?
Well, what else would
do that to someone?
Thorium gas
would be my first guess.
You see the coil over there?
I'm guessing he was stretching
for it up on that shelf there...
when he knocked over
the canister.
It's just an accident, his death.
That's all. Nothing more.
I suspect he was panicked...
whilst in the process of, uh,
trying to avoid this.
You see his hat on the couch and what
looks like his blood on the window?
It seems that he met
an unpleasant end,
but clearly this photograph,
which takes place tomorrow,
had nothing to do
with him at all.
Oh, it's ironic.
Tomorrow?
How could he have taken the photo when the
camera only shoots one day ahead of time?
Why, I don't know where
you're getting your data,
but I believe you're mistaken.
This letter's postmarked
a week ago,
so he had to have taken the photo
at least that far in advance.
A week? How could he have
mailed the photo? Hang on.
You're telling me you can shoot
a photo whenever you want?
No. I don't know about
“whenever you want.”
Evidently, Henry had moved
past the initial tests...
and had got it to look further.
Do you think you could
change the settings?
No.
Henry shared his results with
me, but not his methods.
I don't know any more about
the controls than you do.
That's too bad.
(TOOL WHIRRING)
(RATTLING)
That lady didn't
mean us any harm.
What about the gun in her hand?
She wasn't going to use it.
You don't fucking
know that, okay?
And if I didn't act, then Callie would
be waking up to our dead bodies!
At the very least, the
police would have shown up.
Sounds like Jasper was
just trying to protect us.
Well, you were not there.
(SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Ready for your big moment?
Hell, yes.
Do you want me to go over there and
make sure you've got it right?
Yeah.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
What's tomorrow's look like?
Hey, Callie?
Is that tomorrow's photo?
Well, fine.
I don't want to see it.
Can we please-pack one of
your bags and let's leave?
You're not going anywhere.
Did you not hear
Dr. Heidecker?
She said it was an accident,
so that means things can change.
And I think I'm going to take my
chances with that, so please, come on.
JASPER: Go ahead.
Commit suicide.
But don't kill your
girlfriend in the process.
What-
You're in the photo?
Okay, fine.
Let me see it.
No.
Oh, rip the Band-Aid off already.
How's she doing?
What is she doing?
She's passed out.
She was distraught.
I gave her something
to take the edge off.
Oh, man.
It was so good
when it was good.
We had such
a cool relationship.
Sorry, man.
Oh, it's not your fault.
It's my fault.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
I got this a year ago.
And I couldn't
pull the trigger.
Why's that?
You were right.
I was scared.
(WHISPERS) Coward.
I mean, I'm not a painter.
I'm a glorified janitor.
And she deserves
more than that.
I mean, I wanted to be
I get it.
No.
I've been blaming you
in my head for all of this.
And who knows? Maybe it was me that
was making the decisions, secretly.
You know, just-
(SIGHS)
Sabotaging everything
out of fear.
Maybe there's a way
to fix this still.
I think it's too late. Yeah.
(GROANING)
You know, I'm actually
starting to like that smell.
How fucked up is that?
When I saw the suitcase,
I knew you'd left the program.
And I don't give a fuck
what Dr. Heiden-schmeiden says.
You don't fuck with time.
I need you alive
at least one more day.
If I have to drug you
and put you on that sofa myself,
so help me, I will.
Here.
That should keep you warm.
All right.
(GRUNTING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
(SHOUTS)
(FINN PANTING)
(LIGHTER FLICKS)
(GRUNTS)
Oh, God.
Help!
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Okay. Shh.
The gun.
Goddamn it, Jasper.
I paint this today,
but you saw it two weeks ago.
Did I send you down here?
Why would I do that?
Oh.
Thank you.
(PHONE RINGING)
(SNIFFLES)
Who the fuck is this?
You motherfucker!
Don't you dare! I'll fucking
kill you and wear your skin!
Well, if you do that,
the bucket's gonna fall.
Get Callie
and give her the phone.
(EXHALES)
CALLIE: Stop pushing me.
Take it.
- Callie, can you see me?
- Hello?
Jasper knocked me out last night, and
he locked me in the storage unit.
- What?
- He's going to kill you.
No, he would never-
(TRIGGER CLICKS)
Give me the phone.
If you don't put
that bucket down,
I'm gonna blow her brains
all over this fucking window!
You're gonna kill us anyway.
You're gonna kill me
if! Put the bucket down or not.
There's only one way
out of this.
We walk away.
If we walk away, you get
to keep your machine.
Hurry up! This bucket
is getting heavy!
Give Callie the phone.
Callie, I want you to look
in Jasper's hoodie pocket.
He has something of yours,
something I got a long time ago.
(EXHALES)
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that I haven't
been there for you.
It's okay.
You are now.
Take the gun.
Take it away from Jasper.
Give me the gun.
Give it to me.
Now back up.
Over there.
(GROANS)
Whatever you say.
I'll be there in 30 seconds.
Okay.
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
(KNOCKING) Hang on.
Goddamn it.
Pack.
Quickly.
You know what? Maybe this'll
keep you warm at night.
Where will you go?
Far.
We're going to need
some of this.
Take as much as you want.
Well, yeah, you could
always make more, right?
Don't forget your ring.
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTS)
(THUDS)
(HAMMER CLATTERS)
Oh, my God.
I really killed him.
(GROANS)
You had no choice.
(GASPS)
Hey. Oh.
Come sit down.
Are you okay?
(GROANS) I'm going
to get you some ice.
Okay, but we need to go.
(GASPS) Oh, my God.
Look. The photo-
it changed!
Oh, thank God.
When I saw that photo
of you two together-
No, it's okay.
I just didn't think I'd be
able to change anything...
if Dr. Heidecker's
letter didn't, um-
Oh, shit.
I need to paint this.
I- I don't understand.
I paint this for Mr.
So I'd be able to use his keys
to get out of the storage unit.
It doesn't matter.
I'll tell you when we leave.
We need to go
before the cops show up.
Okay, I'm going to
get you that ice.
This isn't... possible.
I was always
going to paint this?
We haven't changed anything.
Then where did this come from?
- I thought you were getting ice.
- I was. I am.
Uh, what were you saying?
Uh, doesn't matter.
Here. You should probably
go lay down,
put this ice on your head.
What the fuck was that?
The camera just went off!
What? Give-
Give me this.
I can explain.
No.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Talk to me.
Tell me what's going on.
- Look, let's just go sit down.
- No. Talk!
Okay-
(INHALES)
Remember when we got the call that
Mr. “B” was behind on his rent,
and I went to check on him?
- (KNOCKING)
- Hey, Mr. Bezzerides, are you home?
I found the machine, and sticking
out of the camera was a photo.
The reason there are nighttime
and daytime photos...
on the wall
of Mr. B's apartment...
is because the camera takes a
photo at 8:00 PM and 8:00 AM.
By keeping you and Jasper
from knowing that,
I could secretly pass messages
back to myself.
You're up early.
So when I caught you
in the kitchen just now,
what, uh-
what were you doing?
I was hiding this.
Last night when Jasper posed
with all of the money,
I switched out the photos.
I switched them back just now.
I've seen all of the nighttime
photos, and Jasper's dead,
so when was this taken?
It's from before.
Before when?
Before before.
A month ago, drunk charades?
Look, it didn't mean anything.
I was just acting out.
I'd get drunk sometimes,
and-
Look, it was almost as if I wanted
to get caught, so you would wake up.
That's an excuse. Yeah.
I'm sorry for being so weak.
I just-I can't believe
that you would...
allow this-
You had every opportunity to
prevent it, to warn us about it.
Why didn't you do that?
I was just doing
what the photos told me to.
I was getting pulled along,
like we all were.
(SCOFFS)
And don't you see? Everything
happened for a reason.
Look, everything
we had before was fading.
You were so distant.
But then you got jealous
for the first time in ages.
And I finally got to feel
your kiss again.
And you said it-It takes a moment
like this to wake a guy up...
to what's
right in front of him.
Little by little,
we were coming back together.
But then-
You kept picking the machine
and your work over us.
So I had to do something to
bring you back to your senses.
And then today,
you fought for us...
harder than I've ever
seen you fight for anything.
So in the end,
everything worked out.
Uh-huh?
Everything worked out?
(RING CLATTERS)
What are you doing? I'm going to do what
we should have done from the start.
I'm going to destroy
that fucking machine.
Stop! Please, stop.
You said we can
change things, right?
Then all I have to do is put a new note
in the window for tonight's picture.
Then when I get
the message last night,
I'll know to prevent you from
catching me at the window just now.
You'll never find the photos.
We'll never have had
this conversation.
(TRIGGER CLICKS)
If you destroy the machine,
I can't fix this.
(GUNSHOT)
I wish you hadn't
made me do that.
- (GAGGING)
- It's going to be okay.
We won't remember
any of this tomorrow.
It's going to be okay.
What are you doing here, Joe?
I got a message from Finn.
He said that you two
were leaving town.
I might be interested to see
what Jasper was up to.
What's on the window?
(SIGHS)
Can I come in?
Sure. Fine.
It doesn't matter.
Tonight none of this
will matter.
I guess you might have
some questions for me?
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(BULB POPS)
Improved By: Fidel33