[music playing]
[crickets chirping]
[clanking]
[mystical music]
When's my first meeting?
Your first meeting is at 7 AM.
I want all my
calls transferred
to me in San Francisco.
Yes, sir.
Olie, you're in charge now.
Any questions?
No, sir.
And don't forget
to feed my fish.
Where's Joe?
Uh, caught a sudden flu.
[door closing] I'm
your pilot now.
[click]
Expecting turbulence?
RADIO ANNOUNCER:
[inaudible] at 6:00 PM,
an upper low-pressure
[inaudible] on the West Coast
will continue.
[engine noise]
Do you know what time it is?
No.
RADIO ANNOUNCER:
This is Control.
You are not cleared
for take off.
[radio interference]
[engine acceleration]
[flapping]
URBANE: Uh-oh.
Uh-oh.
What?
Nothin'.
[inaudible].
You have family, Mr. Rush?
No, why?
Well, we seem to have
a small problem here.
[flapping]
Yep, thought so.
[shouting] [screaming]
[explosion]
[crickets chirping]
[yelling].
[grunting]
[clanking]
[birds chirping]
RADIO ANNOUNCER: --was
found earlier today.
The small aircraft crashed
sometime last night.
Morgan Rush, the famous
antiquities dealer,
was found dead.
The body of the pilot
has not been found.
Well, that's the
news for this hour,
and now to some music
from the Crazy Horses.
[country music playing]
What happened to you?
Ah, there was an accident.
I don't remember anything.
Cup of coffee, Honey?
Get up, white man.
You speak English.
There was The mission in
the village where I grew up.
(ANGRILY) What do you want?
[mystical music playing]
I'm looking for man.
[yelling]
Let him go, Akira, or I will
turn you into an old warthog.
(GROWLING) Another
time, [inaudible]..
I thank you, sir.
No fight, no blame.
Follow me.
Who are you?
He who does not trust
enough cannot be trusted.
What is your name?
WAITRESS: Buddy?
Uh, [inaudible].
Could I have
another cup, please?
I think you owe me an apology.
Do you want to step
outside and discuss it?
You deaf, boy?
I'm going to jerk
a knot in your ass.
[inaudible] is green and
the birds are chirping.
I'm talking to him.
What'll it be, guys?
BOTH AGENTS: Nothing.
Where are you going?
Stay out of this.
You got something for us?
Look, you fucked Urbane.
You weren't supposed
to kill him.
Look, I don't know what
you guys are talking about.
I got prior business
with this here boy.
Butt out brick-head.
What'd you say?
- [grunting]
- Nobody move.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Where do you
think you're going?
Hey, look--
[gunfire]
[scream]
Shit!
Let's go.
[engine noise]
[gunfire]
[explosion]
Attack me.
- [gasping] You are unarmed.
- Am I?
En Guard.
[grunting]
Your best defense
is not to be there.
[grunting]
Concentrate.
[giggling]
This is for you.
Thank you.
The blade is now yours.
It is a katana made
by [inaudible]..
It will always be your friend.
How old are you?
Run.
Run!
You have got learn to run
if you are to survive.
Jinamas will have
you for breakfast.
URBANE: [inaudible] Further!
[inaudible] [yelling]
[engine noise]
My name is Urbane .
What did Rush tell you?
You're crazy!
Tell me where the Master is.
Fly the plane!
Fly the goddamn plane!
Tell me.
Tell you what?
Who are you?
Very funny, Urbane.
Urbane-- that's what the
guy in the diner called me.
Whew.
License plate checked out.
It's definitely Jane English.
I think Urbane's trying
to double-cross us, Chief.
Christ.
She's never going
to give up, is she?
All right, put somebody
on both their apartments.
I want Urbane back.
So, Urbane not only
didn't acknowledge you,
he pulled a gun?
- Yes.
No.
Yes.
(SCOFFING) And then he
just disappeared, huh?
Yes.
Uh-huh.
So how come you
let him get away?
The whole deal
went to shit, chief.
I think the guy's trying
to double cross us.
He's a lunatic.
No, you're wrong.
He's a professional.
[music playing]
What happened with Rush?
What's the gun for?
Emergencies.
What's your name?
Where are you taking me?
Shut up, Urbane.
Tell me what Rush told you.
Tell you the truth, I
don't remember anything.
Stop playing games.
Get that gun out of my face.
Either you
cooperate or I'll take
you right back to those goons.
Now I want some answers.
Urbane!
URBANE: Let me go.
No!
URBANE: Let me go!
Are you crazy?
Yes, I am .
Get back in the
car, I'll do anything
you Just get back in here.
Promise?
What's your name?
Jane English.
What do you want?
Money.
Like everyone else.
You can take me there.
[music playing]
[engine roaring]
[doors opening]
(ON RADIO) This is
Rawton calling home.
The pigeons have
returned to the coop.
Over.
AGENT (ON RADIO): Stay put.
We'll be right over.
[sighing]
[mystical music playing]
[fire crackling]
Why did that samurai
try to kill me?
We're in the lawless times
of [inaudible],, warrior monks.
[inaudible] rose and
fought the shogun.
The symbol was the same
as pendant you wear.
They killed Many took much land.
In the end, they were destroyed.
I am the last one.
The samurai fear
that I might yet
raise an army from the dead.
What do you know
about immortality?
There are many things I
could teach you if you are
strong enough and not afraid.
But certain things
cannot be rushed.
You can trust me.
No man can be trusted,
else he's not a man.
You have given me
no reason to stay
here and be insulted by you.
[inaudible] You may
not be trustworthy,
but at least you will see.
To start, you will address
me as your master, sensei.
Do you understand?
Yes, sensei.
Close your eyes.
Being a samurai is choosing
that with the pursuit of that,
you will be one
with the Bushido.
Being one with the Bushido,
you will be able to perform
to the best of your ability--
separated and above the
world of daily life.
[water running]
Can I help you?
Thought you might need this.
What'd you wash
your dog with it?
Look, I'm going
to take a walk.
I need to think.
Sure you're not
going flying again?
Just some fresh air.
[music playing]
I gotta get some rest.
Yeah, good idea.
Bye.
Hey!
[gunfire]
What the hell are you doing?
I;m not going to
let you kill me.
You're the one with the gun.
What the hell are you
doing sneaking around?
What are you doing
sneaking up on me?
[sighing] You want to tell
me what is going on here?
Nice sword.
Drop it.
Drop the gun.
[tires squealing]
Come on.
You just wanted to
blow my brains out.
Look, either they
shoot you or I do.
Which do you prefer?
I don't know.
How's your aim?
Pigeons have flown the coop.
I thought you were
watching the place.
They must be hiding inside.
Wait here.
The rest of you come with me.
URBANE: Very nice.
JANE ENGLISH: Thank you.
This car doesn't work.
You We try the key first?
- Oh, shit.
- What?
I can't drive.
(INCREDULOUSLY) What?
I forgot how.
- Get out of the seat!
- No.
(ANGRILY) Move!
Show me how.
(ANGRILY) Move over!
No.
(SHOUTING) Put the
key in and turn it!
Urbane!
[gunfire]
[tires squealing]
Get 'em!
URBANE: Stop the car.
(URGENTLY) Stop the car!
What now?
Check that out.
(SARCASTICALLY) My
god, it's a library.
Then I remember that building.
Let's go inside.
What are we doing here?
Why don't you trust me?
Why should You've been
playing games with me.
No, I'm telling you, I
don't remember anything.
Only the plane crash.
Then you really don't
remember who I am?
I'm not sure.
It comes back in pieces.
You probably bumped
your head in the crash.
You must have amnesia.
It's strange.
I remember this old
Japanese man and
being attacked by a samurai.
Does that make any sense to you?
Not really.
Where do you
fit into all this?
I work with you.
Well actually, I
work for the Agency.
Or, used to.
Uh-huh.
Tell me more.
You were contracted
by the Agency.
You were supposed to get some
information from that passenger
on that plane.
This man on the
plane, who is he?
Morgan Rush.
Ah, he's a world known
antiquities dealer.
We've arranged for you to
replace Rush's regular pilot.
Just get him to give
you what we need.
What exactly do you need?
Rush has acquired some ancient
Japanese tablets of great value
to a certain interested party.
He gave them to a man,
code name The Master.
The Master?
Uh-huh.
Uh Rush should be able to tell
you where The Master's hiding.
Who's the interested party?
Oh, I'm sure you'll meet him.
I hate it when you're vague.
Usually means I;ll be
up to my neck in shit.
[chuckling] That's
why you love me.
Oh, you remember Jane
English, don't you?
Yeah, your assistant.
Yes.
She stole a copy of your file.
I think she's trying
to stick it to us.
So she knows as much as we do?
Uh-huh.
We'll need to get rid of her.
OK.
OK, I'll arrange for a meeting
out at the airfield tonight,
then I'll eliminate her.
Urbane?
[rapid footsteps]
Jesus Christ, you scared me!
I'm sorry.
What's wrong?
Urbane!
URBANE: Shh, shh.
JANE ENGLISH: [gasping]
I'm not going to kill you.
Oh, I remember now that I'm
supposed to, I'm not a killer.
But you've got to promise
to trust me, all right?
All right?
OK.
I know you betrayed the Agency.
What are you trying
to get out of this?
The tablets Mueller's after
are worth a lot of money.
So you wanted it for yourself?
Yeah, why should that reptile
keep everything for himself?
Aren't you guys
supposed to people
working for the government?
We work for the
highest bidder.
[sighing] Well, now this
whole mission has gone berserk
and they want to kill us both.
We have to find The Master.
He's our only way out.
What leads have we got?
Freddie Delago.
He's in on this.
He'd know where The Master is.
Shall we?
(SCOFFING) I'm in your hands.
Well, I'm the
only one you got.
Come on, let's
make a phone call.
[telephone dialing]
[telephone ringing]
FREDDIE DELAGO (ON
TELEPHONE): Hello?
JANE ENGLISH (ON TELEPHONE):
Freddie, this is Jane English.
Be there on time, Freddie.
(VIA LISTENING DEVICE) He
said he'll meet us tomorrow.
URBANE (VIA LISTENING
DEVICE): Where?
JANE ENGLISH (VIA LISTENING
DEVICE): McGill's Road, 11 AM.
URBANE (VIA LISTENING
DEVICE): Good.
You hungry?
They're meeting with
Delago in the morning.
You capture and
eliminate Delago, huh?
That will be no problem.
But you still haven't
told me what's so
important about these tablets.
They contain
certain information
that's crucial to our future.
And in The Master's hands,
they pose a great threat to us.
Oh.
So who is this Master?
A long-time enemy.
Just find him.
That's what you're getting paid
for-- not to ask questions.
[telephone ringing]
[crowd noise]
[non-english speech]
[inaudible]?
No, thanks.
Have you had many relationships?
What, with women?
You obviously have wonderful
relationship with yourself.
I don't remember any.
You asked me out once.
No way.
What do you mean?
How can I be with a woman
who's trying to kill me?
Could turn into
an exciting evening.
Was it?
We didn't go.
I said no.
Why?
You were so close
with Mueller, I thought
you were a jerk like him.
Well, now that you
know what a wonderful guy
I am, how about giving
me a second chance?
I'll think about it.
Right now, we have
a date with Delago.
He's not here.
No.
We'll wait.
So, am I different now?
I it was I a bad person?
I've known worse.
What if I--
what if I don't get
all the old me back?
You're much
better now, anyway.
Really, what if I develop into
this wonderful, compassionate
person, then find
out I have to break
people's necks for a living.
You do.
I think you're overreacting.
Everyone's afraid
of the unknown.
Yeah, yeah, but who wants
to be afraid of themselves?
It's him.
Hold on, you can't
go out there alone.
The deal was, I talk to him.
No, you can't do this.
We're partners.
Then trust me.
Who's your friend?
My chauffeur.
Hey, you said alone.
I meant you.
Hey, still don't trust me?
No.
Don't forget, can always get
Mueller to finish you off.
Yeah?
You're still a scary old broad.
Shut Freddie.
[engine noise]
You owe me.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
don't remind me.
OK, so what do you want?
Where can I find the
guy code named The Master?
(SCOFFING) You don't want
to fuck with the Japanese.
So you know who he is?
Yeah.
The guy you want just happens
to be in town right now.
But I figured you knew that.
Must have slept through it.
Stop stalling.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, so come on.
Just want to make sure
you're not wired eh?
You're paranoid.
Hey, it's what's
kept me alive.
[gunfire]
Oh!
Who is he?
(WEAKLY)The Master.
Come on.
What are you going to do
with that thing, deflect
Would you leave him?
He's dead.
Day
[gunfire]
Somebody told
them we'd be here.
You stay here.
[gunfire]
Drop the gun.
- [panting]
- Oh, Urbane.
Don't make me do it.
[gunfire]
Urbane!
Well, get his body on the van.
[mystical music playing]
[grunting]
[shouting]
Where is The Master?
Gone.
Where?
Away.
Get him!
[grunting]
[shouting]
[clanking]
[grunting]
Give it up.
[inaudible] [inaudible]!
Where is the old man?
May he rot in hell.
[grunting]
[shouting]
Kill him!
He--he's not human.
He bleeds like any man.
[grunting]
Iko!
God, it works.
I cannot die.
So, you have
discovered my secret?
Or should I say, stole?
The knowledge contained
in these tablets
was not for you or
any other mortal man.
It was to die with me.
You know that.
You are no longer
a student of mine.
I leave you nothing but your
guilt. Your soul is weak.
Time will never
heal you have done.
I hope you can survive
eternity with it.
Sensei, wait.
Sensei, wait!
I cannot die.
You hungry?
What do you want from me?
I'll do anything you
want if you let me go.
Well, we'll have to
see about that, huh?
Tell me what Urbane told you.
What exactly do
you want to know?
Tell me what Rush told
Urbane before the crash.
Didn't tell him anything.
Don't lie to me.
Urbane had a special talent
for, uh, extracting information
from people.
Ha.
Probably his charming nature.
Yeah.
So what did he tell you?
Think I'll have
that sandwich now.
Urbane threatened to kill me.
I didn't help him.
He had no intentions of turning
Rush's information over to you.
I think he was
going to sell them.
Not a bad huh?
That explains Urbane's
behavior in the diner.
But unfortunately, the
only person who can
verify your story was Urbane.
Then I guess you're
going to have to trust me.
You help me, I'll help you.
I need more.
After all, what's to
keep you from killing me
after I tell you?
Nothing.
I know where The Master is.
You're going to need
me to get to him.
I want you to take
me to your boss.
I'm taking you to
the tsunami right now.
Is he the interested party?
Yes.
[grunt]
Well, get her!
Why do you insist on playing
these stupid little games,
Jane?
Huh?
Have you forgotten
how nasty I can get?
I'd have to see why
[inaudible] like Urbane.
You still hold
the ace, Mueller.
Well, let's see
how well you play.
Get his body to the morgue,
and then get back here.
AGENT: Where should
we leave them?
MAN: Oh, anywhere.
Got an ID for them?
AGENT: Only for this one.
MAN: OK, John Doe
21 for the other.
[gasping] Hi.
[weeping]
Shit.
[grunting]
Of course, we'll need
you to verify his identity.
[panting]
Merely as a
preliminary detail.
We have 20 bodies here now.
[weeping]
Let's see, what
was the name again?
Delago, Frederick.
[weeping]
I'm not sure what
bag Mr. Delago is in.
I'm sorry.
Seems my assistant
has disappeared.
He probably went out for a bite.
[weeping]
To eat.
Oh, there, there
now, Mrs. Delago.
Why don't we just take a peek
and see if we can't find huh?
[weeping]
[humming] Ah, here he is, they
brought him in this morning.
[weeping]
That's strange.
[humming]
Uh, that's not him.
Just as I was saying, they
brought him in this morning
with Mr. Delago.
Ha, here he is, John Doe 21.
[weeping]
Freddie, Freddie,
oh, Freddie, why?
Why?
Why, Freddie?
Give them some time alone, hm?
[weeping]
[screaming]
What happened?
Visiting hours are
now over, Mrs. Delago.
If you'll just sign
this verification
we'll go look for
your friend, hm?
MRS. DELAGO: [whimpering]
Wanna play?
[grunt]
Gentlemen.
Leave me.
Is there something
you want to tell me?
Jane English, meet
Takeda Sanarma,
owner of Sanarma Enterprise.
I will make this Miss English.
I understand you have
something we need.
I'd prefer not to have to
force you into volunteering
that information, but
your cooperation is
necessary one way or another.
One million dollars cash.
[chuckling]
[grunting]
The information in
exchange for your life.
Surely that is worth more
than the money to you.
And what's to keep you
from killing me afterwards?
You have my word.
My honor.
My trust in that
you'll remain silent.
I have no reason to kill you.
There are far more important
things at stake here.
I'll think about it.
[whispering]
You have one hour.
[door closing]
Whoa.
[grunting]
[beeping]
[whirring]
All right, come out of there.
Come out or I'll shoot.
ROBOT TOY: Hello,
space commander.
Take me to your leader.
You?
At your service.
But-- [grunting]
[grunting] [groaning]
I had a dream, Urbane.
Urbane?
Urbane, you're alive!
Ow!
What was that for?
Don't be so impulsive.
You seemed to like it.
I did.
That's the problem.
Come on, let's
get out of here.
But the bullets, the blood?
I'll explain later.
You were wearing a
bulletproof weren't you?
No, he was a bad shot.
Look, I don't want to
get into it right now.
I want to know.
I saw the blood.
He hit you.
No, it was a scratch.
Urbane, your rib
cage was hanging out.
Tough genes, I guess.
How do you expect
me to trust you if you
won't even tell me the truth?
Oh, god, trust?
I was in the van.
I heard you suck up to Mueller.
Me?
You were dead.
What was I supposed to do?
He was ready to kill me.
Yeah, and what
were you going to do
when it came time to confess?
I would have told
him to kiss my ass.
He probably would have.
I'd have thought of something.
Are you going to tell me
why you're still alive?
Yeah.
I'm immortal.
Very funny.
You expect me to believe that?
How else do you
explain my being here?
Look, see?
Look.
I never jumped out of
Rush's plane, either.
We crashed.
He died, I didn't.
I can't.
I was born 350 years ago
in Portsmouth, England.
I worked on a
Spanish trader ship.
We were in Japan, I learned
the secret of immortality
from an old warrior
priest, The Master.
That secret is on the tablets
that everyone's after.
[door opening]
You expect anybody
to believe that?
You're coming with me.
[gunfire]
Go ahead and shoot me.
Shoot me!
I already did.
[grunting]
Oh, god.
Don't die.
[sobbing] Love you.
Really?
I wish you would
make up your mind.
I don't understand.
In time, you will.
Took me a long time
to accept it also.
Just one thing--
will you always be
jumping in front of guns?
I will try to avoid it.
What now?
Well, we still have
to find The Master.
He's our only way to
resolve this mess.
What did Delago tell you?
He knew that The Master was in
He didn't know where he though.
Rush was the only one who knew.
If only I could remember.
You have to.
Concentrate.
Look into my eyes, remember the
night you were on the plane.
You were with Rush.
You were flying.
I-I can't.
You'd better.
Otherwise--
We're fucked.
Fly the plane.
Fly the fucking plane!
I know you gave the
tablets to The Master.
Tell me where he is.
Release me first.
We're going down about
a hundred feet per second.
I don't have time
to unstrap you.
100, 200, 300.
I'll get you for this.
He's at a house.
349 Alameda Street.
Thank you.
Did the Sanarma
put you up to this?
Oh, shit.
[explosion]
I remember.
He's in a house--
349 Alameda Street.
Let's get out of here.
[door closing]
[sirens]
[sighing]
You're not really planning
on paying her to talk, are you?
That will not be necessary.
She will talk.
And then we will eliminate her.
Yeah?
And then what?
And then we kill The Master.
They've escaped.
What do you they?
[bang]
They.
There they are.
Urbane, you son of a bitch!
Well, after 'em!
That's our car.
That's OK, chief, I
know where they're going.
Well, good.
Good.
Call in the troops.
We're going hunting.
Come on.
I don't understand it.
I saw Urbane die.
We've known for a long
time that a white man stole
the Sohi secret of immortality.
Must be him.
Sohi?
Who are they?
Warrior monks.
The Master was their leader.
Was?
Yes, 300 years ago.
Then how will we be
able to kill him now?
I'd like to talk to you
about that scene at the office.
We don't have time to talk.
Just keep walking.
You didn't want to stop.
If I hadn't stopped we'd still
be groping at each other.
I didn't stop?
You didn't.
If we had gone through with it--
sex, that is-- are
you well, normal?
Why?
I mean, you don't have any
strange body parts, do you?
Want to check for yourself?
No.
Have you had many women?
None.
None of any great importance.
Do you have any children?
I don't know.
Never tried.
Maybe I was just lucky.
Odds must have been pretty
great for you not to have.
Look, I've never shared
my life with anyone before.
You're sure you're
built like a human?
Yeah, I have two eyes,
two hands, two balls
if that's what
you're talking about.
I am a normal man with a gift.
It took me about a
hundred years to stop
being paranoid about who I am.
Physically I'm 28 years old,
but I have been around for 350
years and I'm still all alone.
Think that's fun?
That's it.
You going in?
Yes.
You wait here.
I'll bring him out.
If anyone comes, you lay low.
[scream]
[grunting]
Where's The Master?
Where is he?
[shouting]
Come on.
[grunting]
Sensei?
Michael Urbane.
I am Takeda Sanarma.
Where's The Master?
I was hoping
you could tell me.
Leave it.
We have Miss English.
That's impossible.
I left her by--
By the ridge.
I know.
I've got her.
And now I've got you.
What do you want?
A test.
Raise his shirt.
The wound is gone.
Hold out his arm.
This weapon was was designed
by our space program.
It contains a radioactive alloy
that can destroy anything--
including an immortal.
[grunting]
Stop!
If you value the girl's
life, you will cooperate.
[buzzing]
[whimpering] [panting]
Stand him up.
Enough of these games.
It's time to play for real.
Sanarma will have their revenge.
[shouting]
[gunfire]
[sighing] Ho, ho--
[shout] [groaning] [panting]
Catch him!
[wind chimes]
(BREATHILY) Where am I?
You're safe.
Lie still.
They told me they
had you prisoner.
[mystical music playing]
Sensei.
You are no student of mine.
I betrayed you once.
I have come to repay that debt.
Repay me by bringing
these men here?
No, by helping
you out of here.
The Sanarma have a weapon--
a weapon that will
kill even you and me.
Somebody lost this war 300
years ago, why fight it again?
We have the tablets.
Call the authorities.
We can leave.
There's no reason to die.
We fight for honor.
As long as the Sanarma
live, the battle goes on.
There is only one winner.
Sensei.
[inaudible].
I have 12 men left.
The Sanarma have us surrounded.
We will fight to the
death, but I'm afraid I can
offer you no avenue of escape.
Hold them off as
long as possible.
There is something I have to do.
I will join you shortly.
[speaking japanese]
He will be fighting with us.
Wait here.
No.
I will come with you.
We'll come with you.
Life used to be simpler.
[gunfire]
[grunt]
What?
Come on.
Whoa.
[inaudible]
[gunfire]
[grunt]
You OK?
[gunfire]
[grunt]
[shouting]
OX (ON RADIO): This is Ox.
The north room is all clear.
This place is a fucking maze.
I got two on the run.
There's a hallway leading north.
Should I proceed?
Over.
Proceed with caution, Ox.
We've lost too many men already.
OX (ON RADIO): Roger.
Over and out.
Have all outposts on the
perimeter reported yet?
Yes, sir.
Urbane, let's just get
the hell out of here.
I won't leave him.
Forget The Master.
I'm more worried about us.
Look, if you're afraid, leave.
I've got a debt to repay.
In case you haven't I'm
not immortal like everyone
else around here.
Yeah, well they have a
weapon that'll kill even me.
Look, for the first time,
my life's at stake, too.
Let's finish this together.
OK.
[gunfire]
[grunting]
Give it up.
All the Master's men are dead.
You can't stop a Sanarma.
I would rather die on my feet.
[gunfire]
Jane!
[explosion]
Jane?
Urbane, this way.
These steps will take
you two levels down.
That is where The Master is.
Do you understand?
Yes.
And you?
I'll hold them off
as long as I can.
Tell Sensei it has been
an honor to serve him.
[inaudible] May our
paths cross again.
[gunfire]
[grunting]
All agents report.
AGENT (ON RADIO): One
and two reporting.
Freeze!
Drop the sword.
I said drop it.
He's not listening, Leo.
Snuff him.
Forget it pal.
Nobody's that fast.
[grunting]
We lost agents one and two.
You stay here.
This way.
One and two, do you copy?
These tablets will not fall
into the Sanarmas' hands.
[inaudible] dead.
So they're mortals.
I have lost again.
We can still escape.
I owe you that.
You will die today, my friend.
We can try fight our way out.
Do you think after
300 years, that Sanarma
will give up if we escape?
I am tired of running.
If they haven't given
up, why should we?
Our time has run out.
We have used the gift, now
it is time to give it back.
Think of all the things
you have seen and done.
No one can take
that away from you.
The past is all anyone ever has.
All the else is transitory.
A final lesson.
I wish I could share
my past with you.
I was going to tell Jane, but--
She meant something to huh?
I would gladly have
become mortal to spend
the rest of my life with her.
Love is rash.
Damn this waiting.
I say we face them on our feet.
Not only love rash.
So are you.
Patience is a virtue
I can live without.
There is a passage
out of this room.
Well, let's go, then.
I have no wish to go.
Well, if you stay,
they're going to kill you.
I will not let them.
I want to die on my
own, with your help.
You're crazy.
Is it?
You yourself said you
wanted to be mortal,
meaning you wish to die.
I would like that now.
But there's no blade
that can kill us.
Not a blade--
a soul-- an immortal soul.
You remember the samurai, Akira?
Uh-huh.
I faced his father in single
combat during the final battle.
We were both in
possession of the secret.
We were invincible.
We fought long and hard.
Finally, he charge,
but I was quicker.
I cut off his head and he die.
You want me to
chop your head off?
- A simple thrust will do.
- I will not.
Help me and you can escape.
Stay and you die.
Then I will die.
Kill me also.
JANE ENGLISH: Urbane?
Jane!
Thank God I found hat
Thank God you're still alive.
That explosion knocked me out.
I've been running his place
This place is crawling with men.
I thought you'd gone.
[clearing throat]
Ah.
We were just discussing that.
Would you please pat
the statue of Buddha
three times on the head?
[mystical music playing]
[creaking]
Way out?
- You wait in the tunnel.
- Why?
Just do it.
You have everything you need.
I can't love a woman
and watch her get
old while I stay forever young.
What was done can be undone.
The tablets told you how.
You probably did not read
that far in your haste.
Kill me and the secret
immortality shall be yours.
All right.
There is one thing
you should know.
Once you have become mortal
again, there is no going back.
One life is all a man needs.
[speaking japanese]
May our paths cross again.
Call me brother.
Until then, brother.
I am ready.
[grunting]
[shouting] [groaning]
[speaking japanese]
Bring the body.
We'll burn it outside.
Is it scary being mortal?
I never really thought
about it before I met you.
Everybody dies, Urbane.
Well, I guess
if we're careful,
we should have about 40
or 50 years left together.
Is that a proposal?
[music playing]
[chuckling]