- Nice.
- Thanks.
I don't know how
you work this way.
It relaxes me.
Here.
- Let me fix your tie.
- Try not to get paint on me.
Relax, okay?
What are you gonna do tonight?
Just gonna hang out?
- Like you really care.
- Don't start with me.
I'm not. You are.
And I told you about this
weeks ago. Remember?
- What?
You got a little something going
on the side, Steven?
You can tell me.
I got something on the side called
family and I can't get out of it.
How many times
you wanna hear that?
What? Your family
fucked-up or something?
- Is that why you're being so secretive?
- Hey, I need you to trust me, okay?
- Do not get paint on me.
- Okay.
Sweetie?
I've gotta get going. Now.
What, right this second?
- Yes. Right this second.
- Okay. You know what? Fine.
Have yourself a real ball.
Get out of here.
You're a wonderfully cruel woman.
I'm gonna wake you up.
I can't even take a piss straight.
I'm vibrating to fucking death here.
Shut up, Rolfe. You drive me crazy.
You diminutive French snail.
You know, Maurice, you're the one
who said we could do it in eight hours.
- I could've walked faster!
- It's your problem for going so slow.
We need to cool.
Come on! You bastard.
What are we stopping for?
Go on ahead. I'll catch up with you.
- Breaking ground on
a new, historical museum.
Steven. Good to see you.
Jerry Robin, Jr.
I have known so many
little people professionally.
But what I didn't know is
there are over 100,000...
...little people in
North America alone.
- Hey, Mom.
- Well, if it isn't Mr. Late.
I'm not that late.
- Hello, Steven. Where's your brother?
- He's not here?
I can't believe he'd be late to a
convention. Something's wrong.
- There's nothing wrong.
- How you doing, girls?
Your favorite, dear. Egg salad.
Now, let's cut that rug.
Courtesy of The Lobsters.
Hey, everybody. Hello, girls.
How you doing tonight, Steven?
Doing the best I can.
How about yourself?
Doing all right, thank you.
Hey, Bobby. Do you see this
blond coming up here?
Oh, yeah.
She's been asking us to introduce
you to her since last convention.
- No kidding?
- She's an ice skater...
...in one of those shows,
Holiday on Ice. Kitty.
Bobby, say hello to the indomitable
Miss Kitty Katz.
- Well, hello, Mr. President.
- The pleasure's mine.
See her tits?
- Hello, ladies.
- My daughters.
Hi.
Why don't you girls go out and
dance and have some fun.
Yeah, girls. You ready?
Let's go cut a rug. You too.
Come on, now.
I could use a good, stiff one.
Oh, I mean a cocktail.
- Hey, Steven! Over here!
- Hey, Rolfe!
Rolfie! My friend, you are
in the doghouse.
Mom and Pop are pissed.
That's great. Steven, this is Maurice.
Maurice is an asshole.
Hey, the asshole is the strongest
muscle in the human body.
Do you think there's any food left?
Man, I really couldn't tell you.
- My name's Lucy.
- Hi, Lucy.
Hey, don't go ripping off food, now.
You can't steal food.
Food's from God. It's plentiful.
- God wants me to eat.
- Come on, Lucy. Let's go.
What's going on? You wanna
go grab a drink somewhere?
No, I'm kind of tired.
What about tomorrow?
I can't tomorrow. Tonight's
my last night. I got a class.
I gotta put through finals all week.
What's the story anyway, man?
The hell happened? Where you been?
That's what happened.
What do you mean,
"That's what happened"?
You drove this thing 400 miles?
Yeah, well, Maurice builds
them and...
...I can't afford to fit out a car
right now, so...
...I figured what the hell. Hey,
you laugh, man, it got me here.
Call Mom and Dad.
Let them know you're all right.
Don't let them know you're riding
around on this thing.
Yeah, well, don't you
go telling them either.
Don't I go telling them?
Assholes! All of you!
Fucking assholes!
Where you staying tonight?
We'll go find a cheap motel and
then I'm gonna give Sally a holler.
- Sack over there for a few nights.
- Might as well get used to it.
You two are gonna end up together,
no matter what happens.
They alleged that we
were stealing food.
- It's good to see you, man.
- Yeah.
You can try and make it sooner
next time. We can shake it up a little.
I know. Well, next year.
Have a good time with Sally, buddy.
You know where to find me.
Be careful, buddy.
So did you have a good time?
- Was it everything you expected?
- It was okay.
Whatever it was.
Steven?
I don't want us keeping
secrets from each other.
- It's too late to start obsessing, okay?
- You're the one making it happen.
- Why don't you just let it go, okay?
- I can't.
You're playing me. I know it.
I just can't figure out why.
You do not think that
I'm seeing someone.
No, of course not.
You know how we're always
talking about our future...
...what we're gonna do, where we're
gonna live and all that other stuff?
- Can we talk about this later?
- No, we need to talk, Steven.
- Right now?
- Yeah.
Carol, all right.
This better not be an all-night
marathon or I'll kill you.
- No, it won't. I promise.
- All right. What do you got, babe?
I think maybe I'm pregnant.
Oh, man.
We've been using protection.
Except for those two
or three times a week...
...when you wake me up
in the middle of the night.
Don't tell me you don't
remember, either.
I thought you wanted kids, Steven.
Yeah, but not right this second, no.
Just tell me what you feel.
I'm not gonna tell you I'm thrilled about
an unplanned pregnancy, all right?
I thought you'd be okay with this.
We've talked about it, like,
a million times.
Yeah, for the future.
I mean, this a huge step.
Yeah, but these are our
baby years, Steven.
Let's just do it.
Jesus Christ, Carol. I mean...
This is the sort of thing that people
talk about before they jump into it.
- Well, that's what we're doing now.
- Yeah, after the fact. It's done.
- I've never been to Hollywood before.
- Hollywood's a toilet.
Hey, says you! I feel
glamorous just being here.
- She locked me out of my bedroom.
- That's sad.
That woman does it
to me all the time.
Well, you gotta get
a new woman, like me.
- Hey, baby, what's up?
- Jesus Christ.
Hello.
- Hello.
Can we have a room?
You see that sign?
- We don't allow prostitution in here.
- You think I'm a prostitute?
- You didn't say you were a prostitute.
- She ain't a prostitute.
We just want a room.
I only have one room.
You'll have to share.
You only got one? How much, man?
- One lady and two little children.
- Hey!
- Special price for you. 95 bucks.
- These are not my children.
Damn it!
- You got any rubbers?
- No...
...and if you start fucking that girl
while I'm trying to sleep, I'll kill you.
Then put your headphones on,
my friend...
...because tonight I'm feeling good.
- I'm glad someone is.
Oh, God, I feel so much better.
I'm gonna take a shower.
Hey, Lucy. You notice how
we stalk one another?
For you. For moi.
I like to drink.
Smells good.
Say, that's smooth. What is this?
It's an original creation of mine.
Imported cherry-flavored
morphine syrup from France...
...and cognac. I just wish
I had a fucking crêpe.
You're a very interesting man.
You're very direct.
I think you have a lot of
owl medicine in you.
Hey, come here.
Come here.
So pretty.
- Fuck.
- What is it? Your back?
- No.
- Did your back go out?
Here, stand up. Stand up.
It's gonna be okay.
Look, here, ready?
Oh, God, Lucy, no!
- What did you do?
- I adjusted you.
Make me another drink.
Here.
That is better.
Daddy's back.
- Hey, Rolfe, you want a cocktail?
- In your dreams.
It's okay. Look.
He's got a prescription.
Well, that doctor he goes to,
he ought to be locked up.
Now, I'm real sore
and I'm real tired.
So keep it down.
No smoking.
Fuck!
Hey, buddy, you all right?
Hey, Maurice.
What's the matter with him?
He's got ulcers, a herniated disk...
It's just little people shit.
But he's just too stubborn
to take care of himself.
- Are you all right?
- Bed.
You're bleeding, man.
Oh, fuck.
You're bleeding.
I'm gonna call a doctor.
Yeah, hello? Could you give
me the number...
...of a Dr. Carl Morris in Encino?
- Oh, no! No!
No fucking doctors!
No doctors!
Jesus Christ, man.
I'm just trying to fucking help you.
I'm getting out of here.
So hot.
- Who is it?
- Hey, it's me. Rolfe.
- Rolfe.
- Let me in.
Be quiet, Buster.
Oh, I wasn't sure I'd ever
see you again.
Yep. I'm back.
I saw your article in Harper's
about the Republicans.
Becoming very successful.
Yeah, well, we need to get syndicated.
That's the ticket.
Look at the little love nest.
Come on, Rolfe. I don't
have a boyfriend, okay?
- Yeah? Well, I don't see two beds.
- Well, he sleeps on the couch.
Lighten up, Rolfe. God.
We're not close like that.
I let him fuck me twice. Okay?
I felt sorry for him.
His whole family was evicted from
their apartment in the Gaza Strip.
I mean, how would you feel?
You need to cut loose from all this
shit that seems to follow you around.
It wouldn't be like that
if we were together again.
Come on, Rolfe. I'm ready
for an adult relationship.
Yeah, well, it sure looks like it.
- Sally?
- Oh, my God. It's Adrissi!
- Sally.
- Well, let me come talk with him.
You wait here. Be quiet.
What are you doing here?
I quit my job.
How do you expect to get your own
place if you can't keep a job...
Do not give to me this shit. All right?
I need just money for the bus.
"Do not give to me this shit"?
Adrissi, I have to pay my phone bill.
All right, I will pay you back.
In your G-spot.
Fine! I won't pay my phone bill.
Wait here.
Give me a couple of bucks.
Keep your mouth shut.
Jesus Christ.
You need some money, man?
How much you need?
Who is this man in your
bedroom, huh?
Let's cut the bullshit. Just tell him
what you told me and get it over with.
- What's he doing in your bedroom?
- None of your business.
So get your shit together and get
the hell out before I call the cops.
No. I want to know, now,
why this man is in your bedroom.
- Well...
- Because we are gonna fuck, okay?
- That what you wanna hear?
- We're not fucking.
So just get your unemployed
ass out of here, now!
But all those things you said
in the darkness.
You said I was the sexiest stud
you had. You opened your heart.
- Keep your mouth shut, Adrissi.
- You told me I was a hunk.
Shut the fuck up!
Mercy. In a while, man, this ain't
gonna seem like such a big deal.
- Don't. Rolfe.
- You banged Sally!
- You fucking whore! You slut!
- He's fucking going nuts, Sally!
- Don't...!
- No, you get out of my way, now!
Stop it! Get off of him!
Stop it!
Don't. Get your hands off of him!
Stop it! No! Get off of him!
- No!
- God!
Oh, I'm so sorry. Are you okay?
I'm out of here.
But Rolfe, you gotta tell
the cops what he did to us.
You know what, Sally?
Why don't you tell the cops.
"Wait two minutes. Look to see if two
visible lines have formed in the tube.
Two visible lines indicate a positive
test" for being knocked up.
Let's go, Chuck! You got what it takes
to be a firefighter? I don't think so!
Come on, fat boy! Didn't I tell you
to lose weight four months ago?
Yes, I did! And you have not!
How are you gonna be any good to
anybody if you can't put dirt on a fire?
Stop! Get out of the horseshoe
and get the hose! Get up the hill.
Your execution is piss-poor.
The fires are still burning. Not only
are you slow, but you suck at it!
You're going up to the 18th floor.
You've got a woman and child. What?
What do you think you're doing?
- What?
- You're being a total asshole.
Take five, Chuck.
Hi. Is Steven still around?
Oh, no. He left already.
He'll be back in a week.
- A week?
- Who are you?
I'm Rolfe. I'm his brother.
- Oh, I'm Carol.
Well, listen, Carol.
You think I could come in?
I'm a little messed up right now.
Yeah. I was gonna ask
you about that.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- You were attacked? You're kidding.
- Does it look like I'm kidding?
Go ahead. Come on. Let me...
So, what? You got mugged
or something?
You could say that.
A guy tried to kill me.
Judging from those bruises on
your neck, I'd say he was serious.
Oh, he's probably in jail by now.
So are you and Steven
blood brothers?
Yeah, you could say that.
We're twins.
God, I can't believe that.
We've been living together since May.
We're getting married in the summer.
Well, he didn't mention anything?
No. But maybe he wanted
it to be a surprise.
Listen, are your parents...
What, little? Yeah.
Steven, he's the big guy
in the family.
Listen, Carol, do you think it'd
be okay if I sat down for a while?
I've got nowhere to go
at the moment.
No, sure. Stay as long
as you'd like.
I have to go out for a few hours.
But I'd really like to talk to you.
Oh, God. This feels good.
Would you like something to eat?
You want some coffee?
Rolfe?
Good morning, Romeo.
How you feeling? You feel better?
No. I feel like death.
That's great.
Death's a great transition.
- Maid!
- I'm sorry. Please move along.
- We're making a love nest in here.
- It's 3:00 and I want to go home!
Go away. We are eating each other.
Where's Rolfe?
He left because you
were mean to him.
Checkout time is 12:00!
Merde, I'll kill him.
- You're paying an extra day.
- Hey. Hey.
What are you doing?
Put it away.
Open the door or I'm calling
the cops. Prostitute!
Hey! You go away! You called me
a prostitute last night.
- I heard what you said...
- Open up!
Bastard! I have had enough of
name-calling, you understand?
I'm calling you a prostitute!
You're a prostitute!
Come on.
Come on. Let's go! Get your shit
together. You wanna get pinched?
So beautiful, there.
Come on, Maurice!
Everyone knows
that's called the B.A.
Now, you wanna check
your regulator every day.
Rule number one with the
regulator is never use oil in it.
You use oil in this regulator
and you'll end up in a situation.
We're gonna take five.
Hey, Carol. What's going on?
Is everything okay?
Your brother dropped by
this morning.
You drive here to tell me that?
You could have let me know that
everyone in your family is a midget.
Well, they're not midgets.
They're dwarfs.
Whatever.
But it suddenly occurred to me
that it's a genetic thing, right?
Yeah, it's a genetic thing.
Just tell me. If you and I have a kid
together, is it gonna be a midget?
- Carol, don't say midget. Say dwarf.
- Just answer the question, Steven!
- It's possible. It's definitely possible.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
Look, Carol. Hey. If it makes
you feel any better...
...I was gonna tell you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- So why didn't you?
I don't know. I didn't think it
was that important.
- You didn't think it was important?
- Don't start passing judgment.
Hey, I'm not passing judgment
on you, okay?
I'm just trying to understand.
I honestly don't know why I didn't
mention it. It wasn't the right time.
What's going on here, Steven?
Don't you want to be in
a relationship with me?
Where in the hell did that
come from, Carol?
You go ahead and do whatever
you want. You do what you want.
- What, you just don't care?
- Now, you know I care.
I won't jump through hoops
because you're threatening me.
- What? I was not threatening you.
- Yeah, you were.
This whole will to motherhood, Carol.
It's becoming quite an obsession.
Well, I thought that's why
we were getting married.
Look, there's other reasons
that people get married.
We could always adopt.
What, and never have
children of our own?
I just don't know if that's
gonna be possible.
What did you think I'd do when I found
out your family were all midgets?
Did you think I'd walk away?
Keep saying "midgets,"
you'll piss a lot of people off.
- I really don't care about that stuff.
- Okay. Okay.
Would it really be that big of a deal
if our kid was a dwarf?
Look, it's not something
you just walk into.
Well, you could have told me.
Okay.
I gotta go back to work, okay?
I'll call you when I get some
time to talk, all right?
Okay.
See you at home.
Catch me if you can.
- I can't believe I didn't see it.
- What?
What a treasure you are.
Tell me where you come from.
Well, my body's originally
from New York.
But I've been communing
for the last three years in Phoenix.
Phoenix.
Tell me about Phoenix.
Well, my ex-old man, Jerome,
he used to whittle wood jewelry.
See?
He whittled all this for me.
He even whittled me a wedding ring.
See the splinter?
Then he turned really evil.
He was a truck driver...
...and those guys are all on crank.
And there's those, you know,
transsexual prostitutes.
Anyway, he flipped out
and thought I was an alien walk-in.
- You don't wanna hear this stuff.
- No. No, I do.
What?
Oh, really?
No, I'm sorry you're lonely.
Yeah, well, maybe
your security guard pal.
Now, maybe he can come over
and comfort you.
No, really.
Sally, I'm not being snide.
No.
You know, okay, I'm a bastard.
All right. Yeah.
I'm a motherfucker.
I'm a dick too. Yeah?
I'm a fuckwad. I'm a fucking fart...!
Sally, I'm gonna hang up.
I'm...
Sally?
I'm sorry, I...
That was the girl that tried
to have me killed this morning.
Well, I guess you have good reason
to be cross with her.
Look, I'm sorry
if I acted weird this morning.
It was all right.
I was just in shock, is all.
Meaning me?
I'm pregnant, okay?
It was something we were
making plans for, we just...
We weren't planning
on it happening now.
Right.
And Steven?
He never told you about me?
No. But Steven's a normal-size guy...
...so maybe a child
of ours wouldn't be affected.
I'm not sure that's how it works.
Well, I mean...
...what do I know, you know.
I'm not a doctor.
I know some people, though,
who are...
You know, they'd refer you
to a specialist or something.
I could ask them.
- Yeah.
- Congratulations. Either way.
Thanks.
We could've just gotten
this information on the phone.
Yeah, we could...
...but what you need now
is a real support network.
Hope my Uncle Bobby
don't yell at me.
Don't freak out. It's not like
we're all dysfunctional or anything.
Why is he gonna yell at you?
Well, I didn't make
the convention Sunday night.
- What convention?
- It's a thing for little people.
It's an annual thing where
they get together...
...from all over the country
and they eat or they chat.
Meet old friends, you know, catch up.
- Asshole.
- We're here.
Rolfe's here!
My dad's in the back yard.
Yeah?
Margaret, this is Carol. Carol, this
is Margaret. Margaret's my cousin.
- Hi there.
- Hi.
So you and Steven
are getting married.
Yeah. I think maybe
he wanted it to be a surprise.
Why? Now that
you're expecting a baby...
...nothing to grope around
in a fog of uncertainty.
If I have this baby
and it turns out to be little...
...what does that mean
in terms of raising him?
There'll be rough patches,
there's no doubt about it.
But that's what life is all about.
Dealing with hardship.
If a person can't deal with that,
then they can't ever be happy.
Would you have had us again,
Daddy?
I'd have to think long
and hard about that.
Long and hard.
I think what Carol's thinking about
is the medical aspects of the situation.
Yeah, that's totally
what I'm thinking about.
I could give you
a list of doctors to call...
...and give you literature
on organizations.
- Good idea.
- Look at it when you get a chance.
I will, thank you.
Thanks.
Look, Carol, if you ever
need anybody to talk to...
...I want you to call me, okay?
- Yeah.
I mean it.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sweetheart, you don't have
anything to be sorry about.
I'm just so embarrassed.
Now, why on Earth
would you feel embarrassed?
Because here I am, questioning
whether or not to bring a person...
...into the world who's just like you.
Oh, my God,
what must I sound like?
You're only concerned about
your baby. That's natural, honey.
I just want my kid to have a happy,
productive life.
Of course you do.
There's nothing about being little that
precludes being happy. Or productive.
Yeah.
Look at us.
Hi, Steven.
- Hey, sweetie, how you doing?
- Okay.
Good, good.
Have you been thinking about things?
A little bit, you know?
I mean, it's been...
...pretty busy up here.
Say, how'd it go with Rolfe?
He's asleep on the couch.
Well, good for him.
Good for him.
What, is that a problem?
No, no, that's not a problem.
No problem at all.
We went for brunch
this afternoon...
...at your uncle's house.
God, they were so nice.
Bobby invited me to a party...
...at Jerry Robin, Jr. 's
house tomorrow night.
I was kind of hoping
we could all go together.
- Tomorrow night?
- Yeah.
Well, sure, Carol. I tell you what,
why don't I just meet you there.
You know what, my battery
is just about to die on me.
So I will see you tomorrow. Sleep tight
and sweet dreams, sweetie.
Okay.
That was smart.
You wanna go to a party
tomorrow night?
Oh, it looks like the mothership.
- You look beautiful.
- Thanks.
You said these parties got wild.
I never expected this.
- Well, Jerry sure can throw a party.
- This party's loud.
You know, Jerry, I think
you might be a little too old for me.
Too old? Girl, you done
hurt my feelings.
Oh, excuse me.
- Hey, baby.
- Hey, sweetie.
- You been drinking?
- No, silly. I can't drink. I'm pregnant.
Yes, you are.
I wanna introduce you
to a couple of my students.
Darlene, Bernadette,
this is my fiancée, Carol.
- Hi.
That's my favorite dress.
There's sure a lot
of midgets around here.
Actually, it's "little people. "
There we go. Look who's brushing
up on the terminology.
Is that Jerry Robin, Jr.
Sitting over there?
- It sure is.
- I'm gonna get an autograph.
- Hey.
- Yeah.
- Wanna get a drink or something?
- I'd love to get a drink.
- Hey, Sally. Hey, Rolfe.
- Hey.
- Have you seen Maurice and Lucy?
- Oh, no, not again.
- What happened to your eye?
- He was defending my honor.
Yeah.
- You wanna get a drink?
- Yeah, sure.
That bourgeois shit
makes me want to vomit.
Do you hear me?
You don't approve of my methods?
Well, I don't approve of your methods.
Would you mind
not doing that, please?
- Doing what?
- Waving your finger in people's faces.
- It's rude.
- Hey.
You better back off, Goldie Hawn.
My man can do what he wants to do.
Listen to me.
Because I want you to know what
I think about your organization.
You go, "We are the little people.
Please, we are so cute and cuddly.
Don't discriminate against us. "
Our organization has battled
long and hard...
...to sweep away those stereotypes.
Another thing: I think the term
"little people" is demeaning.
- Carol, Sally.
- Hi.
What sort of political activity
do you suggest we create...
...once we disband,
because we're so bourgeois?
What you people don't understand
is that political power...
...it grows out of the barrel of a gun.
- Yeah, right.
Now you want us to commit violence.
We don't do that here.
Americans don't do that.
Oh, Americans.
Yeah, the people that saved
your ass during World War II.
Oh, now you want to talk about
the fucking war.
Why are we talking to this guy?
- He is very passionate.
- Don't you patronize me.
- Yeah.
- Who do you think you are?
I am French!
And I'm proud to be French.
I am proud not to eat this disgusting
swill you people call cuisine.
- I am proud.
- Excuse my friend... Fuck.
- Fuck.
- Fucking asshole.
Bobby is my uncle. Besides being my
uncle, he happens to be a great guy.
- He is nothing.
- Oh, fuck.
- Who the fuck are you, anyway?
- Hey, I know who I am.
And I know what I am.
I am a Marxist.
- Who are you?
- I don't wanna hear about it.
Just lay off. I don't even wanna see
you the fuck near him. You got it?
Fine.
So have you known Rolfe
a long time?
- Yeah, we used to date in high school.
- No, really?
- He went to high school?
- Yeah, that was ages ago.
I'm just waiting...
What's the matter, you got some
kind of identity crisis going on?
What are you talking about?
Why didn't you tell
your girlfriend about us?
What's it to you, man?
Okay. Forget about us, forget about
family, you just focus on this:
You knocked up this gal and didn't
tell her that her baby might be little.
- And how's that any of your business?
- Oh, I'm sorry, I'm your brother.
It hurts to think that
you're so ashamed of it.
Oh, goddamn you, Rolfe.
Man, sometimes
you are so full of shit.
- I'm full of shit?
- Yeah, full of shit.
Just because I'm not
one of these guys...
...who has to bare his soul
to everybody.
- I'm not like you.
- Sorry, I should've been more careful.
I should've kept in mind
that anyone who meets you...
...will automatically know that you've
got a twin brother who's a midget.
- God.
- You know, when she saw me...
...she got it, straight up.
And I just... I just...
...introduced her to people who could
answer some questions and that's it.
Look, it's my life too, okay?
If you wanna blame someone
for being nosy, then blame me.
I needed information, I got it.
Rolfe didn't do anything.
- Hey, you don't have to defend me.
- I can if I want.
I'm gonna find Sally.
I'm gonna take Sally home.
- Look, you want me to drive you?
- No, I'll take a cab.
- Are you mad at me now?
- No, I'm not mad.
I'm just bewildered.
Look, Carol, I wish I had some
answers, all right? But I don't.
- All right? Not right now. Come here.
- Yeah, well, it's been a crazy week.
Yeah.
- Jesus, Steven.
- It's gonna be all right, baby. All right?
I'll make it up to you.
Just give me some time.
I can't find her anywhere.
- She's gotta be around here.
- I saw Sally there a little while ago.
Thanks, Augie.
You go get the car,
I'll help Rolfe find his girlfriend.
Sally!
Rolfe?
Hey, Rolfe, wait up.
Oh, shit.
- Rolfe.
- What's up, man?
- That's it.
- I'm done with you, Sally.
- Rolfe? Rolfe.
Hey, Rolfe, wait up.
- What's going on?
- Rolfe caught Sally...
...screwing Jerry Robin, Jr.
- He's really broken up.
- Oh, shit.
- Let's just go, okay?
- All right.
- You got the ticket, sweetie?
- Yeah.
- Here you go.
- Right away, sir.
Listen, can you wait for me
just a second?
Yeah, sure.
What do you say, man?
Carol told me what happened
and that's pretty fucked-up.
What a bitch, huh?
I was stupid to think anything
could be different or change.
You think I'm stupid?
- You're asking if I think you're stupid?
- You're taking too long to answer.
Come on, get in the car.
Come home with us.
- I'm waiting for a cab.
- Fuck the cab.
- Come home with us, man.
- You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
You already been on the sofa,
haven't you?
Hey.
You're awake.
What's going on?
Can't sleep.
Why, what's the matter?
It's not too late
to think about adopting.
Look.
I'm not one of those crazy
anti-abortion people, Steven...
...you know that.
But I want this baby.
Having a fucked-up kid
is no bed of roses, Carol.
Hey. Do not apply the term
"fucked-up" to our child, okay?
You know what I mean.
Well, what was Rolfe's
childhood like?
Did the other kids
give him a hard time?
No, not really.
There's other problems
with being little...
...besides the social stuff,
you know?
- Like what, medical stuff?
- Yeah.
I mean, when Rolfe was a kid...
...he was in a lot of pain.
He used to cry all the time.
- Why? Being a little person hurts?
- Yeah.
See, they've got...
They've got organs, musculature,
that's too big for their skeleton.
Yeah, right, but they have drugs
for that, don't they?
Yeah, it's called morphine.
Then sometimes they need surgery.
What do you mean?
Did Rolfe need surgery?
No. Thank God, oh, no.
And what was
his teenage years like?
Rolfe as a teenager?
That guy got laid two years
before I did.
- With Sally?
- Absolutely.
You should've seen those two.
They were hysterical.
They were like this dysfunctional
old couple, you know.
This one time in school...
...and they couldn't have been
more than 15 years old...
...it was between classes...
...Sally corners Rolfe and she screams
at the top of her lungs...
...she says, "Rolfe Bedalia,
you haven't fucked me in five months. "
The principal was there.
All the kids were there.
You should've seen Rolfe's face.
It was beautiful.
I was so goddamn
jealous of that guy.
Have you ever been involved
with a little person sexually?
No, just kid stuff, you know?
All the kids would come over,
sit in a circle, play doctor.
Couldn't have been more than 10
or 12, so that doesn't count.
So you had a circle jerk
with a bunch of little people?
I would've loved to see that.
- You would like to see that.
- Yes, I would.
- Are you sure you wanna do this?
- Yeah, I really am.
You sure you're not just trying to make
some weird political statement?
Oh, God.
What a peculiar thing to say.
Well, I'm a peculiar guy.
I'm serious.
I think you have a lot of ambivalence
about your family being little.
It's not healthy and I think you should
consider getting some help.
Are you saying you think
I need to see a shrink?
God, there's nothing wrong
with seeing a shrink, okay?
Don't you see?
It's not a good thing
for a child, if he's little...
...to have a father who's ambivalent
about little people.
I hope you'll at least consider it.
So tell me, Carol, what is it exactly
you do for a living?
- I'm a painter.
- A painter?
What, you mean, like, fine art?
- Did you go to school?
- Yeah...
...to the New York School
of Art and Design.
I'm impressed.
- You mean you make money at that?
- Yeah, it pays the bills.
Hey, Mr. And Mrs. Lefarge.
Welcome, I'm Steven.
- How do you do?
- Very well.
Carol said you were handsome.
Isn't he handsome?
- Oh, my God.
- Y'all come on in.
- How was the drive?
- Not bad, not bad.
- Good.
- Mom, Dad.
- Hi, sweetie.
- There you are.
Oh, honey, you look beautiful.
Just beautiful.
This is Steven's father, Bruno,
and his mom, Kathleen.
And over behind the bar
is Steven's brother, Rolfe.
- Hi.
- How are you?
Everyone, this is my mom and dad,
Kirk and Sylvia.
- Nice to meet you.
- So, what are y'all drinking?
Let me have a 7 and 7.
Sylvia?
- She'll have a vodka tonic.
- Vodka tonic, coming up.
- I'll help you.
- So you wanna come out back?
- We're all set up out there.
- All right.
Thought she might want a double.
You all right?
So there's pretty good money in this
firefighting business, is there?
Well, actually, I train cadets
to be firefighters.
And, you know, fires
are pretty much recession-proof.
I'd say it's pretty steady, yeah.
- Where did you learn all this stuff?
- In the Navy.
- You're a Navy man?
- Yes, sir.
Well, what do you know?
Navy man myself.
- All right.
- Where were you stationed?
Get me that barbecue sauce
from the kitchen.
Pop's pretty much a fanatic
when it comes to the barbecue.
- You could've prepared us for this.
- I didn't think it was important.
Embarrass me,
I won't speak to you.
- So just get it together, Mom, okay?
- Always the nonconformist.
- How's everybody's drink?
- Still working on mine, thanks.
Sylvia?
- Where's that sauce, Steven?
- Yeah, yeah, on it, Pop.
Okay, everybody.
Hors d'oeuvre time.
Everybody, please gather round.
I would like to propose a toast.
Hey, Rolfie!
To a very beautiful young woman
and a very fine young man...
...who are very much in love and who,
hopefully, as the years go by...
...will find the same joy
and happiness...
...that Steven's mother
and I have found these past 30 years.
- Hear, hear.
- Amen.
There once was a young fellow
from Sparta
- No, Kirk.
- Who was a real whiz as a farter
He'd fart anything,
from "God Save the King"
To Beethoven's Moonlight Sonata
He'd fart a gavotte for a starter
And then a Handelian cantata
Boost up his ass
Blast Bach's B minor Mass
And then counterpoint La Traviata
That has to be the last one.
- Obviously, he can't drink any more.
- Yes, he can.
- No, no, this is getting better, yes.
- No, give him some water. My God.
- You have no idea...
- Yes, drink away.
You know, these steaks
are really delicious.
Genuine prime rib.
I have it brought in from Omaha.
- I'm stuffed like a pig.
- Save some room for dessert, Rolfe.
Oh, no, I can't.
I can barely breathe, I'm so full.
Is everything all right, Sylvia?
Oh, yes.
I was just thinking, is all.
Sylvia.
Don't think.
I think that there's something
that we need to bring up...
...that you won't want to hear.
- Mom.
I'm sorry. But this has
to be brought out into the open.
I certainly wouldn't want anyone
to think that we're prejudiced people.
Daddy.
All right, Kirk, you tell them.
You're a lot more diplomatic
than I am.
Well, the fact of the matter is...
...Carol's grandfather
is getting on in years.
- Please.
- And...
...he's an Orthodox Jew. And he's
never forgiven us for going Reform.
So unless you can bring yourself
to have a Jewish wedding...
...would you at least consider
a civil ceremony?
Otherwise, we won't
be able to invite him.
I got no problem with
a Jewish wedding.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Mom?
Pop? Carol?
- Rolfe?
- Lf he dies before they get married...
...can we switch back to Catholic?
When a man and a woman
come together before God...
...and announce their intentions...
May God be blessed with
the men and women...
...of Israel and every generation...
Look at that wedding dress.
That's a waste of a dress.
Look at that belly.
- I would not kick her out of bed.
- You're starting to piss me off now.
Enough with her.
But you love me.
All right. But you know what?
That should be us down there, right?
Don't you ever think of marrying me?
Marriage is for morons.
It turns a lover into a relative.
Like a brother...
...or a sister.
I can't think of anything that takes
the passion out of a relationship...
...more than marriage.
You may kiss the bride.
Mazel tov!
Oh, my God.
Hello, Mrs. Bedalia.
Nice name, huh?
You know what?
Hold on one second.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
Rolfe.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- I just wanted to say thank you.
I haven't done anything.
God, you did so much.
And I really appreciate it.
Well, Steven's a...
He's a very lucky guy.
I just hope he's smart enough
not to screw it up.
- So, what are you gonna do now?
- I'm gonna go to my parents' place.
Cabin, Big Bear. For the winter.
Get some writing done.
I think you're wonderful, Rolfe.
Dr. Morgan, please report
to the administration desk.
- How you doing, Carol?
- Okay.
Steven?
We're gonna run some tests.
Vincent's gonna have
to stay here at the clinic.
Then we'll start him
on a long-term regimen...
...that we'll keep him
on through puberty.
Just hang in there, honey, okay?
We can handle this.
We're talking biweekly
hormone injections...
...monthly blood samples
to monitor his liver function.
After a while you'll be able
to administer the injections yourself.
- It's gonna be a big commitment.
- Yeah, but we're up for that.
- Aren't we, Steven?
- Goddamn it!
Damn it, how can you two
be so calm?
Because I'm prepared.
And because we don't have a choice.
I read all the books
that you recommended.
Good.
I think you'll be fine.
- As for you...
- Yeah, what about me?
Please, Steven,
you're gonna frighten the baby.
- What about me?
- I think you should seek...
...some counseling.
- That's what I told him.
Look, what I need...
...are new chromosomes.
You're making this so much harder
than it needs to be...
...do you know that?
I can't talk to him.
He won't listen to me.
Nurse Simon, please pick up line six.
- How you doing, sweetie?
- I'm okay. Are you okay?
How's he doing?
Let me take him for a while.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
- Got him?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Listen to this guy, huh?
Oh, my God, he's been going
like this for two hours straight.
He hurts.
Yeah, well, I gave him
the drops, but...
They seemed to help
a little bit, but...
- Give him something stronger.
- I can't. I called them.
They said it was normal
for babies with his condition.
What?
Just say the word one time.
- What?
- Just say the word one time, Carol.
- Please, Steven...
- What's his condition?
Ten months, you haven't said
it one time. What's his condition?
Why is he crying? Why is he hurting?
Because he's a dwarf.
- Carol, he's a dwarf!
- Stop it!
- He's a baby and you're scaring him!
- A baby and a dwarf...
...and he's crying because he hurts.
- Fuck you!
- His insides can't get outside.
- One time!
One time, say the goddamn word!
He's a dwarf!
I'm a dwarf!
Look, this can't go on anymore.
Carol, this is just not working out.
Look, no one said
this was gonna be easy.
I know.
But it's not getting any better.
Not between us, it's not.
Oh, Steven.
I can't take it.
I mean, it's obvious
that I'm just making things worse.
I just think I can
do better by Vincent...
...we can do better by Vincent...
...if I'm somewhere else.
And you really think that?
Yeah.
I do.
Expecting someone?
Not me.
Did you fart?
No, I did not fart.
Enough.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Steven and I separated.
I hope this isn't too much
of an inconvenience.
No, not at all.
Is it okay if we stay for a few days?
Sure. Stay as long as you like.
Thanks.
Is this my nephew?
Holy cow.
He's a good-looking kid.
Hey.
Come in.
So how do you guys get by
so far from civilization?
It's a perfect situation for a writer.
- Oh, how's it going, your writing?
- It's pretty good.
I'm syndicated in three papers.
The San Diegan, The Fresno Bee
and the Chicago Tribune.
That's so great.
Rolfe's a middle-of-the-road kind
of guy. That's what they want.
Yeah, Maurice thinks that my views
aren't radical enough.
- They aren't.
- From what I remember...
...of your politics, I don't think they'd
go over in a mainstream paper.
You better be careful,
they could lock you in a loony bin...
...and that's not fun.
If Maurice had his way,
he'd take the heads...
...of the members of Congress, put
them on a spear and display them...
...out on the White House lawn.
Yeah, that sounds like the Maurice
I remember.
One day, I wanna buy a place like this.
Well, until you do, you can stay here
as long as you want.
Superb.
We need a woman around here.
Someone to do the dishes,
someone to wash the clothes.
In your dreams, pal.
Maurice probably liked it in the
Dark Ages when we scrubbed...
...the skidmarks
out of your loincloth.
I think the women's liberation
movement is an excuse...
...for every poor female pig
who needed a reason...
...not to clean up after themselves.
- You know what?
Until you stop blasting a hole in the
ozone with your toxic gas attacks...
...this little maid's on an extended
coffee break.
Feeding time again.
If you drink, does he get drunk too?
I'm not drunk.
Well, maybe a little bit.
Hey, you ever hear from Sally?
Sally? No. We're...
...not in contact right now.
I liked her.
She had her good points.
Yeah, well, fuckability, Maurice,
is not the be-all and end-all...
Your relationship with Lucy
is nothing to crow about!
Now they fight like this all the time!
That's a shame.
You seem like a really good couple.
Turn it down!
Lucy, I've had it with you!
I am not your old lady anymore,
Maurice.
I am moving out of your teepee.
That is just super with me!
I can't take it anymore!
Bye, Rolfe. Thanks for everything.
Lucy, I really hate to see you
leave like this.
- I am leaving you first.
- Oh, no, you're not. You know what?
Last one who leaves is a rotten egg.
Hey.
How are you, buddy?
Caught in the act.
Well, he was awake.
I figured you could use a break.
You go on. Go back to bed.
Really. Get some rest.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
I'm no expert on babies...
...but I think
I got things covered here.
He's okay.
Thanks.
Good night.
Hey, Carol.
How was your drive?
It was good.
It was uneventful, you know.
Look at you.
He's getting big and strong.
Yeah, he is.
Hello, Vincent.
My little man.
How you doing?
I'm doing all right.
I'm working on it.
Trying to be the man
that you want me to be.
You've gotta want it too, Steven.
You know what, I do want it.
I love you.
I know that.
I've never doubted that for a moment.
But it's not about
you and me anymore.
You've gotta love our child.
You don't think that I love Vincent?
No, I know that you do.
It's just, you can't show it.
If you can't show it,
then as far as he's concerned...
...it might as well not exist.
Don't you see? Right now,
you don't have a lot to offer him.
No. You're... You're wrong.
That's what I want. I...
I wanna show it.
All right? If you'll just give me
another chance.
Look, what goes on
between a parent and a child...
...that's what's really important.
Vincent's gotta come first.
I'm not angry with you, okay?
I'm not angry.
And I don't hate you.
So, what are you gonna do, Carol?
You gonna live up here in the woods
like a couple of hippies?
Listen to me, okay?
This way, we can all still be family.
You can see your kid
whenever you want.
But he can't wait around for you.
He has too many needs right now.
- I'm his father.
- But right now you're too self-involved.
You're too confused.
I've got too much to do already without
spending my time bringing you along.
And this is what you want?
This is what I think is right.
Hey, Rolfe.
Boy, what you two
must think of me, huh?
What does that mean?
You're still my brother.
Coming in?
No, I don't think so.
I'm gonna say goodbye to Vincent
and head on back to the city.
Are you mad at me?
No, I'm not mad.
I'll see you around, big boy.
Love my son.
You're gonna be okay, Steven.
I'm gonna do my best.
You okay?
Yeah.
A little shook-up.
I don't think I'll be getting to sleep
anytime soon.
Here.
Come with me.
Come on.
You okay?
It's heavenly.
Absolutely heavenly.
Look at the stars.
They're so bright up there.
Rolfe.
What?
You can kiss me if you want.