Dream, Dream
You got a light?
Yeah.
Charlie Bronson.
You look just like him.
Bye.
Ok, Charlie. Ok, Goodbye.
Charlie Bronson.
Ok, baby.
Oh my god!
Today, in the bar "La Ilusión"
in Three Corners,
A big show,
Mario "The Curly One"
and his talking dummy,
Today, in the bar "La Ilusión,"
in Three Corners, a big show
Mario "The Curly One"
and his talking dummy,
Ok, baby.
Thank you, thank you,
Thank you very much.
And now we're off to old Paris.
Turn off the lights.
- By the great Aznavour
- Mario...
Hey Mario, over here...
- Do you remember me?
- Yes, Charlie.
He calls me that
because I look like Bronson.
Huh?
I said, he calls me that
because I look like Bronson.
- Huh?
- Nothing, nothing
It's better like that
Turn off the lights
In the darkness of your youth
Tell me the truth
I know Paris sleeps fearlessly
While our hearts burn vis-à-vis
Say it fast, Charlie, firmly
and without hesitation!
If an elephant fell in the water,
how would it come out?
- Uh, I don't know?
- Wet!
Charlie, Charlie, answer fast,
firmly, and without hesitation
How do you get all of the women
in the world to follow you?
I don't know.
Walk in front of them!
Charlie, Charlie, answer fast,
firmly, and without hesitation
What's the first thing a cow
makes when the sun comes up?
I don't know.
A shadow.
What time does the bus to
the city leave?
I don't know, I think around 4.
- Are you leaving?
- Mhm.
I've been meaning to
ask you something.
When you said I look like
Charlie Bronson...
Were you serious?
Yeah, I'm serious.
If I were as handsome as you,
I wouldn't spend another
minute in this small town.
What do you have to do?
To do what?
To do that, to be an artist.
How should I know?
Leave!
Leave for Buenos Aires.
Oh yeah, of course.
Buenos Aires.
The thing is, I'm so happy here.
I work at Town Hall.
On top of the... salary,
they give me two suits per year.
One in the winter,
another one in the summer.
And they let me use the bicycle.
Two suits? Two suits per year?
Are you nuts?
We're talking about art, fame,
thousands of dollars.
And you come up with two suits!
Oh, of course.
And how do you get started?
Get what started?
That, being an artist.
The first thing you need
is a stage name.
If you ask me...
- Charlie Bronson!
- Yeah, but there's one already.
Right...
But as my name is Carlos too...
It's OK, but it's not happening.
I've always liked the idea
of being an artist.
I've already been in the
paper El Pueblo once.
Look. You see?
I got kicked by a horse.
It says right there.
"Our neighbor, Carlos Irrazábal
was kicked by a horse."
That's great.
- With a photo and everything!
- How great is that?
That's when I got the
job at Town Hall.
You see?
Because I got kicked by a horse.
- You got a light?
- Yeah, yeah.
Thanks.
You know what?
I've been meaning to tell you...
If you want, I can invite
you to sleep in my room.
After all, you don't have
a show tomorrow.
I wouldn't want to bother you.
Oh no, no problem at all.
It's not 5 stars, but...
It used to be my Mom's bed.
I'm going to get it ready for you.
- Could you give me a hand?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Thanks.
There won't be any trouble
with the neighbors, right?
The closest hotel is 3 blocks away.
- You're gonna sing?
- No, no, I don't sing.
- I lip sync.
- Ba dum chhh.
- Coffee?
- Sure.
- Can I watch?
- Hmm?
- Is it OK if I watch?
- Mhm.
What's that for?
- What's "that"?
- That.
For my curls.
That's what I'm known for.
It's my persona.
You know everything.
Mine are like wires.
That's how hard they are.
I use gallons of gel,
but they're still that hard.
That's how hard they are!
- Coffee?
- Sure.
1... 2... 3...
Do you have any extra ones?
Can I offer you some
constructive criticism?
About what?
About the ventriloquist's
dummy thing.
In the picture,
you're with the dummy.
But you didn't have it
at the show.
No, the thing is...
Back when they took the photo,
I was working with a dwarf.
I was working as
a ventriloquist.
I used to go on stage carrying
a suitcase with the dwarf inside.
All the while, the lights were dim.
I would open the suitcase,
and the dwarf would jump out.
That dwarf was a genius.
- Polvorita!
- Yes?
- Do you trust your girlfriend?
- Of course I trust my girlfriend!
- Why do you trust your girlfriend?
- Well, because I believe her.
- Does your girlfriend love you?
- Of course she loves me.
- And where is she right now?
- She must be at home.
No, sir, the other day she was seen
buying eggs at the general store.
- Of course, to cook with.
- But they were golden eggs.
- Of course, she went to buy them.
- But the shopkeeper wasn't there.
- So, who'd she buy them from?
- The jeweler.
Oh really?
Turn off the lights,
Jasmine and carnations
My crossed arms
dream of your skin
Stop the clock,
Come closer to me
Only you and me,
It's better like this
Turn off the lights,
And in the darkness of your youth
Tell me the truth
Those were my finest moments.
I bought all that stuff back then.
And what happened?
It went to his head.
All of the success
went to his head.
That's what always happens.
You work hard, invent them
a persona, make them famous,
And when success comes?
Bye. They say, "Haven't I
seen you somewhere before?"
I would never do such a thing.
Everybody loves me here.
Because I'm a good friend.
When I lost my Mom
a little while ago,
A ton of people came to the wake.
A ton!
Mother! Your name is everything.
I cry before your tomb,
And I bless you with my life
Who doesn't feel protected
by your sacred name?
Only he who has lost you
knows your value
I cry because I don't have you
I laugh because I have had you
And now that I've lost you,
I wonder why
Why did God take
her away from me?
Why this infinite pain?
A mother is like a blazon
A mother is everything in life
A mother is a heart
A mother is a torrent of tears
And a mother is forgiveness
if we lose our way
Ay, mother, I get on my knees
And ask for your blessing
Mario...
Huh? What?
The poem was beautiful.
Who wrote it?
- It's mine.
- I'd like to write it down.
Carlitos, you came.
I came to say goodbye, Mom.
I'm going to Buenos Aires
to work as an artist.
To Buenos Aires!
To work as an artist!
I always wanted to
be an artist, Mom.
Let's go tell your Aunts!
Oh no, Mom! Not the Aunts!
They're dead, they scare me!
Don't say that about your Aunts,
poor thing, they love you so.
Not the aunts, they're dead,
they scare me.
Genoveva! Custodia!
Come here, come here!
Carlitos is going to Buenos Aires
to work as an artist!
Come here!
Carlitos is going to Buenos Aires
to work as an artist!
Carlitos is going to Buenos Aires.
Mario...
Huh, what?
It's me.
- What time is it?
- It's 6.
What are you doing up
this early?
I'm making breakfast,
I'm going to work.
- What is that for?
- What?
Your glasses.
- Do they look bad?
- No, just saying.
- Are they for your persona?
- No, no.
It's just that I have round eyes.
They're small, like a little pig's.
Like my gramps.
But when I make enough money,
I'm going to get surgery.
They're going to look like this,
like Omar Sharif.
You know everything, huh?
I've got a surprise for you.
- Good morning.
Good morning, Don Toto.
Carlitos, what happened to you?
Nothing, why? I'm going to Buenos
Aires to work as an artist.
Oh, good for you.
Say, Don Toto, you wanted to
buy my little plot, right?
Good morning... Good morning...
Excuse me, Mr. Mayor.
- Is something wrong, Carlos?
- No, nothing, sir. Why?
No, it's nothing. I'm listening.
Well sir, I, I was thinking,
I came to say goodbye.
Because I'm going to Buenos
Aires to work as an artist.
Carlitos is off to Buenos Aires
to work as an artist, Carlitos!
to work as an artist!
Carlitos is off to Buenos Aires
to work as an artist, Carlitos!
Stay here! Stay here!
Shut up!
Mario.
This is from my plot.
I sold it.
I want you to keep it.
- Because it's for both of us.
- Why?
Why...?
Alright Charlie, it's OK.
Carlitos, look at you!
Stay here! Stay here!
I... I...
Never had a father, or a mother.
That is to say, I lost them.
The town hall...
Was my mother and father.
And although I had a job,
they gave me two suits
One in the winter,
another in the summer,
And they lent me the bicycle.
I never changed, never!
I was always the same
for my friends.
I didn't change when I got the job.
I was always the same
for my friends.
Even now that I'm going to
Buenos Aires to work as an artist,
I'm still going to remember you.
I will never forget you.
Never!
Take care of the bicycle.
It's yours now.
Rosita! Rosita!
You didn't love me, huh?
Now you're gonna see who I am!
Rosita! This is for you!
Mom...
Long live my country!
Mario...
Mario! Mario!
- So you made it?
- You have to take me with you!
Please, please!
I gave you a note saying that
I'd wait for you here.
- That's a lie!
- It's true!
You have to take me please,
they already sent me off.
Please, they already sent me off.
- Speak, answer.
- Lady.
- Speak, answer now.
- Baby.
- Don't hesitate, Charlie.
- Red.
- Answer, speak.
- Coat.
- Now, answer, speak.
- Young.
- Speak, answer now.
- Gentleman.
- Without delay...
- Child.
- Answer.
- Handbag.
- Answer, speak.
- Blue.
- Repeat it, Charlie.
- Coat.
- Speak, answer now.
- Fur coat.
- Answer me, tell me now.
- Brown.
- Think, Charlie. Don't answer, think.
- Child.
- Don't waver, Charlie, answer.
- Mr.
- Think, don't answer, Charlie.
- Red.
- What're you waiting for, Charlie?
- Blue.
- Think, Charlie. Don't answer, think.
- Brown.
- Think, Charlie, answer.
- Old man.
- What're you waiting for, Charlie?
- Say it, Charlie.
- Baby.
- Should we call a doctor?
- Don't worry. Take this.
The House of Horror, with the fattest
electrocuted person in the world,
The decapitated woman,
with blood, lots of blood,
Mixed with oriental beauty.
Come and see, come and see,
ladies and gentelmen,
Come and see the House of Horror,
with the fattest electrocuted...
This is incredible, people!
We have here Manzour
The Cossack prince and the
Queen of Siberia!
And the most spectacular
acrobats of the century!
Come, people! It's a show
worth seeing!
Beautiful girl, the rarest pearl
in all of Jalisco and Guadalajara
Balancing acts, ponies, clowns,
take a good look.
Dog weddings, the one and only,
come, ladies and gentlemen,
Come and see our special show,
Balancing acts, ponies, clowns...
Come see the talking dummy!
Come and see!
Ritar, the Gypsy prince, the dwarf
Polvorita and his great gypsy ballet!
Charlie, the Memory Cowboy,
Will respond firmly
and without hesitation
To each of your queries.
Your hopes and dreams
will become reality.
The reality of an unknown world,
truly mysterious, and truly magical.
And to lead us to
this magical world...
- Hey, careful with that gun...
- Quiet, jerk, we're working here.
As I was saying, to lead you to
this unknown and magical world,
Will be the steadying hand of
Mario, the Curly One.
The European.
Ok, Charlie. Concentrate.
Are you concentrating, Charlie?
Of course, my brother.
Let's go, Charlie. Kazam!
Thank you. Concentrate, Charlie.
Ok, speak, fast, firmly and
without hesitations,
Who am I in front of
and what do I have in my hand?
C'mon Charlie, concentrate.
Who am I in front of
and what do I have in my hand?
Answer, Charlie, fast, firmly
and without hesitations.
Who am I in front of
and what do I have in my hand?
Good, Charlie. Thank you.
Firmly and without hesitation,
Charlie, answer fast.
What color is this man's blazer?
C'mon Charlie, firmly and
without hesitation,
What color is the man's blazer?
Don't think about it, Charlie,
don't think about it.
What color is the man's blazer?
Concentrate.
C'mon Charlie, concentrate.
What color is the man's blazer?
- Hurry up, would you? I'm on now.
- Wait a minute, we're working here.
C'mon Charlie, concentrate.
What color is the man's blazer?
He can't see.
No, people, we can't work like this.
Charlie, don't think any more,
what color is the man's blazer?
What color is the man's blazer?
I forgot.
How did you forget?
Motherfucker.
Charlie...
Come here.
It's over. The past is the past.
I forgive you, OK?
Sit down.
I'm not mad at you.
I've already forgiven you.
Would you be willing
to swallow swords?
- Swallow what?
- Swords, it's the easiest there is.
You stand like this.
The sword doesn't have a blade.
And you swallow the whole thing.
It's easy, and there's no danger.
- And why don't you swallow it?
- Because I'm your presenter.
No, no, I'm not swallowing it.
If you want, I'll present you.
You, present me?
Moron! Indian!
I'm an Indian?
And what are you? European!
Io sono europeo!
- I wish I had the dwarf...
- Go find the dwarf!
You always bring up the dwarf!
Go find the dwarf!
You're always insulting me!
I'll take a double hot chocolate and
6 croissants with jelly and butter.
For him, a coffee. Black.
No, sir. I will also take a double
hot chocolate with croissants!
Here in Argentina, you don't eat
if you don't work.
The money is mine,
it's from the plot.
You spent the money from the
plot on your pneumonia.
I caught pneumonia when I went
looking for you at the station.
Because you were leaving
with my money!
No, sir. I left you a note telling
you to wait at the station.
You're lying.
You don't love me, then.
But of course I love you.
Who took care of you when
you got pneumonia?
You.
So...
Why do you say that I don't
love you?
Why do you always bring up
the dwarf, huh?
-Why?
-Because you don't want to work.
But I don't want to
swallow swords, you know?
It's scary. I'm like this
because of the pneumonia.
That's why I can't remember
anything, you know?
Do you want to rehearse again?
Weren't you the one who said
that I look like Charlie Bronson?
Alright.
We're going to rehearse again.
OK, but don't mention
the dwarf again.
Alright.
The past is the past.
Waiter! He'll have a hot
chocolate too.
- Speak, answer.
- Red.
Come here. Lorena, come here!
I said come here, Lorena.
If you don't come here,
we're never coming back again.
Mario... Mario...
I'm falling asleep, Mario.
I'm fainting from hunger,
I can't take it anymore.
Thief! Thief!
After the thief!
Please, everybody after the thief!
Help, I've been robbed by a thief!
After the thief!
Scumbag!
Help! Everybody after the thief!
Where did the furball go?
Tell me, where is your bearded
friend? Where is he?
- I didn't do anything, sir!
- Where is he? Answer me!
Come on, answer me!
Where is the furball?
There's a thief over there, a thief.
Dimwit! Where have you been?
What happened to you?
I've been waiting for you.
Want to eat?
What's the matter with you?
- Bye.
Thief! Thief! That's the
tip of the iceberg!
- Scream softly!
- Thief!
- Shut your mouth!
- I'm not shutting anything,
- That's the tip of the iceberg!
- Shut your mouth!
What is my dead mother
going to say?
I'm killing myself!
Me, a thief!
Go on, kill yourself, but don't
scream. Let me eat!
I'm going to jump and kill myself.
I'm going to kill myself!
Mario... Mario...
Look, Mario.
It's been so long since
I've been with a woman.
The artist was born to fly.
Women, children...
They're an obstacle.
Stay calm.
Stay calm and stick with me.
I know all this very well.
Yeah, but I feel bad.
I need to go to the
bathroom, Mario.
Look, that brunette over there
is the most...
You, you, you, and you.
The rest can leave, go home.
- Not me? Excuse me.
- No, the rest can leave.
No, I want the darkie, not you.
I want the darkie, where is he?
I brought him, I'm his brother.
I can help with the co-production.
Excuse me.
- I told you, he's a moron.
- Darkie, come over here.
All I'm interested in is the role,
I don't care about the money.
I'm not interested in the money.
What's going on?
Everybody's looking for you.
I didn't do anything, sir.
"God gives bread to
those without teeth."
Let's go, the director is waiting.
- Hurry up before he gets mad!
- Hurry up, please!
- Can he ride a horse?
- Yes.
I'm not in it for the money.
- Can he swim?
- Yeah, I think so.
But all I'm interested in is the role,
I don't care about the money.
You...
You're just like the rest.
Like the dwarf and everyone else.
Now that you've made it...
You say, "Haven't I seen
you somewhere before?"
I'm not the dwarf.
I am true to my friends.
Everybody loves me.
Mario, how do you do this?
Let's see...
I knew it. A role with
dialogue and everything.
I'd sooner be dead than defeated.
I'd sooner be dead.
I'd sooner be dead than...
Than...
Than what?
- Than defeated?
- Yes, defeated.
But what's the matter with you?
Don't you feel it?
Don't you have blood?
Feel it! Feel it!
I'd sooner be dead than defeated!
You're disturbing the neighbors!
You were good. Really good.
That's how you have to do it.
Like that.
You're a prince, Carlos!
- You look like a prince!
- Where are they taking me?
Mario! Where are they taking me?
Don't worry, man.
- Mario!
- Don't worry!
Where are they taking me, Mario?
Film crew. Film crew!
Thanks.
Motherfuckers.
Attention, hill. Tell me when the
zone 2 director's crew arrives.
Attention, they're coming
with the double.
C'mon, baby. Let's go kid.
Step on it.
Stay calm, give the kid the script.
- Give the kid the script.
- Stay calm.
Is there a bathroom around here?
- Here's the script, kid.
- What?
- Read the script, let's go.
- What script?
- The script.
- The script?
Son of a bitch, park it, man!
Step on, get up there. Don't be
scared, you're not going to fall.
Hey kid, don't worry, we're
going to make you look good.
Hey, don't mess with him, man.
C'mon, mount, don't be afraid,
don't worry about them.
No, no, I'm not mounting.
- Let's go, kid, mount.
- No, I don't know how.
You don't know how?
I'm gonna kill you.
I swear it. I don't know how.
I'm scared.
C'mon, c'mon. Get up there.
No, sir! No, sir!
It looks like he's gotten away.
We have some tracks here.
Film crew!
Can you take me?
Turtle-faced bastard.
Attention, attention. Look
for him in zone 3.
Charlie!
- What's wrong with you?
- Ay, Mario.
- C'mon.
Let's go. Calm down.
- Stop crying, come on.
- They wanted me to mount a horse.
If you keep it up, you're
gonna make me cry too, Charlie.
- Calm down.
- They want me to mount a horse.
All you need is a little
practice, that's all.
It's alright, Charlie.
What's up, kid? The Italian
producer's going to fire us all.
I don't want to mount, sir.
He'll mount, he'll mount.
He's like a child.
What's wrong with you?
He's making us lose time.
It's simple. Grab the flag and jump
off the cliff with the horse and all.
What did he say?
It's simple. Grab the flag
and get on the horse.
And then, with the horse and all,
you jump off the cliff.
- Ah, shit.
- Take it easy...
How can I "take it easy,"
I can't take it easy
With all of these animals.
Let's see. He's alive.
- Mario, I didn't do anything.
- Be quiet.
Carmen!
Stop, please!
Stop! Let me through.
Excuse me. Carmen.
Stop, please.
Carmen.
Carmen, how are you?
- How have you been?
- Fine. Can't you see I'm doing fine?
I...
We... wanted to talk to you.
I can't now, I'm busy.
Wait for me in the bar out front.
Bye.
- OK.
- So long.
Let's go, Charlie.
He's a genius.
The midget's a genius.
If you want, I'll leave.
- No, why?
- So you can chat in peace.
Are you crazy or something?
You're with me, right?
Here he comes.
I want some bread.
- This is...
- Waiter!
This is Charlie.
The Memory Cowboy.
What's up, man?
You wanted to talk to me?
Carmen, long time no see, eh?
Come here!
Alright, I wanted to...
- Is there a bathroom?
- There, in the back.
- The usual.
- No, nothing for me, I'm good.
I'm doing fine, too.
We have some sensational
memory routines.
We just shot a film.
You see how handsome he is?
Charlie Bronson!
Milk?
Yes, milk. What did you
want to talk about?
Carmen.
Why don't we work
together again?
Do you remember?
How the people used to applaud...
How they would laugh...
It was...
We were destined for glory.
And the cowboy?
What cowboy?
Your friend, the cowboy.
That fool?
No, he's a moron.
A moron.
An Indian.
I found him in the country.
He's hard-headed.
I was just telling him that
if we get back together,
He has to go.
Who's "we"?
Us. That's what I'm saying.
I told him that if we get
back together...
He has to go back home.
You're always the same dirtbag.
- What's the matter with you?
- Always the same dirtbag.
Why do you want to work
with me?
To sell me to another circus?
Me?
I didn't sell you.
Yes, you swapped me for 100,000
pesos and crept out in the night.
- Me?
- Yes, you, you!
I had to work in that circus for
one year until I escaped!
But I swear I didn't sell you.
The thing is...
They threatened me, you know.
They said they would kill me if
I didn't leave you.
Lies!
You lost me in a card game!
I swear by all the saints.
What saints? Didn't you say
you were a communist?
Me, a communist? Swear on
this that I'm a communist!
I don't know what's wrong
with me. I feel bad.
So, he's a moron? An Indian?
Why don't you say it now?
You're nuts. I said that?
Yeah, you said it.
You're a shitty little dwarf.
An ulcerous dwarf.
No wonder you drink milk.
What do you think you are?
You think you're indispensable?
At every circus I've been,
I've had a ton of dwarves. A ton!
And they were tinier than you!
I hope you grow up.
So you starve to death.
Let's go, Charlie.
You know what the
problem is, Charlie?
This country's not big
enough for us.
- We've got to go to Europe.
- To Europe?
Yes, to Europe, to Europe!
The actors there are all fags.
With your manly looks,
we'll knock'em all dead.
All you're missing is a little
bit of concentration.
- What?
- No, nothing.
But how?
Don't worry, leave it to me.
Have I ever done you wrong?
Firmly and without hesitation,
what is the gentleman's number?
The gentleman has cap number
14994/33.
You see, Charlie? All we needed
was a little bit of concentration.
Incredible, people! Come and see!
It's a show worth seeing!
Come one and come all, people!
Right here! Come and see!
Ladies and gentlemen, come and see
this special show,
Trapeze artists, jugglers, balancing
acts, ponies, clowns, dog weddings,
The one and only in the world,
Come and see!