Subtitles -
Luís Filipe Bernardes
- Yes, sir?
- I want to send some flowers.
Yes, Mr. Wallace.
Two dozen roses, big ones.
I'll get a card ready.
This is my first trip to New York.
Would you drive me down to Grant's Tomb?
More sightseeing tonight,
but I want to see Grant's Tomb.
# Eastside, Westside #
Mr. O'Shaughnessy!
Paging Mr. O'Shaughnessy!
# London Bridge is falling down #
# Boys and girls together #
# Me and Mamie O'Rourke #
# Tripped the light fantastic #
Oh, why don't you just hurry?
Boy, Fenwick goes 100% for Jimmy!
That's Albany shifting. Congratulations!
- What's them for?
- Champagne, sir.
Yeah, well us Democrats drink
whiskey.
I noticed that.
Oh, I'm sorry. We've been troubled
by wandering ward heelers. Thanks.
Whoopee! Queens goes for
Jimmy Jones! Boy, it's a landslide!
Wasn't it practically the keenest
wedding you've ever been to?
- Yes or no?
- Yes, definitely.
Oh, darling, don't let it ever be
any more wonderful than it is now,
because if it is, I couldn't bear it.
Oh, wait, we're embarrassing
our best man.
Where is everybody, tell us best man.
Come on, wizard, do your miracle.
- Pre-war.
- Ah, good old pre-war!
Listen, my children, you shall hear
the midnight pop of Pol Roger 1914.
Hot diggety! Champagne!
Come on. My mother told
me about it!
- No, no, you wouldn't like it.
- Oh, Mr. Hallam, please!
No drink at all!
We should set pearls before swine.
To the happy pair!
Or maybe somebody else
should have said that.
Mud in your eye!
How I love those simple,
gracious old-fashioned toasts.
It's a little early to be making plans yet,
but do you know what, Bill?
We're going to name
the first one after you.
Because I love you
and Jock loves you.
- In fact, we think you're the berries.
- Yes, we do.
Well, that's fine, because I think
you're the berries too.
Both of you.
Always have and always will.
Why don't you get married, Bill?
Did you ever think about it?
Not me. I know when I'm lucky.
Goodbye, Mary.
Why, you dumb bunny.
Aren't you going to take advantage
of your chance to kiss the bride?
Hm, that tastes familiar.
Once when I ws eleven and the other
time when I was thirteen, remember?
You'll, um... miss your boat.
Oh, you're telling me
Come on, darling!
Hey, O'Hara! We've got the Bronx
in the palm of our hands.
Out of 18 districts we got...
Where's O'Hara?
You promised me a glimpse of Al Smith
and what do I get?
- O'Hara!
- Should we tell him?
Yes, but break it to him gently.
Bad news, pal. O'Hara is...
O'Hara is...
He ain't hurt, is he?
Hurt? If it were only that.
O'Hara's gone over the Great Divide, pal.
He choked on a ???
He was the best man a man ever had.
He owed me 47 bucks.
Hi-ho lackaday, we all must
go some time.
Here today, gone tomo...
Pardon me, but that wouldn't
be champagne, would it?
- I'm a stranger here myself.
- Yes, yes, have some.
A drink for the bride.
Personally, I've never been a bride,
but they tell me it's quite an experience.
And now to the groom, poor chap.
Oh, no, the other one. Don't get me
confused at this point, please.
Oh, I'm sorry, I...
I mean, I really am sorry.
Well, darling, I think we've got to hurry
if we want to catch that boat.
Well, goodbye, Bill.
Goodbye, Miss...
Brant. Kitty Brant.
Plaza 3405.
He may be out of circulation,
but I'm not.
Lady, the name is Hallam.
He's heart-whole and fancy-free
and he can also do card tricks.
Well, come on, all ashore that's
going ashore. Goodbye, Bill.
- Goodbye, Miss Brant.
- Bye!
O'Hara!
Wise guy!
Oh, Jimmy, me lad, they told me...
- Bye!
- Goodbye, Bill.
Very nice your friend,
what does he do?
He's an architect.
I'm nice too once you get
to know me.
- Have another drink?
- Why not?
So, you're heart-whole
and fancy-free, are you?
How long have you been
in love with her?
- Who?
- Don't quibble.
You don't seem to get it. She just
got married to a Mr. John Wallace.
- You know, the handsome one.
- Sure, I know. What of it?
It just so happens that he is
my best friend.
Oh, I understand. Just pals, eh?
Well, isn't that simply dandy?
Darby and Joan and another guy.
Damon and Pythias and a girlfriend.
Is it your impression that
the best things in life are three?
No.
That's good, because it isn't
mine either.
How would you like to get
quietly cockeyed?
I'd love it.
- Monsieur, absolument pas.
- Non, mercredi!
Mais non, Monsieur, je vous assure.
Enfin, Madame en refuse.
Elle commande des fleurs lundi,
mardi, mercredi, jeudi...
Mais elle refuse tous, voyons!
- Oui?
- Wallace.
- Wallasse?
Mr. Hampton's car calling
for Mr. and Mrs. Wallace.
- Walasse?
- Wallace.
Wallace?
Ah, voilà, Mr. Wallace.
Wallace.
Mr. Wallace.
Est-ce que je peux compter
sur des violettes por demain?
Mais non, je veux pas que vous
manquez cette...
Jock! Answer the phone!
Or the door or something.
All right, come in.
You ought to say "Entrez", darling.
Remember, when in Rome.
Tell him we'll be down in a minute.
- The Hamptons' car awaits, madame.
- Oh, dear, already?
See if the studs are in my shirt,
darling, will you?
Remember those carefree days
of my girlhood?
When I had only myself to dress?
Uh-huh. Now you have me,
you lucky little woman.
- Oh, look!
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll find it.
You never have yet.
Oh, your strawberry mark.
I love it.
I almost had it taken off once.
I'm glad I didn't now.
If you ever do, I'll sue you.
- Jock, darling, we've got to rush.
- Oh, all right.
- I always did hate operas anyway.
- Oh, a little culture won't hurt you.
Who used to do this before
we were married?
Oh, I don't know, lots of people.
Lady upstairs, lady downstairs,
lady across the hall.
Kindly souls all of them.
Always willing to lend a helping hand
to a poor bachelor.
I can imagine.
- What shall it be tonight, the red?
- No, the white.
That's what you always say.
- Don't you ever get tired of white?
- Not on you.
All right, you win.
What would you have done
if I had worn the red?
I don't know. Created a scene.
- Beat you, maybe.
- Really? Marvelous.
Well, anyway, I'd have thrown
something at you.
Here.
Sooner or later you'll have to learn
to do this yourself.
Stand still.
- You talk too much.
- Darling, stand still!
There.
Looks pretty good if I do
say so myself.
Oh, Jock, we've got to hurry.
I'm ready. You're the one
who's holding things up.
Oh, that's gratitude.
I work my fingers to the bone for you,
I slave and slave over a hot stove.
Oh, Jock, you look beautiful.
No, you're beautiful, I'm merely...
merely handsome.
Of all the conceit.
But you're beautiful too.
Well, if you insist.
Hook me up.
Now, who did this before I did,
may I ask?
Oh, the gentleman upstairs,
the gentleman downstairs,
- the gentleman across the hall.
- Liar.
Neither one of us ever lived before
we were married and you know it.
We simply ate... and slept...
and talked...
and walked.
It's true, isn't it?
- Think of the years we've wasted.
- Oh, my darling.
Jock... they're waiting.
Let them wait.
This ain't half as good as the reception
they gave Bertrand Adderley.
If anyone asks your name,
remember it's full of consonants.
There they are, see?
Mary! John!
Oh, there he is!
Hey, Bill!
Look, Bill!
Look.
- Who's that with him?
- Bentley's sweetheart, remember?
- Bill!
- Bill! Bill, darling!
I adore your strange taste of
your beautiful women. Bill, how are you?
- Hello, Bill.
- How was Paris, did you have a rough trip?
- You remember Kitty Brant, don't you?
- Of course we do.
- Bill, did you get our letters?
- Oh, did he?
He read them aloud to me and told me
your life from the time you wore knee pants.
After that we went to London...
Oh, wait a minute.
Jock, don't forget the... you know.
Oh, yes, I know, I know.
- Look.
- Here, let me...
Shh!
Well, Kitty, hello!
Well, of all people. How are Mama
and Papa and all the kiddies?
- And Aunt Elsie
- Aunt Elsie's fine and...
And how are you?
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Thank you.
I'm bearing precious cargo.
Bump me and I gurgle.
Wallace! Mr. Wallace!
Is this yours?
Don't move, Bill, we don't want
to lose you.
Oh, look, Peggy Joyce just came in.
Boy, we're in the money.
At last we meet nice people.
I catch pneumonia just to see
Peggy Joyce.
Oh, now, honey, we ought to have
a little fun, don't we?
You know, um... I'd like to buy
this piece of land.
Any piece of land you wouldn't like to buy?
That's all I've heard from you lately.
And me too.
Girls, never marry an architect
with delusions of grandeur.
Take it from one who's been
through the mill.
Jock, I'm interested.
All right!
Look. I'll let you in on a secret.
- I'm going to make a million dollars.
- Jock Hallan, that's marvelous!
- When?
- And how, if you don't mind?
Well, not designing buildings
for somebody else, that's certain.
What's become of those fancy
ideas you used to have?
You know, introducing a Renaissance
of American architecture.
Fancy ideals is right.
Architects never made any money.
If they did, it took them
a lifetime to do it.
- But promoters, ah!
- You mean you're going to be a promoter?
Yep, it's simple.
You pyramid.
- You mean "you' pyramid.
- All right, I pyramid.
Look, I buy a property, see?
In six months it's worth twice
its original cost.
Then I sell it. and then I reinvest
the profits in another.
What if that happens?
Then where are you?
Probably flat on your face,
but you had a lot of fun.
Oh, no, it can't happen.
It can't possibly happen.
We're on the verge of an era
of expansion here.
See what a gay world our life is?
We have subdivisions for breakfast,
residential projects for lunch...
Ladies and gentlemen!
Ladies and gentlemen.
And now, for the championship
of the world,
in this corner, at 185 and a half,
??? Gene Tunney.
In this corner, at 190,
well-known "Malassa Mauler"
and present champion, Jack Dempsey!
Oh, look at those prefectly darling
blue trunk pants he's wearing.
I'm a sucker for the refined type.
I'll take Tunney, thanks.
Don't worry, so will Dempsey.
Mr. Mr. Alfred Brendan.
Brendan!
You're cold, darling.
Here, relax.
What's the matter, aren't you tired?
Did anyone ever tell you that all work
and no play makes Jock a dull boy?
Yeah, but a rich one too.
Oh, say, you know
what I heard yesterday?
You know the Waldorf Astoria?
I ought to, because I remember
we were married in it, weren't we?
- At least I was.
- This is strictly confidential.
- They're going to tear it down.
- Oh, Jock, they couldn't do that.
- They are, yeah.
- The Waldorf's history.
Like Concord or Lexington.
I know, but they're going to build
the world's tallest building...
...right on the same sight. Harper says
the combine's forming down.
I might be able to get a little piece of it,
wouldn't that be wonderful?
Jock, I'm scared.
Of what? My judgment?
Is this a wife's touchy phase?
Darling, you stick with me and you'll
wear bigger diamonds than this one.
I don't want bigger diamonds.
- I want...
- What?
Some fun out of life.
Like... like those people over there.
Yes, I know.
You want us to be like that.
I want to...
Listen, darling, we're married now.
We ought to take on things
that marriage means.
- Two's flying, but three...
- Oh, that again.
Jock, I've told you over and over.
I'm willing to take on all the things
that marriage means.
But there's no reason why we should
tie ourselves down so soon.
Oh, darling.
Let's not be serious.
From now on till after we
go to Maine, I...
Now what's the matter?
I can't be running off on vacations, dear.
Don't you realize I'm trying
to build a future for us?
It takes work, and it takes time.
I'm no playboy, I'm a businessman.
We'll have to postpone Maine.
Postpone it? You can't postpone
somebody else's house party.
The Crandall's are counting on us.
And I'm going.
Alone if necessary.
Say, listen. What are you, a prom girl
or a married woman?
You can't go on wearing
orange blossoms, you know?
Honeymoons don't last forever
- Later on perhaps, dear, we can go...
- Later. Always later.
We're going to have a wonderful time
when we're ninety, aren't we?
- Any old rag?
- Any old bone?
Well, if you're so set on Maine,
why don't you...
...ask Bill to go with you, he's got
a vacation coming up.
All right, I will then.
I'm sure I wouldn't want to go
with you in your mood anyway.
Kitty, would you let me sit in there?
You bet.
Oh, be sure to give that back.
The Elks awarded it to me as the girl
who goes for them.
What's all this about?
You'll ask me where?
To a house party up in Maine next week,
do you want to go?
Oh, why, sure. What about Jock?
Other plans as usual.
Well, stone face, how about
a little conversation?
I just had one, thanks.
Oh, dear, I wish I had stopped
and freshened myself up first.
If he loves you,
he'll take you in clean or dirty.
Shh!
Is that you idea of a surprise entrance?
Where's your sense of drama?
Oh, dear, I'm all aquiver.
Isn't that ridiculous?
Some women leave their husbands for months
and after a mere ten days, I'm in a twitch.
Poor Mary, maudlin Mary.
The human-clinging vine,
No self-reliance, no stamina.
All right, then I will call you.
I said I would, didn't I?
Surprise! Surprise.!
Well, I'll be.
I'll... I'll call you back.
Tell them you have to go into
a heavy conference at this time.
I can't talk now.
The one and only Mrs. Wallace!
Oh, I was a nasty, disagreeable,
self-centered little idiot.
To run off and leave you like that.
But I was punished all right. I had
a rotten time every minute I was gone.
Who were you talking to?
- Why, er...
- What a man! What a man!
Did you miss me?
Did you pine and sigh?
You don't look as if you did.
You look disgustingly healthy.
Well, I was too busy to do much pining.
But I thought of you a lot.
Oh, you!
I did, yes, I did.
Really I did.
I'm glad you're back, terribly glad.
See? Evasions, subterfuges.
Look at him blush.
- Why, honey, you are blushing.
- Oh, nonsense.
Fix us a highball or something.
We're parched.
I discovered a new bootlegger
while you were gone.
Remarkable fellow, he reads palms.
Vegetarian too.
Everybody sent loads of love to you.
Liz Chalmers. You remember her,
don't you?
That lovely little cross-eyed number.
Well, my dear, she's at last succeeded
in getting herself engaged.
And they're going to stage the most
enormous and expensive...
Expensive what?
So far he hasn't even raised
an eyebrow.
No wonder you didn't
pine and sigh.
You didn't have to.
That compact doesn't mean anything,
Mary, I swear it doesn't.
Doesn't it?
Oh, Jock...
Jock!
Mary!
Oh, Marry, look. Here...
Mary! Mary!
Locking the door when we have to talk.
Now you're being silly.
Bill.
Bill, what'll I do?
She's got to listen to me,
she's got to!
Better think fast, Captain Flag.
Mary!
Let me in!
Mary! Mary!
- You can't go.
- Can't I?
You haven't even let me try to explain.
You don't have to explain.
These things happen every day, don't they?
You read about them in books, you...
you see them on the stage.
But they happen to me only once, Jock.
- Let me go.
- No.
Let me go!
- Look, Mary, she came up one evening.
Just one evening because she knew a politician
who could help me on the Waldorf deal.
The three of us sat around
and had a couple of drinks, we talked.
- That's all.
- Don't lie, Jock, don't lie!
I'm not lying! Don't you think
I'd have hidden the compact...
...if I had anything to be ashamed of?
Oh, darling, I'll get down
on my knees to you.
I'll do anything, anything!
Up in Maine I didn't sleep
thinking of you.
I used to lie and look at
the clock go round.
I'd wonder what you were doing.
I'd try to guess.
I'd think, now he's reading.
Now he's turning out the lights.
Now he's lying there in the dark
just as I am here.
But, Mary, you've got to trust me.
You've got to believe me and believe in me.
You brought her here. In this apartment
that we planned and furnished together.
She sat on that couch.
- She...
- No, it wasn't that way!
- Let me go, Jock.
- You're here in my arms.
That's the only truth there is.
Can't you believe what you feel?
- No...
- Mary!
Hold me close.
Never let me go.
25th floor.
All out, please.
Going up.
Well, fine business organization this.
Where is everybody?
They say your husband works here.
A likely story, a likely story.
Oh!
- Are we late?
- No, no. Come in, come in.
Lindberg's still way down by
the Battery.
Hello, darling. How are you feeling?
I feel fine, foolish.
Why shouldn't I?
And I knew you when?
Bill! Look!
Yes, sir, there, ladies and gentlemen,
you have something.
- Or you will have once it's built.
- Oh, Jock, it's gorgeous. It's magnificent.
Couldn't have done a better
design myself.
I should hope not.
Looks pretty expensive, Jock.
Sure you're not getting in
over your head?
No, not me. Oh, I mortgaged my shirt
and a few other things, but...
I'm all set now.
Look, here's the... this is the main
clubhouse here.
Here's the pool with fresh water.
- No perfume?
- Oh, here's the ballroom.
With a sliding roof so that people
can dance under the stars.
On the edge of precipices.
Honest, Jock, this thing's got
elephantiasis, and so have you.
Look at this outfit.
You know, nothing ventured,
nothing gained.
Let's have a drink while we're waiting.
- No, thank you.
- What, on the wagon? Since when?
Oh, yes. she doesn't drink anymore,
she won't smoke, and...
Well, on the whole she's not much fun.
- Shall we tell him?
- I think he's old enough, don't you?
I think yes.
If he doesn't hear it from loved ones,
he'll hear it from nasty little
boys in the street.
We're going to have a baby.
I think we caught him off his guard
that time, didn't we?
Ever hear of anything so absurd in your life,
Jock and me being a papa and mama?
Why, that's fine.
Just what you needed.
That's what we thought.
Remember what we said about naming
the first one after you?
Well, it still goes.
If it's a girl, I guess we'll have
to give you a rain check.
Don't worry, it'll be a boy. That's what
you want, and what you want you always get.
I know, if it's a girl, the drinks
are on you, if it's a boy, on John.
And if it's twins, on you, my friend.
They're on me what ever
it turns out to be.
I'll break a bottle of champagne
over it's head.
You're pretty happy these days,
aren't you?
Happy.
- I've got him back, Bill.
- You never lost him, Mary.
I almost did.
Now I know why.
I'd never waked up to being married.
Really married.
But I'm married now.
And I love it.
I don't know why everybody
in the world doesn't get married.
Including you.
- How about it, Bill?
- How about it what?
When are you going to settle down
and be respectable?
Oh, some time. What's the rush?
I'm young yet.
You're thirty-six. They tell me
a person crystalizes around that age.
You know, gets habits.
Dirty ashtrays, and laundry hampers
bother you.
You don't like to hear people
whistle or...
...to have to wait to get into
the bathroom.
We wonder about you a lot, Bill.
And wish you could discover
some nice, companiable girl...
...with charm and intelligence.
And good ankles.
That's the trouble with you
married couples.
It's like somebody with
a contagious disease.
You've got it, you see no reason
why anybody else shouldn't have it.
Why don't they leave people alone?
Why do they have to go on...
Bill, you don't have to bite
my head off.
You can go to dickens, my fine
man about town.
- I'm sorry.
- I hate you, Bill Hallam.
No, I don't.
I love you.
- But you're an awful fool, really.
- Maybe.
- Here! Here, help yourself.
- What for?
Parade! Parade! Help me throw
these out the window.
- Seems sort of senseless. However...
- Here, Bill.
Like that?
Oh, no, no, no!
Like this, silly.
- Why didn't you say so in the first place?
- Here.
Poor Bill. Missing the finish.
Wouldn't you know we have
to go out of town at this point?
I told him I'd phone him
long-distance, dear.
I'm scared.
Why, thousands of women are
going through the same thing...
...this very minute all over
the world.
Chinese women, Arabians, Eskimos.
I'll bet they aren't scared.
I'll bet they are.
- Jock.
- Hm?
Promise me something?
Anything, darling, anything at all.
Promise me you'll tell me,
not a doctor or a nurse, if...
...if it's a boy or a girl?
If it's ugly or misshapen.
Or if it's... if it's perfectly beautiful.
As it's going to be, darling.
I want you to tell me.
Because...
Because I love you.
What do you think he met,
Mr. Wallace?
- Who meant?
- President Coolidge.
"I do not choose to run."
Don't you suppose he means
that if he does run?
Who can say?
Ask Dr. Durand and Dr. Barton
to come up, please, right away.
Oh, nurse. Nurse!
Dr. Durand and Dr. Barton wanted
in Delivery Room A.
- Mary. Mary!
- Not now.
Later.
- Doctor, is she...
- Your wife's going to be all right.
They'll let you know
when you can see her.
Just a moment, please.
Mr. Wallace, there's a call for you.
All right.
You can take it in here.
- Hello?
- Hello!
Jock. Jock?
How are things going?
I said how are things going?
How's Mary?
What? I can't hear you.
Oh.
Oh...
Jock. Jock!
Jock!
You can see her now.
Hello.
Hello, darling.
Mary.
Well?
Oh.
I see.
It's a girl.
No.
No, it was a boy.
A boy.
I'm so glad.
Was?
You promised you'd tell me.
It died.
Oh, darling.
Darling.
I never even saw him.
I never even knew what color
eyes he had.
Stop it!
Stop it, I...
Oh, Mary.
Mary.
You still don't look so hot.
You ought to go away for a bit.
After all, six weeks in a hospital
must seem like a century.
I am. I'm going to Bermuda
if they ever let me out of here.
That'll be nice.
You and Jock both need it.
Jock's not going.
That's right.
Not going.
- What, at a time like this he ought...
- You'd think so, wouldn't you?
But you'd also think he'd find time
to visit me here now and then.
And he doesn't.
But he's coming up this afternoon.
The first time this week.
I suppose work's his way
of forgetting.
He seems to feel that money's
the only thing...
...you can be sure you've got
when you've got it.
I can't say I blame him much.
In fact, now that he's in the market,
it looks as if we're going to be known
as those wealthy Wallaces.
I sure thought you were pretty
well fixed already.
Oh, it's chicken feed, child's play.
Jock's founding a financial dynasty.
Except that those dynasties
have to have...
It wasn't my fault, was it?
No.
You know in the movies,
How it's always the little lisping kiddy that
cements the papa and mama for keeps?
Well, it's going to be an interesting
experiment with Jock and me.
Because seems there won't be any kiddy.
Not now and...
...maybe not later on.
Everybody says that the movies
should be more like life.
I think...
life should be more like...
...the movies.
I guess that finishes everything,
doesn't it?
Yes, except for your personal mail.
Best wait till we get to New York.
Probably old bills anyway...
A hundred and two.
You think that's the top?
With that stock we'll make a new hundred.
This is barbaric.
Is, um... is this the quiet lunch?
Isn't it a madhouse?
What can I do? They just dropped in
and took the place over.
- How do you like the apartment?
- It's, um... very attractive.
Do you really thnk so?
I hate it. Going to have it done over.
All metal this time.
Ought to be very uncomfortable.
Then why have it done that way?
Oh, I don't know. Novelty.
Somehow I can't see you in a chromium
setting, or Jock a either.
Jock? It won't make any difference to him.
He's hardly ever here anyway.
As a matter of fact he hasn't
been home for three days.
Yes, I saw him at his office yesterday
just after my train got in.
You mean you actually managed
to penetrate into his presence?
Congratulations. How is he?
Has he grown a beard or anything?
Has he taken on weight?
- What is this?
- What?
You and John.
Oh, darling, you've been away.
You're out of touch with things.
- Yeas, but are you...
- Are we getting along?
Sure, we're happy as larks.
We can sing before breakfast.
Not to each other.
I hate to seem narrow dear,
but don't you think your playmates
are getting a trifle rough?
Oh, Irene, this is Bill Hallan.
Bill, this is Irene Potter.
How do you do?
Look, he's sober and he's civil.
What a curio.
You sure you've come
to the right place?
Well, I don't know.
Of course he has, and don't try
and fight him out of it either.
I wish you'd come earlier. Tony Goretta,
you know, the gangster was here.
He had to rush off to a party, though.
He's in such demand. You have
to book him weeks in advance.
Um, what's the number here?
You'd think he'd know by now.
In the past hour he's putting calls
to London, Paris and Madrid.
- Want a drink, Bill?
- I don't believe so, thanks.
You'll have one, Irene.
Oh, not me, I'll have to be getting
back to the store.
After all, I'm a decent,
God-fearing businesswoman...
- ...and there are only a few of us left.
- Telephone for you, Miss Potter.
What'll they think of next.
This is the voice of experience speaking.
Irene had a candy shop over
on Madison Avenue.
In fact, I'm sort of a silent partner.
I give her a dollar and she
gives me back two.
It's unbelievable.
Wang Tee, did you say?
How marvelous!
With or without a chaperone?
Oh, with, of course, my dear.
Trust her. Her own crowd's going.
But after all, it is Freddy's bill,
you know.
Oh, so it's Benny Huston now, is it?
What became of Walt Holden, by the way?
Oh, he went to the discard ages ago.
At least six weeks.
A platonic friendship's cheaper.
A platonic...
Platonic!
- Where is Mrs. Wallace?
- Who is she?
Oh, never mind.
Oh, Max, you must contain yourself.
Hello, darling, having a good time?
- Have you met Mr...
- I want to talk to you.
Bill!
Now look here, old man, you can't...
Bill! Bill!
My wrist!
- Get out!
- Stay where you are, Jean!
I said get out!
Now!
Now indeed. Is there any reason
for this melodrama? Really, Bill!
Mary, what's happened to you?
I haven't the slightest idea
what you're talking about.
Let me go, Bill. I have my friends.
Your friends. Do you realize what
those people out there are saying about you?
They're my guests, Bill. I don't care
to hear anything about...
You'll hear what I tell you!
If you haven't sense enough
to care for your own reputation.
Reputation? Oh, darling.
Nobody has a reputation these days,
it isn't done.
Well, you won't have one if you
go to Wang Tee, that's certain.
And I'm going to tell Jock you can't go
and why you can't go.
My dear, Jock isn't even aware
that I'm planning on going.
- He isn't aware?
- How could he be?
I told you he hasn't been home
for three days.
Well, he'll be aware now.
All right, call him,
hear what he says.
Digby 44999.
Jock doesn't care what I do,
don't you understand?
He has more important things
to worry about.
His precious Casino Club, the market.
Those are the things nearest
his heart.
Digby 44999.
There must be someone there,
operator.
Oh, you're a fool, Bill.
You're such a fool!
Wait, Jock, what's the matter?
There he is now. Must have dropped in
to get a toothbrush or something.
Jock, dear, I know it'll really
bore you, but...
Bill thinks you'd like to know...
Jock.
Jock, what's wrong?
Wrong?
I don't know.
It couldn't have happened.
It couldn't. Not overnight, anyway.
What couldn't?
Wiped out.
Could you get me...
Could you get me a drink, Mary?
I think I need...
The Empress Eugénie, eh?
She must have had a lot of self-confidence
if she went around wearing these things.
I don't know. Somehow it looks
different on me.
You'll grow into it
I wish the hobble skirt had come
back in again.
Anyway, it was something a girl
could get her teeth into.
Bill!
You sure you can't stay for dinner?
Sorry, Mary, I'd like to,
but I have to get back to town.
Listen, Mary.
I'm asking you for the last time.
Why don't you come out and work
at the store? Why let Jock keep you from it?
- Where's your self-respect?
- I can't do it, Irene.
My self-respect isn't as important
right now as his is.
If he had any self-respect, do you think
he'd keep on drinking the way he does?
I don't see how you stand it.
I couldn't.
And I certainly couldn't stand
living on borrowed money.
- Borrowed money?
- You heard me.
All right, all right, I got caught,
what of it?
- Business is still fundamentally sound.
- And you're fundamentally stupid.
I won't allow my wife to work.
A woman's place is in the home.
That sort of thing went out with buttoned
shoes and hand-painted china.
Oh, never mind, never mind, Irene,
I know your views, you know mine.
Well, someone in this house ought to have
a job and since Mary wants to work...
Well, she's not going to
and that's that.
I don't know, Jock, a salary's a salary
especially in these times.
Oh, these times. There's nothing
the matter with these times.
Prosperity's just around the corner.
Same corner you said it was
around last year?
The poor thing must be crawling
on its hands and knees.
Which end of the asparagus do you cut off,
the top or the bottom?
Neither. You take out the middle
and knit the ends together.
I had a feeling I'd be cooking
this dinner sooner or later.
I guess I'm not cut out for the home.
In heaven's name! What's the matter
with this country?
Nothing's happening.
Everything's dead.
I'm equipped to do things.
I know I can do them, but...
I can't even get a chance.
Read that.
That's the profession I was
trained for. Architecture.
I'm trying to get back in the firm now.
Anything, I don't care.
Even a draftsman's job.
What do they tell me?
"We regret exceedingly, that under
the present conditions...
...there is no opening available."
We regret exceedingly.
I spend four years in college learning
the things the firm expects of me.
I work for them six solid years and...
Now they regret exceedingly.
You know I'll carry you as long
as you want, Jock, but...
Now, this is for your own good.
Why don't you take any sort of job?
There must be something you can do.
Sure. Clerking for twenty a week.
Well, um... I guess I'll be going along.
Goodbye, Irene.
Well, if you had any manners,
you'd stay and face the music.
- Bye, Bill.
- Sorry I have to rush off.
So that's how we've been living.
He, um... gave me some money once.
You liar.
You sweet liar.
No, no, really.
He gave it to me to keep for him.
You'd better stop.
You'd better stop or I'll start crying.
I wouldn't want to do that.
Is he like this often?
Bill, what am I going to do?
What do wives do, put something
in the coffee or what?
Let me talk to him.
Talk doesn't do any good,
I've tried that.
It might. At least what I have
to say to him might.
- Irene.
- Yes?
I've decided to take that job
at the candy shop.
Oh, honey, that's simply grand.
We'll make a fortune.
You know how I feel about you working.
Why do you have to bring it up now?
- Why do you have...
- This is why.
Oh. I thought you'd gone.
What's the matter with you?
- What do you mean?
- You're a fine-looking specimen.
Is that why you came back,
to give me a sermon?
- I'll give you more than that.
- Oh, yeah?
Look at yourself!
Pretty, isn't it?
I don't blame you for not
wanting to see it.
You might consider the people
around you, though. They have to see it.
Oh... try it.
How long are you going to keep this up?
Who do you think you are?
Leave me alone, Bill, I don't want
to hear any more out of you.
You're going to, though.
You're licked and you've quit.
- You've got a streak of yellow so wide...
- I think you'd better shut up.
I've kept you going for months.
And now that Mary's got a job,
I suppose you'll live off her.
Did anyone ever tell you what they call
a man who lets his wife support him?
I said I think you'd better shut up.
It's a short word and an ugly one.
But here's where you get it.
I'm sorry, Bill.
That's all right, Jock.
I'm sorry, madam, but all sales are final.
Young man, don't stand there
and talk back to me!
Where's the manager?
Manager!
Mr. Wallace. Your wife is on the phone.
Tell her I'll call her back.
I can't take it now.
Oh, sure you can. I'll handle
the animals for you.
All right, thank you.
- Did you wish something, madam?
- It's alright, I'm fine.
- Hello.
- I'm sorry to bother you, dear.
But, could you please get a star
for the top of the tree?
You know, one of those big, gilt,
shiny things?
Say, look. Did the cook get there?
Yes, she's here.
Ooh. It doesn't sound so hot,
but she's here.
When do you think you'll get away?
All right, darling. We'll expect you
when you get here.
Goodbye, dear.
Silent night, Silent night...
La-la-la-la-la-la-la.
I was afraid of that.
Merry Christmas from
Bloomfield's Incorporated.
Same to Bloomfield's, I'm sure.
- Yes?
- I hate to bother you, Mr. Wakefield.
I know it's Christmas and you're
in a hurry to get home, but...
I'd like to speak to you
for a moment, please.
- What is it?
- I'm a salesman in the basement.
At the sweater counter.
I just got my paycheck and...
They gave me this.
I'm very sorry. There's nothing
1I can do about it.
I just wanted to explain that if you...
If you send your application in
after the holidays,
- I'll be glad to keep you in mind.
- You must listen to me, Mr. Wakefield.
I've been here for ten weeks
and I've worked hard.
- I'm sure.
- May I wasn't so good when I first started,
but I'm all right now
and I'm getting better.
I don't think you realize that
there's nothing I can do about it.
- You see, with me it isn't...
- Sales are low after Christmas.
- We've got to cut down somewhere.
- It isn't the money, Mr. Wakefield.
- It's... it's the job.
- I understand, yes.
When I came here ten weeks ago
I hadn't worked for so long that...
...I'd lost the respect of everybody.
Even...
You can't let me go now, you can't.
If you do, it means that I've failed again.
I can't go home like this.
Please, I'll do anything.
I'll work for what ever you say,
or what ever you'll want to give me.
But I've got to have the job.
I'd be glad to help if I could.
But after all you must realize there are
hundreds of people in the same position.
If I made an exception in one case, I'd
have to make it all the way down the line.
It's too bad, but that's how it is.
Here. Merry Christmas.
Anything wrong, Mr. Wallace?
I say, is there anything wrong?
- Anything I can do?
- Oh, no... No, no. No, thanks.
Well, Merry Christmas...
- ...from Bloomfield's Incorporated.
- Thanks. Same to you.
It... it isn't very warm, is it?
Why, mine's swell.
Mine's hardly that, but it certainly
fills the void.
Yes, sir, Mr. Wallace.
If you ask me, them were
the days, too.
Like a gentleman's club
this place was then.
Nice and quiet, and genteel.
Now look. We have to serve all the riffraff
that comes in off the street.
Repeal. Well, so they can have the repeal
if that's the way it works.
Turning a nice, refined place like this
into a... a regular saloon.
Merry Christmas, Kitty!
To you maybe.
Well, stranger.
Well, for the love of...
Say...
Go on, pull up a chair, sit down.
How've you been, Kitty?
- Fine, and you?
- Oh, never better.
Say, Charlie...
You with anybody?
No, I had a date, but, um...
That's swell. Charlie,
scotch and soda for the lady.
Make it two.
- You out on parole or something?
- Parole? What...
Now, now, come, come,
Christmas Eve, darling.
You know, up at home
and cackling in the kitchen?
Shouldn't you be playing Santa Claus?
Seems to me I remember
hearing a rumor...
...about the patter of tiny feet
heading your way.
Uh...
They detoured.
Well, happy days.
Peace on earth, goodwill and...
so forth.
A Merry Christmas.
A Merry, Merry Christmas.
Bill, have you no home?
I'm staying till he comes.
All right.
But I warn you, he's not a pretty sight
when he gets like this.
I'm going to bed.
Oh, um... Would you like to try
the davenport? I'll fix it for you.
May I have one too?
Seems to be my night for insomnia
among other things.
Isn't it funny?
All evening I've been hoping
he'd come home...
Now I dread it.
Dread it?
Because I've been through it
so many times before.
Bill, what happens when people reach
the point where they can't go on?
They just do go on, somehow,
if they can.
I can't.
Not any more.
Oh, Bill, I'm frightened.
We're like two swimmers trying
to reach the shore, he and I.
We're both worn out, but he's limp
and doesn't struggle any more.
And I try to hold him up,
and instead of coming nearer,
the shore gets farther and farther away.
He's going down, Bill.
He's gone down.
And I don't know what to do.
Oh, my dear.
Do you think I haven't seen it?
Do you think I haven't wanted
to do something about it?
To help you.
You should have someone to care
for you, and cherish you.
I've wanted to do that. Always.
Even before you were married.
I've always wanted to tell you
what you mean to me.
The clothes you wear,
the way you wear them.
The way you walk, and talk,
and stand, and sit.
The funny way you drum
on my shoulder when we dance.
The way you used to laugh.
Because you don't laugh any more.
I've watched your eyes
when you were hurt...
...and listened to your voice saying the
things you wanted to believe yet couldn't.
I can't... I can't watch or listen
any longer.
Oh, Mary. I love you so.
You knew it, didn't you?
I... I suppose I've always known.
But...
Bill, I'm fonder of you than
anyone else on earth.
I don't know whether it's liking or love.
Or if it's love, what kind of love it is.
Anyway, it's a lot. But...
It isn't the same thing that
I feel for Jock.
That you feel now,
or that you used to feel?
That I've always felt.
That I'll have to get over.
Because it's doing him no good.
- And it's making me...
- I've waited a long time.
I can go on waiting.
Until you're ready.
Will you go?
Hey, Buddy. Is there a guy named
John Wallace lives here?
- Yes.
- Well, there's been a accident and...
- What?
- A accident.
My cab crashed into
the one he was in.
I took him to the hospital
and I thought maybe you'd want to go.
How badly is he hurt?
- He isn't dead?
- No.
Wasn't when I left him anyways.
But he's pretty bad.
Wait a minute.
Mary.
Take me to him, Bill.
I'm afraid you can stay only a minute.
Mary.
You must get well, darling.
You're going to get well.
Oh, Bill.
He's got to live.
He'll live. He's got everything
to live for.
Would you like to see
the young lady now?
She got off easier than the gentleman.
Maybe you'd better not go in now.
But I thought you'd like to know
she's resting comfortably.
We'll have a party at opening night...
...for all the people that stuck by me
when I needed them.
Bill, and Irene...
You've been so swell, darling.
That's all I've thought about
all the months that I've been lying here.
How I'll ever be able
to make up to you...
I know what you had to go through
and what you're still having to go through.
What's the matter, honey?
Nothing.
Um...
Jock.
You haven't anything you want
to tell me, have you?
Tell you? About what?
Oh... about...
About us.
You and me.
Oh, nothing, except that I'm ashamed
of what I've been and...
But we're set now, and...
...together we can lick the whole world
permanently this time.
Is that all?
And that I love you.
You're tired, aren't you, dear?
Just wait till I get the casino open.
I can take care of myself after that.
Yes.
After that you can take care of yourself.
This is what I was going to say.
Reopening the club has been
merely part of my job.
I've been laying plans for its expansion.
Now, as some of you may know,
I started this project.
And subject of course to our
distinguished board of governors,
I should like to see it continue on the same
scale in which it was begun.
In fact, I see an even bigger casino.
I see a larger, more magnificent
venture.
We need more space, more gardens,
more grounds.
You should be feeling pretty
happy tonight.
- I suppose I should, shouldn't I?
- Well, aren't you?
Has Jock told you about
the new job that's been offered him?
Job, what job?
With the firm of architects
he used to be with.
When did this come up?
A couple of days ago.
They've got a contract for the construction
of a model community in the Tennessee Valley.
It's a part of the new housing program.
They want him to go down
and take it over.
You know, gauge the needs
of the people,
and then design a whole little town...
...to fit their requirements and
geographical background.
Tennessee Valley, hm?
Sort of primitive down there, isn't it?
Yes, I suppose it is.
I don't know, though. Going a little
primitive might not be a bad idea.
It's something rather vitalizing.
Yes, even inspiring about
a project of that kind.
I know. Big and clean,
the washing-an-elephant idea.
It is easy to laugh at, isn't it?
But somehow...
You'd think they're ushering in
the millenium tonight,
instead of just trying to pull
a bad investment out of the red.
About the only thing they overlooked
is to let loose a flock of doves.
Ah, here he is now.
Personal magnetism himself.
Well, what comes next, chorus girls
on white horses or what?
Aren't you ever satisfied?
Here, I think you two deserve
this more than I do.
Better see if it's paid for first.
- How did you think it went off, darling?
- Oh, splendidly.
- I hear you've been offered a new job.
- Yeah, some job that is.
- Why, are you turning it down?
- What do you think?
Oh, darling, you know
what the board just told me?
They say that if everything
goes along satisfactorily,
there's no reason I shouldn't
be getting a cut on the profits.
In addition to my salary.
Oh, that's fine, Jock.
It's simply one more step on
the road back, that's what it is.
From managership, to partnership,
to majority control.
# It's most true dear #
# What the projections tell thee #
# The daring young man #
# On the flying trapeze #
That's all right, you just wait and see.
It's back to a penthouse for us,
darling, before you know it.
Won't that seem good?
Remember that mink you had to sell?
We'll replace it with sables this time.
How'll that be?
Oh, Josh! Hello, Bill!
An admirer of yours wants to meet you.
Mr. Craig, Mr. Wallace.
- How do you do?
- I liked your speech, Mr. Wallace.
- It was very convincing.
- Oh, thank you.
Wonderful place you have here.
See you later, dear.
Bill, are you going to be
terribly busy tomorrow?
Never too busy to see a charming,
young, etc...
I'd like to have a talk with you.
What about lunch, say the Plaza.
No, this isn't social.
It's business.
I'll come to your office.
Well, what's on your mind?
Things going all right at the store?
Booming.
A chain store's going to buy us out and
they want me to stay on and act as manager.
At a good salary.
A really good salary.
Well, you've worked hard
enough for it, Mary.
Want me to draw up a contract?
Is that it?
No... that's not it.
Bill, you were in on the beginning,
so you might as well be in on the finish.
I've left Jock.
This morning.
He doesn't know it yet, and won't
till he finds my note.
I want a divorce.
And I want you to get it for me.
Is... is it another man?
No. And there won't be.
There couldn't be any othr man
except you, Bill.
And it wouldn't be fair to you this way.
No.
From now on I'm the cat
that walks by itself.
Mary, why are you leaving him now?
Now that he's won his battle.
Or rather now that you've
won it fo him.
I stayed with him
when I could be of help to him.
I was the biblical wife.
But now... now we're all right again.
Both of us are all right.
He has his job and I have mine.
But that shouldn't make any difference.
Oh, but it does.
Don't you see?
We don't need each other any more,
that's all.
We've nothing in common.
Nothing in common.
Nothing in common now
or in the future.
Will you make me out a bill of complaint,
or a brief, or what ever it's called?
Say it's incompatibility,
say it's mutual fatigue.
Sai it's...
Say it's just ten years.
Mr. Wallace to see you.
Oh, I can't talk to him now.
In a minute.
Here.
Bill, please don't let him
know I'm here.
I... I just couldn't face him now.
What ever you want.
- Yes, sir?
- Have Mr. Wallace come in now, please.
She's gone, Bill.
Mary's gone, she's left me.
I know. She, um... she was here.
Where is she?
She can't leave me now, she can't.
Take it easy, Jock, don't...
Oh, it's easy to talk.
You've never loved. You don't know
what she can mean to a man, she's...
Help me, Bill.
Help me.
You might be able to tell her.
She might listen to you.
Tell her that she's all I've got,
all I want.
She's engaged me as her counsel.
As...
Oh.
I see.
I'd hoped you might be able
to do something.
It's not only that I love her.
We have so much in common.
What?
I say we have so much in common,
it doesn't seem right...
It doesn't seem...
Mary.
Has he gone?
Bill, you promised me.
I know I did, but...
It's no use, Jock.
Well, there are certain legal formalities
that you'll have to submit to some time,
...so you might as well do it now.
Sit down, please, both of you.
Mary, please.
Now let me make a few notes.
The plaintiff was married
to the defendant...
...ten years ago, on November 5th, 1925.
Ten years ago today in a rice-strewn
room in the old Waldorf...
...on the same plot of ground.
You were wearing a brown velvet dress.
You stood on tiptoe and said...
"Jock, tell me it will never be
any more wonderful than it is now."
Because if it is, I simply
couldn't bear it.
There wasn't a cloud in your sky
back then.
You had everything.
What happened between then and now?
The plaintiff and the defendant returned
from a honeymoon abroad and settled down.
Remember that night on the train...
...when we were coming back from
the Dempsey-Tunney fight?
Remember your being angry because
Jock insisted on working...
...and you wanted to play?
You wanted to have some
fun out of life...
...while you were still young
enough to enjoy it?
That was your first quarrel,
I imagine.
Afterwards you were sorry.
But afterwards was too late.
Because by then something
had happened.
Something that was to hit
back at you later...
...when you stood in a doorway
with a compact in your hand.
And you said, "Oh, Jock, Jock!"
And the last thing I saw as I left...
...was him standing in front
of a door you'd locked.
But you came through that.
You even felt so secure
in each other that you decided...
The couple had no child.
What was it that separated you
after that,
when you should have been
closer than ever?
Shock?
Yes, at first.
So you turned to making money
as a release and an escape.
And she turned to anything
she could find.
New clothes, new people.
Any opiate that would make her
forget the things she was feeling.
Mary needed you then, Jock.
Badly.
But you were to preoccupied
with success,
with the get-rich-quick schemes.
Well, you got your success,
didn't you?
And your money.
And how long did it last?
As long as any bubble lasts.
And when it collapsed,
you collapsed with it.
You'd lost your perspective. Not only
about her, but about everything.
You couldn't even appreciate
what made her stick to you...
...when the false bottom
of your success fell out.
Through hard times, hard work, all the
things your egotism had brought it to.
That Christmas Eve when we were
waiting for you to come home,
I did something I wanted to do
all my life.
I told Mary I loved her.
I held her in my arms and asked her
to come away with me.
Well, she didn't come away.
Instead she went to you
because you needed her once more.
When she came out of your room at the
hospital that night, she was crying...
...and said, "Oh, Bill, he's got to live."
Yes, she said that.
And a moment later the nurse asked her
if she'd like to see the young lady.
She had every reason to leave
you then but she didn't.
She decided to stay with you
till the point...
where you could face the world
successfully as you did...
...last night at the casino.
And now...
Now she feels her job's ended.
You went through all those
things together, the two of you.
And now you've come to me and said,
"We've nothing in common."
Nothing in common.
And you say "we've so much in common".
And you're right because
you're speaking of the past.
And she's right because she's speaking
of the future.
And she's afraid of it, Jock.
She's afraid of anyone who's been
through what you've been through...
...and hasn't been changed by it.
Last night she saw you beginning
the whole thing over again.
The casino thing, the money thing,
the success mania, penthouses
and sables.
Those things are fine, she knows that.
But she's had them once
and they weren't enough.
And that's all you're offering her.
You had a chance to offer
her something else.
A new kind of existence,
it might be better, it might be worse.
Anyway it would be new.
And you laughed at it.
Look back over your life together, Jock.
Can you blame her for wanting
something different?
I'm afraid it's up to you now, Mary.
Shall I go ahead and draw up your briefs
so that I can get your divorce?
Or...
You know the sort of brief
I'd rather draw up for you.
It would be a brief made up
of the day-to-day things...
...that you and Jock have
done together.
The words you've spoken.
The rooms you've lived in.
The streets you've walked.
A brief of the songs you've sung...
...and the tears you've shed.
And even the things your hands
have touched.
You and Jock together.
And I too.
Though that doesn't matter anymore.
And never can matter.
Well, I... I always wanted to winter
in the south.
I know, dear, but Tennessee's
not like Palm Beach.
It'd be calico for you.
And chin whiskers for you.
And aren't you going to look terrible?
That's a pretty picture, isn't it?
Yes... that's a portrait of marriage.
Subtitles -
Luís Filipe Bernardes