What is happening, White Bull?
The wild ones run
like frightened creatures.
If only they let us ride.
We could catch them.
If you had your choice,
which would you take?
The big brown colt
who trails the herd.
He's too slow.
He can hardly keep.
He runs last to protect the little ones.
Ah, he has courage.
He's truly a brave one.
I do not want him.
Good. He is mine.
And look, they're turning back.
Once they get through the canyon,
you will never see your horse again.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to capture my horse.
The rope belongs to Yellow Bull.
He has forbidden anyone to use it.
A friend does not tell on another.
- Why are you not watching the travois?
- I try to catch a wild horse.
You'd catch a wild horse
with your bare hands?
- No, I... I used a rope.
- You do not own a rope, my cousin.
I borrowed one.
From the pack horse?
Well where is it now?
Around the neck of the wild horse.
He pulled it away from me.
Bad enough you disobey orders.
You steal my most prized possession!
From now on,
you walk with the women and dogs.
There has been trouble.
My son walks.
A sign he is being punished.
Look, White Bull walks!
Why do you walk, White Bull?
Did your horse throw you?
The great hunter!
White Bull chase buffalo on foot!
Poor White Bull!
The great hunter!
I'm not hungry.
You must eat
if you are to grow to manhood.
It's not food
that keeps me from becoming a man.
Food is important, too.
Not as important as horses.
Or scalps.
You walked back to camp.
Yellow Bull wouldn't let me ride.
He took my horse.
- Why?
- Because...
White Bull!
The chief wants you.
Yellow Bull.
You will know soon enough
what happened, Mother.
The whole camp will.
Yellow Bull has told me
that you disobeyed him.
That you left the travois,
stole his catching rope
and lost it chasing wild horses.
Sometimes, there are
two sides to a story.
It is your turn to speak.
It is true. But I didn't steal the rope.
I only wanted to use it.
Besides,
Yellow Bull has done wrong, too.
He risked losing the meat
when he chased the wild horses.
But I left you to guard it, my cousin.
It is tribal law
that rank has its privileges.
Yellow Bull has earned rank.
It is his right to make decisions.
But it is not the right of an
untried youth to question them.
It was Yellow Bull's duty to teach him
the arts of the hunt and the battle.
- He has done none of these things.
- The boy was too young until now.
When the time comes to teach him these
things, does he prove himself worthy?
No, he steals my rope.
What is worse, he loses the bow
and quiver of arrows our chief gave him
on the passing of his 16th summer.
Is this true, my son?
It is true.
This is a serious thing you have done,
White Bull.
It fills me with sorrow.
You must not go hunting again until you
have proved you are worthy of the trust.
That is all.
- I'll get even with Yellow Bull.
- Vengeance is a poor substitute
for honest achievement, my son.
You first duty is to find
the bow and quiver of arrows.
- Surely, you did not look hard.
- I didn't look at all.
Yellow Bull wouldn't let me.
He wanted me to be punished.
I'll go with the new sun
and search until I find them.
You should have seen him, Mother.
He was a reddish-brown in color.
Just like the leaves of trees
when winter comes.
He was big and strong.
He did run a little clumsy, though.
Well, that's because
he's young and still growing.
Growing up is a hard time for colts,
as well as for boys.
A time for big heads,
and for bigger feet.
A clumsy time,
a time for making mistakes.
Eat your supper, boy,
and go to sleep with your dreams.
The sun gets up early.
Don't be afraid.
I won't hurt you.
Hold still now.
So you were trying to reach
the water, weren't you?
I'll get you a drink.
Boy, you sure got yourself
all tangled up, didn't you?
Hold still now.
Hold still now, boy.
That's it.
Easy, boy.
Hold it, boy! Hold it. Easy now.
Drink.
Hold it steady.
Pretty soon I'll let you go, but first,
I wanna make sure that
you don't get away from me.
Good. Good boy.
Now.
I could cut the rope,
but then I won't have it to use again.
Hold still, boy. Hold still.
Besides, it belongs to Yellow Bull.
I only borrowed it to capture you.
I liked you
from the first time I saw you.
I thought you ran good.
But Strong Bear, well he's my friend.
He said you were clumsy.
Well, maybe you are. Well that's because
you're still growing, like me.
I'm going to keep you here
and not let anyone know I have you.
Till we ride back to camp together.
You belong to me now.
Now hold still.
Whoa...
Whoa.
You think you are smart, eh?
Tomorrow, I will show you who is master.
Settle down, boy.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I'll be back.
You did not find the bow and arrows.
- I...
- Never mind.
- You will have better luck tomorrow.
- I'll find them, Mother.
And I'll find Yellow Bull's rope, too.
And I will capture a wild horse
and train him myself.
And he will be the best horse
in all the Dakotas.
I will call him...
I'll call him Tonka Wakan.
The Great One.
- Stop boasting and eat.
- I'm not boasting, Mother.
It will happen as I say.
No more will they call you the mother of
a son who does not know how to be a man.
I'm coming, Tonka.
Look, boy. Look what I've got.
Grass is still wet with dew
and very tender. Better hurry.
Oh, if you want the grass,
you come get it.
Hold it, Tonka! Stop, Tonka!
Now behave yourself.
Phew! It's too hot to fight
on a day like this.
You'd like to kill me, wouldn't you?
I guess I'd feel the same way
if a white man capture me.
But, but I
want to be your friend, Tonka.
That's your name, boy. Tonka Wakan.
Now you stop fighting me,
we'll get along real good.
Ah, now that's better.
Now you're being smart.
Hold still, now.
Hold still.
There. Soon as I get you washed,
and the burrs out of your hair, you'll
look as good as any horse in camp.
Hold still.
Ho!
Well, captain,
looks like we're not so smart.
According to our manual, lieutenant,
surprise is a necessary element
of every attack.
Only they forgot to say
who gets surprised: us or the enemy.
We'll make camp here, Mr. Nowlan.
Place your picket line downstream.
- Prepare to dismount.
- Yes, sir.
Troop? Dismount, lead out.
Ha! Hyah!
Look, Tonka,
I brought you a friend.
She'll teach you
what a good horse should know.
Go on. Go on.
In an Indian tepee you will learn:
the woman is always the chief.
You want the grass, you come get it.
You better hurry, or she'll eat it all.
Well, you see?
There's nothing to be afraid of.
This is how a good horse behaves.
This is fun. Come on.
See this? This is wapato,
sweet as sugar and very good.
Mm, you like it. Good, huh?
Good, isn't it?
You want more? More?
No, you must earn it.
Easy.
Easy, Tonka.
Now if you'll let me ride you,
I'll give you more wapatos.
No, this time,
I think I give you more room.
Too many trees to bump into.
Too many rocks, too, to fall on.
No, no, you stay here,
so he'll come back if he throws me.
If he throws me.
Hyah!
You see?
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I'm your friend, Tonka.
You belong to me.
Let's stop and rest a while.
Soon, we'll start for my home,
far to the north.
There'll be rejoicing
when I return to my people.
My uncle is a great man. He'll forgive
me when he finds out what I've done.
Wapato.
No longer will my mother
hang her head in shame.
All that remains now
is to go on a hunt.
To kill a buffalo.
And to take a scalp in battle.
And we'll do these things together,
Tonka.
You'll take me to the hunt.
And you'll ride me to the battle.
Come.
Could be one of our horses.
Throw a couple of shots
and scare him.
Run, Tonka, run!
Come on. Come on, boy!
Ho!
Hold it, Hank.
That horse runs like a scared Comanche
with a load of buckshot in his breeches.
He was a lot of horse, all right.
A lot!
We don't have anything
that could even follow him,
let alone catch him.
On the left, ho!
Strong Bear, Strong Bear,
it is White Bull! Look, he has a horse!
Where have you been?
It is the young colt
we saw running with the wild herd.
Where did you get him?
How did you get him?
You will soon find out, Strong Bear.
Welcome home, White Bull.
It is good to be home, my uncle.
I have come back to prove to my chief
that I can be trusted.
I have recovered the bow and arrows, and
the rope of many-colored horse hairs,
which belongs to my cousin, Yellow Bull.
I wish to give it back,
so there will no bad feeling between us.
You have acted wisely. It pleases me.
What of the horses, nephew?
This one I call Tonka Wakan.
I caught him and trained him myself.
Oh,
he's truly the Great One.
And this one I call Prairie Bird,
after my mother.
I stole her from the white soldiers when
they came to the camp to attack you.
What kind of lie do you tell us now?
It is no lie.
I overpowered a soldier.
I drove their horses away.
All except this one.
I kept her to ride
and to help train the colt.
If you killed a soldier,
where's his scalp?
There wasn't time.
The soldiers came runnin.
I had to go quickly.
But I have the soldier's long knife
to prove that what I say is true.
I wish you to have it, my chief.
It will long be remembered, my nephew.
In return...
...I wish to give you this talisman
to protect you from evil spirits.
Now that you have
horses of your own,
I give you permission to go on hunts.
If all goes well,
you may soon ride into battle.
He looks like a horse of much courage.
He's the greatest horse
in all the land of the Dakotas.
I will show you.
Come, Tonka. Come on.
Come on!
Whoa!
Tonka Wakan,
it is a good name for the colt.
He truly is a Great one.
Did I not keep my promise?
Only a man
could do what you have done.
I am proud, my son.
I forgot to give him his reward.
When he does well, he gets wapato.
Be good to him,
and he will serve you well.
Come, it grows late.
We must take the horses to the pen.
Wait!
I wish to speak with my cousin.
We are in a hurry.
My cousin can speak another time.
You'll wait.
It's a fine horse
you have there, my cousin.
You've trained him well.
Strong legs.
Good teeth. I'll take him.
No. Nobody takes him.
He's mine. Now get away.
- Let go! You're scaring him!
- My horses were stolen!
- I need a horse to start a new string!
- Then find another.
You can't have Tonka. He's mine.
I caught him and I trained him.
- I demand you give him to me.
- No. It isn't fair.
He belongs to White Bull.
You have no right
to take my son's horse.
I have the right.
It's the privilege of my rank.
Take the mare. I give her to you.
- I want this one.
- No! Now get away!
Wait!
We will let our chief decide.
Your mother speaks wisely.
We'll let our chief decide.
While I do not approve
of Yellow Bull's action,
I cannot deny it is his right
according to tribal custom.
He is a great brave with 40
eagle feathers in his war bonnet.
White Bull has yet to earn
a single feather.
I'm sorry, nephew. The horse will
have to be turned over to Yellow Bull.
The colt is young like the boy.
Treat him kindly.
He must learn quickly that I am master.
It'll only be for a little while, Tonka.
I'll get you back somehow.
We'll still be together.
I'll dig wapatos for you.
Come on.
Spotted Tail, Barking Dog.
Bring me the white man's muzzle
with the iron in the mouth.
I'll take no chances
with this young one.
I'll take my horse, White Bull.
Whoa! Hey!
Down, devil! Down!
I know how to treat your kind!
Down!
Get a rope on him!
Hold on, Spotted Tail! I know
how to deal with this one!
He doesn't know
what they're doing to him.
He is young.
He will soon learn the cruelties
of man's ways, and bow to them.
But the blame is mine. I caught him.
It's my fault he's being hurt.
Leave him alone! He's never
had a bit in his mouth before!
He doesn't know
what you're doing to him.
Well, it's time he learned.
Yellow Bull is a madman.
I'll kill him!
I am your friend.
I will help you kill him.
You talk foolish.
Yellow Bull is a cruel man,
but he is also a brave warrior.
You would have little chance
against such a man.
Whoa!
Hyah!
This sorrow will soon pass.
Here, you still have Prairie Bird.
Take care of her.
I'll break the devil's spirit in you!
I'll break you!
I'll break you! I'll break you!
Get up!
I'll make a good horse out of you yet!
I'll break the devil's spirit in you!
I'll break you! I'll break you!
I can't bear to see you hurt, Tonka.
I'm sending you back to your own kind.
Where you will be safe.
This is goodbye.
Our chief said it would protect me.
It will protect you, too.
I'll never forget you, boy.
You'll always be my friend.
Now go.
Go on. Run, Tonka.
Run fast and far
so they'll never catch you. Go on.
All right.
One last wapato.
Well, don't stand there! Go on!
Well, do as I say! Run! Run!
Go on! Run!
Goodbye, Tonka.
Whoa! You boys be ready
with them poles when we peal 'em.
We don't wanna take a chance
on spoilin' 'em.
Now Jeb, you and Jim
circle around to the left
and me and Sud'll
close in on 'em from the right.
I'll signal you when to spook 'em.
Come on.
Hold it.
Looks like there's trouble afoot.
Hey, this is gonna make it easy.
They'll be so busy a-fightin', they
won't even see us. Come on, let's go.
Get your ropes ready!
This young'n's gonna jump!
He's a strong one, ain't he?
He oughta bring 90 dollars.
Yah! Yah! Yah! Ho!
Ho! Ho!
Yah!
- Good morning, Hank.
- Morning, Myles.
Can I have a look at the new broncs
they brought in yesterday?
I'm always looking, Mr. Nowlan.
I'm the hopeful sort.
Well, you have a good horse, your Pokey.
Well, Pokey has good legs.
And a stomach only for hay,
not gunpowder.
You know, a cavalry mount should have
more than good legs and wind.
It should have a little extra...
something.
The glory of his snorting is terrible.
He paweth in the valley
and rejoices in his strength.
He goeth out to meet the armed men.
He mocketh at feat
and is not dismayed.
Neither turneth he back from the sword.
That, Mr. Nowlan,
is the kind of a horse I'm looking for.
That, Captain Keogh, is the best
description of a cavalry horse
I ever heard.
- Did you make it up?
- Book of Job, lieutenant.
Thirty-ninth chapter, 21st verse.
Hold still, you!
Ooh!
Where have I seen
that horse before, Hank?
It's not likely you ever did, Myles.
He's a real bronc.
He'll go down fightin' like a Comanche.
Wait a minute.
You remember that Indian
who ran away from us last fall
when we were looking
for stolen horses?
That's the young stallion he was riding.
Alright, get him down!
Alright, pry his mouth open.
How long has this been going on, Hank?
Ever since Corporal Jeeth was placed
in charge of the remount corrals.
That ring bit's his idea.
It's plain torture.
Grab him! Get a hold of him!
Yee-hoo!
Ah-ha! Ha!
Grab him! Hold him!
Look out! Stop that horse!
Get the corporal!
Whoa, boy, whoa!
Easy now. Nothing to be afraid of.
Easy, boy. That's it.
I don't blame you for doing
what you did, mister.
If that corporal isn't dead,
he deserves to be.
Get the corporal to the doc.
Bring me a halter.
Trooper, take the saddle off.
A good luck talisman.
You did belong to an Indian,
didn't you, boy?
I've got a hunch you took a beating
you didn't deserve.
But you stood up to him real good.
Yes sir, real good.
He goeth out to meet the armed men,
he mocketh at fear,
and is not dismayed.
I'll be wanting to buy this horse,
Mr. Nowlan.
- Make out the necessary papers.
- If you say so.
He'll take a name.
What are you gonna call him?
Comanche.
As for you, let me see or hear of
another breaking bit being used,
so help me, I'll give you a taste of it
in your own mouth. Now clear out.
Yes, sir.
Whoa.
Well, Mr. Nowlan, what did you think
of that little demonstration?
Well, he's a thoroughly trained horse,
that's for sure.
Not only thoroughly,
he's been trained gentle.
With a lot of patience.
We're gonna try
and do as well by you, mister.
No more ring bits, no tight cinches,
not even a martingale.
You can toss this big beautiful head
as much as you please.
Yes, sir, Comanche,
we're gonna get along fine.
Yes, sir.
Would you be good enough
to hold his head, Captain?
Go ahead, corporal,
I'll try to keep his mind occupied.
Well, now. Aren't you the handsome one?
You know, I think I can get
a fair price for you this morning.
Not that I'm gonna sell you, mind you.
Now you listen.
Now you see this?
It's a receipt for $100.
You belong to me, mister.
Until death do us part,
as the minister would say.
Right.
You see this, Comanche?
Plain old single bit.
This won't hurt your mouth any more
than this cigar hurts mine.
Now this, my friend,
is known as ground hitching.
It's very important a horse
learn to stay where a man leaves him.
Case he returns rather quickly with a
half a dozen redskins on his coattails.
Oh, no. No, sugar, you did it wrong.
You've gotta stay where I put you.
Now let's try it again.
All right. Wait a minute, Comanche.
You win. You win. You win.
Here you are.
Great chiefs, listen to me.
The young braves wear paint and cry
for war. We can restrain them no longer.
Each day, we grow strong in number.
Soon we will have more braves
than there are stars in the sky.
We must run the white men from our lands
or kill them off
as they have killed the buffalo.
First, we must know if the white man's
soldiers are many or few.
We will send braves to every fort
to find this out.
They will tell us
if we should have war or not.
Tonka. My horse, Tonka.
Turn out the door! Arm party!
We know how many soldiers
we have seen.
But we do not know
how many soldiers we have not seen.
When darkness comes,
let us go close to the fort.
- I will try to slip in.
- Too dangerous for you to go alone.
- I will go with you.
- No.
No. If I am to be a brave worthy
of trust, I must prove myself. Alone.
When darkness comes, the gates would be
closed and lights would be put out.
- You cannot count sleeping soldiers.
- I could count their horses.
That is true. And the risk is great.
But it would be a good thing to do.
See that he gets a good scrub down
and an extra ration of oats.
- Yes, sir.
- Captain Keogh reporting, sir,
- with 27 transferees from Hays.
- Welcome to Fort Lincoln, captain.
- Thank you, sir.
- General Custer, Commander of the 7th,
- Adjutant Cooke.
- I'm fortunate to have you with me.
I've been looking forward to this
for a long time, General.
Solid looking animal
you're riding, Captain.
Thank you, sir. Not as handsome
as your Vic or Dandy, General,
but all heart and legs.
Give him an
extra ration of oats and boom.
- He's ready to go again.
- What about you?
Give me a bag of oats, sir,
and I'm ready, too.
Good! The 7th's a fighting outfit.
There's some exciting times ahead.
Suits me fine. The sooner
you put me to work, the better.
Well,
then fall out at reveille, Mr. Keogh.
Captain Benteen's heading a small patrol
to run down some Indians.
Burned a wagon train, ran off with
two white women. They must be punished.
And the women rescued.
It's more important to teach those
red savages who's running this country.
They must learn quickly,
or be exterminated.
Mr. Cooke,
show, uh, Captain Keogh to his quarters.
- Yes, sir.
- See you at my table for supper.
- At 7:00.
- Yes, sir.
If I can't come back,
I will throw a rock over the wall.
A big rock
will mean there are many soldiers.
A little one, there are few.
Tonka!
It's good to see you again, Tonka.
You remember me, don't you?
Oh, I knew you would.
I... I saw them bring you here.
My heart was filled with sorrow.
But I knew you'd be protected.
Well, what is this?
Oh, you've been hurt, Tonka.
It's only a little thing, but...
White man's medicine. It is not good.
Only Indian medicine is good.
This will draw out the poison.
Soon as it dries. There.
Sorry to be late, old man,
but Chief Longhair was recounting
some of his Indian exploits,
and I couldn't walk out on him.
It doesn't pay to be rude
to a general. You remember that. Hear?
What's this?
Mud.
Climb out.
You understand white man talk?
What's your name? Your name!
- White Bull.
- What tribe?
- Teton Sioux.
- What are you doing in here?
- I came to see my horse.
- Your horse?
- Comanche?
- His name is Tonka Wakan.
- How do you know what his name is?
- He belonged to me.
I caught him. I named him.
What does Tonka Wakan mean?
- The Great One.
- I see.
And I suppose you trained him?
We had many good times together.
That explains a lot.
I knew he was trained
with great love and patience.
And I figured it was an Indian
because of the charm bag.
What puzzles me is how he got mixed up
in a band of wild horses again.
I was a youth without rank.
My cousin, Yellow Bull, claimed him.
He's a cruel man.
I couldn't bear to hear
Tonka's cries of pain in my sleep.
So I...
I set him free.
You think a lot of him, don't you?
I don't know why.
He's an ugly brute.
- He's beautiful.
- Well, in a homely sort of way.
When you came here tonight,
what were you gonna do?
- Steal him back?
- No.
No, Yellow Bull would only
take him from me again.
I saw you ride in this afternoon. I...
- I only wanted to see him.
- I think I understand, White Bull.
I feel the same way about Tonka.
Only I call him Comanche.
Because he's a fighter.
Well, I suppose it doesn't make any
difference how you got in here.
The fact remains
I can't let you just walk out.
They'll probably
wanna question you and...
But I promise you
no harm will come to you.
Let's go.
Oh, uh, wait a minute.
You think the, uh,
the mud is better than the salve?
Then we'll leave it.
I don't suppose it would do any good
to ask what you told 'em.
This much we know.
Sitting Bull is bringing all the tribes
of the Sioux Nation together.
Why?
I am only a youth. The great shaman
does not tell me what he is thinking.
Does he plan to make war?
- I don't know, Chief Yellow Hair.
- Lying, thieving redskin!
- Speak up!
- General.
He'd have his tongue cut out before he
told you the truth, even if he knew it.
Keogh's right, Custer.
The boy came to see his horse.
We caught him.
Now let it go at that.
All right. I'll let him go.
But first, I wanna give him a message
to take back to Sitting Bull.
Tell your great shaman that we have
many forts with many soldiers.
Tell him they will march and burn
every Sioux village to the ground,
unless he comes back to the reservation
and lives in peace.
Now you can turn him loose, captain.
Um... better lock him up. Turn him loose
first thing in the morning.
- My friends wait for me in the trees.
- Goodbye, White Bull.
I hope there will be no trouble
between your people and mine.
You have a good master, Tonka.
No longer will my heart
be heavy with sorrow for you.
Goodbye, boy.
Comanche, if we should ever meet him
out there as the enemy,
I want you to know
it was no doings of mine.
General Sheridan's plan of attack
calls for a three-pronged movement
against Sitting Bull's village here.
At the forks
of the Little and the Bighorn River.
General Gibbon will go up
the Yellowstone and down Bighorn.
General Custer
will go up the Rosebud two days' march.
Then move westward to meet up
with Gibbon and Cooke's column
on the 26th without forced march.
You will not attack
until you have joined forces.
- Any questions?
- Yes, sir.
Are we making war on all Indians?
Some are still at peace.
With your permission, General Terry,
I'd like to answer Captain Keogh.
There's no way
to separate the good from the bad.
They've burned, pillaged, murdered.
They're all bad.
Are there any questions?
If not, you may proceed at once.
And remember, Custer, the 26th.
Wait for us.
Yes, sir.
It's probably rank heresy, Hank,
but I think Chief Longhair
has a few plans of his own. It'd be
interesting to know what they are.
I'd feel better if I was going with you.
Gibbon's a good man.
You take care of him,
- Comanche'll take care of me.
- Good luck, Myles.
Thank you.
- Ho!
Big Indian village. About half a day's
march away in Valley of Bighorn.
- Over hill.
- Good.
- Mr. Cooke.
- Yes sir.
Make camp. But no bugles.
I want an officer's call immediately.
- Yes.
- Forward!
- Ho!
Close up! Close up!
Oh, at ease, gentlemen.
Be seated if you wish.
I promised Elizabeth
I wouldn't make a target of myself.
You know, it would make
a tempting scalp lock at that.
Mark Kellogg, gentlemen.
Newspaperman from Bismarck.
He's here for a story,
and I think we can give him one.
A large Indian village
lies directly ahead
in the Valley of the Little Bighorn.
We'll hit them at dawn tomorrow morning.
Catch them in their sleep.
Begging the general's pardon,
our orders were not to attack
until we joined forces
with Gibbon and Cooke.
An unsuspecting enemy
lies ahead of us, Captain.
It would be dereliction of duty
if I did not press the advantage.
More Indians than soldiers.
More Indians than stars in sky.
I pay you for scouting, Boyer,
not to make decisions.
Captain Benteen, you will circle west
with troops D, H and K
to cut off retreat upriver.
Major Reno, you will push
straight into the village
with troops A, G and M
and spearhead the attack.
I will sustain you
with troops C, E, F, L and I.
We'll rest here
without cooking fires or bugles,
and move out two hours before dawn.
without the jingle of sabers, gentlemen,
to give away our approach.
Take them off.
- That's all.
- Excuse me, sir.
We saw Indians trailing us.
They fled in the
direction of a village 15 miles ahead.
- They know our position, sir.
- Very good, lieutenant.
We will not wait.
We'll strike the hostiles quickly,
before they have a chance to prepare.
Pass the word to assemble at once.
That's all, gentlemen.
My guns, Boyer.
- No sabers. That's a funny one.
- Funnier, him cutting his hair.
Maybe he's got a hunch.
Into the valley of Death
rode the brave 600.
If we had 600, we'd have a chance.
To split us up...
You heard what the scout said.
- Good luck.
- You too.
Follow me!
- Ho!
- Officers front, Mr. Cooke.
- Yes, sir. Officers front!
- Officers front!
Major Reno's engaged the enemy.
We'll ride north.
Cross the river.
Attack their camp from the rear.
I'm afraid your element of surprise
is lost, general.
Do not turn back until I signal.
- Are you afraid?
- No.
- Are you?
- Of course not.
- I will count first coup.
- I will take many scalps.
Earn many feathers for my war bonnet.
They're trying
to draw us away from Reno.
Which suits my plan exactly.
Rejoin your troops, General. Ready
your small arms for close-in fighting.
You'll get a story today, My. Kellogg.
You'll write history.
Forward to the devil, Mr. Cooke! Ho!
Fire at will! Fire at will!
Look, Strong Bear!
My friend, the white captain.
He's riding Tonka!
All white soldiers are enemies.
They must die!
Chief Yellow Hair is down!
It is a good omen!
Fight on foot! Dismount! Fight on foot!
Close up ranks!
Sound dismount!
- Form a service line!
- Steady now!
Form a line!
Take those horses uphill!
Horse holders, double up on your mounts!
Close up! Close up!
Watch that gully! Keep down!
Steady! Keep low!
Sir, our ammunition bags
are on those horses.
Never mind. Benteen'll be here soon.
Close ranks! Close ranks!
Watch your left flank!
Down, boy. Down! Down!
Close up! Rally! Rally!
Watch those shots!
Make every one count!
Pick your targets!
Watch Yellow Bull!
He will touch a dead soldier
and earn a feather for his bonnet!
I will earn a feather, too!
You won first coup.
You earned a feather.
We'll make 'em pay, boy.
We'll make 'em pay.
Ah!
Strong Bear?
May the spirit of Tonka Wakan
go with you.
Tonka? Tonka?
Tonka!
Your medicine is weak!
It didn't protect him.
Tonka.
Ho!
Lieutenant!
Poor devil.
Might as well put him out of his misery.
No!
No.
This horse is not your enemy.
- I am your enemy. Kill me.
- Glad to oblige you, redskin.
Wait!
This is the lad
we questioned at the fort.
Doctor.
7th Cavalry, US Army,
orders of the day.
Headquarters, US 7th Cavalry,
Fort Abraham Lincoln, Dakota Territory,
April 10th, 1878.
General orders number seven.
The horse known as Comanche,
being the only living representative
of the bloody tragedy of the Bighorn,
Montana, June 25th, 1876,
his kind treatment and comfort
should be a matter
of special pride and solicitude
on the part of the 7th Cavalry.
To the end that his life
may be prolonged to the utmost.
The command officer of Troop I
will see that a special
and comfortable stall
is fitted up for Comanche.
He will not be ridden by any person
whatever under any circumstances,
nor will he bet put to any work.
Hereafter, and upon all occasions
of ceremony, Comanche saddled,
bridled and led by a trooper
of Company I will be paraded
with regiment
by command of Colonel Sturgess.
No.
No. No wapato.
Just because you're a hero, you think
you can do as you please, don't you?
I'm sorry, Chief Nowlan.
Tonka's like a child.
- He thinks he can do as he pleases.
- As far as the 7th is concerned,
he can do no wrong.
He knows it, too, don't you mister?
Too much sweet will make him
- fat and lazy, Chief Nowlan.
- It's gonna be your job
to see that he doesn't
get fat and lazy, White Bull.
- You must give him a ride every day.
- But the orders...
Sure, sure.
But generals who give orders
aren't smart
like you and me, White Bull.
We know he's gotta be exercised,
don't we?
Well, don't we?