A Kyoeisha Production
Masaaki! They're here!
Right here!
- And now?
- Kill them!
What? Scared now?
Ready?
Charge!
Hooligans of Hakata
Cast:
Shimizu Masayoshi
Higuchi Ryo, Yatani Tomio
Kiyosue Hiroyuki, Ueda Toshiro
Egawa Junichi,
Nakajima Kenichi, Jinrei Toshiro
Special Appearence:
Yoshihara Masahiro
Special Appearance:
Hagiwara Kenzo
Special Appearence:
Izumiya Shigeru
Yamamoto Kazuyoshi, Shimizu Sanae
Nakamura Jo
Tokunaga Production
What will we do if we
can't even be proper gangsters?
Fucking smartass!
Stay here, you idiot.
You'll get your punishment.
What are you up to
at this time of the day?
Got no job?
My job...
I quit my job.
Quit? Why?
There was this guy
I didn't like...
I hit him once and they fired me.
- You’re such an idiot.
- Look who's talking!
That's right.
- Will you ever get it moving?
- Hurry up!
Hey, Manji!
Manji! Manji!
Manji!
Hey! Come here!
Where are you going?
Going to buy Maru Magazine.
The Maru!
Maru! Maru!
Maru!
Poor fellow.
It was the syphilis. He's
like an innocent child.
Syphilis? I heard
he had encephalitis.
- No, it was syphilis.
- Encephilitis, I tell you.
A mosquito bite made
him turn into an idiot.
Rubbish. He inherited
his parent's syphilis.
You know it was encephalitis, right?
I heard he hit his head when
he fell down the stairs as a baby.
Bye bye!
Maru Magazine!
- No Maru magazine?
- Not here yet.
Try again tomorrow.
Hey, octopus car!
Your car looks
like a red octopus!
Hey, fuckhead!
I'll give you a good beating!
You octo-pussies!
Get out of it!
Wait a moment.
Come here. I'll feed you.
Chibi!
Where’s big brother?
He's having a bath.
You should go, too.
Chibi, dinner time.
Come here.
Just a second.
MARU
Bang! Bang!
The fundaments of Japan
get more and more distorted.
Bang! Bang!
Bang!
Hey, Manji!
Manji!
That's a fine model gun.
It shoots bullets.
- Right, plastic bullets.
- Real bullets!
So, it really shoots?
Just watch me.
Manji, this...
Masaaki, listen...
I've stolen a TV.
Come and watch it with me.
No time for that.
Here, look at this.
Look!
Why? Just a toy gun!
You’re wrong!
It shoots bullets.
This is the best part of the
show, so will you shut up?
It really shoots bullets.
Seems like the work of Fujimoto.
Isn't Fujimoto with the army?
I heard he quit a month ago.
Fujimoto could really do such a thing.
He's crazy about that stuff.
Let me see...
Here... The bullets.
What do you think?
They’re heavy, eh?
You stupid moron!
You know what you did?
That's no toy!
Have you lost all
your marbles now?
Hey!
Go and get it back! Go on!
Get it back!
Go and get the gun!
Yazawa!
Visitor!
Who's there?
Who is it?
It's me, Oki!
Oki...?
Oshan...?
- Hi.
- Oshan!
How are you?
Long time no see!
Come in!
Hey, it's Oshan!
Get up!
Hi, Chuji.
Oshan...
- When did you get out?
- Just today. This morning.
- I wanted to see you first.
- Really?
I don't want a drink.
- Something cold?
- Oh yeah.
Go and get us something cold.
Thanks.
How about the guys?
Everyone is dead.
The boss got a new girl
and just disappeared.
I see...
He'll be enjoying his life.
So, you’re still
one of the bad boys...
They let you out
quicker than I thought.
- That's all I got.
- Fair enough.
What's this?
At least bring us some sugar!
And what are your plans now?
About that...
I’m too old to
go on playing around.
Maybe it's the right
time for a quieter life.
You want a job?
I thought I’d rest up
for a few days...
and then think
about everything.
Eat as much as you like.
But having you back, Oshan!
We should have some fun.
Go out for some
action with the gang.
No, thanks.
I'll retire.
Don't say that. We’re
friends, I’ll miss you!
I'm so exhausted.
You’re just
having the prison blues.
We'll call Kobayashi and
celebrate your release tonight.
We’ll drink together and
you’ll feel better soon.
How did a stupid guy
like you ever even find a job?
I went to high school,
different than you...
What are you talking about?
We went to high school
together, right, Oshan?
You dropped out of
junior high, didn't you?
See how stupid they became
while you were away, Oshan...
You’re such an idiot!
Oshan, we really had fun
in junior high, didn't we?
You just came to sit
in the back row all the time.
What the...? You wouldn't have
managed without Oshan's help, either!
Yazawa!
Where are you?
Where did that gangster go...
(Japanese anthem starts playing.)
I am good for nothing...
Junior high was just great.
You never saw Oshan as the
leader back in the day.
You just stood there
wetting your pants.
That wasn't me, idiot!
You remember, don't you, Oshan?
Don't say that. That's a
thing of the past now.
But Oshan, there’s
still so much we could do.
Just think of those punks who get
scared just from hearing your name.
Welcome!
Good that you’re back, Oshan!
May I take your order?
What would you like?
- Sake.
- OK.
Come on, boys!
Let's get drunk!
Are you drinking, Kobayashi?
Let's drink to Oshan's release.
Bottoms up, Oshan!
Drink with us, Oshan!
Your bill, Sir.
Thank you for your visit.
What a bastard.
What a fucking bastard!
Why did you stop me, Oshan?
Hope they won't cause more trouble.
Did that guy expect that
Oshan would waste his time on him?
But he really pissed me off.
Bill, please!
Bastard!
- Stupid bastards...
- They must be kidding.
Long time no see, Oki!
Kind of bad timing, eh?
Want to settle that
dispute we had three years ago?
You...!
I beg you.
Please forget it.
I won't let you get away!
Let's run!
Are you okay?
- What was that?
- The model gun.
Just a bit more, hurry up.
Too late. He's dead.
- Report to the HQ.
- Yes.
Son of the leader of the
Tenryu Gang murdered
The eldest son of Yamaoka Daigo,
the leader of the Tenryu Gang,
the 22-year-old Yamaoka Ryuichiro,
was attacked last
night at around 11:40...
in the Higashi district
of Fukuoka city.
He was discovered dead.
He had been shot in the leg.
When the police arrived,
Yamaoka had already bled to death.
Gang leader Yamaoka told journalists
who inquired about his son’s death:
"We'll blow out the lights
of those guys who killed my son."
He added that he would not
rely on the police's investigations.
Authorities fear that this incident
might lead to a violent gang war,
therefore the police are not treating
this case as a normal murder.
Investigations will continue while
securing the safety of the public...
It'll be 200,000 per person.
When do we depart?
The sooner the better...
There's a ship leaving
Hakata port in three days.
Phone me again tomorrow.
I'll give you the details then.
Have the money
ready when you leave.
Pay the full price
before departure.
Understood.
Police are looking for two suspects
in the murder of Yamaoka Ryuichiro.
Yazawa Masaaki, 21 years old.
Unemployed, no fixed abode.
Kaneda Chuji, 20 years old.
Authorities are on
alert all over the country.
You think we’re safe here?
This place should be fine.
But you should stay inside.
- You are Fujimoto Manji, right?
- Yeah.
Is your big brother here?
Would you call him for us?
Big brother!
Your friends are here.
Big brother?
Over there.
Turn left here.
Right there.
Stop!
Robbers! Robbers!
Lose him!
We did it!
I knew we could.
That was perfect!
That's how I do such things.
I know how to do it.
We interrupt our program
for some breaking news:
20 minutes ago, a robbery occurred
in Maeda, in the Higashi ward.
Two armed men entered a branch
of the Hakata Kiyo Bank.
They got hold of around 2.3 million
in cash and fled towards Yoshizuka.
The two young men threatened the
staff with a shotgun and a knife.
They grabbed the money on the
counter and drove off in their car.
We were looking for you, punk!
Take us to your friends!
We'll have to kill you.
Talk!
Where are your friends?
Open your mouth!
- No!
- You take us!
What's the idiot doing?
What now?
There's nothing we
can do without him.
And he took the car.
That idiot can't even drive.
What a disaster!
Let's wait a bit longer.
- Shall I look for him?
- Let's look on the other side.
It's me...
Chuji.
What a surprise!
Run! Run!
You bastard...!
Masaaki!
You've spotted Fujimoto Koichi?
Location...? Yes...
Hakata ward...
Chiyo...
First district...
Opposite Kimura Clinic...
Detective Kurosaki spotted him
while he was out on patrol.
At the moment, Fujimoto is
having lunch at the restaurant.
Detective Noguchi is
inside, as a customer.
10 police officers in plain
clothes are on watch nearby.
Your orders?
It's dangerous;
Fujimoto might have a gun.
We’ll send for back-up.
Stay there and wait.
Yes, sir.
Welcome.
It's me, Masaaki.
Oh, you? That took a while.
We were attacked by guys
from the Tenryu Gang over there.
The Tenryu Gang?
Are you alright, then?
I’m alright, but I
think they got Chuji.
Chuji?
- Really?
- How about the others?
Not here yet.
I see...
They’re still at the park,
waiting for Chuji ...
Then I’ll go and
meet the others now.
Wait for us. Alright?
What the... It's you?
Grandma told me...
- What?
- You killed...
Status?
30 police officers have
checked the surrounding area.
Detective Tanaka is on
his way to the restaurant.
Be careful.
I'm sure he has a gun.
Thank you.
Don't shoot!
Down!
Down! Down!
One man in custody!
Caught in the act.
Let me go!
Let me go, filthy swine!
Our country is in danger!
Japan is in danger!
To Higashi Park.
Go a bit faster.
You can go faster.
Will it take much longer?
Just hurry up!
Come on, hurry up!
Take us to Higashi Park!
Come on!
Seikei Kindergarten
Here they are.
Hurry up, to Higashi Park.
Driver!
Right to Higashi Park!
- Oshan...
- That's bad.
If we don't go,
the cops will get us.
That guy really
is such a big idiot!
We can't just stay here.
We have to go and meet Masaaki.
It's just too much.
Where the hell did he go?
- Go and give Marimo a call.
- Okay.
Faster, man!
Yazawa Masaaki, suspect in
the murder of Yamaoka Ryuichiro...
has hijacked a kindergarten bus
and is heading towards Higashi Park.
Roger, keep on following them.
He's going to meet his pals.
Kaneda is down, so he
will meet Oki and Kobayashi.
We’ve linked them to the
recent bank robbery.
Stay back until
those guys arrive.
- We’ll send back-up.
- Understood.
Hey, Manji!
What's going on?
The guys from the
Tenryu Gang got Chuji.
So I’m here instead
to meet you guys.
Shit!
We've no time for talking.
What will we do?
- Wait, I'll get Oshan!
- Quick!
- Masaaki is here.
- Masaaki? And Chuji?
Follow them.
- The cops!
- Police?
Police!
Just shoot them down.
We'll take the brats in the
kindergarten as hostages!
There are no kids here.
Summer holidays or what?
Manji, come here.
What are you doing?
No need to worry.
We've got a hostage.
We'll get a
helicopter and cut loose.
They won't get us!
Down! Down!
Oshan, you think we can get away?
Of course we can.
I’m excited once again.
The gangsters have taken
refuge in a kindergarten.
Send back-up immediately.
Stay down!
Stop! You can't enter!
We’re from the press!
Let us report!
Hey, you!
What do you think?
Want me to cut off your ear?
Oshan!
- Got any ideas what to do?
- I’m thinking about it.
Status?
They have one hostage.
Wait for further orders.
Understood.
You’re all surrounded.
You can't run anymore.
Let the hostage go, put down
your guns and come out right now.
Nobody got hurt so far.
Come out right now.
You’re all surrounded.
You can't get out of there.
Let the hostage go, put down
your guns and come out right now.
Nobody got hurt so far.
Come out right now.
You’re all surrounded.
You can't get away.
Let the hostage go, put down
your guns and come out right now.
Shut up!
If you have conditions,
let us hear them!
We want a helicopter.
Impossible.
How about that helicopter up there?
You think we’re stupid?
That one belongs to the press.
Give it to me!
Listen to our demands...
Or there'll be bloodshed.
Hey, Kobayashi! Kobayashi!
Sure, I’m all up for it.
Wait! Wait!
We'll have it ready.
The criminals seem
to be very upset at the moment.
Despite the hard work of the police,
the situation remains very dangerous.
Among the men who have taken
refuge in a kindergarten are...
the two suspects in the recent
murder of Yamaoka Ryuichiro...
Yazawa Masaaki, wanted for
arrest in the whole country,
and with him the suspects of the
Hakata bank robbery this afternoon,
who robbed 2.3 Million yen:
Oki Saburo...
Kobayashi Jun and...
Boys, look at this! Quick!
Those are the swine
who killed my son!
Let us through!
You bastard!
You've let those guys run away
and now they’re out there in action.
Now stop sitting around,
and do something about it.
What are you doing?
If you come back without having
killed them you'll be dead instead.
You'll be in deep shit.
I think you got that right now.
Go and kill them!
The helicopter, quickly!
The helicopter’s ready.
Now let the hostage go free.
Liar! I can't see a helicopter!
Oshan, I guess they think that
we wouldn't hurt the hostage.
Kobayashi, bring her here.
Get up, this way!
Shall we chop off one of her arms?
We'll really do it!
You want her arm so much?
Now, hurry up!
The helicopter!
Let's go!
Oshan, I found us a
nice little treasure here.
One injured person!
Over here.
It's his right leg!
His right leg!
Oh, man...
It's just too much.
We should just give up.
Impossible!
We don't have a chance like this.
They'll take new
action in the morning.
They’ve got us all surrounded.
We'll use the hostages as shields...
And break through.
You can't believe that yourself.
It's the only way. The police
will come and get us soon.
They'll be shocked.
What's next?
At dawn, I'll give you a signal.
Then we’ll take the hostages
and attack the police.
You think you can
get away that easily?
Shut the fuck up.
This is a live report.
It is now already
more than 10 hours since...
four gangsters with a hostage
took refuge in a kindergarten.
A serious incident occurred this
afternoon around 5:30:
gangsters of the Tenryukai tried to
enter the place using armed force.
This resulted in the deaths of
three police officers and one gangster.
In addition, more than
10 police officers were wounded.
After that, there has been
absolutely no movement at all.
There are no new developments.
The gangsters must be at
their limit already...
Masaaki.
Did you attend kindergarten?
I don't think he did.
I mean, look at him!
Look who's talking.
Look at your face!
This boy, his name is Oki too.
He hasn't got a
bright future then.
You know yourself pretty well, Oshan.
- Shame about the name...
- He just looks terrible there.
Is there any kid called Kobayashi?
If there was...
he would have to be a bright boy.
Hey, Officer Saeba!
I'm sure you went to kindergarten?
You haven't wet yourself, have you?
Hey, Manji!
You want to go home?
Nah, it's fun being here.
Wanna go to Korea?
Is Korea far away?
Quite near, actually.
Not far away?
- Let's go then.
- Fine.
I'll take you there, Manji.
We'll finish off this shit
here tomorrow morning.
Alright?
He is... he is...
Leave him...
I did it!
Handcuffs! Handcuffs!
Gotcha!
Don't take photos!
Out of the way!
Let us pass!
There he is.
There's one guy.
I thought four guys...?
It's a cop! Shoot!
Wait! I’m not...
THE END