Executive Producer: Raymond Chow
Producer: Leonard KC Ho
Writer, director and leading actor:
Jackie Chan
MIRACLES
The Hansen factory is looking
for young apprentices.
There are 250 vacancies right now.
The pay is $8 a month and you
are guaranteed a year's bonus.
lt's just two dollars to register.
- Ajob in Hong Kong?
- But $2 he said.
You must be prepared to work hard
and long hours.
$2 dollars, that's too much.
No need to push.
There are 250 positions.
lf you feel this is for you,
it's only $2 to register.
They also need a bright lad
to work as a cashier.
- Pay is $12 a month, any takers?
- l will.
Come this way.
- What are you good at?
- Kung fu and acrobatics.
- But can you use an abacus?
- No problem.
- Guarantor?
- What?
- Have you got any money?
- Yes.
- lt's $30. What's your name?
- Kuo Chen Wah from Canton.
- Do l have to pay now?
- That's the deal.
Pay cash, you're in.
Still want it?
l only have $25.
Pay the rest later. Report
for duty tomorrow at this address.
Jobs galore!
Hurry, they're going fast.
You're really lucky.
Line up over here!
Only $2 registry fee!
What are you doing here?
This isn't Hansen's cloth factory.
Who took your $2?
The address is right, but the Hansen
factory doesn't exist.
lt's not easy to make a living
in Hong Kong.
Leave now, you've all been conned.
Leave, or l'll call the police.
Robbery! Robbery! Robbery!
- What do we do now?
- Call it a $2 lesson.
We were lucky.
l saw some guy pay the man $30.
- That was very bad luck.
- More money than sense.
Hong Kong!
lt's all arranged.
- Be careful.
- Sure.
Boss, you look bad.
Uncle Hai, l can't find his medicine.
You forgot the boss's medicine?
One of you must have it.
lmbecile!
Pretending he's boss.
They forgot your medicine.
We'll postpone the meeting.
- We mustn't show any weakness.
- lt's not that...
lf Tiger's reasonable,
don't be too harsh.
You're too kind-hearted
for this business.
ln our business, it's them or us.
That's why l have
absolute faith in Fei.
He's vicious and cold-hearted.
Sunglasses.
- Late, as usual.
- l'm not late.
You were early.
What's wrong, old man?
You're ill again?
Cut the small talk.
Why did you call me here today?
Fine. Remember Yang -
your partner, Mr White?
Sure l do, but he's dead.
Yeah, but he and l made a deal. The
Ritz would be split down the middle.
He may have said so, but l never did.
Come on, calm down. You came to talk.
l'm here because as Mr White,
l won't be forced into bargaining
with you pack of liars!
You're calling me a liar?
That isn't nice. Open fire!
- Are you all right, boss?
- Get him out of here.
- Would you like to buy a rose, sir?
- No.
Don't refuse me
this early in the morning.
No, thank you.
Buying a rose from me
will bring you good luck.
- Your first time in Hong Kong?
- Yes.
Take care.
l learnt my lesson yesterday.
l'm afraid you didn't.
Look at your suitcase.
As l said, take care, sir.
Hey, wait a minute.
l will buy a rose after all.
- Let's hope your luck will change.
- l hope you're right.
Thanks!
Be careful.
Get lost!
What now?
- Don't move!
- l'm just trying to help.
Thanks very much, young man.
Don't move!
Run for it!
- Boss, are you OK?
- How did we get into this mess?
Young man, could you help carry him?
- Who are you?
- We'll pay you $100.
$100?
Over there!
- Where do l take him?
- Anywhere. Move!
Run!
- Where now?
- Ouch! That hurts.
Put me down.
You're hurting my stomach.
- Put him down first!
- OK.
- Boss, are you OK?
- You...
My...
This way.
How is your stomach?
Boss, how are you?
Tell me who is going
to take your place?
Let him have it.
- Let him have it?
- What's happening?
- Are you sure?
- l want him...
Boss! Boss! Boss! Boss!
You all heard Mr White.
We must obey his wishes.
But we must get out of here.
Let's go, boss.
From now on, you're our boss.
Me?
Being our boss, you don't have to
worry where you live or how you live.
You still don't understand. Look,
you get to have elegant clothes.
You're always fighting,
it's a dangerous job.
- l might as well do it.
- What?!
Don't worry.
Just do as l tell you, you'll be OK.
Why did the boss name this jerk?
You were his right hand man.
lf l'm not the right man for the job,
we'd soon know about it.
lf you're not up to it,
then who is?
Let's wait and see what happens.
Boss, any spare change?
Here, now scram.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Keep an eye on things.
We'll go in the back way.
What if nothing happens?
Then fix the car.
Young man, a rose for luck?
Get lost.
l'll buy a rose from her. Hey, lady!
l'll buy a rose from you.
lt's your lucky day, sir.
- There.
- That's very kind. l thank you, sir.
Let's go, boss.
- Why isn't Fei our new boss?
- You really want him up there?
Who else? You?
Fei's the only man,
otherwise it could be any one of us.
Why not you?
We've got him outnumbered.
He doesn't stand a chance.
lf he's got the guts to fight,
he can show us.
l can't go through with this.
Don't force me.
We won't force you.
You can take the back stairway out.
- Thanks.
- But you must be careful.
Why should l be careful?
lf you leave now,
we can't protect you.
lf Tiger catches you,
they'll make mincemeat of you.
But l helped your boss, remember?
l couldn't figure out why you helped.
lt's odd he chose you,
but l must obey his instructions.
l'm cursed whichever way l turn.
No problem. l'll look out for you.
Now you even look like the boss.
Here's your speech.
Let's go.
We'll test him.
Don't be afraid.
Brothers, at the request of Mr White,
l'm here to introduce your new boss,
Kuo Chen Wah.
Uhh...good day to you, friends.
l would like to...
Can't you talk without reading?
l don't know how to be your boss.
ln my opinion you shouldn't
rob banks, or do bad things
like racketeering, killing,
or breaking the law in any...
Our new boss has got a great
sense of humour.
Words are fine, but show us
what you're really made of.
- Show us what he's made of.
- Go on.
- All right?
- OK.
- Look out for him.
Go on, then.
Over here, over here!
Don't be shy.
Come on!
Fatty, you be referee.
Settle down.
Move out of the way.
Ready? One, two, three...
Who burnt me?
Don't make excuses.
Well done, boss.
l tell you, somebody burnt me.
Arm wrestling doesn't prove anything.
Otherwise Tom would've been
boss long ago.
ln this business,
you must be able to fight.
You fight him them.
You're on your own now.
We'll show him.
ls two against one too much for you?
Let me go!
Help him up.
Boss.
- The boss is the winner!
- Well done!
The boss is the winner.
''The King George''
The letter?
- And the paper?
- Here. Write sparingly.
lf the boss finds out, he'll fire me.
l won't waste it.
Here's a rose for luck.
'l was at Mr Chow's party today.
'He was asking after you.
'When l got back to the hotel,
l received your letter.
'l am so happy that your school
friend, lan is so good to you.
'l am very happy for you,
l think he must be very handsome.
'lf you're not too busy, l hope we
can meet in Shanghai later this year.
'We're going to a function
at the lndian Consulate tonight.
'No doubt it will be chicken curry.
'l'm sending you some more money
this month.
'You're getting older now,
so you'll be needing a bit more.
'The weather's getting cold, take
care you don't kick off your covers.
'The chauffeur has just arrived.
l've got to go.
'Sorry to write so little, Mum.'
So we're making a loss and breaking
even? Something must be wrong.
You don't know what Yang is like.
He tricked him in a game of chance.
He lost all his shares in the Ritz.
So l juggled the figures a bit.
Do we have to get involved
in shady deals?
Boss, l'm just following orders. The
brothers won't object if they're fed.
Can you make this restaurant
more profitable?
l won't run a casino.
A whorehouse, then?
Uncle? Sorry, but there's a Miss Yang
here to see you.
Come in. This is Uncle Hai.
Good day, l'm Luming Yang. My father
used to own half this place.
l believe he died in Shanghai
three months ago.
Yes.
That's why l've come to discuss
the business side of things with you.
This is Mr Kuo Chen Wah.
He's our new boss here.
My father gambled his share
of the restaurant away.
He asked me to find a way
to repay you.
lt's nothing. Forget it.
Wait. He meant
at your own convenience.
l've got some money here.
Can l give you that for now?
Your father owed us thousands.
l could work for you without pay.
As what?
l sang and danced
at a club in Shanghai.
- Why did you leave?
- The club closed.
lt wasn't my fault.
l was very good.
One minute. l'll sing for you.
Hong Kong by night, never sleeps
The Pearl of the Orient that we are
Listen to the symphony of waves
and tides
- lt's not much.
- l got it. Build her up.
- We'll open a nightclub.
- Yeah, we'll do that.
- Up there.
- One, two, three...
Be careful, be careful.
What's the total?
lf l knew how to add,
l would have joined the Navy.
You're crazy!
lt's someone for you.
Mr Jang.
Mister.
You're decorating?
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Be careful!
Why are you taking so long?
lf l knew how to write,
l would have joined the airforce.
Are you ready?
Now look at the camera.
Ready.
- Let's go in.
- Welcome!
- Put it there.
- Your reservations, sir?
- Tiger Lo needs no reservations.
- This way, Tiger.
So kind of you to come, Mr Tiger.
You've got a nice place here.
Let me introduce you to our new boss,
Kuo Chen Wah.
Kuo Chen Wah. You're not White, then.
l thought White was your father.
Miss Luming, hurry up.
To what do we owe
the pleasure of this visit?
Relax, this is a social visit.
l see you've spared no expense.
l'm ready to forget Yang's debts.
Give me half of the Ritz.
l think...
- Are you the boss here?
- No, he is.
Then shut up. Well?
Yang's debts are not our business.
You can see we've spent a lot
on the decor.
We don't need outside investment.
Ladies and gentlemen, there's
a great surprise in store tonight.
Luming Yang of Shanghai,
star of Broadway.
l'm usually short-tempered,
but tonight...
Make way, make way!
- Get the lights on.
- Nobody move.
Stay in your seats. Stop the music.
- Spotlights off.
- Turn on the house lights.
The Chief lnspector Ho
of Hong Kong here.
ldentity cards, ready, please.
- Mr Ho, you are disrupting the show.
- lnspector to you.
lnspector, we have a proper license.
And we have a proper search warrant.
l don't carry a card.
What are you saying? No cards? Why?
- So what?
- lmprisonment, that's what.
How are you, sir?
- How's Mr Laughton, your boss?
- He's well, thank you.
You may leave.
These are all good people.
Have you made the check?
lnspector Ho, you are disturbing
our guests.
l will come here whenever l please.
Today, tomorrow, the next day.
- Are you the licensee?
- No, not me, him.
l'm Kou Chen Wah, the manager.
So you're the new boss?
lt's our opening night.
Excuse us for any shortcoming.
Looks like a boss.
l won't disturb them,
but l would like a word with you.
No problem.
Of course.
Now what?
Stop searching.
Let's go.
Come upstairs.
lnspector Ho, please, sit down.
l didn't come here to sit down,
l came here because l saw something.
Saw something?
Something that doesn't belong here.
You must be mistaken, everything here
is bought and paid for.
- l mean you.
- Me? l don't belong here?
Yes, all the people downstairs
make a living through theft,
deceit and other foul means.
Don't argue with me.
l reckon...
amongst all these people...
the only person who hasn't committed
a crime yet...
l want to save you
from this den of iniquity.
- l want to do you a good turn.
- A good turn?
Yes, from now on...
if you can inform me
of Yang and Tiger's activities,
then l will put them behind bars.
Then you and l...
will create the biggest story to come
out of Hong Kong in its history.
l must wipe them out.
l hope you aren't one of them.
But l have been thinking
of a gradual...
Don't reply now.
Think it over and give me a call.
l don't usually trust people,
but in your case...
Boss, some tea for lnspector Ho.
No need, we won't be bothering you
any further.
- What was that...?
- Sorry, l forgot my hat.
Continue.
- What did he say?
- He told me to behave.
He wouldn't say that.
He must think you are the only
innocent person here.
Did he ask you to do the right thing?
- No.
- Of course he did.
He must have asked you to rat on us
and do Hong Kong a great service.
He must have said
he didn't trust anyone
and you shouldn't miss the boat.
So you know what he told me?
Notjust me. Everyone knows.
Even the door man.
Back to base!
Sorry about the interruption.
Continue the music.
Let's give Luming a big hand.
Ask your boss to have a drink.
This is all water under the bridge.
We don't want to start a war.
Very few people
are as peace-loving as you.
lf l was boss, l'd prefer peace too.
Kuo is too young
and Hai is too sneaky.
- Pass on the message.
- lf that's all, l'll leave.
All debts are paid.
Here are the lOU's.
- Thank you.
- Let's go.
- Tong's still out buying roses.
- What for? lt's not a proposal.
Chen Wah.
What is it?
- Have you thought about the future?
- l have thought about it.
Everybody's waiting.
Wait till l come back.
Wait three years anyway.
Hey!
Three years!
Don't you know the Black Tiger gang
had 7 bosses in three years?
l can't find Madam Kao.
Can't you go without roses?
- That's not the point.
- Fine, get started. Get in.
l wish you good luck.
Thank you, miss.
- lsn't it beautiful?
- Lovely.
You people cover the back alley.
- Rush in when l throw the cup.
- OK.
Wait a minute.
Tidy up.
Kid, you do have it.
Sit down, please.
Quick, stay alert.
Don't nag me again.
Now you're here,
some good will come of this.
Sign here, and you go home safely.
With not a hair missing.
Half of the Ritz?
Whatever has happened
between us in the past,
sign here and we'll be brothers.
Understand?
Yes, but...
Are you qualified to sign?
lf not, shut up.
- l'll sign.
- Now you are talking.
With one more clause -
we get half your income from
the casinos then - unconditionally.
Repeat what you said, young man?
Say that again.
Go on.
You take half the Ritz,
we're entitled to half your assets.
Don't move!
Fools! Ten Shantung men
can't beat two Cantonese?
Useless morons!
What are you doing with your guns?
Put the guns away, you idiots!
Young man, if you've got the balls,
come outside with me.
lf you're going to hit me, kill me.
You old rotten egg!
Boss is in trouble.
You're good, young one.
- Pick him up.
- Move it.
Let's go.
Don't push. l'll go myself.
- Go, quick.
- Hurry up.
Give me half the Ritz
and l'll set them free.
Let's go.
Police.
Finished fighting? Seems we're late.
What did you say, lnspector Ho?
Mr Tiger, was there
fighting going on here?
l don't understand your dialect.
Speak Cantonese.
Cantonese?
lt seems there was a fight here.
l'm sure you weren't involved.
A fight? l didn't see anything.
- Nothing?
- No.
You saw nothing.
Are you under duress?
We were having tea and a chat.
Well, our tea and chats are over.
See you some other day.
Any time.
Tell me he threatened you
and l'll have him arrested.
lnspector Ho, l don't understand.
You're refusing to cooperate,
next time l may be too late.
Now l understand. Goodbye.
That's it, then. Let's go.
They were fighting.
Do you believe he was having tea?
l'm not blind.
Mission over.
Dismissed.
The lnspector saved the day,
not the rose.
l won't go anywhere without a rose.
Superstition.
Uncle, do we need to repair the car?
Yes, you and the car.
An overhaul is expensive.
l suspect Fei is behind
the whole thing.
You suspect him?
He's an old-timer and knows the ropes
well, yet he failed miserably.
So you question Fei's loyalty?
ln our business,
there's one thing we can't forget...
trust no-one.
l don't like it.
You don't have much choice.
- Do you want this?
- No.
- Where are you going?
- To the States.
Without consulting me?
You never gave me a chance to talk.
You only have time for fights
and business.
You take a holiday. lt's OK.
l'm not coming back.
What? Why?
- l want to get married.
- l told you, it's impossible.
With whom?
With Mr Lu.
His parents in the States are dying
for him to get married.
You think nobody wants me.
Don't try to stop me.
You can't leave!
- Why can't l go?
- You can't. Listen to me.
- You are rotten!
- Help me, please.
lt's none of my business. Carry on.
lf you leave what will happen to us?
All you care about is business.
You never have time for me.
Who do you think l am?
The piggy bank?
l never treated you like that.
Hey, help me out here.
What can l do?
- How do we treat her?
- As the piggy bank, of course.
He said it. Don't deny it again.
He's lying. Don't believe him.
Right, l lied.
What lies should l tell now?
Lies? You fool!
Lady, you know well how l treat you.
How do you treat me?
You know.
l don't know. You usually mumble,
l don't know what you're saying.
You're driving me crazy.
Lady, lady...
Lady, are you really going
to drop everything and leave?
lt's now or never. Should l wait
till you are riddled with holes?
Fiddlesticks!
Did l say something wrong?
l just heard wrong.
lt's none of my business.
None of your business?
All you do is drink. She's leaving.
That is my business. Stop her.
Lady, please, give me two more years.
You think l'd trust you?!
- l really mean it.
- You really mean it?
Let go of me!
Lady, lady, please, stay.
You lied to me.
No, l didn't.
l paid you back money
which my father didn't even owe you!
l worked hard for you. What have you
got to say for yourself?
l told him not to cheat you.
l've never objected.
He said the same thing.
At first, l didn't know you well.
Later, l didn't know how to begin.
The money is intact.
l'll pay you back.
So you cheated because he said so.
l didn't know you then.
Now you know how to shift blame.
Shut up, you!
Forget it. l don't want the money.
l'm going.
- Lady, listen to me.
- Let go of me.
Listen to me.
Boss.
Mr Lu wants to know
when we are leaving.
None of your business.
No, l've come to report
the engine's dead.
Tell him to go away.
How can they leave?
Yeah, how can they leave,
do l have to push them?
Tell Mr Lu to leave.
Tell him to leave, OK.
You depend on others for decisions.
Only when they are right.
- Lady.
- Let me go.
Lady, you can't go!
Don't go.
Give me a reason to stay.
A reason? What reason?
We don't act on reason.
You drink too much.
Are you all right? l'm really sorry.
l'm really sorry.
Boss, Mr Lu insists
on seeing Luming first.
- What then?
- Gun him down.
Shoot him dead.
- Let me get up.
- Please don't leave.
You can't trap her like a thief.
Kiss her, then she'll stay.
- Kiss her?
- And you refuse to listen.
l do, l do.
He'll leave now.
l'll go and clean the car.
Don't touch me.
Lady, l am sorry.
Baggage in hand? Going on holiday?
l tried to send your letter,
but l was caught and sacked.
- Where's the letter?
- The manager took it.
- Mr Manager.
- Manager, she wants to see you.
Yes?
You have a Shanghai letter
addressed to Mrs Kao, it's mine.
Yours?
But you don't live here.
How come there's a letter for you?
l used your headed note paper.
- Kick her out.
- Mr Manager, Mr Manager...
l'm in dire need of the letter.
Please give it to me.
l was wrong to use your letterhead.
l won't do it again.
Please, give me my letter.
Stop it. ls there a letter for her?
There was but l returned it.
No, that letter was non-returnable.
He's taking it to the post.
- Madam!
- My letter, my letter!
Go back to work.
Nothing. Sorry for the disturbance.
Thank you.
- Leave now.
- Thank you.
Thank you very much.
You've fixed everything. l'm going
to have some tea downstairs.
Let's shake hands and be friends.
l don't know
if he will accept your offer.
l don't think he's a bad person.
You think you know best.
We have a proverb, even pigs can fly.
So where are you from?
Me? The most honest
of Cantonese people.
Remember, morning tea.
l'd better be going.
Cantonese, Shandong people,
they're all the same.
l'll say it once more for you.
Chicken George used to work
on the docks.
l know. He has hundreds
of dockers working on the harbour.
He is very powerful.
When you see him,
don't be too humble.
l know, the dockers are always
delivering goods to Wan Chai.
What are you up to? More business?
You know the Black Dragons have
invited me to dinner, l have to go.
When he's talking to me,
can you not look at him, please?
Boss, l got it.
l bought the chrysanthemum.
- A chrysanthemum? Are you new?
- Chrysanths' are flowers too.
You fool, go out and clean the car.
A flower is a flower.
Hurry up. Time's short.
No flowers. They're waiting.
Don't be so superstitious.
Let's go.
No, no rose, no meeting.
l know you're looking at him.
l'm glad you have your own ideas.
Boss, we can't find Madam Kao.
- l was told she's sick at home.
- Sick?
Mr Wah, this way please.
Mr Wah.
This way.
OK, the flower's here. We must go.
l've come to buy a flower.
Are you all right?
Take your medicine.
- Has she got a temperature?
- No, she feels cold.
lt's not the flu. This is no use.
Give the boss a flower.
He needs it for luck.
Have you ever thought of giving
others some luck? You're inhuman.
Get a doctor here fast.
Boss, doctors are useless.
She's heartbroken.
Tell me who did it and he's dead.
Tell me and l'll cut him to pieces.
Tell me, l'll see if l can help.
Who is this?
That's her daughter.
l don't believe it.
She's so beautiful.
Sorry, l didn't mean it.
Forget about it.
Stop crying.
- l know. Her daughter's dead.
- Shut up.
Go and clean the car.
Hey, it's time now, we must go.
How can we leave?
The dockers may be offended.
- Let me buy the flowers first.
- Then buy them...
Mr Kuo, this is for you -
to bring you and everyone luck.
l hope you are all lucky.
You should be glad
you have such a pretty daughter.
Where is she?
Any way we can help?
Her daughter is studying in Shanghai.
She's coming back to see her mother.
Wonderful. Does she have money
for the ticket?
l'll buy it for you.
She's coming with her boyfriend
and his father
to discuss details of their marriage.
Madam Kao never let her know
about the flowers.
She left to study at a young age.
She was told not to worry about money
because her mother
is well known in Hong Kong.
She said she lived at King's.
Now if the daughter knows the truth,
she'll be very disappointed...
and if the father and son know,
there would be no marriage.
Tell me what l can do.
Only you can help.
You are the only one.
You are obliged to help her
as her rose brought you good luck.
How can l help her?
Easy, send her to King's
and give her a makeover.
Easy to say. That takes money.
We've raised some money for her.
Here's it is.
Do you think it's enough?
lt's OK. There's no need for that.
l'll do whatever you say.
l have to leave.
- No need to worry, you have me.
- l don't know how to thank you.
You sort it out.
- Why bother with this?
- lt's easy. l'm glad to help.
- This way.
- Miss Yang, everything's set.
Take care of Madam Kao.
So beautiful.
- Bring the things in.
- Yes.
Miss Yang, is everything OK?
Say yes if anyone asks
if Madam Kao lives here.
But say you don't know
if they ask about her.
Madam, welcome to your new home.
Chen Wah, over here.
- Beautiful, isn't it?
- Very.
Money buys everything.
l really don't know how to thank you
for all this wonderful help.
- Mr Kuo loves to help people, right?
- Yes.
Miss Yang, all your people are here.
Come in.
Please.
Who are they?
This is the beautician, the tailor,
the hairdresser. All for you.
Afternoon tea is ready.
- Who's he?
- The butler.
The butler?
Mr Kuo, this way.
Madam Kao deserves a butler.
- Uncle, we're leaving.
- Thank you.
- You've everything under control?
- Absolutely.
- What?
- We need a husband.
- What husband?
- She said she had one.
- What should we do?
- Find her one.
Me, find her a husband?
Where will l get one of them?
Don't ask me.
Children mean a husband.
A husband?
Don't get me involved.
Miss, where will l find one?
Miss, l have the perfect candidate.
- Who?
- A friend of mine.
ls he suitable?
Never mind that, get him here fast.
Then you stay.
l'll play any part for money.
Follow me.
l'd sign anything to live here.
Mr Kuo, this is my friend, Mr Tong.
From now on, he's your boss.
Kuo Chen Wah, Mr Kuo.
Haven't we met before?
No.
Go over and greet Mr Kuo.
- Mr Kuo, how do you do?
- How do you do?
- l did meet you some time ago.
- lmpossible.
Thank you. Gentlemen, Madam Kao.
She's your wife.
Don't be nervous. Relax.
Mr Kuo.
When are you going to introduce me?
Miss Yang,
this is the husband, Mr Tong.
You? Come here,
let's see you together. Not bad.
l just need clothes.
Have you finished yet?
- Luming, all done. Can l go?
- You may.
- We're leaving.
- Go home first.
You can't go just yet.
What? ls there anything else?
- We're meeting the ship tomorrow.
- l don't need to be there.
See this thing through.
- Right.
- OK, you can go now.
- Let's talk it over.
- Tea over there.
Why are you staring?
lt's only Madam Kao.
l remember who he is.
l know who you are.
Let bygones be bygones.
l am the husband now.
- What is it now?
- Nothing.
What's the matter?
Nothing, l saved him once.
Let's have some tea.
The ship's docked, boss.
Hurry up.
We're all up front.
- What will Belle say?
- She will be delighted.
- l owe it all to you.
- lt was nothing.
She's docking.
She's arrived.
Have you got it?
''Welcome, Mr Wong''
- Why is it so small?
- l was late back.
- Should have used a business card!
- Why are you late?
There's a bigger sign over there!
- There's someone else meeting Wong.
- lf you can so can they.
Madam Kao is well known.
We can't let them meet her
or we'll be finished.
- What now?
- We mustn't let them meet.
- Tell them to leave.
He bumped into me!
Remember, he's my teacher's
old friend, so behave yourself.
l couldn't get rid of them.
lt's lnspector Ho.
You sort it out.
- lnspector you must listen.
- What is it?
Do you want to know
what Tiger is up to?
- What?
- Not here.
- ln the station.
- l've come to meet the ship.
My information will be useless later.
Then tell me now.
l told you, not here.
Whisper it in my ear, then.
Forget about it.
- All fixed?
- Yes, taken care of.
- You two, follow me.
- OK.
Robbery!
He touched me up.
Don't get involved.
Hold up the banner.
Nobody's molesting you.
Hey, what a coincidence!
- How's the kid?
- Fine. What brings you here?
l'm looking for a fight.
- Where is Ma's money?
- l sent it.
You have?
Stop fighting!
Hit him!
Hit him! Hit him!
Go over there and kill him.
lt's none of our business.
Hold the banner. Higher.
- ls Chief lnspector Ho here?
- That's me.
So it's you. You piece of shit!
- Why are you two up to?
- We're meeting the ship.
Not any more. After him!
Don't let him get away!
- Can you see her?
- No.
Do you recognise her?
There are so many people.
- Do you recognise her?
- l only saw her photo. l don't know.
- Can you see her?
- No.
Can you see her?
Belle.
- Belle!
- Mum! Mum!
That's Belle, my daughter, up there.
l see my mother. She's down there.
OK, OK, let's go.
- Which one is she?
- l'm not sure.
My dear daughter, she's back.
- Where is she?
- l'm not sure.
- Which one is she?
- l don't know.
Can you see?
l heard Mr Wong is very rich.
Take plenty of photos.
- What's that about?
- l'm not sure.
- Boss, boss.
- Let him go. What's the matter?
Two reporters have come
to interview Wong.
Reporters?
- Tie them up.
- OK.
That's against the law.
- We're detectives.
- What are you doing here?
We're reporters.
We've come to interview Mr Wong.
- We'd like a word.
- But the passengers are coming.
- We're not asking.
- Come or take a voluntary holiday.
- Let's go!
- What are you doing?
Do l look all right?
You look fine.
Mum!
Belle!
Look, you did a good thing there.
This is just the beginning.
This is your stepfather.
- lntroduce us to your friends.
- Right.
This is Mr Wong Hsin-chuan.
- Mr Wong, we've heard about you.
- This is my son.
How are you?
Thank you for looking after Belle.
lt's she who looks after me.
lt's too noisy here.
Let's go back to the hotel.
And this is?
- This is her cousin.
- Right, right.
- An Uncle on my mother's side.
- Uncle.
- This is my wife.
- Auntie.
Mummy, you never mentioned
this cousin before.
He was the black sheep in the family.
Marriage changed all that.
Mr Wong, Mr Wong,
let's go back to the hotel.
l'm meeting other friends here.
l've told everyone
to go to the hotel.
Let's go.
- Uncle?!
- Why weren't you introduced?
l'll start the car.
lf you don't get a pay rise,
it could mean exploitation.
Exploitation makes you feel worthless
and that can lead to suicide.
Suicide means you're gone.
What do you think so far?
The missing reporters
are valuable employees.
l am your boss Laughton's old friend.
Stupid conjecture may lead
to yourjob disappearing!
l'm sorry, l just wanted to get
some background information on them.
Trying to put pressure on me.
l've a job to do.
Divide this.
- Miss Yang.
You're going to see the boat people
trying to sell...
lt's so hot.
Let me tell you something nice.
Watching them makes me very happy.
They want us...
Right. Tell Tong
to drive us around tomorrow.
You tell him.
He's your man. You tell him.
Have you finished?
He hopes we'll go easy on him.
But we've never been hard on him.
Hey, Tong,
take Mr Wong sightseeing tomorrow.
What about a boat trip?
Whatever! Just don't be seen.
Have you finished?
We've got business to discuss.
- Call lnspector Ho for me, please.
- Yes, sir.
Tomorrow we'll take a drive
to the Peak, and then the Gardens.
Don't forget the camera.
We'll have...
Don't walk about like that,
you're making me ill.
l want to.
Now don't forget.
The boat people who we left
asked us to entertain...
Mr Kuo, please.
Boss, the telephone.
You're using my shoe as an ashtray?
Mr Wong wants me to get
Chief lnspector Ho.
Where can l find
an lnspector Ho for him?
- What's wrong?
- l thought you'd fixed everything.
- ls that my call?
- Yes.
Fixed.
l'll go clean the car.
- Are Filipino maids popular here?
- lt's becoming fashionable.
They're hard to come by.
There is so little money.
Why should they have first choice?
Fei, you can take it, but we can't.
You've helped us for so many years.
We won't forget it, will we?
You can have anything you want.
Just say the word.
l thank you for your goodwill.
Have faith in me.
Better days are ahead. Let's go.
Let's go.
Where's Snake Ming?
He left without saying
where he was going.
- Have they found Wong?
- Not yet.
Who did you call?
My cousin,
he works for the shipping company.
He's checking the passenger list.
- lnspector.
- Where did you go?
The Five Continents Hotel,
Luk Kwok Hotel...
ls our Mr Wong at the Five Continents
or Luk Kwok?
- Neither.
- Then why did you go there?
Then later l found out
he was at King's.
Then why did you go
to the other places?
- l've got it.
- Got what?
Wong's already here,
so l'll check the hotel.
Who told you to check on Wong?
Find the reporters for me.
Why do l have to do everything?
l've never lied in my life.
l'm really scared.
We mustn't disappoint them.
Uncle, you're more than an hour late.
Tiger means business.
Do you think Tiger will trick us?
- Our boys will be watching.
- l have to get my lucky rose.
- Tiger's been waiting all morning.
- We'll invite him for lunch.
He wants to see you now.
l must get my rose first.
Boss.
A couple of Tiger's stooges.
They've got some nerve,
walking in here.
What's up?
- Our boss doesn't like waiting.
- So l'll invite him for dinner.
Freeze!
- Stay there!
- Come with us, Tiger's orders.
Look, guys...this is our turf.
l'll go with them.
You and the boys...
You dare make trouble here?
Tie them up!
l'll buy my rose,
then l'll see your boss.
Let's go.
Tiger will get you for this.
So you're planning
to issue stocks here?
That's the idea.
The door! When?
Very soon, l hope.
Gentlemen.
We're associates of Mr Wong's.
ls he in?
- Mr Wong is not here right now.
- We were told he was in his suite.
He's breakfasting right now.
- We're good friends of his.
- Long time associates.
Just the man. These are
Mr Wong's business associates.
- What now?
- l don't do anything illegal.
That's kidnapping.
- Close the door.
- How many have you tied up now?
You own a steel foundry as well?
Good morning, good morning.
You're very early today.
Mr Wong, is everything
to your liking?
Fine, very comfortable.
Mr Wong likes it here.
- ls everything OK, cousins?
- Of course.
Fresh roses. They're lovely.
A rose to bring you luck.
Why do you give him a rose?
Tradition, it's a family custom.
- A tradition.
- A family tradition.
- Wait! Come back down!
- Not so loud.
lnspector Ho is coming up
with two others.
Mr Kuo, an urgent call for you.
l'll take it there.
lnspector Ho is on his way up.
He's already in the lift.
What do we do now?
Cousin. Cousin.
He's calling you.
- You forgot our business deal.
- Today?
They're on the phone.
l'd completely forgotten about it.
He's so busy.
Give me some clothes.
lnspector Ho's on his way up.
This way. Take this.
And this.
Go on, follow him. lnside.
Mr Wong, sir.
Tell them l'll be home by noon.
Mr Wong, l'd recognise you anywhere.
You are sharp.
You must be the famous lnspector Ho.
At your service, sir.
Have you been that busy
you couldn't come to the dock?
Oh, but l was. Let me explain.
Come with me. l'm on my way out.
- Butler, that's all.
- Yes, sir.
- Who are they?
- My assistants.
They've gone.
That's that taken care of!
Tiger is on our backs
and you're still prancing about!
lt may not bother you,
but it bothers me.
You taught me to how to dress,
how to walk, how to talk,
how to negotiate, how to fight.
You treat me like a puppet.
Aren't you bothered about that?
He's right. The car.
- That's what you should be doing.
- That's what you think.
- What do you think you should do?
- What l'm doing right now.
- This makes you happy?
- Do l look happy?
- Continue with what you're doing.
- l will.
- Go on, then.
- l would if l knew what l was doing.
lmported goods are excellent here.
- Have you got any currency?
- Not yet.
- l'll lend you some.
- How kind.
- When are you floating your company?
- Soon.
He's worth a fortune.
He even owns a goldmine.
And the shipyard and the steelworks.
Go and find the reporters.
l'll handle this.
Mr Wong, how much
are the shares worth?
One dollar.
$2.80 once they're floated.
Double your selling price?
- There are no outside buyers.
- Can l buy some?
You're not an outsider, nephew.
Nephew, l'm one of them.
lnspector Ho, Chairman of
the planning committee, police club.
That's the police club.
l'm in charge of fundraising.
Nephew, your charitable deeds
are praiseworthy indeed.
- Very good, very good.
- Thank you.
Are you all right?
l'm just sighing.
lt's no use sighing.
You must enjoy life.
l'm sighing
because the club needs $80,000,
but we've only raised $15,000
in 3 years.
That's only about $60,000
short of the target.
After the stocks are issued,
l'll see what l can do to help.
Mr Wong... l'm sorry.
l know all it takes
is one word from you.
You're so clumsy.
My son will treat Belle well.
How can l say no to you?
Thank you for being my guide
for the day.
lt's nothing.
Make a note of what l bought.
l'll pay you back soon.
Consider it a deposit.
Deposit?
You promised to sell me some shares.
- Of course! Take these to my room.
- Yes, sir.
Shall we sign the papers upstairs?
No, let's say your office tomorrow.
The shares will be ready then.
Fine.
Mr Wong, l'll accompany you
to your room.
- There's no need.
- l insist.
l'd really like a cup of coffee
right now.
- Let's have a coffee, then.
- Fine.
- No coffee?
- l'd better go back to my room.
Back to your room.
Why don't you call the station?
- Call the station?
- ln case they're looking for you.
- lt's all right.
- Call to please me, then.
- l will.
- l'll wait here.
- l'll go to the ladies.
- l'll come.
- No, you go to your mother.
- OK.
- Why is he tagging along?
- He wants to.
- Don't let him.
- l'm doing my best.
Luming, let's go.
- What's up?
- lnspector Ho. Sort him out.
l'll be back soon.
Kwong-On Bank, please.
Uncle, why are you here?
Admiring the lights.
lnspector Ho, lnspector Ho.
- You?
- There's a fight outside.
Can't you see l'm busy?
But you are the inspector.
Don't you lecture me. Yes?
Kwong-On Bank? Go away!
Sorry, not you.
- They're still here. Are you busy?
- No.
Then join me.
Why is he here?
Think of something.
l couldn't find you earlier.
l have something to say.
Where's Chen Wah?
He's just gone to the restroom.
We can't leave yet. Come, come.
Sit down and speak slowly.
l've no time.
Floating in three months!
They didn't sell as well
as they thought? Thank you.
- Excuse me.
- One moment. Yes, sir?
- ls Mr Wong living here?
- Yes.
ls that...?
He's over there.
- A friend of yours?
- A small business matter.
Hey!
Nothing. l'm rich!
Finished work already?
Mr Kao has an easy life.
- Sit down for a chat.
- l'm still busy.
lnspector Ho? ls your eye better?
- Who are you?
- l hit you in the eye.
- You're confessing?
- Not exactly, l want your other eye.
Go, l'll chase you
to the ends of the Earth.
Stop, l'll get you!
What's the matter?
l think the gangsters are fighting.
l'll take my leave of you.
Have dinner with us tonight.
We'll be there.
l'm not going to talk business
any more. l'll stay and have tea.
- Don't bring them here for tea.
- lt's difficult to control them.
- You'd better stay here.
- Sit down again?
Take them to the room.
l'd prefer to stay
and have tea and stay for dinner too.
All right.
Mr Kuo, the press.
- How did they get in?
- Bribery, l suppose.
And that's why l came to Hong Kong.
ls that so?
A photo, if you don't mind?
Fine, fine.
- Mr Wong.
- Chen Wah, l'm glad you're here.
Come, let's have a group photo.
Everybody join in.
- A photo, Dad?
- This way.
Good. Altogether. Altogether.
Ready, set...
Thank you.
Auntie, come and sit down.
- A moment. What paper are you with?
- The Sun.
- When will it be published?
- Tomorrow.
Get the flower, then we can go.
- Good luck.
- You're very busy.
- Do you really believe that?
- lt's not a matter of belief.
Why haven't you introduced
your friend?
Why does he hide behind you?
He's shy. You must excuse me now.
- Chen Wah, l want to say something.
- What is it?
Madam Kao has consented
to a Shanghai wedding.
ln Shanghai! Congratulations!
Madam Kao, thank you
for your hospitality
and consent to this marriage.
You're very kind.
My trip is so brief
and l've missed so many people.
l suggest an engagement party
with all the Hong Kong dignitaries
and your friends.
What do you think?
- Chen Wah, what do you think?
- Me? l've no objection.
Then it's settled.
Good idea.
Kill two birds with one stone.
Mr Wong, please, excuse me.
Chen Wah, for an engagement in Hong
Kong, all the VlPs must be invited.
All right. You take care of it.
Did you get that?
Western style is more grand.
Eastern style is more relaxed.
Do your Chinese friends
outnumber foreign friends?
We have more Chinese
than foreign friends.
Cousin, cousin.
He's calling you.
Sorry, shall we discuss
the guest list?
Luming, come here.
We need to talk about it.
- Sorry.
- No, no, go.
Sit for a while.
Madam Kao, any other ideas?
Lots of foreign friends?
How are we to get VlPs to attend?
Nothing is impossible to you.
Thanks for the confidence.
Mr Wong is making such a big fuss
about everything.
lt's all your fault.
Simple, you said.
Just get a suite, buy some
new clothes, a little make-up.
lt's one thing after another.
Kidnapping reporters and businessmen.
Beating up police. This is a mess.
But you just said you were happy.
Shut up!
You started all this. Fix it!
lt's a bit late to start blaming me.
You helped Madam Kao as well.
- Helping people is a good thing.
- Correct.
- But you must know your limits!
- You're just making it worse!
You are all right.
lt's me that's wrong.
This is not a mistake.
lt is. l have too much sympathy,
but not enough ability.
Trying to help Madam Kao
perform miracles.
You're right. l don't measure up.
Please tell her we've done all
we can. l've no more to give.
At this stage?
- When should l tell her?
- You'll ruin the marriage.
- lmagine we never helped her.
- That's rich.
Yes, l'm getting out now.
l won't tell her, l'm not so cruel.
- You...
- l won't.
- Tell her.
- No.
l'll tell her, then.
Uncle.
Auntie, Dad.
- We're not interrupting?
- Not at all.
- What's the matter?
- Mum says you're very kind.
You are very big hearted, so...
So, we'd like you to be godfather
to our first baby.
- Godfather?
- You wouldn't refuse us?
We won't keep you any longer.
Auntie.
Bye-bye, Uncle.
Godfather, what an idea.
Get all the bosses
and their women to pose as VlPs.
Why are you staring?
ls it a bad idea?
lt's a good idea.
But they won't look the part.
Dress them up.
- l'll teach them etiquette.
- l'll do make-up.
- Go to work. l'll make some calls.
- Let's go.
Do you know what you're doing?
- What's up?
- He tried to run away.
Run away?
l can't cope. l just want to go home.
- How are you going to get there?
- By boat or train.
What about in a wheelchair?
l'm not going. l have work to do.
Let's go.
Everyone's assignment
is written here.
This is yours, remember it.
This is yours.
Take it easy.
l might be pregnant
and have to have an abortion.
You don't even know
who the father is. Stop fidgeting.
Please, you're ladies now.
You must be civil to each other.
She's always bad mouthing others.
She already has a gut,
and she's still eating.
Breathe in.
What are you looking at?
Straighten up. Remember your lines.
People! People!
Tong gave each of you
a piece of paper with your part.
Your name and what to say.
Remember your lines. Speak Mandarin.
Mr Wong is from Shanghai.
Don't start yet.
Just remember your part
and act like ladies and gentlemen.
Why should we?
He might be more vulgar than l am.
Who are you?
The Secretary of Education.
Education?
How could he be more vulgar than you?
- Why?
- That's why.
Your face doesn't fit the part.
Who's the Chief Warden?
Who's got that paper?
You're the Chief Warden.
Why didn't you reply?
l don't know. l can't read.
Can't read?! What do you mean?
All right, you be the warden
and you be the secretary.
- You must be crazy!
- What's the matter?
He felt me up.
Help me out here, be civilised.
lt was all a mistake.
- Bastard, molesting my bird!
- You dare to hit me?
Don't fight!
Let me go!
Stop it!
Stop acting like this!
Stop fighting!
Listen to me! Stop fighting!
Listen to me.
Aren't you tired
of all this fighting and killing?
This may be your only chance
in life to do a good deed.
You might not understand
why you have to help Madam Kao.
Just think - when you're old
and your children ask,
''Dad, what are your proudest
achievements in your life?''
What should you say?
Do you tell them you were a gangster,
opening brothels, casinos,
racketeering...
Does this make you proud?
This may be the only thing
you can tell them.
- Do you understand?
- No!
Tong, Tong!
l'm here!
l told you they weren't
to carry guns.
l did tell them.
Ask who else is carrying a gun!
Who's still got a gun?
Me!
Take all their guns away!
l told you not to and you still did.
''The Ritz''
Here's $5,000 from the Ho's
and $5,000 from me.
That's not too greedy, is it?
That's not greedy.
l'll give you the shares.
- Do you need to count it?
- No need.
Thank you.
When did the two reporters leave?
l went back to work.
l don't know when they left.
Sign here.
Mr Wong. Will there be anything else?
l'm going to a party tonight.
- Who's that?
- Mr Wong, the Shanghai magnate.
He's the multi-millionaire, Mr Wong?
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr Wong.
Thanks for looking out for me.
No need. You've been most attentive.
lf we don't look out for each other,
who will?
How much did we spend last time?
- Don't worry about it.
- l insist!
Here's $2,000 for your trouble.
- So much money?
- Keep it.
lt's chicken feed to me,
but it's a quite a bundle to you.
Remember, once the shares hit
two dollars, sell them.
- Double?
- Don't be too greedy.
l'll be rich.
l can't believe this bunch of paper
is so valuable.
lt's only paper.
Remember, these shares
are in high demand.
Don't tell anyone l gave them to you.
Remember, once they've doubled,
sell immediately.
l'm leaving now.
30,000 shares?
Mr Wong. Mr Wong, sir.
What about the police club?
Oh, that?
lt's a good thing
l have one cheque left.
Thanks very much, sir.
Spending more money.
There.
$80,000?
That's too much!
- lt's only $65,000.
- That was my last cheque.
The next time l'm in town,
l'll write you another.
l'll rip this one up.
No need, l'll give you the change.
Change?
Where are you going to get $15,000?
l have it.
Can you keep a secret?
l've got some evidence money.
l'll get it for you.
Mr Wong, there's $13,000.
Add my $2,000, that makes $15,000.
Nephew, you are so clever.
Thank you on behalf of the Ho's,
the police and myself.
Thank you, thank you.
Such small things,
unworthy of mention.
Let go.
Till we meet again.
Mr Wong, let me see you out.
There's no need.
Look after your shares.
Don't let anybody see them.
Remember, double.
Double.
Lucky me.
Hey, you, stop!
Me? What's the matter?
Don't move.
Watch him and don't let him go.
l'm a friend of lnspector Ho.
Some friend! Great! Watch him.
So that's that.
Chief lnspector Ho.
What have you been doing?
There are so many missing persons
and you haven't found any!
We've got some leads.
The gang who's doing the kidnapping
is different from the extortion gang.
- What's the difference?
- Well...
Commandant.
Chief lnspector.
- Why didn't you knock?
- lt's very urgent.
This discussion is very urgent.
We haven't received any ransom notes.
Fool! Even HQ has heard about this.
Find all the missing persons in three
days or one of us gets fired. See?
Get the car ready!
- Damn him!
- Chief lnspector!
Did you send men to the Ritz?
l did so, sir!
- Remember, you are responsible.
- Understood, sir.
ldiot!
lt's me.
- You come in without knocking again?
- lt's very urgent.
Urgent? Where have you been all day?
- l went to King's Hotel.
- l didn't tell you to go there.
But l found something out
about Mr Wong.
l tell you do one thing, you do
another. You disobey my orders.
- Hear me out first.
- You don't respect my authority.
But...
Why did you disobey my orders?
Don't you know my boss is after me?
- l know...
- Then why don't you go after them?
l am about to be fired -
and the rest of you, too.
Nobody is looking out for me.
Why are you here?
Obstructing justice.
That's a capital offence!
- ls that true?
- He's crazy.
Any leads on the missing persons?
- No, but we found Mr Wong...
- Nothing?
After all this time?
ldiot! And your mother
asked me to promote you!
Promote you to the heavens. What's
this about Mr Wong, then? Speak!
l found out he's not
one of Shanghai's ten richest men.
He isn't. l suppose you are.
Do you look the part?
Just say who he is. Go on! Go on!
'Bastard!'
Not only is he
one of Shanghai's richest men,
but he's one of the richest men
in all China!
Well done, well done,
that's very good indeed.
l don't need you to tell me that!
Get out!
'l must get away.'
Chief lnspector.
- You still didn't knock?
- Can l take some holiday?
- Holiday?
- Mother is sick.
- ls you father sick, too?
- No.
Get out! Don't ever come back!
- You look down. Was it that bad?
- l'm going on holiday.
Be smart, like me.
l've got some new leads.
Work hard and you'll get there.
Mr Wong, you're still here?
- l'll just see him off.
- Take Mr Wong back to the hotel.
l will, l will. l'll take him
wherever he wants to go.
Bye-bye, Mr Wong. Walk carefully.
Where are you taking me?
l know where l'm going.
l don't know about you.
Chief lnspector!
- Why does nobody knock any more?
- Sorry Chief.
l saw Kuo's men with guns
at the Ritz. Something's up.
Who are they?
Thieves, criminals,
all those on our wanted list.
Then why did you leave?
Get some men over there
and arrest them!
l'll get the warrant.
Why are you standing there?
Give me my hat.
What are you all staring at?
Follow us.
And that's the truth?
Yes. Apparently,
their people are at the Ritz.
What about the two boys we sent?
No news whatsoever.
lt backs up what l said.
Kuo did take two of your men.
Why are you doing this?
l just want the killings to stop.
One, two, three, bow.
That was great.
This is a dress rehearsal.
Luming will be Wong.
Make an effort.
l'm Mr Wong. And you are?
l'm Miss Foxy,
the Rotary Chair person.
You're Miss Fox, the Rotary Chair
person. What is this Foxy?
That was my Mandarin.
Stick to Cantonese.
- l'm Mr Wong, and you are?
- l'm the Governor of Hong Kong.
You're not the Governor, you're
the Minister for Transportation.
l want to be Governor.
Why?
lf he's Police Commissioner,
l've got to be Governor.
l must be Governor.
Don't take it so seriously.
l must outrank him. l'm the Governor.
He insists on being Governor.
Fine! Let him be Governor, then.
- Run through it again.
- One more time. Please, cooperate.
Boss, Mrs Shun wants to see you.
Once again. One, two, three and bow.
Boss, the police
have surrounded the place.
- Right outside?
- Yes.
What is it?
- The police have us surrounded.
- Police? How come?
They're waiting for lnspector Ho
to come with a warrant.
He must think
we're starting a gang war.
We can't leave and Madam Kao
is waiting. lt's nearly time.
Oh, dear,
we'll be found out for sure.
This is bad.
The poor woman.
- What shall we do?
- Search me.
- He's the boss.
Come on, think!
What shall we do?
l'll go to the courthouse
to get lnspector Ho.
- You can't go out. What can you do?
- l don't know.
We'll have to play it by ear.
l'll go out the back way.
- What are you doing?
- The drinks.
Forget that. Go up and practise.
Tell Uncle l'm going to court.
l'll contact him when l meet Ho.
Tell him to wait for me.
Move on.
What are you doing there?
- What should we do?
- Ring Fei.
Push harder.
The boys must be looking for me.
Thanks.
He's gone to the courthouse
to get Ho.
- All set?
- Yeah, we know what to do.
What's that?
They found the bodies of your men.
Kuo had them killed.
He killed my men?
Where is he? What's he up to?
He's gone to get lnspector Ho.
For what purpose?
Maybe he's working with the police.
Damn it! Let's go!
l've got to leave now.
l'll look your boss up after this.
- What now?
- l'm hungry.
- Me, too.
- Let's go.
l can't find him anywhere.
There he is. Let's go!
- My leg!
- My hand!
- You broke my pots! Pay up...
- Damn you!
Hold it! Don't run!
We've got you now.
Get ready.
The guests will be here soon.
Make sure there are enough drinks.
l'll see to it. Relax.
Problems?
No, they're rehearsing the entrance.
There's plenty of time. Don't worry.
- Where is he?
- Up there.
- Get him down.
- Bring him down.
Tiger, sorry
for not having tea with you.
Damn it! l liked you.
l promise to have tea with you,
but you've got to let me go now.
lt's very urgent.
Let you go? l sent two boys
to invite you to tea.
- You killed them. Why?
- l didn't. l set them free.
Where's my gun?
Didn't you hear what l said? l didn't
kill them. They'll be back soon.
Brother Fei, tell him
l didn't kill them.
But you did.
The bodies have been found.
That's impossible.
Tiger, don't believe him. He's evil.
He's making fools of us both.
He never liked me anyway.
They'll be back soon, believe me.
Where are they, then?
- They must be on their way back.
- To avenge their deaths?
Damn it, don't string me along!
Tiger, believe me.
l didn't kill them!
Tiger! Tiger!
Can you kill me later? l've got
urgent business to attend to.
Shut up! l'll kill you now.
Here they are.
l told you l didn't kill them.
- Why aren't you two dead already?
- Not yet. He saved us.
- He set us free.
- Damn it, you scared me.
Tiger, l told you
l didn't lie to you.
So, you creep,
you want to be the boss?
Tiger, l did it for you.
l would make a much better boss.
There's no way you could be better!
Release him!
Take it easy!
Tiger, l hope you understand.
l did this for your own good.
From now on,
keep out of our family affairs.
Your family affairs! No problem.
l got him. Stop him if you can.
Tiger, l will certainly
have tea with you.
Brother Fei, as you pointed out,
this is a family affair.
Let's go and sort it out.
l've got urgent business, excuse me.
Don't think
you're going to leave here alive.
Tiger.
l won't interfere, but rules are
rules. l'll keep the guns for you.
Canton kid, have no fear.
l'll make sure there's no foul play.
But l might be dead by then.
Get him and the factory is yours.
Get him!
Out of the way!
Brother, you're good.
Stop. l've got to go.
Can we finish this later?
Grab him.
He's over there!
Pull the rope.
Thank you, Buddha!
Don'tjump!
l told you not to.
Stop fighting!
Don't go away. lt's your turn now.
You were great.
Brother Chen Wah.
You've done one thing right,
the factory hands are behind you.
You can have the factory
and we can be family again.
- Thank you, Chen Wah.
- l've got to go now.
Canton kid, l really admire you.
Your family affair is settled.
We've done our bit. Let's be friends.
l don't have time.
Still thinking of the beating
l gave you? Hit me back, then.
Go on, don't be afraid.
- Stand back!
- Don't move!
Great fistwork.
Canton kid, you fight really well.
Now, go on, slap me.
Good friends we shall be.
Friend, l've got to go now,
urgent business.
lf anything happens, count me in.
Count your ass.
What's the hurry?
Shandong man, lend me your car.
- What?
- l'm borrowing your car.
- How was that?
- Perfect, just right.
Chief lnspector, you're wanted.
lnspector Ho.
Go out and keep watch.
lnspector, take your men away.
lnspector, please...
How did you get out?
- lnspector...
- Stand up!
lnspector Ho, please, remove them.
We're doing a good thing at the Ritz.
Putting you lot away
is the good thing.
What are you doing here?
l told you to find the missing men.
Sir...
The Attorney General
just chewed my ass!
From now on, your only job
is to find the missing persons
or you'll go missing!
l know the whereabouts
of the missing persons.
- Who's this?
- The owner of the Ritz.
ls that true?
Four reporters, two businessmen,
right?
Yes, this is why l brought him
to see you.
Follow me.
You too.
The missing persons' case is most
urgent, we must deal with it first.
Order them to search the Ritz.
No, they're getting ready
for Madam Kao's party.
lt's an order.
The missing are not in the Ritz.
Where are they?
Free my friends and l'll tell you.
First let me make a call.
- l can't...
- lf l don't, they won't free them.
Things could get ugly.
- All right, make your call.
- Thank you.
- Hello?
- Luming.
- Tell Uncle to release them.
- The reporters?
Tell Madam Kao we can't come.
Tell the brothers it's all off.
What now? What now?
One more time. Make it better.
There's no need.
Everything's cancelled.
- Why did you kidnap them?
- To keep the secret.
- The secret of your crimes?
- Hold your tongue!
- What secret?
- A lady's secret.
What has she to do with you?
Nothing, really. l just
buy a rose from her every day.
l know nobody will believe me.
We believe you, but we don't
understand the kidnapping.
That's exactly why.
You won't understand.
You see, her daughter has a rich
boyfriend, they've just graduated.
They're getting married here.
This scared the mother,
so she lied about her background.
She's got a heart of gold
and would never lie.
When l arrived in Hong Kong,
she told me to be careful.
A conman had already taken my last
cent. l bought a rose for luck.
You ladies will understand the love
between a mother and her daughter.
So l kidnapped the men,
but they're OK.
l just wanted to help
keep her secret.
- You don't understand, do you?
- Not a word.
We don't know what you're saying.
All right, l'll speak more slowly.
There once was a young flower girl.
No, an old flower lady.
She has a daughter, and...
Dad, the guest...
Sorry, l'll see to Madam Kao.
Why aren't the guests here yet?
The car behind us broke down
and caused an almighty traffic jam.
That's why. They're on their way.
Sorry, we did our best.
l know what l must do.
How do we get out of this mess?
Did you say something?
Mr and Mrs Kao,
what's this all about?
l think...
by now...
you must have realised
something was wrong.
Mum, what's happened?
Everything has a solution.
l know you came to Hong Kong
to look into Belle's background.
You have good reasons for doing so.
Guests or no guests,
we can still have a good time.
Let's go out for some food.
- Come on.
- Let me finish.
Mr Wong.
l hope you appreciate the fact...
that Belle is extremely
important to me.
To make things easier for her...
l've done things
l never dreamed of doing.
Mum, don't be like that.
Tell us everything.
We'll sort it out.
l understand now.
Whatever you do...
you get what you deserve
in this life.
Madam, if it's about the guests,
sorry for the trouble.
l didn't realise it would upset you.
lt's not that.
l wish...
my being Madam Kao...
lf what you're saying has nothing
to do with the wedding,
there's no need to say it.
Mum, l want you to know
l love Belle whatever happens.
That makes it even more important
for me to say it.
l want you all to know...
l want you all to understand...
Music, music!
- l am not...
- The guests are here!
King's Councillor and Mrs Lo.
Commander of the Volunteers
and Mrs Wong.
Magistrate and Mrs Benjamin.
We meet again.
Marine Commander and Mrs Gordon.
Police Commissioner and Mrs Laughton.
Head of the Boy Scouts McGeorge.
- Attorney General and Mrs Stevens.
- Congratulations.
Chairman of the Jockey Club,
General Morse.
President of the Lions Club,
Mr Chan.
Justice of the Peace and Mrs Chow.
President of the Rotary Club
and Mrs Lee.
Supreme Court Judge and Mrs Nelson.
Railways Director and Mrs Watson.
Postmaster General and Mrs Nitton.
Why are you dressed like that?
The Attorney General lent it to me.
How did you get them to come?
l told them we'd be finished
without them.
Chancellor of the Exchequer
and Mrs Harrison.
Director of Waterworks
and Mrs Johnston.
Public Works Director and Mrs Pearce.
The Chairman of the East lndia Co
and Mrs Banks.
What a happy night.
You finally did something good
on your own.
l wanted to do it, like everyone
else, but l didn't have the guts.
Why are you crying?
l'm going to the toilet.
Stop crying,
you'll ruin your make-up.
Do l look ugly?
Quick! The ship's about to sail.
''Former Chief lnspector Wanted
for Embezzlement of Police Funds''
You bastard!
Come and see me in Malaysia,
if you dare!
You finally did a good deed.
You played your part.
Come back any time!
Subtitles by
European Captioning lnstitute