Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Tap out, tap out!
Bit in the head.
Get it, three, two, one, go.
Freeze now!
Hey, let me see your hands!
On the ground, on the ground,
on your faces right now!
Tex, Biggs!
What you got, what you
be still fighting, huh?
Get down!
We're not with him!
We don't even know him!
They just hired us,
they just hired us
for some stupid dance wrestling.
Sir, just let us go.
We just met them
today, I swear.
Get your stuff and get out.
Keep your hands
right up there, boy!
Get out!
- Tex.
- One locked door.
All right listen up in there!
You do not wanna
take a shot at me.
I am heavily armed
and I will turn this place
into the O.K. Corral!
Speak up!
I got a nine, I'm
putting it down.
Hands, hands, hands!
Behind your neck.
Behind your neck,
behind your neck.
Take him to the front
with the others.
Should I
call Detroit PD, sir?
No, not yet.
I know a woman in the suburbs
who runs a no kill shelter.
Get the dogs out of here first
then we call PD.
Hoo rah.
Get his ass up.
You stole a dog.
A rich man's dog.
Rich men don't like
having their dog stolen.
Paid us good money
to track you down.
I'll give it back.
Yeah you will.
You definitely will.
But there's a price
you gotta pay.
See I don't like dog fighters.
You like dog fighters, Tex?
I do not.
Biggs, hold my weapon.
Just so you can never say
that I sucker punched you.
I'm about to beat your ass.
Come on, Cap.
Showed him that.
Just like I taught
him when he was a boy.
Yeah just like
you taught me, sir.
Listen,
I want the names
and addresses of every
single dog fighter
in every house in this city.
You're not a cop.
Oh no.
Tex, we got any coke in the car?
- A whole lot of it.
- Yeah, bring it in.
Bring in enough for
a life sentence.
Ooh, let's get some horses in
the background.
Oh my gosh, we have to have
the horse in the background.
The horse in this one.
- Cheese.
- Yes!
That was perfect.
Keep it balanced.
Very good, very good.
Smile, birthday girl.
Yeah, you wanna look
good for your boyfriend.
Bombshell shot.
Stop, he's not my boyfriend.
I've never even met him.
Love at first sight.
Don't worry, Joanna,
I'll have her home by six.
Promise.
Not worried at all,
I'm just glad you could take
the girls to the stables.
I think she's a natural.
Allison's been
wanting that for years.
So, how goes the
surprise party planning?
Well, since you were able
to get them out of the house,
I was able to make some calls.
It's gonna be fun.
Okay, I'll see you in a bit.
Time to dehorse your daughter.
bye.
Great job, Allison.
Sarah, you're up.
He's a hottie.
Cheating on Tyler already.
I'm turning 16 tomorrow
so I'm not gonna be
this young forever.
Afternoon, John.
Maggie.
How'd it go, Captain?
Everybody gather
around the table.
Aaron, you joining us?
No.
All right, Detroit PD
called every single one
of those animal abusers.
Well done, team.
Hey Captain, don't forget.
You bird dogged those
losers for six weeks now.
We all thought it was gonna
be a dead end, remember?
Sixth sense, I was
thinking like a dog.
All right, I also
hooked Detroit PD
into two other dog
rings, both local.
Okay, all the names, phone
numbers, addresses, everything.
So that's big, well done, guys.
All right.
And, our employer
gave us a nice fat tip
so it's steak dinners on me.
Hey, you want
me to do the drive
to Cleveland tomorrow
on that Simpson matter?
Now that the dog case
is closed and all?
I can handle it, John.
I don't mean any disrespect.
Well it is disrespectful.
But my case is closed.
So you think you
should take my case?
I think there's a missing
boy and I'm available.
John, I can handle it.
That's why I hired you, Karen.
Tex, you'll get lead on
another case real soon.
Hey, you give the
orders, I just follow.
What are we at now, 90 hours?
96.
Aaron, how we doing?
Hey yo pencil neck, the
lady's talking to you.
Oh that's hysterical.
You must be the funniest
guy in your GED program.
Boy, I'm educated
in all kind of stuff
that you don't
know nothin' about.
Anything about.
Obviously English is not
one of your strong suits.
Well I tell you
what, I'm educated
in Greco-Roman wrestling
and western boxing.
So how you like that, chump?
Boys, I don't want any
of that in this office,
do you hear me?
It leads to arguing.
Arguing leads to cussing
and cussing leads to blasphemy.
Yes, ma'am.
Good.
Aaron, how we doing
on finding that boy?
I cracked all of his
passwords fast enough.
I thought I had a lead that
would send us straight to him
but it didn't pan out.
Had to widen the gap.
Need more time.
How long have you
been on that computer?
17 hours.
Hey, you need
dinner and some sleep.
I've got frozen
pizzas in the fridge.
And a lot of soda.
I can lock in and go 72
hours when I have to.
Go to dinner.
I'll tell you meatheads what
door to kick down soon enough.
Well dinner's on you, boss.
I already said that.
Yeah, just getting
it for the record.
Well, let's do it.
Hey yo, pencil neck.
You doing all right, 'cuz.
My man.
Allison has a boyfriend.
Really?
Grow up.
Honey, do you think
you could enjoy dinner
without texting for
- 10 minutes?
- Mom!
Hang on a sec.
Oh, yeah, I'm hanging.
Listen to your mother.
You can continue your love
affair after dinner, okay?
Oh sure, Dad speaks
and you listen.
I ask nicely and
it's "Hang on a sec."
He's the man.
Ooh.
Who teaches them
this kind of stuff?
We have a progressive home.
How'd these teenage girls
succumb to these norms?
You know, I just
think Rachel's jelly
because she doesn't
have a boyfriend.
Mhmm, and she's too young.
Whatever.
I don't wanna date
some middle school boy.
Next year I'll be a freshman
and I'll get a football
playing senior.
Oh, fantastic.
Hey, Tyler.
Hey beautiful.
I thought you'd never be online.
I miss you.
We just
talked last night, silly.
I wanna
meet you so bad.
Me too.
Meet me tonight.
I have
school tomorrow.
Just for a little bit.
I promise I'll be good.
Tyler?
Hey.
Hi.
Where are we going?
You'll see.
No please!
Keep moving!
Stop, no.
No, no!
Stop!
Shut up.
Y'all hoes get
back in your cages.
Please let me go.
Please let me go!
I own you now.
And you ain't never
going nowhere.
Honey, can you
go tell your sister
that breakfast is almost ready?
Hold on, let me post
something real quick.
Now, young lady, please.
Hey, breakfast is almost done.
Ah, just coffee for
me, hon, I gotta run.
But you missed it yesterday.
Oh, I gotta close
this deal, babe.
We need the money.
That's true.
All right, do you have
time for a good luck kiss?
Always.
Allison?
She isn't there, Mom.
What?
No, it's still early.
Come on, Joanna,
it's her birthday.
She just probably snuck out
early to be with friends.
Sweet 16, big day.
You remember what that was like.
Yes, 100 years ago.
Wish me luck, old girl.
All right, old man.
Y'all did good last night.
Thank you, Daddy.
Now y'all have some candy
and get you a good sleep.
Don't put you in no cages.
You gonna come back
and see me later?
Oh yeah, baby girl.
Just gotta break in this
new girl right quick.
Let one of the
other guys do it.
Bitch, shut up
telling me my business.
Lucky I don't beat your ass.
Just take your candy
and go to sleep.
Maybe tomorrow I don't
give you no candy.
You feel me?
No, please!
Bitch shut up and
get in your cage!
First day of school, white girl.
This is moi weird.
She hasn't texted me all day.
Same here.
You think she's playing sick?
On her birthday, no,
that would be social suicide.
Ugh, my phone is vibrating.
Who calls anyone anymore?
OMG, it's her mom.
Should I answer it?
Um, yeah.
Hi, Mrs. R, is Allison okay?
Not a peepster.
Copy that.
That girl is MIA.
Man, you right about her.
Dude, she gonna make us
a lot of money for real.
I'm about to go again.
No.
What?
Go get you one
them other hoes.
What?
You heard what I said.
Man, come on, for real?
Come on.
Do that thing that
you know I like.
Please.
Please, Mister.
If you let me go home,
I promise I won't tell anyone.
My name is Daddy, not Mister.
Daddy.
And you ain't never
going nowhere.
Have some candy.
Make you feel better.
Rose, it's not like her.
Not a single text.
Well, she's 16 today.
Maybe she's with
her new boyfriend.
What new boyfriend?
Tyler.
I saw a picture
of him yesterday.
Cute kid.
She never told me.
Well, you're her mother, J.
It's a teenager's
first prerogative
to keep stuff from
parental units.
Hello?
Hey hon, I just
sold the Miller place.
Done deal.
Case, Allison's missing.
What do
you mean missing?
I mean I haven't heard
a single text from her,
none of her friends
have heard from her
and I'm scared.
Honey,
it's her sweet 16.
She's out with her friends.
Look, just calm down.
I'll be home in 10 minutes.
Betcha she walks
through that door
any minute with that new boy.
If I win, you're in to
me for martinis at Al's.
That's a bet I'd gladly lose.
Look, why don't we
give her another hour?
No.
Joanna, try to relax, dear.
I can't, Mom, my
daughter's missing.
We don't know that yet.
I can feel it in my heart,
something's terribly wrong.
All her best friends are here,
she didn't go to school.
No text, no post, nothing.
I hope she's okay.
Okay.
I'll make the call.
Okay folks, I'm sorry.
Obviously Allison has
been missing all day.
My wife's a little upset so
I think we're gonna
call it an evening.
Thanks so much for coming out.
We'll reschedule all of this.
But thanks, thanks so much.
Yeah, right inside there.
It'll be okay, Mrs. R.
Allison can be a
bit crazy sometimes.
She'll be home soon.
And she hasn't called all day?
That's right.
No emails, no texts.
Nothing, just silence.
She have a boyfriend?
Well I heard this
morning that she does.
What?
And how did you
learn about this?
Does it matter?
Joanna, let's just answer
the questions please.
I heard from my best friend
who happens to be her
best friend's mother.
Do you have
the boyfriend's number?
No, like I said,
I just found out
that she has a boyfriend.
I don't know anything.
Can we do something
more proactive?
Do you know
the boy's name, ma'am?
Trent or Trevor or something.
We can call Rose and ask her.
Well Mrs.
Riley, your daughter
hasn't been missing
a full day yet.
Is it possible she's
off with this Trevor,
Trent, Thomas guy and they're
off partying someplace?
And you know, just being kids?
No, it isn't.
Joanna.
What?
Yes, it's possible, officers.
Look, whose side are you on?
There aren't any
sides here, Jo.
Your daughter
has run away before, Ma'am.
No, my daughter's
never run away.
Two years ago, you filed
a missing persons report-
- No, she was at a sleepover
and she came home
the next morning.
So we'll just
give it a little time.
Look, my daughter's missing!
I know her.
There's something terribly wrong
and you guys are
just sitting there!
What do you guys
suggest we do?
Just give
it a little time, sir.
These things, they normally
work themselves out.
And if they don't?
If she's still
missing after 48 hours,
give us a call.
We'll come back,
we'll file a report.
Try to get the boyfriend's name,
see if you can track
down his phone number.
- Can you do that?
- Mhmm.
They should be
easy enough for us to find.
All right guys,
thanks for coming out.
Our pleasure, sir.
- Good night, ma'am.
- Something's wrong.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
I'm gonna ground that girl for a
week when she gets back.
Don't you mean if
she shows up, Case?
She hasn't texted
me either, Mom.
Case, she's missing.
All right.
Don't scare her.
You're just standing there!
Rachel, go to bed.
But I...
Now.
Scoot.
Okay.
I'm gonna check all
the hospitals, okay?
You keep calling her friends.
Okay if we don't
find her tonight
I'll call Mike and Justin
and first thing in the morning
we'll jump in our cars,
we'll check out all the places
where the kids hang out.
Yeah.
Tomorrow's Saturday.
We'll look all
weekend if we have to.
We'll track down this Trevor guy
who I'm going to
kill by the way.
Listen, Allison will
be back in our house
by Sunday at the latest.
Okay?
Oh.
Mom.
Aight, bitches.
Grab your coats and let's go.
Hurry up, we got paying
customers in there.
It's work time now, girl.
I suppose you're
thinking about running.
Maybe you're thinking
about asking one of them
nice white boys for help.
Or doing something stupid
like calling the police.
Don't.
You see this?
That your sister, right?
You mess with me and she next.
No, please.
Oh she pretty too.
I'll be good.
You're in room 45.
I'll be out here the whole time.
You got me
and I got my nine.
I got you, now.
Ain't nobody gonna
hurt you, girl.
Take this.
Go on now.
I'll be right here.
Now what?
Well, we go out
again tomorrow.
And if 48 hours goes by,
we call the cops again
and file a missing
persons report.
And um...
And what?
Nothing.
No, don't do
that, not right now.
All right.
I called Kessler.
Oh god.
Who's Kessler?
Case's idiot
friend from college.
He's a loser.
He's actually
quite successful.
He's a professional poker
player and he sells weed.
He's one of those guys with a
22 year old bimbo girlfriend.
Is any of that
relevant, Joanna?
He knows people.
Really?
Who does he know, huh?
Who does your pothead
poker playing friend know?
Never mind.
I didn't wanna get into it.
Just tell me who he knows.
Belton Private Investigators.
Kessler says this PI,
John Belton and his crew
will find Allison or die trying.
John.
You can't save every one of 'em.
Sorry, guys.
It wasn't your fault.
You tracked the kid
down, you found him.
That's your job.
I couldn't have done any better.
All we can do is get
back on that horse, boss.
Belton Private Investigators.
John Belton speaking.
All right, Mr. Riley.
How long has she been missing?
Have you called the police?
No, no, no, tomorrow
might be too late, okay?
I'm sending my to investigator
out to speak to you.
We'll conference on the speaker.
Can I have your address please?
Yes, sir.
Clock's ticking.
Hey, she
broke in well tonight.
Have a seat, ladies.
Honey, you done good.
I know the first time's
always the toughest.
Daddy?
Huh, baby?
Am I still your favorite?
You is.
You all is.
John, she's 16.
Blonde, 5'3, photos
are on the way.
Okay, got it.
Listen, Mr. And Mrs. Riley,
the police won't consider
this a missing persons issue
until 48 hours has elapsed.
That means that if your
daughter does not return
you will fill out the
necessary police report.
Okay, got it.
All right, Tex, go
up to the girl's room.
Toss it.
Mr. And Mrs. Riley, he's gonna
look for another cell phone,
iPad, laptop, and
address book, a journal,
anything like that.
I'm on it, boss.
I'll show you.
Mrs. Riley.
We're gonna do this
by the numbers, ma'am.
Okay, my team and I
are gonna question
everyone that Allison knows.
You're in very good hands.
Thank you, Mr. Belton.
And call me John, please.
I hope this doesn't happen
but we may be together
for a little while.
Well then no more Mrs. Riley.
It's Joanna and Case.
Okay, Joanna.
Now I know the police may
have asked you this before
but does your daughter
have any issues
with drugs or alcohol?
No.
You're sure?
Yeah, I mean I may have
missed with the boyfriend part
but I know her really well.
She's not into that.
Okay.
Any past psychological
issues, ADD,
depression, anything like that?
No, not at all,
she's a great girl.
She's a sweetheart,
she's an angel, John.
I'm sure she is, Joanna
and we are gonna
find your angel.
Do you promise?
I promise.
She will be found.
Laptop, old cellphone.
I'm sorry, what
was your name again?
That is Aaron.
Write down the
name of her horse.
Any other pets, middle
name, best friends' names,
favorite colors,
favorite numbers,
celebrity crushes,
birthday, favorite holiday
and everything else
that you can think of.
Hey, he'll have her
passwords in 15 minutes.
Me, I can barely find the
speaker button on my phone.
How do you take your coffee?
Hot.
Look, we're gonna
find your daughter.
This is what we do.
John.
How much is this gonna cost us?
We're middle class.
We're not rich.
There's a standard
commencement retainer
of 20,000 tonight.
Even if she walks in that
door 10 minutes from now
on her own.
Whoah.
Fine.
And then it's 20k
a week after that.
John, I don't know.
Case.
I'm just trying to
be practical, honey.
We're talking about the
girls' college funds here.
We don't need college if
we don't have our daughter.
Maybe we should
just think about it.
Let the police try.
Look, sir.
I'm not trying to
sell you on this,
but the police, they're
just not gonna do anything.
That's just the long
and short of it.
Yeah, maybe she's
with this boyfriend.
Are you sure?
No.
I'm not sure of anything now.
And that is the hell of it.
Maybe Allison is doing a
Juliet thing with her guy.
But then again maybe not.
Can we just have
time to think about it?
Honestly sir,
every minute counts
and we are on the clock.
You want us to
find your daughter
we need to start right now.
I'll pay for it.
Mom, your retirement.
How can I retire
without my granddaughter?
Barbara, we can't accept.
You don't have to accept.
Mr. Belton, you're hired.
Computer nerd, keep
doing what you're doing.
You, Cowboy, get
me the paperwork.
Yes ma'am.
You'll have your
money wired to you
as soon as the bank
opens tomorrow morning.
Find my granddaughter!
I will.
Mom.
Where are you, pretty girl?
I just hope it's not
where I'm afraid you are.
Well, did you enjoy
church today, baby?
It was cool.
You're such a nice boy.
You pick your grandma up,
you take me to church.
It ain't no thing.
The Lord was good giving
me a grandchild like you.
I told you, I got you, Grams.
All right, honey.
Yo Grams.
I put a little something
in your purse for you.
Oh, no, child!
I can't take no money from you.
I'll see you next week.
Go on in there now.
Bye.
Drive careful.
Okay.
Our mission is one Allison
Riley, age 16 as of Friday.
Now missing for almost 48 hours,
she'll be an official
missing person as of tonight.
Sweet little thing.
No call from the
parents this morning?
No, not so far.
I am working on the supposition
that she is a taken.
I'm betting I would say
she's with the boyfriend.
Yeah, yeah, I know that but
I just don't think so.
That damn nose of
yours again, boss?
It's a curse, but yeah.
I got a bad feeling on this one.
Aaron, tell them what you know.
Her boyfriend Tyler is
a typical catfish profile.
Tyler is actually Ryan Mcnaff.
Professional model out of LA.
All the photos were taken
from his various sites.
The cellphone that was
used to text Allison
went dark at 11:05
p.m. Friday night.
And I presume it'll
never be turned on again.
Trace down Tyler's cellphone.
I'm guessing it's
prepaid with cash.
We might get lucky.
Okay, Karen, get in touch
with this Ryan Mcnaff
out in California.
The odds are overwhelming
that he has no idea
any of this is going on.
But make him prove to you that
he was in L.A. this weekend.
Will do.
All right, Maggie.
The Rileys go to
church at Vineyard.
And they have a lot
of friends there.
Yeah, I know it.
It's a nice place.
All right, good.
Well then make inquiries as
only you can, church lady.
Oh, getting paid
to go to church.
The Lord is good.
Mhmm.
All right Ben, hit the
high school tomorrow.
See if you can get her
friends to tell you things
that they won't
tell their parents.
So you're telling me to
hit on high school girls?
I'm telling you to
go there, be charming
and then leave.
Man, I want a case
at a college campus.
Yeah, I bet you do.
Biggs, head down to
the usual hotspots.
See if you can get any
chatter out of the community.
I'ma be working the
homies all day, Captain.
Karen, when you're done
with that model in L.A.,
hit up the various shops
and the street corners.
See if the working
girls know anything.
Why do I always
get hooker detail?
What are we gonna
do, put heels on Ben now?
Rookie.
All right, Ben, you
actually go with her.
Hang back but not too far.
Her safety is
number one, got it?
Yes sir.
Now guys, if our little
girl here is a taken,
every minute is an enemy.
Okay, we're on the
clock, let's do this.
Come on.
Well, our brothers
and sisters in Christ,
the Riley family are going
through a tough time right now.
Many of you know that Allison's
been missing for some time.
And we wanna pray for
God's healing and comfort
to come in their lives
during this difficult season.
So let's pray.
Jesus, we ask that
you would be with our
brothers and sisters.
We pray that you
would comfort them
during this difficult season.
And we pray that you would
help to bring recovery
for this young
woman who's missing.
We pray Lord that
justice would come
into this situation.
Would you help and
bless and comfort
and encourage this family,
and help us Lord to be a
blessing of support to them.
In your name we pray, amen.
What's up, big man?
Looking for a girl, cuz.
Girl?
You gotta tell me
what you want, man.
White girl, about 16.
Man.
Oh she cute though.
See that?
She cool, bro.
Yeah she nice.
Yeah, she bangin, man.
She a ho?
Might be.
A brother remember
a girl like that.
Suburban girl.
Suburban girl, of
course, of course.
Yeah, that's why you be down
here slumming with us huh?
That's why you be down
here all the time.
Her daddy must be rich, huh?
Huh, yeah, that's right.
Hey, spread some of
that love around here.
Share the wealth.
Tell me where the girl at,
then you get paid, aight?
I'll give you five Gs
you tell me where she at.
I'll give you 10 Gs you
bring her to me, aight?
All right man, I got your
phone.
It's got to be verified,
aight?
I got your phone.
Aight, aight, aight, make
it happen for me, baby aight?
The Detective handling this
matter will be Jack Carson.
He's a good man, he
walked a beat in his day.
That's fine.
Yeah we hired a
private investigator too.
Well that may have
been premature, sir.
We didn't think so.
Do you mind if I
asked who you engaged?
John Belton.
What?
He seemed very professional.
Professional?
Officer
Helsdon, just..
Wait, what about him?
Well, he, let's just say
he likes to work
outside the box.
He's not exactly orthodox.
We'll that sounds
exactly like what we need.
We're gonna find your
daughter, Mrs. Riley.
Now having John Belton talking
to the same people we are
is only gonna get in our way.
Unbelievable,
unbelievable.
Case, what is that?
What's what?
That thing on your hip.
It's a gun, Barbara.
Please don't ask me
rhetorical questions.
I don't have the energy for it.
Why are you wearing it?
Case.
Because the second
amendment says I can
so I am.
Can we just leave it
at that and drop it?
We're not gun people.
Well I just became gun people.
Do you have any
idea how many gun-related deaths
there are in the US alone?
Barbara, this
is not just some debate
at one of your
liberal arts colleges.
My daughter's missing.
My
granddaughter is missing.
Don't take that tone with me!
Case.
You have to see this.
What?
Captain John Belton,
US Marine Corps,
dishonorable discharge.
Says here he disobeyed
a direct order
in the line of combat.
He's been in and out of rehab
for alcoholism three times!
No wonder why your
friend Kessler knows him.
None of that matters, Jo.
He's looking for Allison.
Is he?
Or is he just drinking
away my money in some bar?
Stay out of this, Barbara.
Don't you tell me
to stay out of this.
I'm paying the
bills around here.
And strutting around
like John Wayne
isn't doing anybody any good.
Why would we trust
your friend Kessler, why?
How the hell was
I supposed to know?
This is all happening so fast!
Where are you going?
Out, looking!
And standing around here
isn't doing us any good!
Where?
I don't know!
Girls.
Go to class.
The bell hasn't rang yet.
Sir, I'm a
private investigator
- for John-
- One moment.
Now, ladies.
You're aware you have
a girl missing, Allison.
Yes, I'm well aware.
We're all well aware.
That's why the city employs
a Police Department.
We don't need wannabes
scaring the children.
Wannabe?
Sir, I served two tours of duty
with the United States-
- Yes, yes, yes, spare
me your resume, okay?
Find your own way out.
Let the police do their job.
Just one guy tonight.
You like that?
Pay 1500 for three hours.
Easy money.
Just sit there, listen
to him talk about he job
and all that nonsense.
Ain't like them other
ones at the motel.
He wants you to think
you he girlfriend, see?
Do good and it stay like this.
You act like a cheap ho,
you go back to the motel.
10, 20 men a day
for a hundred a pop.
Feel me?
And remember, you don't
want me to come visit
your little sister now, do you?
No.
Go on girl.
Make Daddy proud.
Honey.
Try to get some sleep.
- Hi.
You really are beautiful.
Want a glass of
wine, sweetheart?
Thank you.
You're hot.
I mean, handsome.
I'll take both.
What's your name, angel?
Allison.
So, Allison.
Tell me something
about yourself.
I'm in vet school
working specifically
with horses.
Horses?
Why horses?
Right before my 16th birthday,
I went riding with my friends
and I knew right then that I
wanted to be a veterinarian.
Brains and beauty.
Wanna do me a favor, Allison?
Sure.
Take off that dress
so we can go have some fun.
Why don't you
take it off for me?
Talk to me, John.
I need to hear
something good, please.
Just spoke to Ted Carson,
the Detective on Allison's case.
So we have the eyes of
Bloomfield Hills PD on this
as well as us,
but I'm gonna be
honest with you.
The odds that she's still
in the suburbs are slim.
I've made calls to my
friends at Detroit PD,
they know about her
and they have her photo
but honestly, they
are overwhelmed
with their own problems.
Is that it?
Well I have a man on
the street in Detroit.
Everybody knows him,
everybody respects him.
The word is out to all the gangs
that they can get 10 grand
if they find your daughter.
Now Aaron is working
the computer.
He hasn't found her yet.
Sometimes the pimps-
- Pimps?
I'm sorry, Case, but
we have to face reality.
Oh God in heaven.
Maybe...
Maybe you don't want
all the details.
I want every detail, John.
Go on.
There haven't
been any escort ads
that match any of the photos
from her social media sites.
Aaron's run them all
through the computer.
Okay next he's checking
for similar photos
but that has to be done by hand
and it takes a lot longer.
Is that it?
Well the noose is
tightening, Case.
But that's all I have for now.
Thank you, John.
Hey, how is Joanna?
Things at home
are not good, John.
Okay, well that's normal.
You two hang in there
now, you need each other.
I know.
Thank you, John.
All right, we'll
talk tomorrow.
Yeah.
One week!
One week, people
and we got zero.
Zilch, nada, nothing, come on!
It ain't unusual, boss.
Yeah,
Captain, you know that.
Yeah I know it,
but I don't like it.
Okay usually there's some sort
of something in the ether,
some chatter, some
talk on the streets.
We got nothing.
There will be, boss.
There will be, sooner or later.
Aaron!
Searching social
media for any profiles
using Tyler's picture.
Nothing yet.
Whoever this guy is that
lured Allison out is smart.
But I'll find him!
Yeah, you better find him.
Karen, my office.
Come on.
Karen, get in here.
$20,000 check from
the mother-in-law.
What have you got?
Nothing, not a peep.
Our pros have heard
zero on our girl.
Right, tomorrow you
start talking to everyone.
Who?
Everyone!
Okay, their kids
are gonna trust you.
Her friends will trust you.
I want you to call every
single phone number
in her entire phone.
Got it?
Got it.
Rookie, where's the rookie?
Tell him to get in here.
Yo, Benjamin, let's go!
Front and center, son.
Sir?
All right, I want you
to coordinate with PD.
I want you to give
me every location
that every kid has been
picked up in the last year.
Every single one.
On it.
Get me some leads,
people, let's go!
You need to get
some sleep, Captain.
Can't keep pulling
these all nighters.
We ain't kids anymore.
I can sleep when
I'm dead, partner.
But I will take a cup of coffee.
Where are you, kid?
Everybody get up.
We going for a ride.
Ain't no working today.
No, I don't know.
I don't know.
I gotta go okay, I love you.
You did good.
Allison, you up.
Allison!
Hi, Mom.
Where are you?
Everything's okay.
Mom, I'm in Chicago with Tyler.
Honey, just come home.
We are not angry with you.
Just please, come home.
I have to go.
Bye.
What?
No, Allison.
Hello, Allison?
No.
- Allison?
- It's disconnected.
- Allison!
- Call back.
Hey there,
it's Allison's phone.
- Oh my god.
- Dammit!
- We traced her cellphone.
- Is that legal?
No, it's not. Do you have a
problem with that?
Not in the least, go on.
And the call did
come from Chicago.
Yeah she's in Chicago
with her boyfriend.
Maybe.
I hope so, but I don't think so.
But she said that she was-
- Joanna, please, just let,
please, will you
just let him speak?
The cellphone went dark
right after the call.
Allison may have been coerced
into making that phone call.
I'm sorry, but it's a
very real possibility.
What?
No, why, she wouldn't...
- No.
- When these girls are taken,
Joanna, the bad guys make
the kids call the parents.
It's protocol to
throw off the police.
I'm telling you, she's fine.
She's in Chicago and she's okay.
She's with her
boyfriend, she's okay.
There is no boyfriend.
What?
At least there doesn't
seem to be a real Tyler.
Those pictures are fake.
They're from some
model in Los Angeles.
The entire profile is a catfish.
What?
Whoever lured
your daughter out,
that's not his name.
Those are not his photos
and he probably doesn't
even drive a Mustang.
And when were you planning
to tell us all this?
Mr. Riley, my job is
finding your daughter.
You don't need every single
piece of information, sir.
The hell I don't!
I don't believe
anything you're saying.
We know everything about
you, dishonorably discharged.
Three times in rehab
for alcoholism.
Joanna.
No, he's trying
to take our money,
can't you see that?
We should have just let
the cops handle this!
Stay on it, John.
These some high class
folks, little girls.
Good old white boys having
theyselves a bachelor party.
I want y'all to have
some fun tonight.
Me and the boys be right here
in case things get
out of control.
Allison, you collecting
the money tonight.
It be five Gs.
Just keep this
under wraps, you know.
What happens in the basement
stays in the basement.
Aight, y'all go
get that white boy money.
You know they daddies
gave them a lot of bread.
Come get all that.
Do good for Daddy.
Y'all did good.
Y'all made Daddy proud.
20 grand a week, man.
That's a lot of bread.
Too much.
Hey Biggs,
you know that girl
you were looking for?
Yeah, what up, Blink?
I think I've
seen her man, for real.
If she there, you
getting five Gs, homie.
If she ain't, then you don't.
Let's talk
about the money.
I ain't
giving you nothing now.
I'll tell
you what I know.
All right.
Now if you for sure for
sure, give me the address.
At the dog park,
I saw this van pulling up
with these girls getting out.
Dog?
No, I wanna
talk about the money.
You gonna mess around all day?
Like I said.
If she there, you
gonna get paid.
I'm not gonna play you, homie.
All right,
all right, yeah.
All right, bet it up.
What you got, big man?
One of my regular snitches.
He said he seen the
girl, blonde girl.
White, suburban, stranger.
She's been wandering
out the house a lot.
That's our girl.
We only about a mile away.
Let's roll.
Where have you been?
Shopping.
Still gotta eat.
It's been a month.
I know how long
it's been, Joanna.
Don't you think I know?
I can tell you to the day
and the hour.
Please, don't
start fighting again.
Nobody's fighting.
We're not fighting.
Good.
Now, I'd like to
make a suggestion.
I'd like the two of you
to take the night off
away from the house.
Go see a silly comedy movie.
I'm not seeing a movie.
Then have a dinner,
go for a walk.
Joanna, you-
- What are you wearing?
Clothes?
No.
Go change.
Why do I have to change?
Because I said to,
and I'm your father.
Dad, there's nothing wrong-
- Go to your room and change!
It's not her fault, Case.
Mind your business, Barbara.
Well.
With another $20,000
check due tomorrow
I'd say that everything
that happens around here
is now my business.
Don't pay it.
What?
She's not coming back.
Honey.
Belton is a crook.
He preys on people like us.
She's still missing
and he collects
$20,000 a week.
She's not coming back.
It's your friend Captain Belton.
And I'm sure he gave
Kessler a nice referral fee.
John?
Case, hey.
Look, my man on the street just
got a very, very strong lead.
Now normally I wouldn't call
you for every little detail
but you told me you
wanted to know everything.
Wait, wait, are
you gonna check it out?
Now.
My guys are strapping
the gear on right now.
Keep me posted.
I don't know, Case,
this could be it.
Let's go!
I'm good!
All of a sudden,
I step on there!
Easy, bros!
Man, that ain't even funny.
You almost got smoked.
Oh, man look at y'all.
All look scared.
Man, ain't nobody scared.
You look scared.
I ain't scared.
You scared.
What the hell is
wrong with you, cuz?
I oughta shoot your
black ass just because.
Better check
your drawers first.
But you be happy I come.
Word on the street, is
y'all got a blonde girl.
Suburb girl.
And Biggs be looking
for her everywhere.
10 large man, 10 large to
the man that bring her in.
Next man through that door,
he probably will
shoot your black ass.
But I know you.
You the type,
you the type to take
care of a brother.
I'm just here to get paid, man.
Let me check it out.
What you say is true,
then I straighten you out.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, thanks, John.
It wasn't her.
They raided the house,
there's a blonde
girl there, young.
Looked out of place for Detroit.
But she was there of
her own free will, 19.
Looked like Allison.
But it wasn't her.
Fire him.
God, Joanna.
I can't handle
it anymore, Case,
I just can't take it.
Case.
Maybe it's time.
No, it isn't.
He's getting closer.
No, he's just
stringing us along.
I'm telling you, it's...
Oh my god, I just can't
handle it anymore.
Jo.
Now my daughter's alive.
You know what, she's
alive, she's in Chicago,
she's with her
boyfriend and
she's happy.
It's a lie, Jo.
It's a lie I'm
willing to live with
because I can't live
like this anymore.
Case.
She may be right.
I have to save some
money for myself.
And there's Rachel's college.
It's time.
Look homes, I ain't got nobody
chasing none of my chicas.
That problem's on you.
Man, I ain't even
gonna lie to you.
I got some special interest
in one of my girls.
Friend of mine say you
be like some expert
professional interest in her.
He's on, man.
You owe me.
homes.
What you want?
I need four you girls.
You loco, esse,
get off my phone.
I'll give you one.
I'm talking a
prime white girl.
Educated, smart.
I'm taking 1500 a night
every night, you feel me?
And you trying to give me
one of them Mexican bitches
that don't speak no English?
You got a white
chica with heat, homes.
That's what you have.
Man, heat's in Detroit.
If you take her to Houston,
ain't nobody gonna be chasing
you there and you know it.
Come on playa, be real with me!
I need three.
I'll give you two.
Come on, man.
Two.
Two and you make the drive.
You drop them off here.
You pick up your
white girl up here
and drive her outta
here to Houston.
Done.
I'll see you in
three days, vato.
Allison be gone in three days.
We working her to
the end though, right?
No, put one of them
other hoes to work tonight.
It happens, boss.
The intel was good,
just not the right girl.
We got fired today.
Well, that happens too.
It's all part of the deal.
The girl is lost.
We move on, try to
save the next one.
It's all we can do.
I'm gonna go home and
get some sleep, Captain.
You should too.
Case?
Hey, John.
What's going on?
We friends, John?
You my friend?
'Cause I could use a friend.
Yeah, sure.
Hmm.
My $20,000 a week friend, huh?
It's my job, Case.
It doesn't mean
I don't like you.
Yeah, sure.
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm on top of the
world, old buddy!
How's the family?
The family?
Your wife?
Your mother-in-law,
Rachel, the family.
The family.
I don't know.
I'm in a hotel, John.
It's a nice room.
It has HBO.
I hear there's a
continental breakfast
so I'm looking forward to that.
Hey, come down here and
have a drink with me.
Can't do that, Case.
Three time loser, huh?
That's right.
You have a family, John?
Yeah, they're slipping
away from me, Case.
Mmm.
Captain John Belton.
Alcoholic with a dishonorable
discharge from the Marines.
You know, that wasn't
part of your sales pitch.
One of my boys was
behind enemy lines.
I was ordered to stand down
but I let my team in anyway.
And when I returned, I
assaulted my superior officer.
It was a long time ago.
Can you find her, John?
Can you find my girl?
You fired me, Case.
My mother-in-law fired you.
I'm hiring you.
Allison's college fund
is good for a few weeks.
You're drunk.
Look, do you want the
job or not, you coward?
Let me ask you something, John.
Is there any hope left?
Yeah, there's
definitely hope left.
And every second counts, Case.
I'm gonna get back
on it right now.
Okay.
I bet you'll come down
for that drink now,
won't you, my $20,000
a week friend?
Do you wanna insult me
or do you wanna help
me find your daughter?
I'm sorry.
I mean it, John,
I didn't mean...
You and me partners?
Butch and Sundance?
Yeah.
You and me.
Why don't you get some
sleep now, partner
and I'll call you
in the morning?
All right.
All right, I'm gonna
get some sleep.
I don't want you to
be mad at your mom.
Okay.
Life is hard.
I guess it doesn't
get any easier
but you're gonna be okay.
Dad?
Yeah?
I don't want you to go.
I know.
Come on, Vanessa.
You be working tonight.
Take a real good look at this.
I bet you ain't know Detroit
has some nice
neighborhoods, did you?
High class negroes, Jews,
Caldeans with they gas
station money, big houses
built back when the auto
industry was booming.
Henry Ford heself lived
out two blocks from here.
I bet you you didn't even know
I knew my history, did you?
Yeah, I know a lot more.
I'ma get us a big house
like this one day.
Just gotta get my money right.
He paid for three hours
but I'll be right here.
Go on now.
Hi.
Hi, sir.
Wow.
You're really handsome.
What's going on?
Relax, child.
My name is Pastor Brown.
You're with good people now.
No, no, no, no.
Daddy's gonna kill me.
- Hold her!
- No, no, no.
- Hold her now.
Daddy!
Let me go!
You're all right.
You'll be okay.
It's all good.
It's okay.
Come on, go with me, okay?
Come on.
We got you.
We got you, baby.
Just got off the
phone with Detroit PD.
They're backed up.
Don't have time to
come arrest the pimp.
He's gonna get
away with it again.
No he's not.
What do we do?
I'ma go out there
and I'm gonna get
his face on video.
Good way to get
yourself shot, sir.
I lived a long life, son.
If the Lord's will
for me to die tonight,
then I'll trust his will.
If I go down, pick up my phone.
Show his face to the world.
Let me get my gun and go
out there with you, sir.
No, no.
No violence tonight, son.
You got this.
May God bless you, sir.
- God bless you.
What's your name?
I see your face!
I see your car!
You get out of my neighborhood!
You stay out of my neighborhood!
If I ever see you in
my neighborhood again,
I'ma forget I'm a pastor!
John.
Just got a call from
one of my contacts
at the hospital.
A church group rescued a girl.
Looks like she's been
through the ringer.
You know the type?
Go on.
The girl says that she's
been imprisoned for a while.
The nurse said that she
mentioned a blonde girl.
Description matches Allison's.
Tex, go with her.
Hi, we're trying
to find Vanessa Garcia.
Down the hall to
the right, third bed.
Wait, wait!
What do you want with my niece?
Private investigator, Ma'am.
We're trying to find
somebody we believe
may have been kidnapped
alongside your daughter.
She's been through enough!
She's answered the
police's questions!
Tell them, Pastor.
Tell them to leave
my girl alone!
Ma'am, we're just trying
to help find somebody.
Esperanza.
This man is trying
to save other girls
just like her.
The Lord wants us
to help him do that.
If you think
it's best, Pastor.
I do.
Thank you, Pastor.
Hi.
You here for Vanessa Garcia?
One second.
Thank you.
Okay, I gave her something
for the withdrawal.
She's hooked on oxycontin.
She's gonna crash
hard, real hard.
As tough as it is,
talking to her now
is probably the
best thing, okay?
There she is.
Thank you.
It's okay.
My name is Karen
and I'm a friend.
Honey, what's your name?
My name?
Yeah.
You remember your name, right?
Vanessa.
Vanessa, where
did you come from?
He used to call me
his little songbird.
I'm a singer.
Daddy's house.
Do you know
where the house is?
I don't know.
What's the house near, honey?
Can you remember anything
that's near the house?
Dogs.
There's a park and,
there was a store in the corner.
Good.
Vanessa, have you
seen this girl before?
Yeah.
She's my friend.
Okay, and you're
sure you know her?
Allison.
Vanessa?
Vanessa, I want
you to look at me.
We will find Allison.
Do you hear me?
We will find her.
And you, you're safe now.
You're safe.
Yeah.
She gave a positive
ID on your daughter,
knew her by name.
She's ali...
Allison's alive?
Yes.
And in Detroit?
Well we assume so
for the time being.
What do you mean
for the time being?
Look, Case, these
people that I deal with,
they're smart, okay?
As soon as they feel
the noose tightening
they get up and they move their
operation to another city.
Our leads are strong.
Okay, we got some
really good breaks.
Thank you, John.
How are things at home, Case?
I haven't been home in a week.
Well you tell Joanna
we're getting close.
John, be honest with me.
Are we gonna find my daughter?
If I tell her and we
don't find Allison,
Joanna will never forgive me.
What would you do, John?
Pray.
I may
be all prayed out.
You always have one left.
Yeah.
Look man, give me the Caddy
straight up for the Benz.
Stolen?
No man, it ain't stolen.
I got papers for
you and everything.
Why do
you wanna get rid of it?
You talk too much.
We talking business or
we talking personal?
Hey, you're on my lot.
And I'm about to
not be on your lot.
You want my money or don't you?
Straight up for the Cadillac?
Straight up, let's go.
Let's do it.
36 hours since
Vanessa was rescued.
The clock is still
ticking, people.
Biggs?
Well, I mean there's
a few of those Benzes
floating around the city.
Detroit's a big place.
This might be the right Benz
or it could be some other
cat's Benz, I don't know.
All right, but
your contact says
they are running girls
out of that house.
That's what the brother
say, but he a crackhead.
They'll say anything
to get paid.
The neighborhood?
Well there's a dog park
and there's a corner store too.
Huh, but they call it
that because there's one
on every corner.
Aaron.
Park me up front of the house,
I'll pick up the
wifi if they have it.
Probably pick up a
few other houses too.
I won't know which signal
is coming from our house
so I'll have to
break the passcodes
and that can take time.
How much time?
I don't know, time.
Then it's gonna
take me even longer
to go through everything.
I may have to break
emails, social media,
if they've recently
cleared their history.
All right, all right, all
right, I got it, I got it.
Tex, take the van, park
it out there tonight.
See what computer boy can get.
I'm in their system, John.
There's definitely some girls.
There's just no
pictures of Allison.
You tell me that there's
a tan Benz in that driveway,
it's time to kick
down some doors.
No, sir.
Cadillac, red.
What do you wanna do, Captain?
Stand down.
What did he say,
are we going in?
We've been
ordered to stand down.
Dammit!
I got it.
Call everybody, get
them in the office, now!
Hoo rah, son.
How sure are you?
100 percent.
Ain't nothing a
hundred percent.
Find, then I'm 99.
Somebody in that neighborhood
is pimping out girls.
I see them posting
ads for it constantly.
Biggs.
I got one more guy.
Said the house with the Caddy
used to have a Benz over there.
So now along with the crackhead,
that now makes two.
But my one new guy,
he said he believes
that the Benz was white.
How do you feel about it?
I'm not sure, boss.
Maybe 50 percent.
Case, it's your daughter.
You gotta make the call.
If we go into the wrong house,
they are gonna move her.
To some other city,
Chicago, New York, Atlanta.
I have no idea, we may
never find her again.
If we wait, we may
get a stronger lead.
The truth is, they know
the noose is tightening.
They know we're looking for her.
They may move her in the
next couple of days anyway.
It's your call.
Kick it down.
All right, you heard
the man, let's go.
I'm going with you.
No, you're staying here
and letting us do our job.
I'm getting in that car.
You wanna stop me, shoot me.
Got one coming to you, Tex!
Get his ass out of here!
Good work, son.
Hoo rah.
Allison.
Excuse me.
Alex?
- Hey.
- Hi.
Where are we going?
You'll see.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull