I think this is a no-parking zone.
- What's taking you so long?
- Let's go.
Street of the Liberation,
then Buddha Alley and Shuangta Street.
Then west on Changle Street
to Yikang Street.
Why not Temple Street?
It's under construction,
they're redesigning it.
That leaves us with Kangjian Street and
the Alley of the Forest this afternoon.
Didn't we already do it yesterday,
the Alley of the Forest?
Okay, let's start again.
The data has been rejected.
You're supposed to be collecting data.
Not chasing skirts.
Are you going to pay me my bonus
if they take it away from me?
FOREST LANE
Move over.
Go hold the pole.
I don't want to come back
a third time.
What about the notebook?
Hold it steady!
Hurry up!
We'll hit rush hour.
How about eating around here?
Where?
The eatery over there looks good.
What's wrong with you?
Rush hour, right?
My treat.
Are you eating?
You can go home and dream.
Check.
I don't believe it...
So much for your treat.
If we waited a bit,
maybe the rain will stop.
You can wait here by yourself!
Hey, I didn't mean it!
Here.
Thank you.
Hey, watch it!
I'm sorry.
It's okay, I'll get it
You done staring?
May we go now?
Jump! Jump!
Shoot him!
There's lots of them!
Awesome!
Kill him!
That's the one who killed me!
That's him! Kill him!
Great!
Your mom brought you some stuff.
That's him, Kill him!
- Did she say anything?
- Yes... But I forgot what.
That's him, Kill him!
You're almost there!
New record! You broke the record!
What are you putting up there?
I'm talking to you!
It's a new regulation.
We have to do it.
What the hell?
I don't want anybody looking at my ass?
- It only shoots from the shoulders up.
- Don't bullshit me!
- It's for your own safety.
- My safety?
We only keep it for 24 hours.
It's taped over after that
Great. Go ahead.
I'm counting on you this time.
I owe you big.
- Where's my share?
- What have you done?
Hey!
Take it back.
Asshole!
- Let's go.
- Tight ass.
Boss says no bonus unless your van
passes the health inspection.
Again?
Hey, Jinginjg.
How about Mah-jong tonight?
Who else is going?
He's too young for adult games.
I'm busy tonight.
Oh, come on...
NAME: GUAN LIFEN
TEL: 65281753
Our motto is: service first,
credibility first and customer first.
Honesty and trust are our guidelines.
Mr. Li Qiuming?
How do you do?
We spoke on the phone just now.
I am Xie Bo.
Sorry to make you come all this way.
- Can I get you a drink?
- No, thank you.
Guan Lifen has an experiment to finish.
She won't be able to make it.
I'm her supervisor.
If you have any doubts,
you can call her to check.
That's okay.
Let me get you something.
A coffee?
Really, no need.
Coffee, please.
You must know Miss Guan well.
Oh, no. We just met.
Then you're a moral
example for all of us.
I must be going. Just a moment.
Write down your company's
contact information.
What for?
I'll write a letter of
thanks to your employer.
No need for that.
Really, I insist.
Your surname is Li,
write next to the letter L.
Turn right again.
Make a left here.
Slow down.
Turn in there.
FOREST LANE
Did we take a left on Guling Street?
Yup.
Why doesn't the GPS indicate
Forest Lane?
You never know with these things.
- Going any further?
- No.
That's 15 yuan.
LABORATORY 203
Women's living has a circulation
of less than 10,000 copies,
but employs more than 50 people.
We've become a retirement home.
When the Party's publications closed down
their ex-employees all flocked to us.
Why are we selling so few copies?
This is a women's magazine.
Look at us:
we're all men.
And old men at that!
What do we do about it?
We need to attract female comrades,
especially young, fashionable ones.
Female comrades are the key.
Lao Ma...
I proposed this to you long ago.
And what did you say?
That women don't know anything
about their own lives.
That only men know what women need.
What kind of magazine is this?
Who dares to cross the line?
We're being ridiculous!
Absolute crap!
You're the one talking crap!
Come here and say that!
I dare you to repeat that!
Your tricks won't work with me.
I'm telling you. This isn't over!
We'll see about that.
Fine.
What are you doing here?
I'm taking you to dinner.
What the hell for?
It's your birthday. Remember?
Mom's already gone to get us a table.
Hey! Pass the ball!
How many times have I told you
not to play here!
We'll eat at home. And that's that!
...While at the People's Court.
Minister Zhou inspected the
state-of-the-art facilities
and watched live feeds of
police interrogation procedures.
Zhou said that stress should be laid
on fairness and impartiality,
and that all court verdicts
should stand the tests of time.
Vice Premier Li Kegiang..
met with US Secretary of State
Hillary Clinton in Beijing today.
This is for the month.
Give it to your mother.
...The ball hit the net.
The Chinese players have a clear
advantage over their opponents.
None of the Vietnamese players
is taller than 2 meters.
- Put the apron on.
- I don't need it.
Put it on!
You can stop giving me money.
I've got enough.
I don't want to get
you in trouble again.
I won't.
Where did you get the extra money?
I'm not a trainee anymore.
It's true.
Welcome!
Starting today, this floor will be
reserved exclusively for officials.
The utmost discretion
must be maintained.
- Is this understood?
- Yes.
As for appearance...
your makeup should be light.
Sweep every room on this floor by 5pm.
- Make sure everything is clean.
- No problem.
Who dares to mess with officials?
What did you say?
He's a joker, sir.
We'll take care of it.
Bedrooms are mine.
Take a look at this.
I sweet-talked the boss
into lightening our load.
Wait a minute.
Are we changing districts?
- We're done with Jianye.
- What about Forest Lane?
Forget about it.
The system won't register some places.
- Why not?
- There's no reason?
Let me check with the manager.
He's the one who decided this.
- I just want to ask him...
- What are you trying to do?
Who's in charge here? The manager, me,
or you, the trainee?
Hi.
Have a seat.
What can I get you?
- A Coke.
- Will that be all?
Coming right up.
You're open late.
What can you do...
You have to make a living.
Business is good?
This is a lousy location.
Hardly any companies.
I have a few regulars during the day.
Do you know anything about lab 203,
on Forest Lane?
Lab 203?
Never heard of it.
As long as they eat my wontons,
they can do whatever they want.
That'll be 5 yuan.
I would've gone looking for you
even if you hadn't been "passing by".
Why is that?
To thank you in person, of course.
It wasn't a big deal.
So you work at lab 203?
How did you know that?
Just a guess.
Do you come around here often?
Not really.
Just a few times for surveying work.
I've run into you more
than "a few" times.
We run into each other every time.
What a coincidence...
You must be my guardian angel.
You appear every time
I have a problem.
Tonight it doesn't count.
How's that?
I'm no help to you,
you're the one who's taking me home.
Oops...
Shouldn't I have turned left?
Don't worry.
We can turn left further up.
You should install a GPS.
A GPS?
What would the GPS have told me?
"Turn left on Fengdeng Street.
"Turn left on Fengdeng Street..."
Can you lend me some money?
What?
Spending it on someone special, are we?
Who is she?
There is no girl.
You can't even get the thing to
focus today. Still pretending?
I'll pay you back
from my next pay check.
Don't date out of your league.
Don't waste your money.
Fine. Don't lend it then.
Come back!
You're getting touchy.
You think I can't afford it?
So here we are...
Behind us, Lifu Street
and in front, the Zhongshan Gate.
And on the right.
There's a "Shanghai garden" after all.
You can have a 3D view
by pressing here.
Thank you.
It's nothing.
Where are we going now?
Forest Lane
Enter.
Address unknown
Let's go somewhere fun instead.
Look at that baby monkey!
He's eating a lot!
Here's one more!
What's your favourite hobby?
My favourite?
Playing video games.
- Where do you play?
- At home.
My roommate loves zombie games.
And besides games?
Internet.
Do you spend any time online?
Not too much.
I just read the news.
We should play online games sometime.
I'm no good at video games.
We could chat online then.
I don't just play games.
I look stuff up too.
For my map.
Your map?
I'm making my own map,
with my favourite places.
Such as?
Give me your hand.
Our latitude is 32.0936° north
and our longitude is 118.7939° east.
where Li Qiuming and Guan Lifen
hold hands for the first time.
Two sodas, please.
Mr. Surveyor!
How many times have we met?
This must be the fourth time.
Why is that?
How do you know
I don't have a boyfriend?
When I asked you out,
you didn't hesitate.
And besides.
And besides what?
Besides...
Even if he went after you,
you wouldn't like him.
Who?
That Xie Bo guy.
He said he was your supervisor.
But I can see that he likes you.
Except that...
I don't think you two
would make a good match.
You're only half right.
Which half?
Figure it out yourself.
Who do you live with?
A couple of friends.
What do they do?
Anything that comes along.
I should be going.
- Was that the lab?
- Yeah.
We can go back to the park
next Sunday.
Next Sunday?
That's a date then.
That's 15 yuan.
Here you go.
Which one?
This one?
The other one, below.
You can't see her face clearly.
That's the one I want.
Is everything ok?
To: Guan Lifon
Sending...
The number you are trying to reach
is turned off..
I made the photo brighter.
It's better now.
The number you have dialled
is not available.
That was fast!
She was hot!
Hello?
Which model?
Got it.
Going in?
That's the one.
Isn't that one a little big?
Not at all.
Behind a tinted window,
no one will notice.
- Are you the installer?
- Yes.
This will go in an
old whitewashed house.
Will it stand out?
Probably.
- Otherwise, get the pinhole camera.
- Too expensive.
You won't find cheaper than this.
I could always hire someone else?
Ask around if you like...
Listen, I'm going to go
out and make a phone call.
Think about the price a little bit.
Hey, boss,
What's up with this guy you sent over?
He said the price was wrong.
Too expensive.
What price did you tell him?
What?
No, that's like doing it for free...
Look here.
It's a set-up.
Go!
Can I help you?
Where is she?
She's coming.
- What brings you here?
- I was just passing by.
This is my son.
He looks like you.
Where does he work?
In a digital mapping company.
He is a survey engineer.
Are you alright?
You can tell me.
You look well.
How's the new medication?
I think it's really working this time.
Listen...
Your father has been
re-elected editor-in-chief.
He's in a good mood these days.
Come home for dinner tonight?
- How much is this?
- 60.
It's handmade.
I make them myself.
What do you say?
- I'm going back to work.
- Already?
Longitude: 118.7624° East
Latitude: 32.0627° North
DEMOLITION IN PROGRESS
RELOCATING COMMUNITIES
FOR A BRIGHTER FUTURE
I swear to you... What a dump!
What's left to survey?
This way.
Excuse me, is Scissors Lane this way?
- Who are you?
- Surveyors.
The developers are back!
Again?
Who is your boss?
Why isn't he here?
You're misunderstood us
We're looking for the Scissors Lane.
You haven't corrected
the measurements of my house here!
Fellows, it's a mistake.
- We don't survey houses.
- We do city maps.
If you don't survey, why do you
carry this? To beat people up?
Calm down!
No need to get violent!
Come back here!
Even a blind man would see
that this is a trap street.
Nonsense!
A "trap street" has to
blend into its surroundings.
Let me show you...
See how this street curves to the side?
Add another bend at the end.
See how seamless it is?
Here...
Leave me alone.
What are you two doing?
Teaching her to create
a "trap street".
Show-off!
Qiuming,
the manager was looking for you.
- What did he want?
- No idea.
Just say I'm gone for the day.
Tell him yourself.
Hey, you there!
Hello, I'm looking for someone.
Come over here.
You have to sign in.
Your ID.
Who do you want to see?
Li Qiuming.
You like it here?
Yes.
You seem different today.
Something good happened?
Tell me about it.
Give me your hand.
Read it.
Latitude: 32.052° north,
longitude: 118.771° east.
This is where Li Qiuming and Guan
Lifen hold hands for the first time.
Isn't this the second time?
Last time didn't count.
Why not?
There's no reason.
Your watch.
I am not the one you are looking for.
Can I have a cigarette?
Can I sit down for a bit?
Remain standing.
Do you remember me?
Please don't get the wrong idea.
I'm not responsible for
your current situation.
I'm here to help you.
You have to trust me.
Here you go.
I brought you this.
Eat it while it's hot.
Take it.
I have a few questions for you.
Give me honest answers,
and I can explain everything to them.
Come on.
Have a seat.
Why did you befriend Guan Lifen?
You bureaucrats.... You always have to
know everything about private matters.
I'm just a scientist.
I don't consider myself
as a bureaucrat.
Besides, very few matters
are completely private.
Let's stay on track.
What do you want from her?
Is she in trouble?
She'll be fine as long as you talk.
Better talk here,
rather than somewhere else.
I told you.
I didn't know her.
She was on foot that day,
I gave her a ride.
And after that,
You never saw her again?
I did.
- Still by coincidence?
- Yes.
- Where?
- Outside Forest Lane.
- When?
- At night.
What time?
I'm not sure... around 9pm.
It was 11:46 pm to be precise.
Do you still survey at that hour?
Think harder.
What else do you want me to tell you?
When I got my measles vaccination?
You're the one who's investigating me.
You should tell me
what this is all about.
Can you at least give me a hint?
There's a big difference between
me telling you and you confessing.
You synced your phone with mine?
Don't you know everything already?
What type of institution
is this "Lab 203"?
Our work is classified.
What did my son do?
He is suspected of having stolen
state secrets.
Do you have any evidence?
We don't hunt down innocent people.
Did he confess?
That's not your concern.
You should focus on
what you can tell me.
He doesn't live with us.
We only see him once or twice a month.
What kinds of people
does he associate with?
I don't know.
Does he have a girlfriend?
Let me remind you...
As a veteran Party member,
it's in your interest to cooperate.
But I don't know anything.
How much did he pay you back so far?
What are you talking about?
Three years ago, he started a
small business with a partner.
His partner ran off with the money.
It was you who covered
his debt of 150,000 yuan.
He paid me back about a quarter.
Be precise.
Well... we've reached an agreement.
He agreed to pay me back
1500 yuan a month.
It's been 2 years and 4 months now.
Everything you tell me will be checked.
So far your political record is clean.
Anything else?
For the past 2 months,
he's been paying more than usual.
How much more?
2,500 per month.
I don't understand.
What don't you understand?
I've never set foot in Lab 203.
How would I steal secrets?
You must have opened this.
There were two flash drives inside.
I didn't touch them.
Can anyone else
have gotten hold of them?
A colleague?
Your roommate?
I kept the box on me the whole time.
Then it can only have been you.
I told you I didn't touch them.
The night you picked her up,
Miss Guan left work at 7:45pm
You returned the USB sticks
the next day at 9:16pm
Can you prove that you didn't touch them
during these 25 hours?
Can you prove that I did?
It's not me who needs
to prove that you did.
It's up to you to prove
that you didn't.
If I say you stole it,
can you prove otherwise?
You can't do this.
My mother has a heart condition.
I'd rather avoid it too.
She has nothing to do with this.
- Why don't you tell the truth.
- I keep telling you!
- Go and talk to her.
- No, please!
Let me think...
It was the USB stick.
It had classified data on it.
You discovered a leak then you
suspect me because I found it.
Keep talking.
But I didn't steal anything or
touch anything. I swear I didn't!
But nobody can prove that.
Who can prove it?
So you gave them to someone else.
Who was it?
Nobody, I swear.
You'd know if I did.
That's it. There would be a trace.
The key must be encrypted.
You'd see if it had been cracked.
Go check it out!
The stick was not encrypted.
How's that possible!
It had to be!
It must have...
Your work is classified...
How can you not encrypt your drives?
That's impossible...
How much for a standard room?
80 yuan per night.
A seven.
A ten.
A King!
- Two.
- Your turn.
Pass.
Your turn.
Come on.
- Hurry up.
- Beautiful.
Don't move it... Take this!
Pass.
Three of a kind.
You've finished work already?
What work?
There is no more work.
How come?
The company's surveying license
has been suspended.
What happened?
The manager must have pissed someone off.
Or he didn't grease the right palm.
Look how low he's sunk...
Sounds like you didn't grease
the right palm either.
Three Kings.
Did you bring your things?
- Pass.
- Three Kings?
Hold it there...
Three twos!
Take that!
I've had it... Your turn.
Pass.
He wasted his three Kings.
Hang on.
- A straight.
- Nice hand.
I asked the boss to advance you
two weeks' salary.
I owe you money.
- What did you play?
- A suite.
Pass.
A pair of threes.
A pair of nines!
- How many do you have left?
- One.
This is yours.
I know it.
I know why you're fired.
Why did you keep going to Forest Lane?
That's a secret institute there.
It's not on the maps.
Didn't you know?
Why did you go there in the first place?
Qiuming, are you there?
Open the door, Qiuming.
It's Mom. Open the door.
Qiuming!
He's not home.
Have you seen him?
Do you know where he is?
No way!
- Not bad.
- I put it in.
My turn now.
But I got it in!
Hey, Qiuming!
Look.
Look who's here.
It's you.
Oh, yes...
My cousin made us move back in with him.
I was in a rush,
and forgot to pay you the rent.
Take it.
I came to see
if you have any work for me.
- We need help, don't we?
- Get out of my way!
Now.
Work... well
I've been busy renovating
my cousin's house.
There's no work.
The game's starting.
Join us if you want.
I am in a hurry.
Can I pick up my photo?
It was picked up on Wednesday.
I don't get it.
What don't you understand?
It was picked up and paid for.
How can it be?
What's the point of the receipt then,
if anyone can pick it up?
Print another copy then.
Tell me!
Why did you give me this receipt?
It's just a picture, why the big fuss?
You're crazy!
Tell me what the receipt is for?
I want an explanation!