- A drink while you're waiting,
ma'am?
- Uh, I'm... I'm fine for now.
- Certainly.
- Did you pull the horns down?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Can you put it in the...
Can you, uh, go back
and just play it
with the foley next to it?
Well, that's going to have
to wait till Tuesday. No.
But, you know what, just
email me. Yeah, email me...
Okay.
- Just right there.
- Okay.
I am so sorry.
Oh, shit. I gotta get this.
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah...
No, the dark one...
Because the show is sunny enough already.
It doesn't need the sunny theme...
It's too twee-twee. It's like
butterflies and rainbows... I...
The dark one...
It's not that dark...
It's not a dirge...
Okay...
Good...
Yes.
This is going on vibrate
right now.
I've been working as a music adviser
for Lifetime in LA, and,
they want to rebrand
the Canadian version,
so I convinced them
to send me here for a few days.
I could have done the work online,
but this way I get the hotel
and the flight paid for.
You know how it is.
- Not really.
- Anyway, I'm sorry I was late.
I know you hate waiting.
We said 6:30, right?
- Six o'clock.
- Oh, you waited 45 minutes?
- I was early.
- How early?
- It doesn't matter.
About 15 minutes.
- No. You waited an hour?
Something's changed.
Back in the day, you wouldn't
have waited an hour for anyone.
Except maybe your dealer.
Aw, give me a hug.
You look terrific.
- You look terrible.
- No, I don't.
- And I don't look terrific.
- How are you?
- Ah-ha.
- Oh, I'm afraid I forgot.
You hate that question.
- Do you want me to ask
how you are?
- Only if you're interested.
- How are you?
- Good.
Busy.
Tired.
Hungry.
You took a look at the menu?
- I had a chance, yeah.
- Plus, they'll do up something
special for you if you want.
I came here a lot the last time
I was in town
and I got to know the chef.
- Can I get you a drink?
- Uh, a drink...
What do you think?
- You drinking?
- Um,you?
- No, you?
- No, but...
- But?
- No. Um, San Pellegrino,
big bottle, lime on the side.
Is your lime fresh?
- Oh, yes.
- Okay, lime on the side,
no ice. Thanks.
Are you ready to order?
- Sure.
- Um, is Henry in the kitchen?
- Oh, Henry's not here any more.
- Oh, no. Where's Henry?
- He went to Ultra.
- Ugh. We should have gone to Ultra.
- But Denise is here
and she mentored under him.
- Do you still do that quail?
- Yes.
- Great. I'll have the quail,
no starch. Um, organic greens.
- Sure.
And, um, you?
- What's this?
- It's the potato soup.
It's very delicious.
- Just a salad.
- We... we have a selection
of salads.
- Number one.
And we can do without this.
- So, this thing tonight...
- Ah, how embarrassing.
- Yeah, I know.
- "Women in Rock"...
Why not "Women in Labour"?
Are they doing
a bake sale, too?
- It's a tribute.
- To who?
- To us, for one.
And it's a benefit.
- Are they giving out medals?
I'd rather have the cash.
- They want us to do something.
- Uh-huh.
- They'd like us
to do something. I mean,
I'm not prepared to do anything.
- I'm not sure I'm going.
- But you have to go.
- No, I don't.
- Well, uh...
You have to at least go. I mean,
we don't have to do something.
- I'm not doing anything.
- But you have to go.
- No, I don't.
- No... true... No, you don't have to.
It would be nice, though.
- Nice for who?
- Okay, fine.
It's just, you know, I'm...
It's happening,
and I'm here, and...
- You're here because
you're working, I thought.
- No. I mean, yes, but I planned
the work around tonight.
I'm here for tonight.
- That's nice.
- I could have done
this work at home.
- Home.
- What?
- LA is home now?
- Uh, well, yeah,
as much as LA can be.
- You and LA.
- Silver Lake is nice.
Malibu.
- You doing any modeling
these days?
- It wasn't modeling.
- Well, what would you call
having you picture taken
in a magazine to sell clothes?
- I wasn't selling clothes.
- Well, you weren't wearing
much clothing, that's true.
- It's ancient history.
You know, it was fun,
what I remember of it.
I was drunk most of the time.
I can't believe you're still
carrying that around.
- I'm not carrying anything around.
I'm just catching up.
- So, what are you up to?
- Not much.
- You're good though, right?
I'm hearing you're good.
- Where are you hearing that?
- From Bill.
- That asshole.
- He says you're in touch.
- He still wants to manage me.
I have nothing to manage
but my cat and my laundry.
- He likes Florida.
- He's fucking golfing.
Can you believe that?
- He says
you're making new music.
- That's Bill's Story.
- You're not?
- Well, it's not new.
What's new? Nothing's new.
- It's acoustic, he said.
You were always talking
about doing that.
I'd love to hear it.
Do you have a copy with you?
- No.
- You know,
I was thinking about you,
because we are looking
for some themes
for a couple of programs.
It's really great money.
It's easy.
- Themes?
- Themes for a couple programs.
- Jingles?
- No. Themes.
Lots of people do it.
- And lots of people give
blowjobs for crack.
- You're reading.
- Yep.
- You finally learned how.
- The Spirituality
of Imperfection. Okay.
"Okay?"
- What?
- What do you mean, "Okay"?
- What? Nothing.
- Nothing?
- Yeah. What?
- What? Yeah.
- Yeah, what? Nothing.
- Nothing.
- Nothing. Good for you.
- Good for me what?
- If that stuff works for you.
- "That stuff"'?
- That Jesus stuff.
- Its not "Jesus stuff".
- No I didn't-
- It's not Billy Graham.
- I didn't say that it was.
- You might as well have.
Just... you know, your attitude.
- My attitude?
- Your attitude. Yeah.
This restaurant.
What the fuck is this place?
Fucking quail?
Fifteen-dollar potato soup?
An hour late?
- It was 45 minutes.
- I thought it was 15.
- Well, you said 45.
- You said 15
and now you're saying 45.
- Because you said 45.
- Yeah, it was actually
a fucking hour.
- You were early.
When have you ever been early?
It is not my fault
you were early.
- It's not your fault, no.
It's never your fault,
just like in London.
- Oh, okay. Because
you're the one who disappeared.
How do you think
that made me feel?
- Made you feel, made you feel.
You, you, you.
It's still all you.
- Oh, take a look at yourself.
- Oh, you're talking to me
with your attitude?
And your, what,
"rebranding the network"?
And your, what, $2,000 sweater?
How much did that sweater cost?
And "I know the chef",
laying on the bullshit
just like always.
Offering me jingle work?
Give me a break.
I didn't show up here to eat
your disrespect for dinner.
- So why did you come?
- I don't know, maybe because
I thought I'd get an apology.
- For what?
- "For what"?
- OK. I'm sorry.
- What for?
- Whatever
you want me to be sorry for.
- Let's start with being late
and work backwards.
- Okay. I'm sorry I was late.
- Who is 45 minutes late
by accident?
- Like you were never late.
Like you're perfect.
- Fuck you.
- Shit.
- Woo... We're back.
- Yep.
- So, how's
the spirituality going?
- Mmm... so-so.
I'm pretty good
with the imperfection, though.
- I'm sorry I was late.
- There's a solution.
- What?
- Get a watch.
- Yeah.
- Got to wash my hands.
- Waiter.
- Waiter?
Can I have a coffee, please?
- Sure.
- I know why you're here.
- I told you why I'm here.
- No, why you're really here.
- Why am I really here?
- I don't need your help, okay?
- My help?
- A job or whatever.
And don't try to slip any cash
in my pocket
when I'm not looking.
I'm fine. I've got what I need.
- What's that?
- To do the next right thing
and maintain a conscious
connection with my higher power,
just like the book says.
- So, do you pray?
- Do I pray?
- Get down on your knees
and humble yourself
before your higher power?
- Not with that attitude,
I don't.
- Maybe...
it's different for addicts.
- Not really.
A drunk is just a messier junkie.
- I guess.
- Not you, though.
You're terminally unique.
You don't do meetings?
- I do meetings.
- But you don't pray?
- I'm more of an agnostic
than anything else.
- Yeah, well, so am I.
It's just questioning.
Agnostic means "I don't know".
Who isn't an agnostic?
Who can say they know?
- I've met a few.
- When did you start
to eat like that?
- I always ate like this.
Like what?
- You used to eat like me.
- With my fork in my fist
like a spear? Or with my hands?
- No. You used to switch,
like me.
- Switch?
- Switch. Switch.
Like, switch.
- Mmm...
I never switched.
- You switched.
- I didn't switch.
I was well raised.
- You weren't well raised.
- Yes, I was,
and so were you.
Our fathers went to work
in their Oldsmobiles every morning.
Our mothers stayed home, ironed napkins,
and made macaroni casserole.
That's the way it was.
We just played
rock and roll house.
At least we were
honest about it then.
- My mother never
ironed our napkins.
- No, but your mother made
excellent macaroni casserole.
- To macaroni casserole.
- How about...
we agnostics.
- We agnostics.
- Come with me.
- All right.
But I'm not doing anything.
I said I'm not doing anything.
Did you hear me when I said that?
I'm not doing anything?
- I want to change.
- Your clothes?
- Yeah.
- You look fine.
- I look like I work in television.
- You do work in television.
- I just... I want to change.
- But you're not going to wear
the $2,000 sweater?
You probably bought it
just for tonight.
- It wasn't $2,000.
- One thousand?
- No.
- Nine hundred.
- No. Lend me something.
Lend me something.
I can wear something of yours.
- You want
to wear something of mine?
- Yeah. We used to do that
all the time.
Why not?
- Hmm...
Uh... I wasn't expecting
a guest from LA.
- I am not "from" LA.
I live mere. I'm from here.
I'm from down the street,
around the corner from you.
- Not in a $900 sweater,
you're not.
- It wasn't $900.
- Eight-fifty.
Bingo!
- I just want to change!
- All right.
You can say hi to Brian.
- You're kidding!
- What?
- So...
- Yeah.
So, you're good?
- Good.
- Yep.
- You want some cereal?
- No. Thanks.
We just had dinner.
- Well, I'm going to get back
to the novel.
- You're writing a novel?
- It's more of a memoir, actually.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
It's either going to be called
The Average Life
of a Magnificent Man, or...
The Magnificent Life
of an Average Man.
- They're both-
- Compelling.
- Yeah, but don't worry.
Either way, it's not going
to be full disclosure.
You know.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
So no worries.
- Oh.
- The only thing clean
are t-shirts.
- I'll just take a t-shirt.
- Ah! Ha! Ha!
She's still got it!
- Stop.
- Ah, well, this is not
going to work.
- What?
- Well, we're dressed the same now.
- Lots of people wear
ironic t-shirts.
- Why is The Commodores ironic?
- It's just,
a band t-shirt is ironic.
- But why?
- It's... usefulness.
- Hmm... I'm going
to put on something else.
- Here, wear my sweater.
- Oh...
All right, baby,
I'll wear your sweater.
She's a brick
House
She's mighty mighty
Commodores.
- Yeah.
- So it's here.
Sweet memories.
- Sometimes.
She's a brick... house
- Brian?
- It's comfortable.
- Do you love him?
- Love is a minefield.
Love is a-
A battlefield
- This is love:
I secretly believe
that I'm unloveable,
and then I meet you.
You taught me
that you loved me.
I loved you
because you loved me,
but that has nothing to do
with you.
It's about you loving me.
I only love you
because I imagine myself
unloveable,
and you, against all odds,
love me.
And then, at some point,
you do something
that makes me think
that you don't love me,
which I'm more ready to believe
than you loving me-
because I'm unloveable.
So I stop loving you,
because I only love you
because you love me,
and I'm unloveable.
- What about
the other person?
- Who?
- The person who loves you.
- No, no, it's the same thing.
Everybody is doing
the same thing.
- Why?
- Because everybody thinks
they're unloveable too.
- I'm not unloveable.
I am all-loveable.
I am the very meaning
of loveable.
- Oh, yeah.
You really believe that?
- Hey, just because
you're living in the shadows
doesn't mean some of us aren't
walking in the sunshine.
- We block the sunshine
to make the shadow.
- How Go Ask Alice.
- People think
that love will complete them,
but, see, what people really
want isn't to feel complete.
What people really want is
peace of mind.
I used to sit around waiting
for it to come tap me on the shoulder:
"Hey there! Come with me."
For something to descend upon me
and lift me out of my shit.
But no, I had to do the work,
and, you know, the work started
when I stopped waiting
for someone to love me.
- Well, I think you're running
away from something.
- What?
- Ghosts.
The future.
Ghosts of the future.
- Yeah, I don't know.
I think I'm going to head.
- What is the problem?
- Nothing has changed.
It's just like yesterday.
- Tomorrow was always just
yesterday disguised as today.
It's all yesterday. Come on.
- No, I don't like yesterday.
- You were just scared of it.
- What were you scared of?
- You.
- Memo.
- Come on.
Look, you could either be in the world,
or you could be out of the world.
You want to be in the world,
it's right in there.
You want to be out of the world,
go home to your apartment
and eat cereal with Brian.
I don't know how you're going
to sell records that way, so...
- Records? I didn't know
people still sold records.
- Whatever. They're downloading.
It still involves cash.
Come on in. See what
the kids are buying.
- I don't know...
- You're safe with me, baby.
I'm loveable enough
for both of us.
- Aww...
But I'm not standing in line.
- Okay, I'll go see
if I can find somebody.
- Sorry.
You go ask.
- Hey.
Are you Vic from Trigger?
- Oh, no. Sorry.
- Are you sure?
- Uh, pretty sure.
Vic!
- It is! it's Vic from Trigger!
- Can I touch the bottom
of your shoe?
- Oh, no, no, no, no.
Listen, listen, up we get.
- Vic from Trigger
just touched my hand!
- Wait. Wait.
Would you listen to our band?
- Oh, yeah.
Oh, a cassette
- I've got a CD. Do you want a CD?
- Oh, no. Cassettes are good.
I like cassettes
- Yeah, me too!
- Fuck digital.
Piss Flap doesn't do digital.
- Yo, Piss Flap! Nice.
Catchy.
- Yep.
- Bill Gates can keep his hands
off of Piss Flap, okay?
- I'll see you... girls later.
Come on!
- Bye!
- Bye.
- Well, this is not so bad.
- In what way?
- We're going to get fucked up.
- Woo. Fucked up.
The tribes have gathered
and the natives are restless.
- If this is a tribe
then you are the chief.
- Aww, Billy.
How's it going ihere, asshole?
- It's going good.
- You look great, Vicky.
- Kat.
- Hey, Bill.
- Hey.
- You scouting for talent?
- Not this time, no.
I'm just talking to Vic.
How's Florida?
- Uh, it's, uh...
kind of like Thunder Bay-
hot, and with tourists.
- He's fucking golfing.
Can you believe it?
- You know, it's cheaper
than a shrink, and it's less
crowded than meetings, so...
Boom!
- You and Alice Cooper.
- Yeah, I know...
He's pretty good.
I might be better.
Look, boys from EMI
came to me with it.
- Yeah, yeah...
- Ball's in your court.
- I'm thinking about it. Yeah.
- EMI. EMI!
EMI! EMI! EMI!
- E-M-I!
- How's LA?
- LA.
- Yeah?
Staying out of trouble?
- Do I look like I'm staying
out of trouble?
- Yeah, but you were always
good at disguises, so...
- Don't worry about me.
- "Don't worry about me."
Keep an eye on her.
- Mm-hmm.
- Somethings up there.
- Yeah.
All right.
- All right. Mmm!
EMI!
- Hey. What's up?
- Nothing. I dunno.
I'm not feeling this scene.
- It's not so bad.
- You got a little attention.
- What?
- I saw that kid outside.
Oooh, oooh.
And the boys from EMI want to meet.
- Whatever.
- Doesn't take much
to wake up your ego.
- It's not about my ego.
It's just, you know,
I've got this music
coming out and...
I've been asking myself why,
you know?
Like, what's the point
of another song?
It's not the music; it's who
the music brings together,
and that's what we've been
looking for.
- And your 12 songs
of acoustic intro-spec-tion
are going to bring
the whole world together?
- What?
No... That's not
what I'm saying.
- Maybe you should go out there
and do one of your new numbers.
- What? "Acoustic introspection"?
What happened to turn you into
such a bitch all of a sudden?
- Just don't look for depth
in this scene, okay?
This is the same superficial
shit it always was,
only actually
it's fucking worse.
- Whatever,
it's still rock 'n' roll.
- Ha! Rock 'n' roll...
Rock 'n' roll is
a fucking smell.
It's a whiff you get
and it reminds you of something.
It's an odour.
- All right, well,
let's go smell the band.
- All right, people. This is
basically a stage area.
I'm looking for laminates
that say "full access".
If I don't see laminates
with the words "full access",
you're going out front with
the regular folk, all right?
- We're, um...
- Oh, I know, I know.
My God, I know, you're Trigger.
I'm a huge fan.
You made high school
less than hell, honestly.
I bow down, really.
Just, tonight it's business.
Guys,
I don't see your laminates.
Can you please be somewhere else
right now? Thank you.
Thank you for putting this whole
thing together, by the way.
- What?
- No, um, she just means, um...
just for being part of it.
- I thought you were on the board.
- No. No, no, no.
No, um, we're just...
We're just here to be here.
Happy to be here.
- Great.
Are you going to perform, or...?
- Uh, she's not, but I might.
- What?
- I mean, she might do something
acoustic from her new stuff.
- Okay.
- She's being a comedian.
- No, I'm... I'm definitely
going to perform.
- Who are you going
to perform with?
- You can play with Fox Fire.
- Perfect. When?
- Now.
- Now? Okay. Okay.
- Great. It's done. All right.
Hannah, one half of Trigger
is coming towards you.
Bow down. Seriously.
- Save it for Carole Pope.
- I know.
- You guys good with that?
- Yeah, we're good.
- So, uh, we obviously have
a very special guest with us tonight.
Rock legends, Trigger.
Here's a song
that you might remember.
- What a cunt!
Look at her,
so fucking full of herself.
What a bitch!
Doesn't it just twist
your fucking tits?
You know, you make her look pretty
fucking good when it comes down to it.
At least she hasn't
cashed in all her chips.
At least she's still got
a fucking job.
You and your shame,
and your fucking apologies,
and your fucking
making amends bullshit.
- Shut up.
- Give over.
Give over. It's just a matter
of time anyway.
Your music sucks,
your liver is fucked,
and you think you've got
another chance? You're dreaming!
All those prayers,
all those meetings...
Where does it get you?
Dead.
Oooh, that's nice.
Thank you, Edmonton!
Chicks rule!
Those bitches went off!
That was like dropping a match
in a gas station.
What are you doing
dropping matches?
It wasn't my fault.
I can't go in there in these shoes!
Well, then take the shoes off!
Come on!
God damn it,
this shit is no fun sober!
Ugh!
- Piss Flap?
Poor kid.
- Ugh.
All right, I'll take a listen.
Ugh. Poor Piss Flap.
- It's better than The Shut Ups.
- What? We were 14!
- We were so lame.
- No, no, no.
The Shut Ups were pure.
The Shut Ups were
when we were perfect.
- Oh... I'm tired all the time.
- Yeah, I know.
I never used to get tired.
Well, I never slept.
I just passed out.
- Even if I did get tired,
I'd just take a drink
or a hit, and click again.
Even a nod isn't like being tired.
Going into a nod is like
the air turning to Jell-O.
and an emotional flatline,
but it's not like tired.
When I get tired now,
I feel:
"This is probably
how normal people feel.
This is as close to normal
as I'm ever going to get."
- Life's too short to get tired.
Life... Life is short,
but ssss... somethings long.
What do they Say?
Life... Life is short,
but hell is long.
Well, that's what
my grandmother used to say.
- Hell...
I don't know if it's long,
but it's deep.
- Mmm.
And dark.
Dark and deep.
And deep and dark.
And deep and dark...
Deep.
- And dark.
- And deep.
- I remember in a meeting
one time, somebody said:
"They opened the gates,
and I thought
I was getting let into Heaven,
but it turned out
I was getting let out of Hell."
- That's good.
- Well, it's all deep and dark,
isn't it?
- You know what started it for me...
the real beginning of the descent?
Love.
That Scottish guy I met
in London when I left the tour.
All fucked up and beautiful.
Or maybe he was just beautiful
because he was fucked up.
And he knew how fucked up
he was, like I did.
Sometimes it was like looking in a mirror.
And he'd get that same look
in his eyes.
I could see
what he was doing to himself.
And I wanted to help him.
More than wanting to party with him,
I wanted to help him.
And that's what made me think
it was love.
It was.
Doesn't matter how long
you know someone.
You can give them your heart
in a minute.
Your soul.
And...
we did.
And we were going to help
each other stay clean.
And we did for a while, and...
I'd slip, and he'd be there
to catch me, and...
I'd do that for him, too.
But then it only took
one time. Once.
We hit it together.
It was a free fall.
His uncle had this apartment
in Paris, and...
the uncle lived in Dubai
or some fuck where.
And we stayed there
for a month,
and by the end of it,
we didn't talk to anybody
but the dealers who came by.
We were so bad,
one dealer started calling
to check on us.
And the deeper we got,
the more connected we were.
And it wasn't the drugs-
it wasn't the fuck up
that was killing us;
it was... the love.
I had split myself open
from the neck to the waist,
pried my ribs apart,
and he crawled in, and I...
I did the same with him.
One inside the other
inside the other.
We were this one person.
This... new organism.
It was like we were the mirror,
and then we scraped off the back-
the stuff that holds the reflection-
and... crushed it up
and cooked it and shot it...
Everything was dead.
But the love.
And the love was death.
And it never made a sound
but it was the loudest thing you ever heard.
It was over for me.
It was the end.
I was waking up disappointed
I was still alive.
And all the time,
I had in the back of my head-
way deep in the back
of my head-
me dying meant he would too.
So maybe that's what saved me-
knowing it was the only thing
that would save him.
One morning in Paris...
the apartment we lived in...
was in an alley with another
building really close across,
so there was only
a small amount of time
when any sun would get in the room,
at this point
where the sun would rise
just over...
the building across
on its way to overheard.
There'd be this little lick
of sun...
on the floor.
It'd last maybe less than an hour.
Most mornings, I'd sit in the corner
and wait for it
and watch it move across the floor
and disappear,
but this one time
it was... like... it...
wasn't moving.
Like it was staying there,
like it was calling to me,
so I...
I crawled
across the floor toward it,
slowly, slowly inward it,
and I... I stuck my hand
in it. I...
just laid my hand
on the floor in the sunlight,
and my body soaked it in
through my hand,
and it was like
the sunlight went to my brain,
like it went straight
to my brain, like it...
woke me up for a second.
Like it burnt out
all the shit
for a... a minute.
And my brain told me: "Go!
Or he'll die."
And somehow I got up
and I...
put on some clothes,
and I left him sleeping on the sofa,
and I left and I got out
and I...
found the sun and I just
started walking toward it,
like I was trying
to walk into it,
thinking: "Go! Go! Go! Go!
Or he'll die".
And I never went back.
- What was his name?
Something Scottish?
- Mark.
- Oh.
- Well, he said it
in that Scottish way.
Mark.
- What happened to him?
So is that love?
Leaving people is love?
- It's a kind of love.
- Is that what happened to us?
See, 'cause to me,
love isn't leaving, because...
love isn't something
that you're in-
that's just the love
that gets played on the radio.
And love isn't something
that crawls up inside you-
that's the love
they make movies about.
- What is it, then?
- I... I don't know.
I mean, I... I don't know.
But I know what it isn't.
I don't know.
Maybe my mother would know.
Your mother.
They seem to be able
to make it work.
The mothers, the wives...
- Making it work?
Is that love?
- Making it work? No, that's
a song they play on the radio.
On those late-night call-in
dedication shows.
- To the wives.
- To the wives everywhere.
- Can I ask you a question?
- What?
- Who do you... pray to?
- I don't know...
- See, how can you pray
if you don't know
who you're praying to?
- I just...
pray to whatever is...
keeping those other assholes sober.
- Right.
You sure this is it?
That's what it says
on the card.
- Whatever.
Let's check it out, I guess.
- Will you wait for us?
- How long?
- This long.
- I'll wait.
- You'd better come back.
- Don't worry.
We'll be back.
Hmm...
I don't know...
- Yeah, I don't know, either.
- I hated high school the first time.
- Needed to take 5 years to finish.
- Good one.
- Let's get out of here.
- Hey, hey! Hey!
Look what the oat dragged in!
- B.B.! Hey, gal!
- I didn't think
I'd see you here tonight.
Hey, Kat!
- Hey, BB.
- Jesus, girl,
you're awful skinny.
Must be that LA diet, is it?
Bullshit and bottled water?
- Good one.
You look the same.
- Ouch!
- No, you look good.
- Oh, yeah, right.
I'm about 1,000 years old.
Shut up.
Well, that was quite
the performance tonight.
- It wasn't me!
- Oh, yeah, right. Never was.
Me neither.
- So, is this the after party?
- Oh, well, I guess
one of the suits thought
it would be rad to get
messed up in a high school.
I don't know. Looks a bit like
Detroit Rock City meets Sweet Sixteen.
Look at these kids.
Thank God I'm not their age now.
I would be dead in a weekend.
Hey, let's go
to the green room.
Come on.
All the stalwarts are gathered.
- There's a green room.
- Yes, there's a green room.
Come on. Let's go.
Come on. it'll be fun.
- Apparently, Jeremy took one look
at the high school, and he wouldn't even
come up the driveway.
- He was probably scared
a bully would steal his bicycle.
- No, he's upgraded
to a scooter now.
- Which he rides all winter.
Fucking Canadian.
- Aren't you Canadian?
- I'm a Martian.
I'm a Saturnurite.
I'm a Plutonian.
- Yeah, don't listen to him,
honey.
He is so Canadian,
he probably shits loonies
- Veins full of maple syrup-
if I could find one.
- Beer?
- No, no. I'm good.
- Oh, she's good, all right.
She is very, very good.
- Toby played me some of the tracks
he engineered for you.
Really beautiful.
- Oh, it is what it is.
- That's the way to go, you know?
Scale it way back.
.Just you and a piano.
Keep it simple.
That's right.
"Keep it simple, stupid."
- I think she sets you off.
I do.
- Well... maybe I set her off.
- Well, you good?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? You clean?
- What about Kat?
- Uh, yeah. According to her.
- You know, sometimes I think
it's easier for junkies.
I mean, we've got the threat
of jail, right.
But... drunks? What do they got
to worry about?
Just, well, blackouts
and cirrhosis.
- Well, that's something
to worry about.
- Let me take you home.
- Oh, Kat's got a cab.
- No, no. I mean,
let me take you...
home... with me.
- Oh... Oh.
- Come on.
You're so beautiful.
- Eh... Um...
Mm...
It feels kinda... incest-y.
You know? Family...
Heh-heh-heh...
- Okay, sorry.
I couldn't help myself.
- That's all right.
- Well, maybe later, right?
Another time.
- Yep. You're the first in line.
- Well, I guess it should be
no surprise-
you can go home
with old money bags.
- What? Who?
- Kat.
I mean, she put up the dinero
for this Whole Shindig.
- I think I'd know that
if she did.
- Oh, really? Okay.
Well, I guess my sources aren't
all that reliable, then.
- Later...
- If you Change your mind,
I got a Car. I can give you a lift.
Got a hybrid now.
No more "Mustang Sally".
I am saving the planet.
- Right on.
Hey. You ready to head out?
Hey, what's up?
- Oh, yeah,
you're clean and sober!
- Hold on.
- Hey.
- Jesus.
- Here.
Hey, it's no big deal.
This wasn't my idea. It was his.
- Yeah, I wonder if his company
knows he smokes and drives.
Maybe I should give them a call.
- What? Since when did you Start
snitching to employers?
- You're exactly the same.
You say one thing and do another.
- I never said
I wasn't smoking pot.
Poi's not my problem.
- It's all a problem.
- Yeah, for you, maybe.
Aw, come on. Lighten up.
We could just take a cab.
- I'm not driving
with someone high.
- Well, we'll call another cab.
- I'd rather go with B.B.
- I don't live up to your expectation,
and you're just going to write me off?
- It's not my expectation.
- But I never tried to Sell you
on my Sainthood.
- Oh, yeah, yeah, sell-
that's all you've ever done,
from fucking lunchboxes...
prostitution...
- What are you talking about?
- I'm not talking to you
when you're high.
- I had two puffs.
It was Crappy Shit.
I'm not high.
Okay, I fucked up.
- So now you're apologizing?
- No, I'm not apologizing-
- Well, then get the fuck
away from me.
- Wait, wait.
- I don't want to play
these games any more,
and I don't want people
in my life who play these games.
- What games?
It's all a fucking game.
- "It's all a game."
You ask the question and
answer it in the same breath!
- You think it's not? Wake up, sister.
Just because you've grown fucking wings
doesn't mean the world
has turned into Heaven.
- Fuck you.
- Oh, good one. Nice one.
Yeah, you really got me there.
Nice comeback.
I'll see you after school.
Don't forget
to do your biology homework.
Hey. Hey!
Don't walk away from me!
Shit.
Vic, wait.
.Just wait.
- If you want to live
in a world of bullshit, fine.
At least believe in it!
At least believe in something!
- I want to. I do.
- You've put this whole thing
together, didn't you?
- No.
- Don't you think
you should have told me that?
- No, I did some consulting.
- What does that mean?!
- I just...
I threw some money at it.
- You paid
for a tribute to yourself.
- It was a benefit.
- For your ego!
- I.
I just wanted to see you.
- Why?
- I don't know what I need.
You say you have what you need,
but I don't know
what that is for me.
Nothing's... enough.
Nothing's ever enough.
And I...
I feel...
I want to...
You know me.
You are the only person
who knows me.
And I do what
I'm supposed to do, you know?
And there are these promises,
but they're not coming true
for me, and...
...I need your help.
- My help?
Fuck-
- Do you know hard it is for me
being sober
every fucking day?
- Oh, you and your wine coolers,
and your cranberry martinis!
- Oh, you think I don't want
to get high too?
- You just did!
Congratulations!
OW! Oh!
- Oh! Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
- I'm bleeding!
- Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
I was just trying to-
- Trying to what? You hit me!
- Just talk to me.
- If you're going
to fuck yourself up,
I don't want to be around
to watch, okay?
- I had two puffs.
I got overwhelmed.
I just, I got a lot going on,
that's all.
- Yeah, well, I got a lot
on my mind, too, all right?
I might be fucking dying.
- What?
- I've got a liver biopsy.
- You had one,
or you have to have one?
- They saw something.
- You had one,
or you have to have one?
- I'm having one!
- Okay, well, I've had two.
It's... it's no big deal.
They're always seeing stuff on my liver.
- Oh, so, what, you're saying
your liver is worse than mine?
- I know it is.
- My liver's like a sponge.
- It's supposed to be like a sponge!
Mine's like a fucking stone.
- I don't think so.
- Uh, don't tell me about my liver.
- Yeah, well don't tell me about my liver!
I think I know my own liver!
- Ah, but if you did,
you wouldn't need to have a biopsy.
- Fuck you.
Everybody's dying.
- Oh!
I don't care
about the destination.
I'm more concerned
about the velocity.
- Here, let me see your eyes.
- Why?
- Iridology.
I see the best iridologist in LA.
Uh...
Okay.
- What?
- Well, just look up
into that lighting.
Oh...
- What?
What?
- Sugar. You eat a lot of sugar?
- I try to cui down.
- And salt.
Yeah. Salt's the real problem.
You eat a lot of salt!
- I like saliy...
- Well, salt..
...Salt binds the toxins
so you can't Sweat them out.
That's what's going on
with your liver.
Do you read labels?
- What labels?
- Food labels.
There's salt in everything.
You've got to read the labels.
- The print is too small.
- Well, wear your glasses
when you go to the store, you know?
No more salt
There's something on my liver.
- It's the SEMI.
It is.
- Okay.
it's the salt.
- It is.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Let's get the fuck
out of here.
- Oh!
- What?
- Oh, it's just
my shoulder goes out sometimes.
- It's not my fault.
- I didn't say that it was.
- You're the one who attacked me.
- Fine. Fine.
- My lip is killing me.
- Oh, come on.
- Are you sure it's not bleeding?
- It's not bleeding.
- What's wrong with your leg?
- Oh, it's my knee.
From running.
I might have to stop running.
- Mm. You shouldn't be
attacking people.
Here, give me your arm.
- Well, fuck, watch my Shoulder.
OW!
- Is it your shoulder
or your collarbone?
- Uh, it's my shoulder.
- 'Cause you broke
your collarbone that time in Cuba
when you fell off a moped.
- No, no. it's my shoulder.
It's my rotator cuff.
- Is that the thing that you scrape?
- Yeah.
I'm wrecking my knee, too.
You and I
we make a grand salute
Stare at each other
Like lost little birds
across the room
And I remember
the way you looked
I learned how to dance
But I'd never shown it to you
My love
Stay for a while
While our leaves are still green
Please
- We played our song.
- Our hit.
- Our greatest hit.
- We Should put it out on EP.
- Asingle.
- Forty-five.
Running out of room
All night saying
That you're standing
alongside gone
I know I tried
But it's hard sometimes
The routes don't take
It takes a while
And you pull at the strings
But they're broken it seems
The dance isn't over for me
No my love
I know I was wrong
But you know
that you'll always be
My love...
- Check them out.
It's quite a sight.
- I always wanted to do that.
- You always used to say
you wanted to snowshoe.
- Yeah.
Yeah, and I did.
- How was it?
- Brutal.
Cold.
- Well, what did you expect?
- Elation.
- Ah, well, that's setting
the bar a bit high, I think.
- But I did, though,
feel something like that.
Elation.
But it was afterwards,
sitting at the fire,
thinking about having snowshoed.
But that's the thing, isn't it?
It's not the doing that feels good;
it's the having done it.
- Yeah, it's the surviving it.
- What if the sun doesn't come up?
- The sun will come up.
- What if the Mayans are right?
Calendar stops
and it all just ends.
- Wasn't that supposed
to have already happened?
- And the Earth explodes
into four flaming orbs.
- A flaming orb.
- According to the Mayans,
four flaming orbs.
- Nice.
- And it just ends.
Everything reduced to balls of ash
and melted plastic
hurtling through space.
What difference
does it all make then?
All the music, the gigs,
the deals...
The art, the beauty, the men...
Jaeger...
Pregnancy tests, bad biopsies...
Maybe that's it:
there is no everything;
just me and my everything.
My calendar, my ending.
- A flaming orb.
- Four flaming orbs.
- Okay.
Well, that's like four suns, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- And the sun created the universe,
so there you go.
You have four brand new universes.
- Four universes of fuck up.
- And wonder.
See, that's what people really want.
Wonder; not sex, not more stuff.
What they want is wonder.
That's... that's what...
the new world is: wonder.
Four new universes
of fuck up...
and wonder.
It's progress.
- It's something.
- It's cold.
- You want your sweater?
- No, you keep it.
This is nice.
- Yeah.
It's nice.
- God.
- Yeah.
This time in between
the day and the night
The light kills
my sense of life
So scared
I'll turn it on
Turn it on turn it on
turn it on
its dull this dusk
this desk this dust
My eyes adjust
I'll blow out the Name
Can you and me remain
Changes
I've never been good
with change
I hate it when
it all stays the same
Caught between
the cold and the wave
My heart beats up again
Once said
Words make a world of their own
I misread
I can? get you
back on the phone
So tired
I'll turn it off turn it off
turn it off
How's that
last week we were whole
You're far away
And I hardly know
Can you and me delay
Changes
I've never been good
with change
I hate it when
it all stays the same
Caught between
the gold and the gain
Changes
I've never been good
with change
Troubled when
it all stays the same
I'm caught between
this cold and the wave
My heart beats up again
Are you my trouble
Trouble