Subtitle by: Kamyar (BiGBang)
Dr Léo SEMENEAU - MD
Let's go !
Come on !
Again...
You should stop the cigarettes Mr Perrin.
Yes doctor.
Of course, you always say that..
Put your clothes on.
No I didn't forget you Mrs Calmat.
Don't worry.
See you later.
- OK. We'll see each other the 20th, as usual.
- Good.
It's no big deal...
You'll pay me next time, ok ?
Christelle ?
Is the 321 ready ?
Ok, can you come here one minute please ?
What do I do with that guy then ?
What guy ?
Do you take his call ?
Listen Malécot...
I haven't finished yet...
Always on time
I don't want to wait anymore, Léo.
I want to die.
Breakfast, please.
Malécot !
Listen Malécot I've nothin to tell him,
What's this ?
It's all his faxes actually.
You psycho !
I'm coming !
Come on, let's eat !
- Come in !
Come, come, come !
What's this shit ?
Come see this !
- Fuck no, let's go now !
- Please...
Yeah...
Last night
Oh shit !
I hope I didn't make a mistake...
Shiiiiit ! Shit !
You wouldn't have a cigarette Malécot  ?
Thank you.
- I need six months.
It doesn't fit !
You know that i don't ask for much.
I need a little time.
It does not fit !
Do it for Coré at least!
I can't...
Allo ? Who's calling ?
You don't feel well ?
Yes...
Hello. How are you ?
See you tomorrow honey.
English subtitles : Ericb