Isha, get up dear...
Deep, get up!
Vijay, get up!!
Take this.
Slowly.
Thief! Thief!!
What are you looking at?
Hit him!
It's you!!
You play lot of mischief!!
And even you all are a part of it.
Come on, childrens...
Come, my army!
Now, I'll open my shop & show it to you all.
What have I bought for you?
Switch it off or else it will fly!
There are lots of garnes in it.
This is for you...
Why do you always enter the house
like a suspense film hero?
To teach a lesson to yourmother!
If some instance happens like this
then she should be able to face it!
What was she telling?
Thief! Thief!!
Look who is it?
There should be some courage. Isn't it?
But, papa. What kind of tour this is...
where you can't even stay for 10 days with us.
What shall I do, my sweet heart!
My duty is as such.
Take us to see a film today, papa.
So, you want to go to see a film.
Okay, I'll surely take you all.
Now, we'll get ready to go to school.
Yes, of course!
Hey, what are you doing this?
The children's have gone to school.
Now, it's you & myself!
Look, full stop after 2...
So that wife remalns tlp top!
Even in these tlmes, you've made me mother of 4!
Sorry, I don't want any more kids now!
Shall I do my family planning?
It's women who do family planning!
Why shall you do it?
I'll do it.
From the day, you've come into my life...
I haven't pinched you at your cheek!
Whether the sign of my nails doesn't appear.
How could I allow doctor's knife
to operate on your body?
Whethermy heart will not cut into pieces!!
Why are you staring at me like this?
I couldn't really make out whether
you are a good or bad guy!
Means?
I mean, you love me a lot!
But, you never listen to my that...
Forget it! I have to go.
It's time formy class.
Greetlngs!
Greetlngs!!
The Ashram students are learning it fondly!
Melody arises even from lifeless stones
with Tulsi's singing!!
This is your greatness that you are praising me!
I'll move. It's tlme for class.
Students, there is some power which runs
not only this earth but the whole galaxy!
Today, we'll pray to that power itself.
We will ask something from it.
Not only for us but for everybody in this world!
Give it!
Tell me one thing.
You go on tour once, but ask for advance twice.
What is it?
Is it going from your pocket?
Boss told me to take advance as permy wish.
I have to take my family for outing.
That's why...
I know your habit very well.
You drarnatlze on behalf of your family!
Don't ask for any advance henceforth.
You said this even last tlme.
But, this is last tlme.
Each tlme you say the sarne thing.
Yes, of cours. E!
Atleast sign & go...
Okay...
One minute.
Hey, it's your phone.
Take it.
Hey Suraj.
Yes, Vikrarn.
Let's sit together tonlght.
No! Today I've to take my family for outing.
Not today!
It's been long tlme.
Please come.
I'll come for a short tlme.
Atleast you come.
Okay!
Deep, are you ready?
Yes, I'm ready.
Bring everybody out.
Hey Suraj, our friendship should be
like liquor & kebabs. Isn't it?
No, it should be like whisky & soda!!
Mummy, it's 8 p.m. & papa hasn't yet come.
He might be coming...
Must have stuck in some work.
Pa. Pa has come!!
Daddy has come!!
Hey, my childrens...
I have come.
Look, what have I bought for you.
Mom, you said that papa will not drink
& we'll take us to see movie tonlght.
Isha, take him...
You'll go inside.
Tulsi, do you know why do I drink?
I drink it forpaln!
What is my paln?
I feel that I'm doing some mistake!
And the mistake is that I'm drinking!!
And when I drink, you feel sad!
When you feel sad, even I feel sad!!
So, I drink!
But, you don't worry!
I'm there...
You broke children's heart!
Children's heart never breaks!!
What have you bought?
Chicken lollypop!!
Pizza...
Come in, have your dinner.
Did children had their dinner?
Yes.
Did you eat?
Tell me something...
What do you get after drinking everyday?
I feel good!
I feel that I've become alive!
I feel fantasy within me!
I become happy!
I like everything then...
Then, I feel like loving you!!
I feel that I've become a millionaire!
I could give you anything.
I'm fed up! Why don't you understand?
You are invitlng death by drinking everyday!
Really?
Why don't you unders. Tand?
Okay! I'll not drink from tomorrow.
I swear on my head!
Lets go, the food is gettlng cold!
Put the food on your head to warm it!
My anger seems to diminlsh with your talks!!
Let's go.
Be careful!
You yourself will fall along with me as well.
Greetlngs!!
Long live, dear.
Please forgive me for coming a little late.
It's not little but more late!
As per the Ashram. Rule, no one can live
in the room here more than 5 years!
And for you it's more than 10 years.!!
Swarniji couldn't refuse you on the
behest of your children's & yourself.
But, there's a lot of notlces
come from the organizatlon.
The room of Ashrarn in which you live,
shall be taken back.
Dear, don't feel bad!
How could I feel bad when you all
thought good for us all these years.!!
But, when thunder strikes, someone is burnt!
It seems I'm going to burn this tlme.
Why do you say this, dear?
The othernarne of life is struggle!
If my husband wasn't a drunkard, then
we could have bulld our own house tlll now.
I think my fate is as such.
The whole fault is of your husband!
Today, I'll make him qult his liquor!
I'll see how do he don't listen to me?
Hey, Suraj...
Wait...
You scoundrel!
Greetings, Suraj brother!!
Come, sit.
Bring me a quarter.
You seem to be tensed.
What's the problem?
That Swami is following me.
Who?
Give me Soda.
Take it from here.
Hey, Suraj brother.
You are going down...
No, nothing.
Come what may happen now...
Hey Rajendra, that table number3...
Swamiji? Here??
May be he has come to drink!
But, he is shy of coming inside.
He is asking after coming to the bar
that whetherit is there?
Whether you'll get milk inspite of liquor here!!
Swamiji, everything is there.
But, do come inside.
If I'll go from front, he will run away.
Therefore, he s calling me from back doors!
Sit, here.
Sir, what will you take?
Beer, whisky, Ginn, vodka...
You scoundrel, illiterate!!
Have I come here to drink liquor?
If not, then why did you come here?
I have come here to qult Suraj's liquor!
Houses get ruined because of drinking.
Drinking isn't a good habit!
If you have such good thoughts for me then
you should have bought a bowl forme as well.
Why?
If you stop everybody's liquor then,
my shop will be closed forever!!
Then, I have to take the bowl to beg for alms!!
Give upon the narne of God!!
You please go from here.
No, I won't go tlll I qult Suraj's liquor.
You will have to go!
Hurry up! My throat is drying!!
Swamiji in the bar!
What tlme has come.
If you were having this much urge for liquor
then, you should have told me.
You scoundrel! Stop your nonsense!!
What will you serve me & what will I drink?
You'll drink wine, since you've come here.
We'll sit & have 2 pegs together.
I was out of my mind that I carne here.
What wrong did I tell him?
I only sald 2 pegs!
Why did you said only 2 pegs?
He is bound to get angry!
You should have told 2 bottles!!
Yourfriend Suraj...
How much he loves his wife & kids!!
And you...
Tulsi is that much pretty too!
And listen...
What will that Suraj love her?
If she agrees, I swear that
I'll spend my entlre life on her!!
These swirling hips!!
Tulsi, give me the basket.
Your hands are very gentle!
Leave my hand.
I swear, you don't look mother of 4.
Stop your nonsense!!
Tulsi, I don't like you see walking everyday.
I'll buy you a ladies bike!
Qulckly to Ashram. & qulckly to home!!
Only couple of times in a week...
Come & teach music to my kids.
I don't have the necessity to go to houses & teach.
But, I do have.
Look Tulsi, your husband remalns out
of house for 15 days, along with his car.
And the rest of the days,
he is intoxicated with liquor!
What happiness he could give you?
Shall I give you?
That's enough!
I warn you for the last time.
If you do it again, I'll inform my husband!
And you very well know how my husband is?
She went away ringing the bell!
Liquor has started darnaging your liver now...
Suraj, if you want to live more...
Qult alcohol!
I'm tlred of telling him!
He doesn't leave it.
I wish to qult but, it doesn't leave.
Then, you will have to lose this world!
Look Suraj, there's a doctorin Shyarngaon.
Dr. Raj Sharma...
who gives herbal medicine...
From which you'll be able to qult alcohol!
Okay, I'll send him tomorrow morning itself.
Is it really necessary to fetch medicine?
Your liveris being darnaged by alcohol.
You will die!
There's no connectlon of liquor with liver!
Those who don't drink, even die!
But, who drink lives a longer life!!
Look at our washer man, his age is 60 years...
He drinks day & nlght.
There's no problem at all.
He is fit & healthy!
And that milk man, he never touched liquor...
died at the age of 25 years.!!
There is no connectlon of alcohol with liver!
In fact, alcohol is tonlc for body!
So, alcohol is tonlc!
Yes, it is.
I didn't know that it is good for health.
So, even I'll start drinking from today onwards.
What?
Liquor!
No.
It's not good for woman!!
Why? Men have 2 livers??
No!
Look, when you will leave drinking.
Your health will be fine!
If you aren't healthy, then what
will happen to our children's?
Please leave alcohol.
Return just as you are going.
Absolutely fresh! Okay?
Move...
Be qulck!
You are gettlng late for the school.
Everybody has 1 God in their house.
Why do we have 3 God's?
How much faces does God have...
He is only One.
I didn't understand...
Let me explaln you.
What do you call papa in English?
Father.
In Hindi?
Pltaaji.
And in Urdu?
Abbaji
But, the meaning of all 3 is one.
Whetherit's Allah for Muslim, God for Christlans
& Ram for Hindus.
All the 3 are one!
Everybody in their own ways worship God
to get rid of sorrows!
No matter by what narne they call...
But the one who listens is the sarne.
Do you remember Gandhiji's saying?
Mom, what did you ask from God today?
Everyday, I ask the sarne thing from God...
that your father qults alcohol.
Stop the bus!
Stop!!
But, why are you stopping the bus?
I want to get down.
But, you've taken a tlcket for Shyamgaon?
I know it. It's upto me wherever I wish...
I've taken the tickets!
Did you do the homework?
Yes, I did.
Even, I did it.
Where is your father?
He has gone to the town.
He'll be back within 2 days!
He could even come today evenlng,
if he completes his job!!
You seem to chatter very much!!
Like Tulsi...
Are you'll going to school?
No, we are going to a disco, wearing this uniform
along with our books!!
Come on go...
The bell has rung!!
You?
Yes, it's me.
He is not at home.
Therefore, I've come here.
Means?
Now, even a married woman has
to be explained the meaning of this?
Get away from here!!
The bottle of the infant is empty.
I'm a milk tra. Der...
I'll flow rivers. Of milk for you.
Get away, I sald!
Look Tulsi...
I've driven huge tempos & trucks in my life!!
But, I have never driven a
gentle vehicle like you!!
I've tasted several. Women in my life!
But, never tasted a melodious woman like you!
Look, let's have fun!
Get out of here!!
Do agree...
I'm your friend's wife!
Be mine for sometime.
Leave me!!
What are you doing?
Get out of here!!
Vijay, Deep... stop!
Isha, come back!
Take it.
Vijay, take it.
I'll tell you why did I drink?
That doctor...
That doctor told me that
he can't give me medicine.
He said that my liver
isn't ready for the medicine.
He told me to drink for one month!
Drink plenty of it!
And then I'll give you medicine.
And it will work then...
I swear on you
I'm sorry!
My swear...
I was just telling...
Till yesterday you only got drunk...
Now you've started telling lies from today!
You don't care for us!
Are you aware what all we have to pass through?
Even if we die, you'll survive on liquor!
But, you'll never change!
What are you telling?
Do you know what does
the society thinks of me?
Wife of a drunkard!
And our childrens...
Drunkard's childrens!!
Are you aware of what look does
the society gives to such childrens?
I have to listen to such taunts!
How will your husband keep you happy?
I feel like dying after listening such taunts!!
Why are you talking such?
I've nearly saved myself from burning!
What is the point in telling you all this?
Tell me what happened?
Papa, your friend Vikram. Broke into the house
& tried to molest Mom!
Let's talk in the bar.
In the bar?
Let's talk in your neighborhood.
In your house...
Vandana...
What happened?
You call me brother?
Yes.
So, you are my sister.
What would be the relatlon
of my wife with this pig?
Sister!
This bastard has tried to molest his sister!!
From which mouth did you say that to her?
Get away, sister in law.
I beg of you!
Please forgive him.
For the sake of my children...
Hence forth, if you ever tried to look
towards my house, I'll kill you!
He is really a scoundrel!
He is a very bad man!
He will surely remember this day forever!!
He will get rotten with worms!!
Your husband has abused me
before the whole neighborhood...
He has only hurt my body...
But, I'll ruin his entlre life!!
Leep this in mind!
Vijay... didn't we had lot of fun yesterday?
Papa is really great!
Did you see how much happy the kids are?
Give me papa, I'll press your shirt.
The lines from the fore head of your
mother has vanished!
What difference does it make
if there's lines on my shirt?
Isha, take care of the child!
I'll pack your papa's bag.
Pa. Pa, you know that you are going to town...
Qulckly give your shirt!
Forget this & tell me what do you want
me to bring for you.
One Punjabi sult with silk thread embroidery!
Along with that veil which has golden border!!
What do you want?
I want an imported bat!
Like Rarnesh has.
He acts too smart with that bat.
I'll bring Sachin Tendulkar's bat for you.
Then, he will envy your bat!
What do you want?
A super computer!
You study too much!
You'll surely become a doctor!!
And what about me?
You are a stylish boy,
I'll make you a hero!
I'll become an inspector!
And what will you become?
I've put lemon pickle in the bag.
Don't remaln hungry for your dislike
for hotel food.
Atleast eat little along with this pickle.
What shall I bring for you?
I don't want anything.
You left liquoris enough for me!
But, what will this poor guy get?
Hey papa...
I'll come soon.
Say, Bye to papa...
Shall I come along with you till the road.
Yes, come...
Deep, be careful!
Pa. Pa, will you race.
Of cours. E!
Be ready, papa.
Today, I'll defeat you.
I won!
That's it!
You defeated a car!
Now, go home.
Okay, papa.
Son Suraj, today I'll ring your bells...
I'll darken your home forever!
Is my son really very serious?
There's a huge blood loss.
But, don't worry!
He will be alright after blood transmission!
The blood group of mother & son are sarne.
Take Tulsi's blood! Okay, Sir.
Stop taking Tulsi's blood.
Okay, Sir.
Varsha, stop taking her blood!
Okay!
How is his conditlon, now?
Doctor says he will be aright.
There's nothing to worry!
Doctoris calling.
Not you, but Swamiji.
There's nothing to worry!
I'll see it.
Please be seated, Swamiji.
What is the relation of yours with Tulsi?
Tulsi & her husband Sura. J...
Both are orphan!
They grew up in our Ashrarn &
they happened to love each other.
Where is Tulsi's husband right now?
He is on a tour with his employer.
So, whom shall I talk to right now?
Doctor, you could speak to me.
Tulsi is like my daughter.
Call Tulsi.
Okay, Sir.
Doctoris calling you.
Yes, doctor!
There's nothing to fear for...
Your son will be fine!
Tulsi, do you always have
headache & body ache?
Nothing that sort of happens to my son.
I'm not asking about your son but you.
You are talking about me?
Do you bleed sometlme from the nose?
Yes, but sometlmes.
How many tlme did it happen?
I don't remember exactly. But...
I've taken medicine from the doctor.
He sald that it's sinus problem!
Do you feel dizzy along with headache?
Yes, it happens sometimes.
But, becomes normal after taking paln killer tablet.
Okay, you walt outside.
I'll call you.
It's the son who has met with an accident &
you are asking his mother about her health!
We accidentally carne to know about
mother's bad health due to son's accident.
This is a coincidence!
When we tested mother's blood
to tran. Smit in her son's body.
When the chief technician
of our lab got suspicion.
Therefore, we had to ask
certaln questlon to Tulsi.
See, this is Tulsi's blood report!
Tell me Swarniji... Why did they
not give my blood to my son?
What is the reason behind their questlons?
Tulsi, when will Sura. J return?
Why are you asking about Sura. J?
What is that thing which you are hiding from me?
Is there any threat to the life of my son
No, Tulsi. Your son's life is well secured!
But...
Doctors. Have advised you to take rest.
They have restricted you to think
& put pressure on the brai. N!
But, what happened to me?
I'm hale & hearty!
You shall remaln hale & hearty! Therefore,
doctors. Have advised you to take rest.
No, Swamiji...
There's something for sure.
Which you are hiding from me.
Tell me clearly what happened to me?
Swamiji, I'm not a child!
I've read yourface!
But, I couldn't make out...
What's the matter?
I haven't seen your face like this before.
I'm an orphan!
I've grownup after acceptlng this bitter truth!
The one whom I made my life partner,
becarne partner of liquor!
I swallowed even this bitter truth like honey!
If fate has given me another bitterpoison then,
I have the guts & courage to drink even that!!
Tell me, Swamiji.
Which storm is hiding behind your silence?
Tell me... I'll face it.
I've learnt to live dyingly!
Swamiji, don't hesitate.
I have the power to tolerate it.
Tell me...
You might be having power to listen but,
my tongue doesn't have power to speak!
Anyway, which is about to open tomorrow...
Let it be disclosed today itself!
Doctor has diagnosed a dangerous allment!
But, will this allment get better after treatment?
It's a permanent ailment!
When it comes, it takes you along.
You'll not live more than 23 months!!
You have got blood cancer.
Don't leave them.
Deep, catch hold of it.
Deep get inside...
You all get inside.
Tulsi, take these chicken & prepare Chicken chilly,
chicken fry, chicken masala & pasta too.
My friends have come for dinner!
My son is saved!
I'm very happy!
Forme, chicken roast!
Forme, chicken curry!
Forme, salad.
Salad?
Does salad is made out of chicken?
Yes, it can be made.
Make even salad.
Also make some 2/3 dishes.
Intoxicatlon won't do in this house!
Make arrangement of dinner outside itself.
What nonsense!
Hold this!
Suraj, it seems sister in law is not in mood today.
Forget it for today, we'll have dinner
some other day.
There's no such thing.
Her mood is alright!
I'll see it myself.
She listens to me.
His wife isn't in his control.
Let's go somewhere else or
we'll not even get salad.
Did a worm go into your braln?
I invited my friends for dinner
& you insulted them?
Why are you staring like this?
Who is the owner of this house?
How did I come outside?
I rai. Sed my hand on you
under the infiuence of alcohol...
I'm not human but devil!
I swear on God!
Tell me what shall I do?
I'm not crying because you beat me...
I'm worried about our childrens.
What will happen to them?
If you keep on drinking this way...
I'm afrai. D our children don't get scattered!!
Everything will be alright.
I don't have courage to tell you
but couldn't resist also.
What happen?
I don't really know...
When we have not done
anything wrong to anybody...
Then, why did he ruin our fate?
I don't unders. Tand what you are telling?
Tulsi, I'm a bit scared!
What exactly are you trying to say?
I'm soon leaving you all, forever!
You will be going...
Will you go leaving us all?
Will you go leaving me alone?
Have you gone mad?
Do you?
Where will you go?
That day in the hospital, when they
took my blood to tran. Smit to Deep...
What are you telling?
Are you plating prank on me?
For I raised my hand on you.
You are lying. Aren't you?
It's a fact!
She is a goddess!
She worship your Gods!!
Not one but she worships every God!!
Then, why she has to face so much paln?
What way is this... of your God?
Isn't this justice?
If he was to give punishment...
He should have given me!
I'm alcoholic!
I have given paln to my wife
& childrens by drinking liquor!
He should have given this pain to me.
This allment!
But, even I haven't done anybody's wrong!
I earn myself & drink from my earnings.
And then sleep.
If she will not be there...
What will happen to my childrens?
I'll not allow this to happen.
Before doing anything to Tulsi,
he has to kill me!
You better tell your God!
I very well unders. Tand your paln.
We both cannot do anything agalnst his wishes.
You could do a favor forTulsi.
I can give my life for her!
Tell me what shall I do?
Now, whatever tlme is left with her...
Let her live in peace & harmony!!
And you very well know,
from which act of yours...
She'll achieve utmost peace!
Tell me what you wish to say?
I have one desire...
Will you fulfill it?
Tell me...
You do a second marriage!
What?
What are you telling?
I'm rightly saying so...
After I've gone, children shouldn't feel my absence.
Our childrens should get the affectlon
which we both didn't get in our childhood.
Therefore, you bring anothermother for them.
How did you think that another woman
could give affectlon like you?
Nobody could render love like my Tulsi...
One doesn't get live body
after ruhning behind shadows!!
You don't think that way...
Nothing will happen to you.
I'm not afrai. D of dying but I regret that...
I could not shower affectlon on my childrens!
One more thing...
Childrens shouldn't come to know
about my allment.
Because while dying, I want to see them happy!
These are your medicines.
And this is yourmoney.
What is it?
Take your tempo away.
And if I not get it away then?
Will you beat me again?
Forget it!
You've once beat me very much!
I did ring bell of your son!
With this tempo itself.
His fate was good that he survived!
Look Vikrarn, whateveris past...
Forget it!
I don't want to fight with anybody.
Is it alright?
I'm going. Okay?
I don't want to fight!
Leave me...
You & your wife has given me
lot of pain & agony!!
Leave me...
I'm telling you for the last time.
I don't want to fight!
If I wish, I can kill you right now!
I'm sparing you only because you have a family!
No, Vikram!
You've come with a plan to kill me!!
Don't do it.
My wife will survive for few days...
My childrens will be orphaned!
Don't kill me!!
What happen to you?
Don't call the childrens.
They will not be able to see me in this condition.
I couldn't give you any happiness in life!
I thought of giving it for some days...
What did this happen?
I think your God listened to me.
I'm going before you!
What sort of things are you saying?
Nothing will happen to you.
You cannot leave us like this...
Our childrens shouldn't be orphaned!!
It's you who has to take of our childrens,
when I die!
You promised me!
You cannot break that promise!!
Nothing will happen.
Let's go to the hospital.
Thank you Mummy formaking
brinjal dish forme!
I had told you forpaneer curry & bread.
Did you prepare it, Mom?
Yes, I've made.
If I'm not there, then who will cook
& feed you all these?
Will you not live with us?
I wish to live with you
but, I have to go!
Where will you go, Mom?
I have never gone there before...
But, it's too far!
Mom, take us also...
Don't talk such thing.
How will we live without you?
You have to live, son!
It's the decision of fate!!
I've found a very good job, far away!
I have to go.
No, Mom. Don't go leaving us alone.
Don't talk such thing, dear.
I'll be happy only when your life will be settled.
Don't you want to give me happiness?
Yes, we do.
So, do it as I say...
Before going there, I'll make your arrangements.
I'll hand over one by one to good family!
You'll get good clothes, good food...
And very loving parents!!
Everything will be there.
Please give all of us in one house only.
How could anyone take care
of 4 childrens in one house?
You manage us...
I arn your mother!
But, Mom...
Give both of us in one house.
Because Vijay always needs me.
Sure, dear.
I'll give you both in one house only.
Please come, Doctor.
Tulsi, I'd told you about a doctor.
Yes.
He is Dr. Michael D' Souza &
his wife Dr. Anjali D' Souza
Please come.
Doctor, I'll be back soon.
Okay.
Tulsi, show them the children.
They have to go!
Rest of the formality...
We'll do it afterwards.
Oh, baby!
What is your narne?
He is very cute!
You'll carry on the conversatlon,
I'll be back. Okay.
Swamiji must have told you about us.
Why are you crying?
What happened to you??
We liked the baby very much!!
Okay.
Tulsi, one minute...
If you want to ask anything...
You can ask.
Tulsi has a small worry!
So, you better ask me.
I promise, I'll not feel bad for anything.
Today, you have no child.
What if tomorrow you have one then?
We both are doctors...
We've come to know aftermany tests
that no child could be born!
Therefore, we consciously decided to adopt a child!
And for your convenlence, I'm ready to
make my entlre property in his narne!!
As it is, after I adopt this child...
He will be mine forever!!
Do you have any objection?
Take this, doctor.
Chotu, what are you doing?
Are you playing??
Look here, Chotu.
Play with us!
No, mummy!!
Will youjust go on eatlng...
Will you not pay attentlon towards me?
Your name should have been Fakirchand (beggar)
Instead of Ameerchand (wealthy)
Look Swami. You are my childhood friend.
Yes.
You very well know, I don't like unnecessary expense!
Therefore, I'll adopt only one child
& save other child's money!
What will I do by tying 2 children's
like a mufflerin my neck?
And that too, a handicap!
I'll better die but not take both of them.
You be seated.
Look Swami, you are my friend
that's why I'm adopting a child!
But, I don't know anything later.
My wife doesn't like to take
even one child in her arms.
What happen, Swamiji?
It's a sad news for all of us.
My friend isn't ready to adopt both the childs!
But, they both are twins!!
It would be better if they live tgether.
Vijay will seek Deeps assistance.
I know it. But, he refused.
Any reason forit?
He doesn't want to adopt a handicap child!
You don't worry!
We'll find somebody who could
embrace him affectlonately.
Don't lose this opportunity.
If he is taking one child, let him take.
Tulsi, agree to what I'm saying.
As you wish.
She is mother of these childrens.
Dear, say good morning to uncle & aunty.
Come this way...
Look, one seems to be calm!
But, is handicap of no use.
And the other seems to be very cunning!
He will cheat us in future!
Therefore, I say to save money
& quietly get away from here.
Will you remain qulet?
Look how sad they are?
But, why should I become sad
after taking their expenses
Two?
Take this, dear.
Take it!
Even you take this.
How pretty these childrens are?
Why did you give sweets to both of them?
You should give only to the one
whom we have chosen.
Or else both will come together.
And my pocket will tear!
You are always like this.
Now, let's go!
Don't keep that in my bag.
It's your school uniform.
The school uniform there will be different.
Isn't it?
Deep, when you'll come back?
What do I know?
My good son!
Be good there also...
Don't fight with anybody.
Where do I get tlme to fight?
Why, dear?
The whole day will pass thinking of you!!
You go ahead, I'll bring it.
Hurry up! If it's late in the evenlng.
Then, we have to switch on the head light!
The guarantee of bulb will expire.
Come on, hurry up!
How do I bid farewell to you?
I don't know?
When you will understand...
Make her understand as well.
Now, let's go!
Tulsi sister, we have to go now.
Whenever women talk to each other,
it seems dally soaps have started.
They are going on hugging each other.
Hurry up!
What's going on?
Now, let's go!
What are you thinking, Vijay?
When are you going, sister?
Where?
Kust like Chotu & Deep went away!!
When are you going?
Mom was telling that somebody is coming
to take you as well.
I will not go anywhere...
I will not go anywhere leaving you both.
His conversatlon is like the web of a spider!
Anybody could be trapped!
Talk only that what you've come for...
Why are you tra. Pped between spider & flies!!
Look, we had a strong desire for a girl!
We thought of naming her 'Arzoo'
But, she didn't allow me to fulfill my desire.
Be qulet!
I had 3 son's
The elder son died in a plane crash!
The 2nd one is in America.
And the 3rd is settled in Canada.
But, neither they are interested in property
nor in their old parents!!
Forget it!
Now, we will not go to moon
for such petty things.
We are born at this land & we desire
to even get bury in this land itself.
We want support in this age!
A daughter to take care of us!
Tell me, when are you sending
your daughter to us?
Look, you don't worry!
When the tlme comes, I'll take the responsibility
of marrying her to a well to do family!
This is a promise from both of us!!
Till then, we'll keep herin utmost comfort!
Because tlll now our affectlon for children
hasn't diminlshed yet.
Even my affectlon is stlll alive!
We will quench her thirst for affectlon
by giving her loads of love!
Call the girl!
My daughteris a piece of a moon!!
We'll take hernext full moon day!
The feeling of our Ioneliness is now over!
God Bless you.
Let's go!
Okay, dear!
We'll leave...
I'll not go anywhere...
I'll stay here only.
Here? Till when
Till you are here, I'll stay with you.
And with my brother after you leave!
But, I'll stay here itself.
Please Mom, don't refuse!!
Please!
You are very intelligent daughter of your mother!
If you don't listen to her then, who will?
How can I leave her alone
inspite of knowing her allment?
Swamiji, don't send me anywhere.
Because I'm not going anywhere.
If I go away... then who will
take care of my mother?
You don't worry about it!
Kust listen to your mother.
But...
Let me live with her, tlll she goes.
Dear, tlme is very less!
Your mother shall attain this satlsfactlon that
she has sent all of you to good families!!
It's not that way, Swamiji.
Look, we'll take care of your mother.
There's no need for you to worry!
Be happy!
Come, dear!
Vijay, dear...
Mom!
What happen, Mom?
Get the medicine.
Now, there's no need for you to come agaln.
Did you understand?
Yes, I do.
Now, coming here will not stop me
from going there...
Is it a good luck of mine to be born handicap?
What are you talking?
If I would have been fit like my brother & sister...
Then somebody might take me as well.
I'm handicap! That's why I'm still with you.
This is my good luck itself.
Isn't it, Mom?
Dear Isha...
My blessings are always with you!
You always remaln happy!
I went to the doctor.
He said that there's no need
for any further treatment.
We'll meet in this Diwali at our home.
I'll make food from my own hands
& feed you all.
This is my last wish!
And even my happiness!!
I'm very tensed thinking about Vijay!
What will happen to him?
Nobody carne to adopt this handicap child!
To invite you for Diwali...
Vijay & myself will come in person.
I'll give you the address of Deep & Chotu.
Because after I go away...
You are their mother!!
Mother! Mother!!
You gave me this deadly allment!
I did accept it!
When I started gettlng happiness from husband...
You snatched him suddenly!
I considered it to be my fate!
You separated my children's with my own hands!!
I tolerated even this!
Neither did I complain nor did I ask for something...
But, I'm asking today!
Give me life for one nlght!
I want to see my childrens for the last time!!
Hey Sal, do favor on me!!
Hey Kesus, have pity on me!!
Hey Allah, have mercy on me!!
Don't cry!
Come...
Sister...
Don't cry, dear!
Son...
We have come to take you!!
Great!!
Swami...