TUNE IN FOR LOVE
Take care of it via phone or fax.
In economic news...
Too bad. You wouldn't expect it.
But I bet
there are a lot of people like me.
What's so hard about it?
You're listening to Traffic News 57.
Right now, there's a slowdown
on Banpo-daero
to Seoul Saint Mary's Hospital
intersection on the southbound side.
So give yourself a little more time
to get to where you're going.
The 110 is very backed up right now
with an accident
on the right side of the road.
Seventh and eighth.
There is another accident there
so take the long way around
to get through downtown.
Down to the 110.
When entering the 101,
keep in mind
that there is a little fender bender
on the right side of the road.
Stay in the left and keep going.
There's been an accident on Route 58,
and it's closed down to one lane.
Plan ahead
and use service roads if you can.
Uh, I'm sorry, we're not open yet.
Are you looking for something specific?
Do you have anything with soybeans?
Tofu or...
Uh, well...
would soy milk work?
Yeah, sure, I'll take that.
...regular scheduled program
after the tone.
How about... regular milk?
It has to have soybeans.
There's a grocery store up the street.
It'll have something with soybean.
Radio, love, and rockets.
Do you know what these three things
have in common?
They all use enormous amounts of energy
in the beginning to launch.
Hello, you're listening to Music Album.
I'm your new host, Yoo Yeol.
There's my miracle.
I'm delighted to be here.
And I'm so excited for you to...
This show is dedicated
to all those who loved.
...all of your stories.
That sounds like Yoo Yeol.
He must be hosting the morning show now.
I'm a huge fan of his.
Eun-ja, you see that guy over there?
He was just in here asking for tofu.
- Tofu?
- Uh-huh.
He went into that store.
I bet he just got out of jail.
No way. He's still in high school.
Oh, he's coming.
PART-TIMER WANTED
6 DAYS A WEEK, 1,200 WON PER HOUR
MISU BAKERY
Hey.
Oh, your mother's here.
Hi.
Okay, thank you.
- Have a nice night.
- See you soon.
- Please come again.
- Okay.
Hey!
I told you not to come in today,
you need to focus on your exams.
Let me.
Go inside, I'll take care of this.
Don't worry, I got it.
Like, really. It's not a problem.
I don't need to go to school.
What do you mean you don't need to go?
I dropped out.
Uh... Wait.
Did you really just get out?
Out of where?
Prison.
I rather not talk about it.
All right, get to work.
Hm.
MISU BAKERY
Hey, Tofu.
Tell us some stories
from when you were in the slammer.
Okay, whatever.
There you go.
You two aren't related, are you?
We're not telling you.
I guess we don't look like each other.
I think...
she was just 18
when she started working here.
She learned fast.
Learned how to knead bread dough
almost right away,
and she became as good as my mom.
Come on.
My mom relied on Eun-ja
especially after she got sick.
She is my family.
Well...
I should get the store ready
for the evening rush.
When I was at the juvenile center,
I always went to breakfast
at 9 a.m. sharp.
Every day, I'd hear the music
and think to myself,
"Oh, I'm still here."
After I finish my breakfast
and return my tray,
I'd hear the reporter finish talking.
Then I knew...
it'd be about 9:50.
Prayed every day.
"Just get me out of here.
Please."
After my prayer, the radio show would end.
And I would know...
nothing...
will happen today.
Every day
was the exact same routine,
but one day, during my prayers,
I said this,
"God, let at least one thing
change by the time I leave this place.
I don't think...
I can go on if nothing has changed."
There's a grocery store up the street.
It'll have something with soybean.
Radio, love, and rockets.
Do you know what these three things
have in common?
They all use enormous amounts of energy
in the beginning to launch.
That's my miracle.
Hello, you're listening to Music Album.
I'm your new host, Yoo Yeol.
I see.
I guess you could think of it
as a miracle.
Miracles aren't that special.
Right?
On this gorgeous, sunny day,
sunlight streams on the window...
Can you get the curtains?
Hey, it's such a beautiful day.
Let's go do something fun.
Should we go somewhere we've never been,
and eat something
we've never tried before?
So, dear listeners, call me.
Tell me what you're gonna do
on this beautiful day.
- Do you want something to drink?
- My suggestion,
if you want it, go outside...
- Hey.
- You're here.
Yeah.
Cheers.
Today is a beautiful day.
Mmm.
Stay still.
Uh, wait...
Tilt your head this way.
What are you going to do?
Nice.
- Can you give me the mirror?
- It's fine.
Can you, please?
Calm down, it looks perfect.
Yes, perfect. Trust me on this.
Hey.
- Hi, there.
- Hi, hello.
- Will you be here tomorrow?
- I'll be here.
- How about tomorrow?
- And the day after that?
Have a nice day!
He talked to me.
Girls, you gotta go home.
Uh, hey, what year were you born?
'75.
Oh.
Uh, well, me too.
I started school early.
My friends were born in '74.
Oh...
Okay.
Uh...
What's this?
"I hate bread.
Bread, bread, bread."
Oh.
That...
I wrote it when I was a kid
and Mom was making me work.
I was so over bread.
I would've been so happy
if my parents had owned this place.
BREAD
I'm back.
Hey, you.
Oh, you're still here?
Have you ever seen anything this adorable?
Definitely not.
Christmas cupcakes. Looking good!
They're so cute.
Hey, Hyeon-u.
The Christmas tree is in that box.
Could you take it out and dust it?
You can leave after that.
Eun-ja, let me just wash my hands.
Okay, but he wants to help.
Yeah?
- Do you?
- Uh-huh.
Let's try to boost our sales a bit.
Just set it up outside.
Yes, ma'am.
Outside?
You don't have to be so formal.
Most of my friends
are the same age as you.
Okay.
Wow.
My mom would always put
the Christmas tree outside,
so everyone could enjoy it.
It's pretty.
Oh, it's beautiful.
They look so good.
- Come in, it's cold.
- Yeah.
- Okay, those do look good there.
- I knew it.
- Let's put that there.
- This one?
Yeah.
Can we take a picture?
A picture?
Uh, yeah, of us three together.
With everything, even the cupcakes.
That's a really good idea.
We should get all this in the picture.
- Uh, we should give them names.
- Huh?
Like, "Fly, Little Birdie" cupcake,
"An Old Memory" cupcake,
and "A Long Time Ago" cupcake.
What are you talking about?
There are music award shows
every year.
We should do the same for our cupcakes.
I'll give the award
to whichever cupcake...
is the best singer.
Sure, why not?
But I'll have to taste
each one of these first.
Why do they have to start construction
right around Christmas?
This is usually our best time of year.
They're building apartments.
We'll get more customers soon.
Hey! That's too loud!
Good morning.
Hey, buddy. Merry Christmas.
Hyeon-u?
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
I got a job around here
because I ran away from home, all right?
It's so freaking
cold out there.
I'll just hang out here for a bit.
Oh. This...
looks good.
Would you like a coffee with that?
I'm fine.
Probably should've waited
until the spring to run away.
This is brutal.
- Uh...
- I saved his ass.
I'm the one who got him out of jail.
And now, we run into each other
right before Christmas.
I didn't expect to see him here.
You know, if it weren't for me,
you'd be spending this Christmas
back in prison.
Quack, quack, quack!
- Little duckies.
- Oh.
- Let me hear you.
- They're here.
Duckies!
- Go on in.
- Hello.
- Hello!
Quack, quack, quack!
I'll give you one, hold on.
This one has chocolate buttons on the top.
Oh? Which one?
Can't believe he still rides that scooter.
- Yo! What took you so long?
- Dude, where were you?
Let me at least say hi to him first.
- What's up? I'm glad you're back.
- Yeah.
Yeah? Do you realize
what time it is?
I saw this all the way back
at the intersection down the road.
Did you know?
Yeah, I did.
That's how I found the place.
We all did.
You're the only one who's late, dumbass.
- What?
- Yeah, that's...
Take this and leave.
Hey, we're helping you
with your sales.
We don't need your help.
- Oh, yeah?
- Hey, let's talk outside.
- Why?
- Come on.
- Why do we have to talk outside?
- We're just visiting our friend.
- Get out, all of you.
- Forget it, let's go.
Would it be possible
to get paid in advance?
Hey, let's go already!
What are you doing in there?
Come on!
Hey, what are you doing?
Let's go! Get us out of here!
Let's go!
Hurry up!
They're not all bad.
We've gotta go!
Fuck, let's get out of here!
Let's go.
You think he's leaving for good?
Mm-hm.
Probably.
You think he'll ever come back?
Hm.
He's too good-looking.
Zero!
- Seven.
- Bang!
Yo, what's that?
- Okay, I gotta take a piss.
- I gotta take it, my hands are shaking.
- I really need to piss.
- Yeah? No way.
- Tell this guy to drink!
- No, no, no.
- I can't, I can't.
- Guys, guys...
I would slur my words.
Have some kimchi.
- Don't let me off easy.
- Hey!
I'm glad you're back.
Ah! Shut up.
Calm down.
Oh.
Coming through.
We can't call it a night just yet.
Oh, it's freezing.
- What's this, a funeral?
- Come on, let's go.
- Hey!
- Easy.
Hey, you fucking bastard!
What?
- What did you say?
- Hey, calm down. What do you want?
What did you say
as you were walking past me?
Come on, what's wrong with you?
What the fuck did you say?
Come up, four down.
- Oh!
- Let's go, let's go.
Hey, pass it. Pass the ball!
Hey, over here!
I'm open.
What was that? You suck.
- No, no, no. I'm open.
- I'm wide open.
Over here!
- No!
- Pass it.
- Here.
- What was that?
Oh, my god. Let's go.
He pushed him. The guy just pushed him.
He pushed him, I saw.
Did you see that?
That asshole pushed him!
Hey, fuck you!
Don't push me! Let go of me!
WE ARE CLOSED TEMPORARILY.
WE WILL REOPEN SOON.
As the year comes to an end,
we often hope
that things would be different.
We say,
"I wish for only good things
to happen in the new year."
But remember, dear listener,
if the weather's always sunny,
our world would turn into a desert.
Snow and rain, they nourish the soil.
Without water,
all the plants and trees,
and eventually, everything
would wither and die.
So we'll make our wishes for the new year.
How about we change things up?
I'd like some good things
to happen in my life.
Some good is enough.
What about the big companies?
You didn't get into any of them?
- No.
- Hmm.
Your grades are pretty good.
Hiring managers used to line up
to recruit our students.
What's happening this year?
Let's see.
There are two places
where you can start working right away.
One of them...
Have you heard of the company, Gwangjang?
- Oh, what do they do?
- Newsletter editing.
This is a full-time position.
They're offering 15 million won a year.
- They're looking for a literature major...
- Ah, I see.
...from our school, so...
so you'll get the job.
The other option is...
a part-time job in radio.
It only goes for a couple of months.
Oh, it's that show
hosted by Yoo Yeol.
When you hear that melody, it's 9:20 a.m.
After that, he reads off a script
written by someone else.
And you can totally tell.
Ooh, then you hear the theme song
by Kim Kwang-jin at 10 a.m.
Okay, you need to take that job
at the radio station.
I know nothing about radio shows.
Hello.
Forget it.
I'll just listen to the show
at a different job.
Oh, you know, fun fact.
Yoo Yeol started hosting the show
on October 1, 1994.
Stop. How in the world
could you remember something like that?
Yeah, I know, right?
After all this time.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
You need a stable job.
Stable?
No, it's "safe."
Okay, I know it's safer
than the part-time job
at the radio station.
Well, thanks.
I just think it's crazy
to have someone else
pack up your stuff for a move, you know?
The movers that packed your house for you,
they're all gonna go under.
They charge three times more
than what we do.
Why would anyone hire them?
Moving gives you a chance
to go through everything you own.
You could finally get rid
of the crap you never use.
Give me that. It's heavy.
If you don't do it yourself,
how're you gonna know where everything is?
Right, totally.
- Oh, man.
- You're right.
What's with you, man?
You... You're so distracted.
Well, I'm pretty sure I've heard you
say that at least five times today.
You are the master of your own life.
That's why you need to pack
your own stuff, huh?
Here, take these to Mr. Kim's bookstore.
- Oh, these two?
- Yeah.
I'm coming!
I gave you a little extra.
This is so good.
- Isn't it? It's just for you.
- Mm.
- We're ready to pay.
- Of course.
Bye now.
Nine thousand won.
Thank you.
I just got a job.
Really?
- That's my girl.
- I'm gonna be a writer.
Awesome!
Oh, sorry.
So, will you make a fortune
now that you've got yourself a job?
I'm gonna be super rich.
That's nice.
What?
- You paid my tuition fees.
- Enough, come on.
Stop.
You spent that little bit
of savings you had
from the bakery on me.
We're family.
Thanks, Eun-ja.
Don't mention it.
What?
That's my fat.
All that good food.
I'm proud of you.
- Good evening.
- Oh, you're back?
Yep.
USED BOOKS
I'm back.
Hey, Hyeon-u.
Li-sik asked me to drop these off.
Okay.
Good evening.
Oh, hi.
Hyeon-u,
could you take my mother home?
Thank you.
I'm practically blind at night.
But I can see everything during the day.
All right.
I'm serious.
My vision is just fine in the daytime.
Yup.
What's with all these red flags?
They're going to build apartments here.
Oh.
MISU BAKERY
BREAD
Mom.
I got a job.
I'll come back soon.
I'll do visit you, I promise.
Mi-su?
Hm?
Oh, Hyeon-u!
- Who is she?
- Oh, uh...
Oh, good evening.
Uh, she's...
So, do you...
Yes, I live here in this neighborhood.
Oh. Oh.
- Okay, yeah.
- Mm-hm.
I, uh...
I have to take her home first.
Uh, do you mind waiting here?
Oh, all right.
- Don't go anywhere.
- Get home safely.
Thank you.
Hm?
Did you run here?
No.
Can you tell?
How have you been?
I have some good news.
I got my GED.
You did?
You kept studying.
Mm-hm.
I'm impressed. I'm proud of you.
Eun-ja's gonna be so happy.
Oh, she's running her own noodle shop.
I miss Eun-ja too.
If you happen to be free tomorrow,
how about we go see her?
Uh...
- Well...
- Mm-hm?
I start my military service tomorrow.
Uh... Oh.
Really?
You must be tired.
No, I'm fine.
You don't need to walk me home.
It's okay.
When I woke up this morning,
I never imagined my day
would end like this.
I'm so happy
I decided to visit the bakery.
It's like I got my own little miracle.
This is it. This is where I live.
- Right here?
- Yup.
Ah.
Well...
Uh, thanks for walking me home.
Of course.
I'm happy...
Huh?
...that I ran into you today.
Me too.
Well...
Be safe out there, okay?
Mm-hm.
Good night.
Hyeon-u!
I must be nervous.
I entered my number wrong.
Your number?
Yeah, I use my student ID number.
It's the only thing i can remember.
Oh, your school gives you a number.
Ah, it's not a big deal.
Are you cold?
Hm?
Just wait here for a second.
Don't come in until I tell you to, okay?
All right.
Okay.
Come in.
This is all I've got in the house.
Are you okay?
- Uh...
- What... How did that happen?
Uh, thanks.
- I hope that they're...
- I got it. I got it.
Do you want... I can get you a new shirt.
Hold on.
Uh...
Hey, don't worry about it.
This blanket looks thin,
but it'll keep you warm.
Uh...
Ow.
Oh, my god.
I'm sorry. You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- I didn't know you were behind me.
Hyeon-u, is everything okay?
Uh... yeah.
Oh.
Those are Eun-ja's pajamas.
Eun-ja...
These are Eun-ja's?
Sorry. I'm sorry.
Uh...
What's wrong?
- Is it the shirt?
- Uh, yeah.
Let me see.
Uh...
All done.
Hyeon-u.
Are you asleep?
No.
That day...
I thought...
that I would never see you again, but...
I tried to...
wait for you.
That day...
Back then...
we got into a fight with this drunk guy.
I was with Tae-seong.
And, uh, my probation was revoked.
So...
I had to go back to the juvenile center.
I wanted to come back to the bakery.
So badly.
Sleep tight.
You too.
CHOLLIAN
REGISTER
THE NEW CHOLLIAN, CHOLLIAN CHOL
Hmm.
ENTER THE USERNAME YOU'D LIKE TO USE
ENTER YOUR PASSWORD
REENTER YOUR PASSWORD
ENTER YOUR KOREAN NAME
OR BUSINESS NAME
CHA HYEON-U
Oh, I'm so tired this morning.
With you showing up,
and it being my first day of work...
...I barely slept.
Me neither.
Here.
- What is this?
- This is your new e-mail address.
- I made an account for you.
- Uh, okay.
You know how it works, right?
Just check your inbox for my e-mails.
And you have to write me back.
This way, we can stay in touch.
Yeah.
Hey.
Promise, I'm gonna come back.
Okay. I'll be right here, waiting.
Hey.
This way.
SAFETY, DEVOTION, QUALITY, EFFICIENCY
Good morning.
Good morning, how can I help you?
- I'm supposed to--
- Oh, are you Kim Mi-su?
- Ah, yes.
- I see.
- Well, it's very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
Uh, this here is Gwon Eun-su.
- Hi.
- And that's Kim Hyeon-suk.
- She'll be the one training you.
- Ah, thank you.
- Hyeon-suk.
- Yeah?
Meet your successor.
Oh, hi. How are you?
- She'll take over from here.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Put these in your ears.
Uh...
I forgot to write down the password.
How...
You don't need to wear them right away.
Huh?
Sorry?
The earplugs.
Oh, yeah.
♪ When my loneliness grows ♪
♪ As much as my shadow has grown ♪
♪ My nostalgia ♪
♪ Takes me to that place ♪
♪ There, I find you ♪
♪ My prayer for wanting to be with you ♪
♪ And our last moment together ♪
♪ How come I haven't heard ♪
♪ Any news about you? ♪
♪ Perhaps you're too far away ♪
♪ By the riverside at sunset ♪
♪ Our old memories still breathe ♪
Someone named "Doughnut"
sent me a letter today.
"Dear Mr. Yoo,
I'm writing to you
because I won't be able to meet Tofu
even if he comes to visit me.
I'm moving away.
I've been sending e-mails to an account,
that he can't even check,
for several days now."
"The password is my student ID, Tofu!"
I feel like this story is written in code.
You got things like,
"password," "student ID,"
"Tofu" and "Doughnut."
I wonder what these e-mails say.
I've been really curious now.
Hi, Hyeon-u!
The last time we saw each other,
my nose was red from the cold weather.
But now, summer is in full swing.
I hear soldiers prefer the hot summer
to the cold winter.
Is that true?
How are you doing?
I hope you get to see this, eventually.
I've written you so many e-mails.
UNREAD
MISU BAKERY
As we barrel headfirst
into the 21st century,
what fascinating inventions
will be unfurled?
When I attended
an international exhibition
for future technologies,
this guy pulled out an amazing new gadget.
It was a phone
that had a digital camera inside.
Apparently,
we will all have a cell phone
and a camera small enough
to fit in our pockets.
When we think of it,
we can carry around an entire photo album
of all the people we love, everyday.
The future is mind-blowing.
MYEONGJIN REAL ESTATE OFFICE
Hey, Mi-su. It's Hyeon-u.
I've finally figured out the password.
You must be surprised.
I went to your place,
but they said you've moved.
Excuse me!
Is that apartment for rent?
You're probably wondering
how I figured out the password.
- What I did was...
- Here's the address.
What's the code for the door?
2-6-2-6-7-0.
- 2-6-2-6-7-0.
- Right, 6-7-0.
Sorry,
is this the last tenant's door code?
Hold on. Uh-huh...
Yeah, I think so.
I'll tell you how
when I see you.
Also, I've got something
I'd really like to show you.
Hi, can I use the computer?
I got it.
I...
WHEN DOES YOUR SERVICE END?
I'm so happy
that you're finally able
to figure out the password.
I even sent the story
to Yoo Yeol's radio show,
just to try and tell you the password.
E-mail me your phone number.
I'll call you sometime
between noon and one tomorrow.
Hey, Hyeon-u.
Hey, man.
Is this really it?
We get paid just to be here?
Yeah, just relax,
and, you know, walk around a bit.
That's what I've been doing all day.
Your form looks good.
Hello?
Hyeon-u?
Yeah, it's me.
How have you been?
Well, you know me.
Just hard at work.
You're as positive as I remember.
Just hearing your voice
is brightening up my day.
I miss you.
Uh, what kind of work
are you doing these days?
Well...
What kind of work do you think I do?
Uh, the kind of work you wanted to do.
Eun-ja always say
you're such a great writer.
It's kind of related.
I'll call you later.
Around 6 p.m., okay?
Oh, uh... Yeah.
Uh, I'll be waiting
for your call.
I like to see you.
Mm-hm.
Cool.
The person you are trying to reach
is not available at this time.
Please leave a message after the tone.
The person you are trying to reach
is not available...
Hey, look at this!
Hey, please be quiet.
You took off with the membership fees,
which are four million won per person.
And there are over a hundred members.
These days, so many fitness clubs
change their names,
just so they can get new members
and can scam them.
Sir, we told you,
we don't know what happened.
I don't know anything.
I just work there part-time.
Sir...
I, uh, really didn't do anything wrong.
When, when the fight broke out,
I, uh...
I didn't hit anyone.
I didn't even fight back.
Please, I'm in college now.
- I didn't do anything--
- Uh, I can't hear you. Speak up.
Hyeon-u.
- Hyeon-u!
Hey!
Hey, man, thanks for keeping me out of it.
- Hey, hold on.
- Where are you going?
Hey, let's grab a drink.
- Hey, man.
- Come on, man.
- Thanks for taking care of that.
- Hold up, hold up.
Hey, you know, I was just trying
to help you out, right?
Tae-seong stuck his neck out for you.
And he got you that job
'cause you said you needed some cash.
Dude, don't be so salty.
The owner lied to Tae-seong too.
Yeah?
Can you please just leave me alone?
What the hell?
So you're just gonna ditch us?
- Huh?
- Where you going?
- Yo.
- Seriously?
Hey!
Hey.
Fuck you. It's not like
Tae-seong did it on purpose.
Hey, Hyeon-u!
MI-SU, I'M SO SORRY
I MISSED YOUR CALL EARLIER
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH
EVEN THOUGH IT WASN'T MY FAULT
Hey, open up!
You!
Oh, watch out!
- What's going on?
- Getting away from us, huh?
- I want my money!
- I want my money back.
MI-SU, I'M SO SORRY
I MISSED YOUR CALL EARLIER
MI-SU
CLOSE
43 MINUTES AND 33 SECONDS
Something must've come up.
But...
I'm kinda thankful
that I didn't hear from you.
To tell you the truth,
I feel like a total loser these days.
I'm not really in the mood to catch up
and laugh with you
after all these years.
I hate myself.
I don't even want people to look at me.
I'm sad.
I made all these choices myself,
so why do I feel this way?
There's only one thing
that made me happy recently.
You figuring out the password.
Thanks to you, I got to laugh
for the first time in a long time.
Hyeon-u, get in touch
when something good happens.
And I'll do the same.
♪ Why is it so hard to start the day ♪
♪ Should I take it easy
With a cup of coffee ♪
♪ A grateful cup of coffee
That can wake me up ♪
♪ The smell of freesias
When I walk out the door ♪
All right, dear listeners.
Today, we're gonna do something
to fulfill our intellectual curiosity.
In this segment,
we're gonna learn about a new book
and meet its author. Mr. Jeong Su-man,
the author
of Charming People and Their Travels,
is in the studio.
- Good morning!
- Hi.
I'm Jeong Su-man, the author
of Charming People, Their Travels.
You know,
I couldn't help but notice.
Are you feeling
a little nervous right now?
Well, this is my first time
on a radio station.
Uh-huh.
I drank so much water
that I have to keep going to the restroom.
Oh, I see.
Mi-su, you're allowed to talk here.
What?
Oh.
Come on, don't be so shy.
Well, I thought maybe the microphone
would pick me up.
Your friend's pretty funny.
I swear, when I imagined...
Yoo Yeol's studio,
I always pictured it
looking very different.
I thought he looked out an actual window,
because he was always so detailed
with his descriptions.
Uh, can I give them the, uh...
I brought these for you.
Here.
Look who's back. It's Mi-su.
Hi.
- I'm back.
- Oh, nice work, Mi-su.
Mr. Jeong sounded so nervous on the show.
He made me nervous.
- I know, right.
- Hm.
Well...
- Did you take some photos?
- Yeah, I did.
If my mom hadn't shown up out of nowhere
and taken up half my day,
I could've made it to the radio station.
See if you could give him more interviews.
- Sure, okay.
- I'm serious.
I'm on it.
- I'll give you a bonus.
- Yes, sir.
I know you're all talk.
Back to work.
Okay, see you later.
Mm.
Hey, who's moving into the space upstairs?
I'm not sure.
They make movies or something like that.
The boss knows one of them.
Ah.
They're just some college kids
working on a project.
Apparently, their goal
is to make their dreams come true.
That's been everyone's obsession
since the World Cup, hasn't it?
20TH CENTURY BOY
What are you doing here?
Oh, I've been waiting for you.
Did something happen?
Something amazing.
- Oh?
- Come on.
Uh...
- No, it's okay. Have a good night.
- No, no, no, come on.
I have to take you somewhere.
- Where?
- Come on.
Let's go.
KYOBO BOOK CENTER
- Did you see it?
- See what?
Oh, you don't see it?
- Huh?
Oh!
CHARMING PEOPLE, THEIR TRAVELS
Is that our book?
The book we published
has made it to number six.
Oh!
Congratulations, this is huge.
Oh, come on.
After all this work, that's it, huh?
I've never seen you more stressed out.
You acted like the whole world
was coming to an end.
Come on, let it out. Show me how you feel.
Yeah!
The book I published
made it to number six!
Yeah! Whoo!
- Yeah!
- Yes!
This is awesome!
- This is awesome! Number six!
- Yeah.
Hey!
You did good.
As I sit in this new studio
overlooking Yeouido Park,
the sunlight, uh, feels so strong,
yet it holds me in its warmth.
And I'm reminded
how lucky I am, dear listeners.
So, I want all of you to think about
someone you may have left behind.
Somebody special in your life.
Sounds like he got his window.
Think of them and let the sun
- carry your thoughts to them.
- Hm.
On this beautiful day.
From this day forward,
Yoo Yeol's Music Album...
- Good morning!
- ...will be broadcast
From an open studio,
overlooking the splendid park.
Where the sun filters through the trees.
It's gonna be hard for me to focus
on the show today.
I'll be too busy gazing on my window.
And to all of you out there,
Yoo Yeol's Music Album
is starting right now.
When I first started this company,
it was just a place for me
and a couple friends
to work on projects for fun.
But in just two years,
we've managed to publish
a best-selling book.
Let this not be our last.
Cheers!
♪ Perhaps ♪
♪ We were longing for each other ♪
- Have a good night.
- Oh, thank you.
♪ We may have failed
To notice one another ♪
♪ While strolling along the same street ♪
♪ And walked past each other ♪
♪ We might have regretted our decision ♪
♪ At the moment ♪
♪ When we were exchanging
Our last farewell ♪
♪ Because I'm timid ♪
♪ I'm afraid
We might walk past each other ♪
♪ Once ♪
So...
looks like we meet again.
It's...
nice to see you.
Hm.
I should be heading home.
Yeah.
There's something I like to show you.
♪ If the thought ♪
♪ That you're all alone ♪
♪ Makes your heart ache as well ♪
♪ Every time you head out the door ♪
Hmm...
♪ You're probably keeping it
All bottled up inside ♪
♪ Like a fool ♪
♪ Mmm... ♪
Wait right here.
- Hmm...
- Oh.
Oh...
Uh, wait, it's...
Why are we here?
I'm renting this place.
No, I mean...
How is this possible?
Oh.
Well, I've always liked this apartment.
It was available and within my budget.
So I signed the lease.
When I saw you today,
I didn't know what to say at first,
because there are so many things
I wanna tell you,
but I can't remember any of them.
I'm glad to see you again.
What?
Uh, nothing.
I'M TAKING 3 DAYS OFF
Hm.
I think we should make some kimchi stew.
Uh, okay.
Kimchi stew and, uh, stir-fried pork.
Yeah, let's make omelet rice too.
I know how.
That'll be too much work.
I'll do it. Just go relax.
No way, that's too much for one person.
We should've bought minced garlic.
This is just...
- I'll mince the garlic.
- Are you sure? 'Cause...
- I'll do it.
- That's a lot of garlic.
- I'll mince all the garlic.
- Well...
Are you sure you wanna do everything
by yourself?
Yeah, go take a shower.
All right, then.
Hyeon-u,
did you turn on the water?
What?
Are you running the water
in the kitchen?
Yeah?
If you do that,
the water turns ice cold.
Cheers.
Thanks for cooking.
Ahh.
Is it good?
Mm, mm-hm.
This is so good.
Wow.
When I was living here,
there was a huge patch of mold
on that wall.
So, you had no idea that...
if you run the kitchen sink,
the shower gets cold?
I mean, I get it because you live alone.
I guess you've never brought
a girlfriend back here before.
I'm not gonna tell you.
Just eat your food.
I am eating.
One sec.
Huh?
What are all these?
I only have
a handful of happy memories.
But some of them,
I just can't recall the details.
They don't even feel like they're my own.
I almost can't believe
that those things actually happened to me.
I took those photos so I wouldn't forget.
Oh.
You scared me.
You take good care of me.
Hmm.
Are you still scared of me?
Hm?
You were scared of me when we first met.
Mm-mm.
How about now?
Still not scared?
Try and catch me!
♪ Do you feel my love? ♪
♪ Even though ♪
♪ I'm hiding it from you ♪
♪ If you can feel it ♪
♪ Does it mean
You're hiding your feelings too? ♪
♪ Do you feel my love? ♪
♪ When did you ♪
♪ Find out? ♪
♪ If you feel the same way ♪
♪ Please ♪
Are you done yet?
Did you finish your book?
I have about three pages left.
You're a slow reader.
Back when you were a kid,
did you ride motorcycles around
like these punks do?
I have, in the past.
Hm. Mm-hm.
With a girl sitting on the back?
No.
You're such a liar.
Oh, stop.
You finished? Give me that.
Hm.
I don't wanna see
Eun-ja like this.
My mom really cared about her.
She wanted Eun-ja to marry a nice man,
and start a family of her own.
I told her to follow her heart
and not settle,
but she insisted she wanted to marry
that old man with a kid.
Go on in. I'll wait here.
Can't you just come with me?
Hm?
Come on, let's go.
Um...
Maybe next time.
Go on.
All right.
Just go.
No, I'm just gonna wait here.
- Let's just go together, hm?
- Mm-mm.
GEUM-I'S PLACE
NOODLE SOUP
Have a seat anywhere.
Oh...
Hyeon-u?
Is that you?
Yes, Eun-ja. It's me.
Oh, my god. Tofu! Tofu!
Oh!
Oh, I can't believe it.
You're even more handsome than I remember.
Oh, my god!
Here, have a seat.
Sit, sit.
How did you find me?
Uh, Mi-su, uh...
She didn't want to come, right?
Miss Eun-ja.
She's... She's in trouble.
- What?
- She's gonna get beat-up!
Stop! Stop!
Come here.
Let go!
Say you're sorry. Do it.
Apologize.
I'm sorry.
- She's here.
- Hey, who is this?
What? Who am I?
You little...
Mi-su...
- Mi-su...
- You shouldn't have to deal with this.
You pretending you don't recognize me?
Mi-su?
I caught her smoking.
Your stepmom
is the best chef in the world,
but she's stuck
in that restaurant all day long
making noodle soup because of you,
you understand?
We'll talk later.
- Everything's fine.
- Don't do this.
It's okay.
I've missed you.
Why do you let her
treat you this way?
Where's the Eun-ja I know?
She would've never let this happen.
All right, dinner is served.
This is two-year-old kimchi.
I only serve this to a few special people.
You can take some home with you.
Wow.
You can have more after you finish this.
Here.
- Hm?
- Looks good.
Thank you for the food.
- You like it?
- Yup. Delicious.
- The soup is amazing.
- Do you want more pepper?
Mm-mm.
Try it with the kimchi.
Don't you think it's weird that Eun-ja
didn't even ask
if we're seeing each other?
I mean, she doesn't have to.
I just wonder why she didn't bring it up.
Honestly, it doesn't matter to me.
Hm?
We can be together or take it slow,
it's whatever you want.
So it's up to me what we do, huh?
Are you sure you want me
to make this decision?
MI-SU!
ARE YOU AT WORK NOW?
YES, I'M IN THE OFFICE
DIDN'T YOU SAY THERE'S A MEDIA VENTURE
OR SOMETHING ABOVE YOUR OFFICE?
WHY DO YOU ASK?
WE NEED A PART-TIMER
FOR OUR LIVE VIDEO STREAMING
I KNOW OF A GOOD PART-TIMER
IS HE HANDSOME?
YOU'D BETTER NOT MAKE A MOVE ON HIM
FINE
What are you doing?
Uh...
I'm getting ready to develop the film,
but it's kinda tricky.
Hey, Hyeon-u.
What do you think about
this Pepsi T-shirt that I'm wearing?
I think it looks great on you.
So then will you give it to me
if I say that I want it?
Sure.
Smile.
What? What?
Hey, I have a question for you.
How is it...
that you have such an adorable smile?
Is that a genuine smile?
Or is he just trying really hard?
I ask this, because,
when you feel like a loser,
everyone else also looks...
like a loser,
and your whole world looks like shit.
I'd want more from life
if I had more to begin with.
There are very few things in this life
that I hold dear.
Hm.
But I'm staring at one right now.
Go on.
To me, at least...
you're the most wonderful...
beautiful person in the whole world.
That's so sweet.
This coffee's so sugary, I feel dizzy.
Coffee is best when it's sweet.
You go ahead.
What?
I'll be right up, okay?
Uh...
Do you wanna get married?
I guess this is how guys feel.
I said that without even realizing
what I was saying.
I'm just kidding,
so just forget what you heard.
- Let's go inside.
- Mm.
In your old neighborhood,
there was an apartment complex over here.
And the hair salon was here.
There's a real estate agency
where the bakery used to be.
Uh, if you turn right
at the corner of the convenience store
and keep walking,
you get to the old corner store, remember?
Uh, I'm sorry, what are you trying to say?
Didn't I...
Didn't I tell you?
Oh, I guess I forgot to tell you.
I've decided to buy this store.
Gonna open a bakery there,
and it will offer cooking classes.
The classroom should be fairly large,
the store has a good amount of space.
You could help me.
Huh?
What do you... you think?
I promise to make you smile every day.
If that's what you want.
You sound so cheesy right now.
Hyeon-u!
I'm returning these.
You can just leave them there.
- Have a good one.
- You too.
Hello.
Why didn't you answer my calls?
I guess you're too busy
living a normal life.
You know, today's the ten-year anniversary
of Jeong-hyeop's death, huh?
You, of all people,
should pay your respects.
We're leaving in the afternoon.
We'll wait for you.
Come on, make it quick.
Hey, don't tell me what to do, okay?
- You didn't do anything today.
- Yo, why me? What's the matter with you?
Can one of you just do it? I'm tired.
Rock, paper, scissors.
- Rock, paper, scissors.
- Real men use their fists.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Everyone, put your hand in.
One, two, three.
- Hey, are you playing?
- Let's play without him, come on.
Okay, you ready?
- One, two, three, shoot!
- Shoot!
Goddamn it!
- Hey!
- Oh, shit!
You...
Fuck! Guys, she saw me.
What do you want?
I got my GED and went to college.
I got a job in the city.
If Jeong-hyeop were alive,
he would have graduated
and be working too.
The fact that you and your friends
aren't behind bars...
that makes me sick to my stomach.
You don't deserve a good life.
You guys should be locked up
so you can never do this to anyone again.
It was an accident.
I beg you, forgive me.
Please, I'm sorry.
I...
I don't care.
When you die, apologize to him yourself.
See you around.
Ah, shit.
Where are you?
I'm waiting for you outside,
it's about to rain.
Are you Hyeon-u's girlfriend?
Well...
Who is this? Who am I talking to?
He left his phone in my car.
Uh...
Why was he in your...
Tell me where you are.
I'll bring it to you.
Oh, yeah.
Aren't you that girl from the bakery?
Not that Hyeon-u would tell me anyway.
Uh...
Hm.
There it is.
What did you do... today?
Um...
I went to my aunt's place
to see my grandma.
Well, I wish that you had told me.
Sorry.
I got distracted.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Hyeon-u.
We have to move.
Jong-u's starting
a new business or something.
Uh, where are we gonna go?
I'm getting so tired of this.
The movie is never gonna get made.
We can't afford to keep jumping
from office to office.
It's just setting back our timeline.
Pretty messed up, don't you think?
Uh, what about the radio station?
Think that'll be okay with you
working there?
Hey.
So, uh, have you started looking
for a new office?
No, not yet.
I see. Sorry it happened this way.
You'll be fine, though.
You're still young,
you have time to start over.
You know what, I gotta get outta here.
Mm-hm.
See you later.
What was Mi-su like when you knew her?
Was she pretty then too?
She's always been cranky, right?
I don't know.
- Wow.
- Hey!
Hey, stop it! It's really dangerous.
Hey, kids. Be careful.
Yes, sir.
You scared me.
This is it.
Ta-da.
Wow!
- Thank you.
- Mm-hm.
- Is it good?
- It's great.
- You should eat.
- Mm-hm.
I went to see...
Jeong-hyeop's sister has moved away.
What?
How do you know that?
Well, they're gone.
I spoke to her neighbors,
but none of them know where she went.
Hyeon-u.
You don't need to go
and visit her anymore.
That was the last time--
How did you find out about him?
Tae-seong told me.
Uh...
I thought everything was okay now.
What's okay about this?
Tell me, how is this okay?
It will never go away.
You know everything.
Don't go.
You don't have to.
Couldn't you...
have been the one person that didn't know?
Why do you have to go searching for this?
How could I not?
You were never gonna tell me.
Please...
I'll forget everything.
I'll forget about all of it,
and you should forget everything
I told you.
What should I pray for now?
I...
I always prayed for God
to please just let me live a normal life.
To take this all away.
Then...
when will you be okay?
When will you stop running?
When?
You smell just like
those assholes, you know that?
You smell like an ashtray!
Have you lost your fucking mind?
What the hell?
The owner of the dojo
won't be happy, right?
You better get out of here.
Are you insane?
You say you're my best friend, yeah?
Is life just a game to you?
No, I take life very seriously.
People die playing games.
"Playing games"?
You really think that's what happened?
You were there with us.
Whether we were beating someone up
or stealing stuff.
But do you ever stop to think about us?
None of us are okay.
You know...
I think it's kinda fucked up.
We all made the same mistake,
but I feel like only you are forgiven.
Why do you think that is, hm?
Is it because you think you're better?
Shut the fuck up,
you know that's not true.
Maybe you should take a look
at yourself in the mirror.
You were the one who let him die.
Son of a bitch!
Fucking...
Hyeon-u?
Are you hurt?
Can I ask you something?
Are you and Mi-su...
really seeing each other?
I'm gonna ask you something, okay?
Mm-hm.
Why are you always so mean to your mom?
Eun-ja?
Why would you ask me that?
What if she stops supporting you?
Me?
Never.
Mm-mm.
That won't happen.
Because...
I'm all that she has in this world.
Anyway,
are you two seeing each other?
You're not, right?
Who's there?
There she is.
Hyeon-u, is that you?
Hyeon-u.
What's happened?
I came by 'cause I was hungry.
I'm glad you did.
Eat up.
Thank you, Eun-ja.
It's so good.
What the...
- Hey...
- How's it going?
Uh, good.
What's up?
I left something in the office.
Do you mind if I go and get it?
Uh, well, I'm busy now.
Tell me what it is.
I'll give it to you when I can.
Uh, well...
It's the photo. The one on Mi-su.
Huh.
That photo.
- It's at my place.
- What?
I'm really sorry. I just thought...
I thought you threw it out.
You're a piece of shit.
I think you're a good guy.
But you're too serious and gloomy,
and so is Mi-su.
I think she needs someone
who can bring some happiness
back into her life.
We all need to have some fun.
Are you going to see Mi-su?
Huh?
If I follow your car,
will you take me to her?
You're gonna follow me?
Good luck with that, kid.
♪ As darkness befalls me quietly ♪
- Slow down!
- Where's he going?
Told him to slow down.
♪ I dream of the first day of spring ♪
♪ I can't see you ♪
♪ Since you are ♪
♪ So far away ♪
♪ But I still tend my flower garden ♪
♪ Autumn is nearing its end ♪
♪ And winter is coming ♪
♪ But I won't forget
The spring sunshine... ♪
Mi-su!
♪ Snow is falling hard ♪
Get in.
♪ And vanquish
Even the slightest bit of sunlight ♪
♪ But in the faraway land,
Spring resides ♪
♪ Oh, love ♪
He is really, uh... something.
Should I pull over?
Uh...
Yeah.
I love you, Mi-su.
I love you.
Don't run after us.
Please don't, okay, hm?
You'll get hurt.
Why do you wanna have soju
with doughnuts?
No reason.
I just haven't had doughnuts
in a long time.
I hope they taste good.
I didn't have all the...
proper ingredients.
Well, they look great. Thank you.
Eat up.
Mm.
You see? Nothing like the old days.
Wow.
Everything in the world has changed
except for these doughnuts.
Mmm.
- Same taste?
- Mm-hm.
Hang on, let me just...
You can't eat doughnuts without coffee.
I'll go make some.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I was just thinking about the old days.
You know, when...
Hyeon-u,
the guy who loved tofu was around.
Yeah.
Hyeon-u promised me he'd be back...
and open a bakery for me.
When?
The other day.
It looked like he had been
punched in the face.
He just had some food and left.
Apparently,
I had told him that I trusted him.
He said I told him that years ago.
I don't even remember.
His grandmother, his aunt, his teacher.
No one believed him.
But I said that to him back then.
I have no memory of saying that.
But he still remembered
after all these years.
- What did he say?
- We're keeping this.
Keep this.
But he said this part, instead of here.
- Sorry.
- Yeah.
Remember the ones
about hiking in England?
Oh, yeah, okay. Right.
I made a change here.
- Uh, Hyeon-u.
- Yeah.
- You can go in now and set up.
- Okay, thanks.
It's a twin story.
- Mm-hm. Hey.
- Sounds good.
Hey.
Twins. Okay.
Come in.
Oh, it's nice to meet you.
Oh, that must be the camera
for the livestream.
But why exactly we have to offer
video footage of a radio show?
Uh, well, the camera
will take a bunch of screenshots,
then we'll put them together
to look like a video.
- One image after another...
- Mm-hm.
So it'll look different
than what you're used to.
Hm.
Well, today is the first day
of our video stream.
Is there a name you'd like me to mention?
Uh...
Whose name comes to mind?
It could be someone you barely know,
someone you miss,
or someone that you see every day
but just can't stop thinking about.
Kim Se-in, Gwon Ye-ji, Park Song-i.
And...
Kim Mi-su.
The names that we cherish in our hearts
are like our diaries, journals.
The very records of our lives.
When I feel the warm sunshine,
and see the beautiful greenery,
I can't help but think of the thousands
of cherished names
and memories in my heart.
This is Yoo Yeol's Music Album.
And to all you lovers out there,
this song's for you.
20TH CENTURY BOY
Hi.
KBS COOL FM 89.1
Hyeon-u! You were so good!
ALL CHARACTERS, ORGANIZATIONS,
LOCATIONS, INCIDENTS, AND RELIGIONS
IN THIS DRAMA ARE FICTITIOUS