Turn A Gundam I
EARTH LIGHT
- One little, two little, three little Moonrace...
- Mary had a little lamb...
Approach speed, angle nominal.
All units, confirm reentry systems.
FLAT One, green.
FLAT Two is green.
FLAT Three is green.
FLAT Four is green.
FLAT Five is green.
FLAT Six is green.
- Ten little Moonrace girls...
- Mary had a little lamb...
- Close face guards.
- ...little lamb, little lamb...
Mary had a little lamb
whose fleece was white as snow.
Mary had a little lamb,
little lamb, little lamb...
Ready!
Launch!
Careful, Loran, that's hot!
But it's neat!
Take care, Fran!
You, too, Loran!
Take care, Keith! Loran!
The coyote is running!
Take care, little boy!
Mary had a little lamb, little lamb...
Sis! That boy is drowning!
Queen Dianna?
Oh, dear...
You wanted this, right?
Please give that back!
Nothing doing!
Miss!
This is what he...
She looks just like
Queen Dianna...
Here is your goldfish.
Under the gaze of the White Doll!
To the Mountain Cycle!
- Let's go!
- Isn't that your sister?
Men will be men...
I will now select my partner
before the statue of the White Doll!
Loran! Finish what you're doing!
Yes, sir!
Boss Heim wants to see you!
He does?
Given your knack for machines,
you'll be our family's driver starting today.
You can handle that, right?
The color of your hair.
Excuse me?
It's the same as a boy I saw being
attacked by a coyote two years ago.
Spin up the motor!
Keith?
Loran?
It's only violin today?
Yes, isn't it dreadful?
Composition has also been canceled.
Take care!
I'm sorry to cut your lesson short.
That's all right.
- I'm off to the reference room,
- I missed you!
- so feel free to take your time here.
- Same here!
A meeting of hometown friends, huh?
What happened to it?
Don't talk about that!
Sorry, I'm just curious.
What are those three looking at?
We're counting on you.
I'll go check on it tonight.
Cahallan!
Everybody, the Earth
is a really great place!
Universe! Universe!
Everybody! The Earth
is a great place!
Come back soon!
Okay, take the picture!
I can't! I'm still swapping out
the film plate!
Turn off the radio! How are we
supposed to concentrate?!
Bostonia Castle? This is
Hills Socis Observatory.
Understood.
Continue your observations.
Colonel.
Yes?
The parade will have to be moved up.
Our uninvited guests are coming at last.
And... stop!
Sochie! Congrats on your solo flight!
Spare me the flattery.
You haven't logged many hours,
but you passed!
He's the amazing one.
Loran's grasp of machines is special.
He only started lessons
because I suggested it.
You're special, too. A Heim girl,
trying to become a Militia pilot?
Only because I have a friend
whose father makes airplanes.
My sister can handle
the family stuff.
That's asking a lot.
The Militia parade is the day
before the summer solstice?
That's what they decided.
But the Coming of Age
Ceremony starts that day!
That's why I won't be able
to see your ceremony.
I have to take these planes
to the parade.
Yeah, your father's planes
were put into service.
Got it! Okay, it's in!
This is all because Galia looks
like they're going to attack!
It's the Militia! All these
will be in the Nocis parade!
Listening gear and searchlights...
Loran!
Keep to the right!
Keep right!
This is pretty impressive...
Isn't this a little big for you
to use as an apartment, Sis?
This doubles as
the company dormitory.
I'm jealous, you get to go to
a party at Bostonia Castle.
You'll be invited
the year after next.
Sir?
We have to leave Nocis by 3PM.
You know where the garden party is, right?
Yes, sir.
His Excellency Lineford, Lord of Inglessa!
Present arms!
Isn't this grand?
Do you really think that Galia will attack us?
We created this mechanized military
to ensure that they don't.
Are you serious about enlisting in the Militia?
It's just like skipping university
and joining the workforce, right?
Don't be rude.
Good luck, soldier!
I'm gonna be a soldier when I grow up!
Here comes the Militia Air Corps!
Why do Earthers always have their
eyes on the skies and never look down?
I guess because they don't know any better.
Hey, once the Return begins,
what are your plans?
I'll put good bread in everybody's bellies.
I'll work hard to become a reporter
at the paper here.
And you?
I'll be a real citizen of Vicinity
after today's ceremony.
Miashei's in one of those!
Goodness, you summer up in Canadan?
I do hope that you will
consider it, Excellency.
Don't worry, I'll consider your proposal.
Excuse me.
It's true, I swear!
Laura.
Laura!
Are you looking for Mr. Heim?
Yes, sir.
Find Diran Heim!
Right away!
Would you be interested in working
at Bostonia Castle after your ceremony?
Well, Nocis is too big a city for me.
In that case, I'd like you
to assist Sid in his work.
Nowadays, even a prospector
needs engineers for his work.
Oh, work for Mr. Sid?
You know him, right?
Yes, sir.
If you're discussing employment,
perhaps you could also mention me?
Oh, dear.
We are in a time
when real-world experience...
...counts for more than studying
outdated subjects in a classroom.
True enough.
Young Lord, my younger daughter and
I will take our leave now.
Preserving local festivals is important.
Laura, think about that job with Sid.
I will.
Excuse us.
Master Guin, why do you always
call Loran Laura?
I'm not sure. Laura just seems
to suit him better.
Are you gonna work as that
prospector Sid's assistant, Laura?
My name isn't Laura.
It's Loran.
With Master Guin, it's always
Laura, Laura, Laura...
Lift!
Now, to the Mountain Cycle!
It's a shame the Missus isn't here to see this.
Hello.
Good evening.
You mentioned that you were
interested in the new age?
I'm also quite fond of dancing.
Allow me to show you a
product of the new age. Later.
A chosen pair of representatives
will anoint each other...
...with the sacred stigmata
before the White Doll!
Who among you will join me?
Sheesh, Tom!
I'm over here!
That's embarrassing!
You can do it!
Don't lose out to Jack!
The Earth is great!
Everybody, come soon!
Loran Cehack!
This is a machine that can send
messages without wires?
That's right. The Moonrace sent it to us.
There is a people whose name means
the race that dwells on the Moon?
I've beefed up the Militia because
a group calling themselves that...
...want to settle in Ameria.
Do they intend to come here
in large numbers?
What's this noise?
What in the world?
What's that?
Let's go! We have to fly patrol!
This is a night flight!
I have plenty of experience
with Hip Heavies!
They're holding rituals like this
in an era when planes fly through the skies.
It takes more than reason
to make the world go round.
The mountain's deserted now,
so this is a perfect time
for survey work.
Ready, Loran?
We apply the stigmata, right?
Right.
Hurry up!
Right!
Stigmata, huh?
The container I gave you.
I know!
Hey!
Come on, Loran! How could you bring
a toy to my coming of age ceremony!
It's my last night, so I thought...
T-These are...
W-What are these?!
Leeches! We use those to brand
our backs with the sacred marks!
- Leeches?!
- They're coming out...
- I didn't know!
- That's how it's always been!
If I don't do this,
I won't be an adult?
That's cold!
Just do it! You're already two
years behind schedule!
They're wriggling!
Again?
What was that?
There's a glow coming from Nocis.
- That's the color of a fire!
- Hey, Loran!
Can you tell where it's coming from?!
It's definitely coming from Nocis!
What the heck is that?!
It's running!
But it looks like a machine to me!
The Bull Ones are attacking it!
What?
An earthquake?
Loran!
Sochie and Loran are...!
This is a...
What is it? What happened?
I don't know!
I can't believe it,
the White Doll is wrecked...
What's that?!
Whatever it is, it's glowing.
It's weirdly pretty.
It looks like it's turned on.
It moved!
Miss!
What?
It's safer in here.
Please, come down!
I wonder what made it turn on?
How should I know?!
It's the same as
a FLAT's VR Head?
The control panel's pretty
different, though.
Ow...
Miss!
It moved!
That's impossible!
The part that looks like
its arm is moving!
Something like this was inside...
the White Doll?
What's a mobile suit doing here?
Get down!
It fired!
What happened?
Loran, are you...
Loran?
What's the matter?
A machine ought to have
some kind of manual.
Oh, you're right. A manual.
Loran! You've got stigmata
on your back!
The sacred marks?
Yes! They're right there,
plain as day!
Fire!
If the searchlight would hit it...
Move it!
This is no time for photographs!
- Leave the children!
- This way!
- There's another airship!
- You can't all fit on board!
Can you make it up here?
I'm climbing up!
Me first!
My boss's daughter's on board!
Crap! Is the Dianna Counter invading?!
Keith!
Boss! Can you make it?!
Stop, Keith!
Sorry, Keith!
Somebody fired a beam towards Nocis!
What was that light?
It's the same as that last one!
It's the same as
that earlier shaft of light!
The Young Lord must be informed!
The Duchess has fainted...
Of all the...
Where are you going?!
I must go to Master Guin's side.
- What should I do?
- What's that?
Those pillars are moving!
The barrage balloons are loose!
Mother!
Mother! Mother!
Wake up!
Mother!
Right, the general rule is to fall back!
Send our troops to the south.
We don't know what comes next.
- As the commander, I mustn't leave the castle.
- Don't fire from here!
- Have Col. Michael contact communications HQ!
- If there are fires, put them out!
- Don't get mad at me, we don't know, either!
- Sorry. You're a big help.
Not at all.
Did you anticipate this horrible situation?
This goes far beyond human understanding.
But if they're the people that we've
been in talks with for these two years...
Yes?
Then they'll listen to reason.
Dianna Soriel will, anyway.
Dianna Soriel?
Loran, you've got the hang of it!
Old Man, someone's in there!
Who's operating it?
You did it, Loran!
I'd hardly call this piloting it.
Hey!
Is this one of the machines written
about in the secret Dark History?
What's the Dark History?
Loran! Make it move this instant!
Make it move?
Don't be careless and let the enemy see it!
See? You can do it!
Miss, please don't
sit on my legs.
Why not?
You'll make me press the...
Watch it!
Control it properly!
Balancers! Get control!
The ground collapsed under its feet.
There are mine tunnels all around here.
There was a cave-in?
So we might find more of
these mechanical dolls.
In that case, excavate the area around
the White Doll. You can use the Militia.
All right. I'm not sure if this Loran boy was
controlling it, but I'll have him help.
I will. It's a Dark History relic, after all.
Oh, about the mechanical doll
that came to life. It's a little odd.
It isn't operational?
No, it's not that.
The crazy thing has a mustache.
It's a mechanical doll
with a mustache?
The White Doll has a mustache?
Touchdown point is clear!
All hands, prepare for landing!
- That beam didn't belong to the Dianna Counter fleet.
- All stations, check in!
This blip to the upper left
of the firing point...
Isn't that the landing point of
the FLAT we sent two years ago?
Yes, sir.
Isn't it possible that it's fallen
into the hands of their Militia?
The beam is different.
Queen Dianna says to act peacefully,
but the Earth is a big place.
Why am I carrying you?
You're our driver, so it's your
job to give me a lift home, right?
I suppose it is.
Miss!
Sam, the Little Miss has returned!
Miss...
Sam! Jessica!
No!
Boss Heim...
Can't this do something?
I don't even know what era it's from.
I need to access the basic system...
Can't it even do voice input?
Father!
This is all your fault!
You wasted all that time!
Why didn't you save him in the mechanical
doll that came out of the White Doll?!
Father!
Miss!
Let go!
Where are you going?
To Nocis! I have to tell Mother
and my sister what happened, right?
You can't! Nocis is under attack, too.
You saw the fires from
the White Doll, remember?
What should we do?
What should we do, Loran?
- I'm going!
- You can't!
No!
Calm down!
Was... was this your doing, Queen Dianna?
I'm amazed you managed to
fire off that second shot.
The cover is so caked with nanoskin
buildup that it should have been stuck.
Is it wrecked?
- Ensign Poe! Lt. Cmdr. Phil wants to see you!
- The entire dome will need repairs.
Understood.
Am I looking at ten years in prison, sir?
The use of mega particle
cannons was banned,
and you fled back to base in spite
of spotting an enemy mobile suit.
You're looking at 15 years.
Or even 17.
Yes, sir.
But we're too shorthanded for that,
so you're going to redeem yourself.
Help out on our operation to
capture the mustached mobile suit.
Yes, sir! Thank you, sir!
Given the time of year, we need
to bury him now, Little Miss.
I know you aren't feeling well,
but there are papers
that need to be signed.
Little Miss...
Keith, you idiot...
What are you doing here?
This way, Miss.
Sprinkle some dirt
on your father first.
Go ahead and cry.
Cry until you've got it all out.
Come on, hurry.
I can't believe this is two or
three thousand years old.
Do you think it was made by
Moonrace living on Earth?
Oh, hey, I saw two beams
fired last night. Was that you?
I only fired once.
I don't even know how
to read this thing yet.
I guess not.
Let's sell the FLAT to the Militia.
Sell the FLAT?
I think we could get a lot for it.
What are you saying?
That's Dianna Counter property!
Maybe, but the Earth and Moon
just started a stupid war.
There won't be a...
How do you know that?!
The fighting won't stop here.
Scarecrow spotted!
It's in the corn fields!
Ready!
Fire!
Ensign Poe! I don't want to
get hit by a lucky shot!
Please take out those guns!
If we have to defend ourselves,
they leave us no choice!
It sounds like the shelling's
getting close again, Jessica!
Miss Sochie, get out of bed!
We might be in danger here!
Have you loaded up the auto?
Just an emergency kit.
- Protect the fields!
- Outsiders go home!
Mechanical dolls go home!
How barbaric... They're savages!
Our orders are to not fire on people!
We're being shot up!
Don't let them reach town!
These Militia maniacs...
Two WaDs have been destroyed?
And now their biplanes are here?!
They're running!
They got away?
The little guys are running, too!
Filthy Militia savages!
I thought that all hostilities had been banned.
The savages have a
cutting-edge mobile suit.
A mobile suit?
I only wanted to capture it, and
then everybody got involved!
Lt. Harry? Where are you?
Above Nocis.
The Soleil is coming down.
Set up a defensive perimeter.
I answer only to Lt. Cmdr. Phil.
I'll return after I've gathered
intel on that mobile suit.
Lt. Cmdr. Phil has...
Has what?!
He seems to have a soft spot for you, Ensign.
So what?!
A suit is closing in?
What is it?
I don't want to let it get too
close to the manor. Or the Mountain Cycle.
So this is an Earth breeze, huh?
I'm a Moonrace!
I'm Loran Cehack, sent to Earth
two years ago...
...for an environmental
adaptability test.
Wait there!
That was a woman... I wonder if
she's the person who fired twice.
Those people they say
are from the Moon...
...are after the mechanical doll
that came out of Mt. Ark!
The Militia's gathered together
and has been fighting them off.
But here you are, even though you
said you wanted to fight in airplanes!
Your late father wouldn't be
pleased if you didn't try to avenge him.
Avenge my father?
Isn't this why you learned to fly?
I can avenge him!
That's him!
Old Man Sid?
Did you find anything?
Another mechanical doll appeared?
Hang on.
You need manpower?
- Another cave-in!
- It's an earthquake!
- Again?!
- Old Man Sid?
Put together a rescue team!
Col. Michael also ordered us to hurry up!
We're going to go excavate
Dark History relics! Got it?!
Loran Cehack,
born in the Meizam district
on 11/2/2328 of the Correct Century.
Upon graduation from middle school,
participated in Earth drop in FLAT #2!
You have been extremely robust
in both mind and body...
...in the two-year medical study mission.
Y-Yes, sir!
Your biometrics transmitter
has already dissolved.
Yes, sir.
He had a goldfish with him?
Sir?
Oh, you must mean Mary.
I have permission for it.
A prized childhood possession?
Yes.
Perhaps you could repeat to us
what you told Ensign Poe?
In Vicinity, I never heard any
rumors regarding mobile suits.
However, they say that one
appeared after a WaDom...
...fired on the Mountain Cycle during
the Coming of Age Ceremony...
...on the night of
the summer solstice.
Are there no rumors to the effect
that the Militia has built mobile suits?
The Heim mines don't produce
mineral resources on that scale.
No speculation, please.
That may be the case at the Heim Mine.
I'm sorry.
Captain!
Stress and nerves must
have gotten to him.
Take deep breaths, Loran.
Lt. Harry. Keep questioning Loran
while we travel to the castle.
Old Man Sid, this doesn't look natural.
You're right. This metal isn't mine ore.
Joseph! What do you make of this?
Did they find something?
- I'm not sure. It's not a machine...
- Bring a light!
An electrical circuit, maybe?
Those look like electrical traces.
Does it go further in?
The air is fresh, so it's big.
Lt. Harry. If you've heard everything,
perhaps you should let the boy leave?
Yes, sir. I was about
to send him home.
Military men only think
in terms of war, I guess.
Don't forget to note the
name of the speaker.
Yes, I understand.
Loran?
There's something that I
need to tell you, Miss.
It's time for the stenographer
to enter the room.
Understood.
Miss Kihel.
They're shorthanded here, so I have
to fill in as stenographer.
Stay here. We'll talk
after the meeting.
Please let this boy stay here.
Look after him.
Who is he?
My family's driver.
Surely that wasn't her...
We didn't bring her.
It should be abundantly clear to you...
...that our level of science and
technology far surpasses yours.
And you must be aware of
the might of our mechanical doll.
Its pilot, Laura, is not a unique prodigy.
- Are you suggesting that we settle this in battle?
- A mustached mobile suit piloted by a Laura, huh?
Not at all. The father of the young
lady transcribing this meeting...
...was killed in the attack that you launched.
We will take no offensive action if
you yield this continent's Sunbelt to us.
You are concerned only
with your own interests.
We negotiated for two years.
We said that we wish to return to
what was our homeland 2,000 years ago...
A bolt?
If it's a fight you want,
pick up a gun!
Don't do this, Elder Iru!
My wife and nephew
were killed last night!
Draw a gun, old man!
Shut your mouths, you barbarians!
Another!
Another cavity opened up!
Elder Iru!
Young Lord... You cannot
be allowed to die...
Do not think that this
evens the scales!
There will be a temporary
cease-fire. But only temporary!
- I must ask you to leave!
- You don't belong in a place like this.
- Carry the Captain out of here!
Let's go home.
That's a good idea. And I'm sure
that your mother will recover at home.
Yes.
About your mechanical doll, Laura.
Master it, no matter what.
Will there be a war?
I don't think we can
fight them for real.
Look!
Metal spheres?
Th-They're machines!
Were beautiful things like this
spoken of in the Dark History?
They look like they
were built yesterday!
These are relics of that time?
Military might makes it
easier to negotiate?
What's going on?
We're changing course.
A Militia squad is coming.
Where?
A squad?
Do you see them, Miss?
Sochie?!
You see Miss Sochie?
Isn't that her and Miashei?
It's a Hip Heavy, but I don't...
Attention, airship!
Lower your altitude!
It's my sister!
Is Loran with her?
Wasn't that Sochie at the controls?
It was! She joined the Militia!
Are we back home?
Fighting in an airplane like that
won't do any good!
Loran, be careful!
The reason Miss Sochie joined the
Militia is to avenge your father.
Then haven't you found any weapons
that the White Doll can use?
No, nothing but mechanical dolls
with round bodies.
They found more doll-types in
Lousana, so the Mustache's weapons...
...have to be somewhere.
It sounds like the Universal
Century really did exist in the ancient past.
That's probably why there are also
people living on the Moon.
It'll take more than size
to beat the Dianna Counter.
Are you sure there aren't
any gadgets inside it?
I've looked through this notebook,
but haven't found anything.
Dummy.
I am?
Where did you press it?
It's tricky.
Let me see.
Hello, Sam. Keep up
the good work.
Kihel?
This photo needs
its glass replaced.
Yes, Mother.
Your father makes such a fuss
if I don't stay on top of these things.
Yes, Mother.
I am not implying that
your side started all of...
...the skirmishes that we have
been seeing everywhere.
Anyone would be startled by the
sudden appearance of 40-meter tall machines.
If you had only believed us...
Words alone are worthless.
Excuse me.
Queen Dianna is coming down
for that very reason.
I said that I approved that.
Can't you forward that call
to this phone?
Personal calls go through
to this line. It's my fiancée.
Their supreme commander will be
coming down at Nocis' north airfield.
That's fine. It will be the perfect
chance to demonstrate our strength.
Those ball-shaped mechanical
dolls... Kapools, you said?
Yes. I had a memo to that effect.
Would you mind doing it
this way, Col. Michael?
Yes.
Are those the mechanical dolls
that you excavated?
They're called Kapools.
Our mechanical dolls are finally
being sent into action!
Hi, Sis!
Sochie! Come down this instant!
I can't!
I'm the one driving it!
A woman pilot? She's amazing!
She is...
Don't put oil in them!
The machine oil they mention in
the Dark History isn't like ours!
- Loran!
- Col. Michael, this is crazy!
Keep your voice down!
- The truck squad isn't enough!
- Thank you.
Then mobilize some motor buses, too!
They're going to have weaknesses,
no matter how advanced they are.
These orders come from
Guin Lineford himself.
From Master Guin?
Aren't they amazing, Sis?
Do you drive one of those,
too, Miashei?
You can't drive one of those
unless you're an airplane pilot.
I'm here to take you home.
Let's go, Sochie.
I can't! They say we'll
have a mission today!
Aren't you worried about Mother?
I can tell that she's okay
just by looking at you.
Sochie...
If we capture their
supreme commander,
no matter how powerful their
weapons are, they won't dare to use them.
On the other hand, if we kill her,
it spells our defeat.
If we wait until AFTER Lady Dianna
enters the city, this will...
What's with this lady stuff?
I'm sorry.
Your mechanical doll will act as
Master Guin's bodyguard, Laura.
Understood?
Yes, sir...
They're really something, aren't they?
Indeed, sir.
Laura will be here. I'm fed up
with being beaten one-sidedly.
He's something else.
It's come unarmed, has it?
How brazen.
She's here!
It's the Soleil! Queen Dianna
is leading the return here!
Queen Dianna's there
on the bridge...
Col. Michael is inside
Bostonia Castle?
Yes, sir.
He went to Bostonia Castle...
That will be all.
Yes, sir.
Behind the tower!
Something is moving!
Maybe at maximum magnification...
Queen Dianna!
It's really her!
She's riding in that!
I am Dianna Soriel.
Lord Guin Sard Lineford, I assume?
I-I am. And you are
Her Majesty Dianna Soriel?
I am pleased to meet you.
As am I.
All members of the advance team,
thank you for your hard work!
These are SUMO mobile suits,
Dianna's Royal Guard.
I see that you have a fine
mobile suit, as well.
We were surprised.
Laura's mobile suit is
still only a prototype.
Laura's mobile suit...
They must think they're disguised
as greengrocers, but that won't fool anyone.
What's that?
Here he comes! Go back to the Moon!
The citizens are rioting?
Did Guin put them up to it?
Drop dead!
Queen Dianna went down
the road to the left!
Hold your fire! Don't let her
out of your sight!
Capture that Dianna woman!
The Militia have blocked the road!
Have you ordered them to take
Her Majesty prisoner?!
This limousine is too conspicuous.
The castle is close enough to walk to.
You expect me to walk?
I refuse.
It sounds fascinating.
Majesty!
We traveled here
all the way from up there.
You've got nothing to complain about!
You're always like this!
Let me believe in you,
Dianna Soriel.
Very well.
There's still no reports that the
Moon queen's been captured?!
Open fire, I said!
Their mechanical dolls aren't
shooting! Okay, let's move!
All right, let's go.
We aren't budging.
Why not?
We brought you here in order to
hand over Bostonia Castle to you!
We will not...
Get down!
Let us do as
Guin Lineford suggests.
May I?
Here comes!
Lt. Harry! The Mustache is coming!
Where?!
Permission to open fire!
No!
The Royal Guard? Is that
the SUMO from the airfield?
Don't open fire. There's no telling
where Queen Dianna is in all this.
Lt. Harry!
Stop!
Stop this, Laura!
Lt. Harry! Queen Dianna
is over here!
Magistrate Miran?
She is there?
Laura! You mustn't fight inside Nocis!
Queen Dianna!
It's really Queen Dianna!
Harry Ord! Desist!
A fine mobile suit.
I can even tell that
its pilot is shaking.
I'm shaking?
Lt. Harry, see to my protection!
Laura, stand by outside Nocis!
I have no combat command authority.
Nevertheless, last night's incident
cannot be tolerated.
We handed over Bostonia Castle to
show that we wish to continue negotiations.
I would like you to hand
over the responsible parties.
I am dusty after all that commotion.
Of course.
Your rooms are this way.
Thank you.
This way, Majesty.
Please follow me.
They might have kicked the Militia
out of Nocis, but look at how close they are!
It was Queen Dianna's decision.
What are you talking about, Poe?
Our job is to compensate for her weaknesses.
The Militia is beefing up their forces.
That's what happens during
cease-fires. Take us out.
Yes, sir.
Lousanan troops are the toughest!
We'll never give them our women!
I can't believe they eat food
placed directly on the ground.
Basically, they're the same as dogs.
Patrol the Vicinity area.
Yes, sir.
What are those people doing,
gathered together like that?
It seems like wherever there's a
crowd in this area, there's a party.
Cheers!
- Eat up!
- We brought more food than bullets!
- Machines can't beat people!
- These aliens ain't so tough!
- What territory you're from don't matter!
- I'll love aliens and Moonrace alike!
- You Lousanans are okay by me!
- Love will save the Earth!
Let us throw a party.
A ball is just the thing to thaw
relations between the Moon and Earth.
Such timid diplomacy would be...
There mustn't be a war.
Indeed.
About the truth of the Dark History...
The Dark History relics, Majesty?
We must end their excavations.
Agreed.
I've been waiting.
I heard downstairs.
There will be a party?
The Royal Guards' Lt. Harry Ord says
he is eager to meet the White Doll's pilot.
But I can't dance!
I'm ordering you as a
member of the Militia.
I don't have anything to wear.
Kihel Heim will
assist you with that.
Master Guin wants to show that we
have a mechanical doll as good as theirs,
and that it is a woman who is driving it.
We want a cake like this.
It's two meters tall?
Here's the deposit.
The rest will be paid on delivery.
Thanks.
Bye, then.
Thanks for waiting.
Should we be accepting
orders from the enemy?
This money couldn't have come
at a better time. Thanks, Keith.
Don't mention it, Miss.
So, a cake over
two meters high, huh?
One, two... One, two...
I told you to keep your
back straight, didn't I?
Take a look.
Does it look strange?
It looks strange.
You think so?
You're kidding!
Corsets...
...make your waist slimmer,
and that's crucial to a woman!
That hurts!
Good! Like that!
Move with your partner!
- Good!
- I wouldn't call this a partner!
- What unusual clothing...
- Well, history is the product of war...
Thank you.
Both sides are simply eyeing each other.
We need an icebreaker, or this
will be an awkward evening.
Are they going to call it off?
I doubt it.
Then allow me.
Be relaxed.
I will.
He's coming over!
The dance floor is going to waste.
What gaudy clothing...
Given the situation, it would
be rude not to accept.
You're right. Go on.
I couldn't possibly! I don't...
Get in there and show off
the fruits of your lessons!
It's Laura Rolla!
This is turning into a battle of the sexes!
- Ah, Miss Laura.
- They're mechanical doll pilots?
Excuse me. Would you care
to dance, Lieutenant?
I'd be delighted, Laura.
Lead... Lead away, Lieutenant.
Right this way.
Let's go, too.
Carry out the mission!
May I have the honor of this dance?
It would be my pleasure.
The people from Donkey Bakery are here.
We'll add the finishing touches here.
The Militia brought in the Moonrace's cake?
Call it a show of friendly cooperation.
I don't believe you utterly
outclass us militarily.
You refer to the excavation of
relics of the ancient space age?
Lt. Harry.
Yes?
I would like to introduce Laura
to Queen Dianna.
Yes, of course.
I will return her afterwards.
Laura Rolla is coming over?
There's no need to make chit-chat.
Oh, what's the harm? Hush!
May I introduce Laura Rolla,
ace pilot of the White Doll,
the pride of the Militia?
Thank you for the honor of an
audience with Your Majesty.
Queen Dianna...
Yes?
Why does the fighting continue in
spite of Your Majesty's arrival?
Young lady, this is neither
the time nor the place!
Laura! Don't be rude!
Queen Dianna, did you...
I believe a hand-kiss
is customary first, Laura Rolla.
Y-Yes, Majesty.
Our wish is the same.
We do not wish to fight.
Of course.
Lord Guin, we mustn't keep people
whom we both hold dear in a state of worry.
I agree.
It's a friendship cake!
That's a cake?
The star of the show is here!
Now that looks worth eating!
And now...
How magnificent!
Please step up to the cake.
Queen Dianna
and Master Guin, together!
As a sign of your friendship,
please place a rose in each other's lands.
Very well.
Prepare to...
Bastards!
Dianna!
If Dianna hadn't come here...
...there wouldn't be any fighting!
Why, you!
There's more outside?
That way!
Security!
Hold it!
After them!
What happened, Laura?
Assassins!
Miss Laura?
In a mobile suit?
Is that them?
Militia fiends!
A mechanical doll!
Why are you people doing this?!
One got away!
I can't control it
precisely enough!
Why didn't you hold them tight?
Did you let them escape?!
If I'd grabbed them too hard,
I would have crushed them!
Are you that clumsy a pilot?
What do you make of this, sir?
Make of what?
It's a portable oxygen respirator.
A respirator? Then they...
Assassins that were using respirators?
Then they must have been...
I want all hands helping
to unload that ship!
Remember to match the contents
against the checklist!
Three mobile suits?
I don't see them anywhere in the manifest!
That man, he's...
You know him, ma'am?
He's more dangerous than all
the explosives they just sent us.
Worse than explosives?
They sent a guy like him?!
He was pardoned and released from
the military cold sleep prison?
From the cold sleep prison?
New input?
Our Earth arrival report.
We're the Corin Nander Autonomous
Squad. It's a pleasure.
I'm Bruno. This is Jacop.
We're just as unhappy about this
walking catastrophe as you are.
The blue sky! Green, green!
Everything's so gaudy on Earth!
Where's Lt. Zenoa?
Out on an excavation survey.
Could you forward me their location?
Yeah, we're gonna unload this guy
and have them ship us back to the Moon.
- This doesn't make any sense!
- Miss?
I've set it to recognize your voice,
so you just have to say a topic heading.
I don't even know what the topics
are! That's why I can't use it!
That's why I've been
studying every day.
I can't instantly be able to work
a Moonrace-level machine!
Sorry...
A Moonrace-level machine...
Loran, are you...
What is it?
I'll study harder.
Please do, Miss.
Moonrace...
Higher-ups and common folk alike
are getting too excited here.
I regret that as a result,
our talks have stalled and our
soldiers are starting skirmishes.
I'd like you to use your advanced
communications gear...
...to inform all Moonrace
how you feel.
What sort of woman is she?
She humbly bowed in apology.
What is your purpose in stationing
an airship at the castle?
I'm having it survey the damage
from the fighting.
In order to provide relief
to the victims.
Ah, I see. Will it be
conducting further flights?
I'm glad you're here!
Hide the White Doll in the woods!
The mechanic squad is here?
That's right. You and Loran need
to go to Bostonia Castle!
But there are Moonrace there!
That's why!
Kapools, start digging out its feet
starting from the left side!
Move those on the right
to the left side, too!
Watch your feet!
Move as a group!
- Move the Kapool this way!
- The money we agreed on.
Oh. Thank you.
That's enough to buy a house.
Can you drive this thing?
No, I want to expand
our bakery with this.
Too bad. It's going to take a while
for our airplane pilots to figure it out.
Don't worry.
I bet this has some
kind of manual.
We will be on an airship, so it
ought to be something loose.
Oh, I see. How about this?
Might I trouble you to model
them for me, Miss Kihel?
Model them for you?
What do you think?
I like it!
Miss Kihel, would you mind letting
me see you in my own outfit?
You want me to wear
your outfit, Majesty?
It's all right, isn't it?
Please.
And the finishing touch...
Ah, I see.
Would you mind turning
around slowly?
So this is what
I look like from behind.
But surely you can see yourself
from behind in films or whatnot?
It's not the same as seeing
the real thing.
Sir Magistrate Miran!
No sir is needed.
I see.
Miran, we shall now embark
on our inspection flight.
Oh, well done!
Miss Kihel, you scamp!
Queen Dianna!
Queen Dianna must have been lonely...
Who is it?
Magistrate Miran. I am here to
escort you to the airship.
You may enter!
Yes, Majesty.
Proceed, Queen Dianna.
What if we're discovered?
Then we shall simply
apologize together.
Right this way,
Queen Dianna Soriel.
Magistrate Miran, please lead the way.
Are you sure we should go
all the way to Vicinity, sir?
There will be nothing but wrecked
gun batteries along that course, correct?
Lord Guin, visitors.
Who is it?
Loran Cehack and Sochie Heim, sir.
Show them in.
Yes, sir!
Is their move-in coming along?
Are we really giving the castle to Dianna?
If I don't, the local lords won't play along.
You came?
I have a report from Old Man Sid.
- Thank you.
- Also...
Also, send my sister home.
Our mother isn't doing well.
I'll send her home on the
airship that is about to leave.
The mustached machine
has a sword of light?
Yes.
It's more of a device that emits a stream of
superheated particles than light, though.
The airship is leaving soon.
And now you, Miss Kihel.
I shall go with you, then.
So, this is the gondola...
I've never boarded an airship
this way, either.
Please be careful. You must
speak in a haughtier manner.
Of course, I must sound
more pompous.
Please put your mind at ease.
Airships float in the air by their nature.
I am aware.
Queen Dianna, the aft section
is set up as an observation area.
Ah, it is?
Dianna? Sis?
Loran? Sochie...
Sochie Heim!
We had not been informed that
you would be here, Majesty!
Your sister told me
all about you.
Please put yourself
at ease, Loran.
Thank you!
Sis, Mother has been crying,
saying that she's lonely.
This airship is scheduled to make a
loop around Vicinity and then return.
Why don't we get out there?
Yes. I would like to
disembark there, as well.
Is that acceptable?
As you wish. Miss Kihel,
could you make us some tea?
- Yes.
- Allow me!
Let's see, where's the tea set?
Dummy, isn't that my sister's job?
How beautiful...
Yes. It is particularly lovely today.
Such a landscape mustn't be marred by war.
There is also the food issue.
Yes, neither side's forces must
harm this breadbasket region.
Of course.
Do the lords of the
Amerian continent agree?
Let's convince them.
I'd like to borrow
Miss Kihel, if I may.
Feel free.
Mobile suits!
You don't have a change of clothes?
I'm afraid not.
And you, Miss Sochie?
What kind of clothing?
Queen Dianna's outfit is conspicuous.
It will draw the Militia's attention.
Your room wasn't damaged
in the fire,
so just lend her something.
Or don't you want to?
It's not that. I just thought that perhaps
there was something aboard the airship.
Talk about stupid.
Of course there aren't.
You have similar builds, so I
expect that Miss Kihel's will fit her.
They will fit her perfectly.
Or so I would think...
What are you looking
so happy for?
Keep a stiff upper lip.
But I... You can see how I feel, right?
I can. What you're saying isn't wrong.
Be strong. My intention is
to set things on a better course.
Harry... Help me.
Miss Kihel! It's so good
to see you!
And you, Miss Sochie!
Your mother is waiting!
Um, if you'd like to pay your
respects, I'm sure they wouldn't mind.
Wouldn't they?
I think they would allow Queen
Dianna Soriel to offer her best wishes.
Aren't you going to
show her the way, Laura?
Of course!
Excuse us!
It's Queen Dianna Soriel.
Come in.
Summer vacation seemed to
go on forever, didn't it?
I've had too much homework
to come home before now.
That's all right. Just seeing
your face makes me happy.
Mistress, Miss Kihel has
come home, as well.
Mother, forgive me. I have been
so busy at work.
Are your studies going well at university?
Of course. And I've made
many friends, as well.
I'm alone with Sam and Jessica
in this huge house.
I know.
Your father is always in the
mountains expanding production.
I know that he's working hard for
the country, so that's to be expected.
I launched a war against a land
with people such as this in it?
I am so terribly sorry.
Your hands have gotten warmer, Kihel.
Thank you, Mother.
Sis, I think we should go
pay our respects to Father.
Yes, of course.
Tell your father not to worry
about the house, all right?
We will.
Miss Kihel?
Father! Please forgive me!
I'm so sorry for taking so
long to pay my respects!
I thoughtlessly used my work as
an excuse to put off returning home.
I am so terribly sorry.
Please rest in peace.
Miss Kihel...
Queen Dianna Soriel...
You truly mean those words, don't you?
Harry is leaving...
I'm sorry, Laura, but could you go
meet Sid and help with the excavations?
Did they find something new
from the Dark History?
Sochie, meet up with Col. Michael.
Yes, sir!
They say they've located a ship
capable of flying in space...
...in Kingsley Valley near Aubany.
Aubany?
That certainly piques one's
curiosity, doesn't it, Loran?
You want to come along?
Col. Michael seems to be carrying
out an operation without my knowledge.
I've heard of it.
Miss Kihel,
it's not bad that you see a
revolutionary artifact from the Dark History.
Thank you!
Miss!
You heard him!
There's an operation!
Well, this should be
usable in combat.
No, we'll do it ourselves.
Impossible! Even if you've gotten
yourselves a Moonrace FLAT,
it's just the one!
The Inglessan Militia is more than
enough to drive the Moonrace out of Nocis!
We don't require
Lousana's assistance!
This won't be anything like the
petty water disputes we've engaged in.
Good, they've come!
Who's come?
Joseph!
There!
Mechanical dolls!
Dianna Counter mechanical dolls are here?
They were discovered in our territory,
so we have named them Borjarnons!
Excavations are still underway,
so their numbers will only grow!
Even if we destroy that Soleil
ship, we won't lay claim to Nocis.
Hello!
What?
I'm Gavane of the
Suicide Squad, Joseph.
I operate the FLAT.
Nice to meet you, Sochie Heim.
You know who I am?
You're the gallant lady pilot
who operates a Kapool, aren't you?
Y-Yes, that's right.
Nice to meet you.
Spirit of the Moon!
Spirit of the Moon, be one with us!
One with us! One with us!
With our souls, be one!
Be one! Be one!
What are they dancing for?
They're happy to be able
to serve Queen Dianna.
Lt. Cmdr. Phil has a screw loose.
Just because they say
they're descended from Moonrace,
he lends them mobile suits...
Who's in charge here?
What is it?
Sign here to acknowledge receipt
of the FLATs and WaDs!
Sure, Cancer of the Rett team!
Sorry about that!
Miss, are you all right?
Rather shaken, but otherwise fine.
Where are we?
This must be the underground
passage that Mr. Sid mentioned.
Let's see where it leads.
Fine.
Is the White Doll all right?
Yes. Wait here a moment!
There's no sign of it!
There sure isn't...
If you can't find it, make it so you can!
Smoke him out with those
railguns of yours!
Roger that.
The White Doll is providing
the perfect diversion,
so we'll be able to drive
the Soleil out of Nocis.
They'll never expect us to attack
without the White Doll.
Leave out the Bull Ones.
They're too slow.
It's a little late for that, Miashei.
We'll follow you with our
mechanical doll squads.
Right, Lt. Col. Mallygan?
You can count on us.
We have ideas for close-quarters
mechanical doll combat.
We've been training in our
Borjarnons for just that!
We won't let them give
you ladies a hard time.
Oh, my!
Tough talk, Suicide Squad...
What of the returnees here?
They'll be used as hostages
by Inglessa, I expect.
And that is acceptable to you?
We will retreat to the Sunbelt...
...and claim that we require more
territory than we anticipated.
And then negotiate down from there?
What say you? I agree that the safety of the
returnees should come first, but...
Could you arrange for one
last round of talks?
With Lord Guin?
Magistrate.
When we meet, I should like to speak with
that secretary, Kihel Heim, once more.
Understood. I will make the
necessary adjustments to your schedule.
It's the white mobile suit!
If I can break their legs...
There was no sign
that he used a weapon...
Loran! Are there many enemies?
At least one more!
If it's only the one,
shall I tell him to let us go?
What did you say?
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's just that I've often been told
that I resemble the enemy's leader.
Oops. That's not good!
Everybody, get out of the tunnel! Get clear!
What the hell?
There's tunnels like this under here?
I see people!
I'm falling!
Isn't there a way out?
There's nowhere to run!
- Isn't that the excavation team?
- Can we hide anywhere?
It looks like there's
been a cave-in.
An enemy doll came in
from the ceiling!
That way's no good, either!
Why not?
There are still enemies there!
How do we get out, then?
I'll hold him off here, so you take
Miss Kihel and look for a way out.
Loran!
Don't do anything crazy, Loran!
I sold the FLAT.
We decided to live here as Earthers.
We need some seed money to do that.
But how could you sell it?
I want a chain of bakeries here on Earth!
Isn't that a big undertaking?
That's why I need the money.
I understand that, but still...
Isn't that across from the
airfield? What happened?
The Militia must be attacking
the Moonrace settlement!
I'll head back to the newspaper!
- Fran, get clear!
- Keith!
Where are they coming from?!
The northwest... and also from inside Nocis!
Those are airplanes!
Lt. Commander!
It's an airplane squadron?!
Is the Militia seriously
launching an all-out assault?
More of a temper tantrum.
Enemy mobile suit force closing in!
What do we tell Queen Dianna?
I will inform her.
Put the Royal Guard on Soleil defense!
The Phil Ackman team will halt
the Militia's mobile suits' advance,
and then attack only
the Mountain Cycle to their rear.
Don't lay a hand on the city.
It's going to be our capital.
The Lt. Commander is an ambitious man.
What?!
Master Guin! We must evacuate!
But the Dianna Counter is using this castle!
Where has Lt. Harry gone?
Into battle, ma'am.
I see.
Those are SUMO mechanical dolls...
Loss of life is not to be
tolerated, even that of the enemy.
They have been informed.
The Air Corps?
People are on those airplanes made
of canvas and wood! Do not target them!
Get us above the Soleil, Miashei!
Roger that!
This attack is madness...
Queen Dianna, please leave the bridge!
The Soleil's presence at their
airfield is what is antagonizing them,
so get us off the ground.
Yes, ma'am!
I'm not about to
stand idly by!
Miss!
Please stop this foolishness.
I can't brace myself!
You're tarnishing the Gundam name!
The likes of you shouldn't be
allowed to use the white mobile suit!
That's more like it!
That was a cave-in!
Lieutenant! Please give us
permission to engage directly!
No direct targeting!
Joseph, go from there!
Suicide Squad, advance
from the left flank!
Watch this!
What squad do those on
our right flank belong to?
What are those mobile suits
to the rear?!
Boss, we're falling back!
Mobile suits?
Our cannons are hitting,
but they're having no effect?
John! Bill! Fall back while
covering the other mechanical dolls!
Lt. Harry!
They've developed
mobile suits like those?
Perhaps they were unearthed in Lousana.
- Lousana?
- Soleil, lifting off!
Tell the Suicide Squad!
It'll take more than that!
The Soleil is getting away!
Tell the Suicide Squad!
Let's chase it!
Why are you stopping me?
Calmly observe the enemy's
fighting strength, little lady!
Nanoskin strips that were
covering the monitors?
They'll work as well as before,
right? What should I do?
I hope you aren't dead, Gundam!
The White Doll
isn't gazing over me?
Just look at the glow
of that magma!
Do you see?
Melting in that bubbling magma will let you
become one with your precious Earth!
There's a memory in
my brain somewhere...
...that a Gundam once
made a fool of me!
I wanna get rid of it!
I want to smash you all!
Corin Nander!
Your Majesty!
Miss Kihel!
Your mission has been
completed, Corin Nander.
Now, leave us!
That's not right, Majesty!
It's the Gundam!
It's right here! See?!
This is a different time,
and your mission is complete!
If you do not obey my order,
I shall execute you!
Y-Your Majesty!
Withdraw this instant!
You have atoned in full
for your crime!
He didn't listen?!
Fall! Fall into the magma
and melt away to nothing!
Corin!
You are continuing, so in the name
of Dianna Soriel, I will execute you!
Majesty! Everything I've done,
I've done for your happiness!
I never asked for that!
Now!
Don't fall!
The symbol of Bostonia Castle has collapsed?
The Dianna Counter's flying
warships are heading south!
I've got 20/10 vision,
I can see that.
Can't do much if they're flying...
Is their plan to occupy the Sunbelt?
Indeed. They fully intend
to live on this continent.
If they didn't, they would have
completely wiped out Nocis.
What now?
Why don't we launch
an attack against the Moon?
What?
We've found mechanical dolls like
the Borjarnons among the Dark History relics.
Meaning that we're sure to find a
warship that can fly to the Moon.
Yes, I've heard something about you
using Moonrace engineers on Sid's teams.
You've heard about that?
May I enter?
Go ahead.
I would like you to go over the
draft of the statehood declaration, Majesty.
Is it truly necessary to take the
Sunbelt as our own country?
Yes. It is crucial
to avoiding a war.
Very well.
I will stop by first thing
in the morning, then.
Of course.
Will this allow the Moonrace and
people of Earth to coexist, Queen Dianna?
According to the
Moonrace engineers,
that spaceship will be
able to fly, Laura.
Willghem isn't a name
for a warship, though.
It depends on how it's used.
The queen herself sent you an
invitation to tomorrow's ceremony.
That's amazing!
I'm not thrilled that it's
for Laura Rolla, though...
That has its uses, too.
I can't believe we have to listen
to the Dianna Counter declare their statehood.
This means we've totally lost!
It can't be helped. After all, even
Master Guin fled from Nocis.
I'm glad that I got to see
you again, though...
Miss Sochie! Your manners
are appalling!
You're no fun.
Will Miss Kihel only become the
pawn of Miran and the others?
Loran. Wake up.
I sensed that something was off
about you. For a long time now.
I've always respected Queen Dianna...
And I admire Miss Kihel...
How could I not tell you apart all this time?
Kihel Heim is a woman of
great inner strength,
so I find it unlikely that she
will let herself be Miran's pawn.
When I think about what
will happen tomorrow...
Miss Kihel is aboard the Soleil?
She is, isn't she...
I cannot imagine that she will be able to
take control of the return policy in my place.
No...
Loran Cehack.
Please help me.
We'll pay you back double!
A likely story!
Pops! I'm here to pick up the liquor!
Hey, Pops! If you sleep here,
you're gonna catch cold!
They said you guys were coming,
so I waited for you.
Sorry about that.
Where's the owner?
I'm waiting here in his place.
The order's so big that the
supplier will deliver it directly.
We just need to show
this at the rear gate, right?
Good morning!
I have one truck's worth for now.
Can we take two trucks at once?
Thanks, lady.
You're coming, right?
Of course!
Nice to meet you.
Where is the auto of Lousana's
Miss Lily Borjarno?
On the road to the right.
I know what you are up to.
You find it amusing?
You can't launch a guerilla
attack against the Soleil,
not with lords from across
the continent present.
Miss Lily!
Miss Laura Rolla?
Yes?
Why don't you bring your mobile
suit over to our side?
I think it would be faster
to mingle in with the Earthers.
It's good to see
you safe, Master Guin!
Miss Lily Borjarno, you are
as bewitching as ever.
Miss Kihel, your servant Loran
has arrived with Queen Dianna.
So, the Mustache is here
along with that Laura Rolla floozy?
All these Earthers here for the ceremony
are turning this into a school festival!
These are my two guests,
along with Lousana's Miss Lily.
Unbelievable. These guys are so
tactless it's not even funny.
How do I set it to
maximum magnification?
Oh, that's the one?
That got it!
The Inglessans' trucks got in?
When Col. Michael gets started,
it'll throw a wrench in
the Moonrace's plans!
I will excuse myself.
Do you have a message
from your father?
He says to proceed as you see fit.
Where did Miss Kihel go?
I mustn't be seen taking
any action here personally.
What are you doing?
Hey, who are you?!
Why, you!
Well done.
I wished to see how well my men
performed their duties.
The Royal Guard
snuck her out in secret.
I will go back up.
This is the last of it!
Call over Mitchell's squad!
Oh, come on! You can't even
handle this weak stuff?
You should finish off this
last cask yourselves. Right?
I said to carry that in!
You call this booze?!
On Earth, even children drink this.
How are things going on your end?
They're all offloaded.
Good work.
There's no pilot in that mechanical
doll that's holding up that striped curtain.
Make it run wild.
Will do.
Yanny!
Sir?
It's time.
Yes, sir!
What about the woman?
She's playing along with our plan.
You didn't bring her, Colonel?
I had nothing to do with her.
Really?
Master Guin's in the ceremony pavilion.
We'll roll the barrels with
99% alcohol towards the back.
Down I go!
Next!
Let's use the elevator!
We'll never get past any guarded area.
After all, we have no idea what
sort of situation Miss Kihel is in.
Thish ish the invoice?
Too easy.
Where are you going, baby?
This bust is too tight...
Internal power struggles?
All right, time to go!
Yes sir!
Okay! Let's give them
what they asked for!
That's the signal!
Fire at will, and then retreat!
A Militia attack?
Master Guin!
A bombardment?
I wasn't told about this operation!
Neither was I!
Enemy attack!
Raise the barrier!
Hang in there, petty officer!
She should be one floor up.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please stay inside the tent!
I could've fought if I had stolen
that mechanical doll!
Stay put, Suicide Sochie.
Suicide Sochie?!
Even when fighting, one must
first gauge the situation.
That was a decoy!
I've found you at last,
Queen Dianna Soriel.
Identify yourself.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
If you kill me, the Earth
Return Plan will...
Not every Moonrace wants
to return to Earth!
Did Agrippa Maintainer
put you up to this?
It's nothing personal.
Just die!
She got away!
Are you hurt, Majesty?!
What of the attack outside?
What happened?
I had the SUMOs and other suits
deal with it.
No guests have been injured.
Just one look!
This deck is off limits!
Get rid of her!
Yes, sir!
Harry, the elevator can't be used.
I will take those stairs.
Yes.
Take me to Queen Dianna!
Just for a second!
Kihel Heim!
I insist you leave!
Go on!
- Queen Dianna is here...
- We're leaving! Stop pushing!
It is clear.
You're going to issue a
declaration of statehood?
Kihel Heim?
Queen Dianna.
It is to improve relations
between the Earth and Moon.
Truly?
Of course.
I-In that case... Tread lightly.
Harry!
Majesty?
Let them return to Master Guin.
- But Majesty!
- That is an order.
Yes, Majesty.
Our mother Earth was once
turned into such a wasteland...
...that she became unfit
for human habitation.
The Dark History tells us that
there was such a time!
And yet, in spite of that, the children of
Earth forget this fact! Why is that?
- This Moonrace is telling it like it is.
- Mankind's tragic nature is to forget...
- Indeed she is.
...its most painful experiences and memories.
Until the Earth was habitable once more,
we Moonrace dwelled on the Moon.
To bequeath our memories of mankind!
To aid in the rebirth of a new humanity!
And today, after the passage of
some 2,000 years of history,
the human race can now thrive
once again on Earth.
And so, the Moonrace wishes to
return to the Earth to assist in her rebirth,
and to make certain that this
mistake in our history is never repeated!
Loran, Kihel Heim is spelling out
my true feelings better than I ever could.
Yes, Ma'am. I think so, too.
The people of Earth have built up
the strength to be reborn...
...by spinning mankind's past march
into space into tales of gods in the heavens,
or by sealing it away
in the Dark History.
This is because mankind cannot
be reborn or rise again...
...through a tragic,
cruel past alone.
It is for this reason that we alter
our interpretation of historical facts,
and, at times, rewrite history itself.
Our bodies are...
...no different from those of Earthers.
This means that we will be able to
reunite into a single race one day.
I have therefore decided not to
claim the Sunbelt as a Moonrace state...
...and instead ask the people of
Ameria to reopen negotiations!
Is that Dianna Soriel?
Kihel Heim, I believe that I can
safely leave the Moonrace in your hands.
Miss Kihel has come so far...
Dianna Soriel!
Say nothing.
This will only embolden the Militia!
Then we will defend ourselves
with noble ideals.
Is she joking?! If that's Dianna's
plan, what use are we soldiers?!
We're like buffoons
for her amusement.
One can't keep a military in line
with noble ideals alone, Kihel Heim!
Even a civilian like Kihel Heim,
Guin Lineford's personal secretary,
wouldn't be as naively sentimental
as you just were, Queen Dianna.
I want to tell you that.
Do not compare that commoner to the
woman who holds the Moonrace together.
Only concern yourselves
with obeying your queen!
Without orders from their bigwigs,
mechanical dolls like that...
...are just showpieces and
nuisances. Right, Miss Lily?
That's right.
While we have even found an armored
vehicle that doesn't use wheels.
Along with a flying battleship.
Not here! That is classified.
Master Guin?
Is what she said true?
We must prepare for the
eventuality that Dianna Soriel...
...will be unable to control
her forces.
That thing was one hell of a find.
Ladderrum, it's really that big?
Yeah.
One, two, pull!
This is that nanoskin stuff, right?
Yes, it protected the machines
that were buried in the earth...
And at the same time, it formed the
dirt that kept them hidden all these years?
Huh? I don't get
how that works.
I'm not surprised. Oh, the head of
that mustached mobile suit is damaged.
That's where it gets strange. It
wasn't like that when it was first damaged.
There's these blisters
on the surface.
Then let's remove the head
and take a look.
Loran, I opened the window
over here.
You'll get dirty, Miss!
- Surely a fluke resemblance...
- Laura!
I'm making you the captain,
so please get it up and running.
You're the most qualified, aren't you?
Queen Dianna...
I am Kihel.
We should take geopolitical
implications into account...
...when establishing our borders,
is that what you are saying?
Precisely. The initial proposed
territory boundaries will tip our hand.
Why did you say so
before the speech?
This recent incident reintroduced
me to the concept of geopolitics.
My apologies.
Of course.
However...
We cannot turn a blind eye to the
spaceship the Militia is excavating.
I am considering the issue.
Harry and Miran.
Majesty?
Agrippa Maintainer, who is
entrusted with the capital city of Gengnham,
has turned traitor along
with his entire clan?
No, starting the Earthfall
operation signaled that times had changed.
Which, in turn, altered the mindset
of the Maintainer clan.
And this new mindset caused them
to send assassins to kill me?
Do not forget Corin.
We should assume so.
We can't allow the Soleil to remain
surrounded by those Militia savages.
The Zenoa team has presented their
Lost Mountain survey findings?
If we wait for that, we won't be
able to break free of the Soleil.
You're still having second thoughts?
Stop crying!
I'm not crying, sir!
Let's make our move,
Lt. Commander!
You want the White Doll's
head set outside, then?
We can manage after that.
Hey, boss!
Yes, what is it?
Um, we're looking for the captain.
They said he was here.
You know the captain?
That's right!
It is nice to meet you.
I'm Horace, chief engineer.
Huh?
Who are you?
Are you Captain Loran?
Mr. Horace kindly gave us referrals.
Oh, you work here?
They intend to fight anyway?
Ah, thank you. Did you learn
Lt. Cmdr. Phil's plan?
Yes. He says he intends
to drive off the Militia...
...and seize the spaceship
that they excavated.
Guin Lineford is
there now, is he not?
Yes. Moonrace engineers
who defected are also there,
so he intends to
capture them all.
Where Lord Guin is, Kihel Heim
is sure to be at his side.
It is likely.
Are you not concerned for her safety?
Indeed.
As much as I am for yours.
In that case, Harry Ord...
Yes?
Go to Kingsley Valley
and carry out your true duty.
But I mustn't leave
your side now.
Dianna Soriel has given you a direct order.
Yes, Majesty.
However, please return quickly.
Of course, Majesty.
What unit are you with?!
Stop tearing up the road!
We're the Rett team,
an autonomous squad!
The Zenoa survey team
is down this road, isn't it?
This is no place for Moonrace who
went native on Earth! Get lost!
Bastard! Do you wanna get squashed?!
Let's go.
But, Boss!
The Zenoa Team has found
some kind of treasure!
In an empty wasteland like this?
Do it!
M-Moving out!
Don't step on us!
This makes three, huh?
Are there any more?
The whole place is buried in
nanoskin! Send a WaD down, sir!
Will do.
Send these three mobile armors
to the Soleil!
The Soleil isn't a repair shop, damn it...
Idiot! Watch where you're driving!
Sorry! I nodded off!
You alone, missy?
I'm a reporter for the Nocis
Chronicle! Give me an interview!
Sure, come see me tonight!
A Militia FLAT, huh?
I've got it! That's the one
that Keith sold them!
Mobile suits, Kapools,
and an armored hover vehicle...
I knew it!
You knew what?
I-I'm with the Nocis Chronicle.
You're a Moonrace, right?
Did you come from the Moon
in this mechanical doll?
O-Of course not!
My grandparents might
have been, but I...
You're Fran Doll the reporter, right?
I've read a couple of your articles.
Thanks!
You're a Moonrace for sure.
Why would you insinuate that?
I can tell those who are
out of the ordinary.
You've even linked up with
Lousanan Borjarnons!
Yeah.
He's here!
As a result of various factors...
...I was forced to have my men
deliver the dress I got you as a gift.
H-However, I hope to have you
stand at my left in that dress,
and have come to
hear your answer.
It's to the right.
Don't get mad at him!
I'm not mad.
Just wear it?
N-No! My intention is
to make you my bride!
Oh, that! Well, if that's
what you're asking,
that's a big question, so I would
need time to think it over.
Of course!
Thank you, though.
I love it.
I'm honored!
I need to discuss it
with my mother and sister.
Of course!
The mustached mechanical doll is
able to power such a large ship?
No, they're simply going to
jump-start it using the White Doll's engine.
What a clever idea, using the
White Doll as a starter...
Poe! Don't destroy the
Dark History relic!
We need to study it!
I know, we're to capture it along
with all the Moonrace engineers!
They didn't even notice my
approach. Whatever shall I do with them?
Give it more power!
Good! A little more!
Do we have it?
Yes!
They're lit!
Let me through!
Good work!
Once you've stowed those tubes,
stand watch in the White Doll!
Roger!
- To think that humanity had to forget...
- This is great!
- ...this part of their heritage...
- They say this can take us into space?
Excuse me.
Yes?
If I might have a word, Miss?
That voice...
When a machine is running,
one has an urge to touch it.
That is true.
Was it like this with the
White Doll, Sochie?
It's less than half as impressive,
but this is much bigger.
How true.
This mobile suit's hidden potential
is amazing... Huh?
Who's she leaving with?
That's strange.
I am asking you to leave
this area immediately!
If you stop Phil's attack...
I can't do that!
What's he... Stop that!
Get away from her!
Don't interfere!
This is Lt. Harry.
Harry? The Royal Guardsman?
He came to inform me that this
valley is about to be attacked.
Does that mean you're deserting the
Royal Guard and joining the Militia?
Don't be absurd!
Then you're here to
abduct Miss Kihel.
She's Queen Dianna!
She's Miss Kihel here.
They're testing the spaceship's engines!
Next to that valley?
Captain, look at this!
What is it?
They look like Dianna Counter
Scarecrows to me.
What? We still have cargo to offload.
- John! Aims! Have them bring us weapons!
- Defensive positions! Climb up the valley!
Make them hurry!
Don't drop anyone!
Grab on!
- We have to get to our Kapools!
- Enemies spotted!
Send up the Suicide Squad, too!
The White Doll, too!
Enemy numbers?
Ten mechanical dolls, of which
five are jumbo Scarecrows!
That was a big help, showing me how
to use this FLAT properly, Fran Doll.
Come on, you can let me observe
the battle from here!
You aren't a soldier!
But I...
You can report on how we fight
just as well from the outside.
Joseph?
We'll be fighting Moonrace.
Don't die, Joseph!
Beginning containment attack!
Ready!
Queen Dianna, please
leave with Lt. Harry.
Can you protect the spaceship?
Of course. Good luck.
And you.
The next one's gonna hit!
Let's try that Hyper Vibration
that Fran Doll mentioned!
This thing's Vulcans can't
keep up with missiles!
What's keeping the Militia?!
If what Mr. Horace said is right, I
can channel the I-field into the shield...
This way?
Left side! A beam?
Wow...
I-field, activated!
React automatically to alerts, set!
Locate enemy!
The Mustache put up a barrier?
It can even do that?
Militia scum!
If they fire a beam,
block it with missiles!
Kapool squad, stay behind me!
They think the Militia has the
firepower to drive me off?!
Go!
Miss, you need to get back!
Mr. Horace!
Oh, no! The airship!
Kapool squad, please stay put!
Ow, that's hot!
That's the rifle they unearthed?
Why am I being forced to
protect our enemies?
Poe will be the only one to attack
via mega particle cannon!
We will capture the spaceship
and return with it!
Don't worry about the little stuff!
Lt. Harry can help.
There is nothing
to impede our liftoff?
Activate power source!
The cliff won't collapse, will it?
We must leave before it does.
But won't we be fired on as
soon as we leave the ground?
The Dianna Counter wouldn't do
something as foolish as destroying this ship.
So we can stop the fighting if we
plow this baby into the thick of it.
Can we?
It's from the Dark History, after all.
Anti-aircraft corps, fire!
If I can get a great shot...
I'll be dead by then!
Lt. Cmdr. Phil doesn't know
that Queen Dianna is here!
Harry!
The relic is moving?
Oh, my. Isn't that golden
mechanical doll an enemy?
The Mustache is here?
Here we...
...go!
Okay, then!
I'll flatten you!
Sochie! Are you okay?!
That was awesome, Gavane!
No, we aren't armed
with ray guns!
That's two! Col. Michael, tighten
your defense around the Willghem!
Nozzles?
Temperatures normal.
Should it be shaking like this?
I know it's risky. Mr. Horace!
It seems to be fine.
All personnel, we're lifting off!
Sochie, the Willghem's breaking
free! There's still two more Scarecrows!
So, have you won?
I'm not quite that optimistic.
You're not getting off the ground!
The Mustache?!
Loran! Are you okay?
Are you still good to go, Loran?
Laura, buy us time!
I know!
But I'm not your Laura and I'm not your tool!
Loran!
I-It got my legs!
Lt. Commander!
It's flying...
The relic is flying...
The Dark History relic is flying?
Yes, at an altitude of 80 meters!
I can see that!
I'm sorry, sir!
Are you unhurt?
I don't think that Miss Kihel
walks around quite so much.
Queen Dianna?
When did she leave the ship?
Where did you go, Majesty?
Do I not always say that evading you has
become a game with which to amuse myself?
She got me again...
Kihel Heim!
Queen Dianna!
Thank you! Thank you for
all your hard work!
Surely it was harder
for you out there!
Any difficulties I had
were of my own making.
You were amazing,
keeping the Soleil pinned here
while dealing with the constant troubles...
...brought upon you
by my own forces!
Your actions have prevented the Dianna Counter
from committing any grave sins.
You truly think so,
Your Majesty?
Please do not refer
to me so, Kihel.
Of course, Queen Dianna.
It must have been most difficult
to learn about the Moon,
study the military, and examine
my relationships with others.
It was. I surreptitiously learned
how to read your computer data files.
I also took the liberty of
reading your private files.
You are Dianna,
so that is only natural.
I have come to realize that
a long life is no blessing!
Do not say that. There is much that
is not contained in those files.
In my past, there were
many joyous events, too.
Queen Dianna...
Who is it?
Lt. Harry Ord.
Is everything all right?
Of course. Thank you.
It was nothing.
Thank you for protecting Kihel.
Think nothing of it.
Say, Mottke... Does this remind
you of our homeland, the Moon?
Except the sun doesn't
shine like this.
They're digging all over the place,
but there's no sign of Zenoa himself!
They should've let us handle this
job since we're used to living on Earth!
Move out!
Yes, ma'am!
There are Dark History relics
in a place like this?
Commander Gavane, we found a shaft
below us that goes further in!
You did? Is it deep?
And how! This shaft must have
been made for a special reason.
Okay, that's enough!
Where have you
been goofing off?
You didn't find my sister?
I think she was taken by that
golden mechanical doll.
- Yeah, yeah!
How can you say that...
...so casually?
That mechanical doll didn't do...
We've got trouble!
Gavane's squad has bumped into
a Dianna Counter team!
They did?
They're excavating at the Lost Mountain.
That's a mountain that we
prospectors stay well clear of.
Then let's head out!
Miss, don't rush out just yet!
Why not?!
They're in a standoff.
In any case, we should at least
send in the Gallop, right?
Joseph's Jalapy Squad has to
stay and guard the Willghem.
R-Right!
Sochie, take command of the Gallop.
Okay.
Okay, Loran?
Let's do that.
Yes, sir...
Did you get pictures?
Yes, Commander Zenoa.
You say you found something
strange? Let's have a look.
A missile or bomb
container, maybe?
That's the mark for
radiological hazard, isn't it?
What're the things on the racks?
Must be cases for
nuclear engine fuel pellets.
These are ancient relics!
Show me the underground
scans you took.
Was there anything that looked
like a nuclear power facility?
No, I didn't see
anything like that.
Which would make the things on the
racks nuclear missiles or nuclear bombs?
Mobile suits? Whose?
What?
That sounds like a landslide!
We haven't scouted this shaft!
You mustn't fight!
Tell the Militia people, too!
If we fight here, we all die!
Commander!
Dianna Counter forces!
They're digging up relics!
Let's make them give anything
they dug up on Earth to us!
We have to make the
Zenoa team understand that!
Spirit of the Moon!
If we don't hurry, Gavane and
his squad will be in trouble!
The throttle is the
lever on the right.
You should go get ready to
head out in the Kapool, Miashei.
Did the Militia people understand?
I think so.
Might as well try...
They moved!
That's amazing!
Every one contains a warhead...
E-Eight of them! These warheads
can't possibly be dead!
Muron! This calls for all units
being armed and ready!
All I can see is the Zenoa team,
but what's going on underground?
I'm getting a bunch
of metallic readings!
Cancer, didn't the message from the
Zenoa team say they'd run into the Militia?
There's a shaft down there! They're
hiding in it, so flush them out!
Commander, look!
Don't fight, my ass!
Commander, they fired on us!
I'm not surprised! Even a headless
Scarecrow is a threat to us!
Aims! Don't listen to a word
the people down there tell you!
One unit destroyed!
Commander!
They're digging up treasure!
So that's why they made that fake
threat that we would all die if we fought!
Mr. Horace! Make sure Miss Sochie
keeps an eye on those mobile suits...
...to our left flank!
I've told her.
Captain Sochie!
Don't suck up by
calling me captain!
I think it suits you, personally.
Don't wreck my Kapool!
I know! Launching!
Loran's taken up position in front
of us. Ladderrum, slow us down.
Got it!
Mr. Horace! You have
Jacop and Bruno acting as...
...our gun batteries, right?
They're moving now.
This is the Lost Mountain, Loran?
It must be! The terrain is
just like on the Moon!
Didn't I tell you that if we
fight in here, we'll all die!
Don't give me that!
What the hell?
There's nothing in here!
Bombs?
You mustn't touch those!
If you don't know what they are,
then at least do as I say!
If you're that panicked, there must
be a story behind these old bombs.
How powerful are they?
These are nuclear bombs!
We all have to evacuate
the area immediately!
Sure thing!
Aims! We're falling back!
But with spoils of war!
- You fools! What are you...
- Stand aside, Pops!
Reinforcements are here, huh?
Sounds that way.
Hold onto these, Commander!
Will do!
Stand back, Zenoa team!
The Rett team will finish off
these Militia puppets!
The Rett team is here, too?!
There were two left!
Tell them not to fight!
We'll grab those two!
No way, sir!
We have to run a function check!
And what if they're armed?
We drop them and run!
These two haven't been armed...
But some of the ones the
Militia took might be!
Gramps! Are you okay?
This is nothing!
Mottke! Deal with that Militia Zaku!
We're on it!
You puny Zaku!
I have a lock!
Those fools!
Direct mobile suit hits are taboo!
A mobile suit exploded!
Was that a bomb?
What?
They shut themselves?
Automatically?
A mobile suit's engine exploded!
What was that explosion?!
It looks like the automatic
defense system kicked in...
You wish me to continue to act
as your double aboard the Soleil?
It has become necessary to assemble
a group whom I can truly trust...
...and ascertain the state
of affairs on the Moon.
But I am a mere
miner's daughter...
Given the many conspiracies
in motion on the Moon,
it is vital to allow Queen Dianna
to work covertly for the time being.
Yes. For the sake of peace
between the Earth and the Moon.
In order to make the two
worlds a single nation.
Aims! John! Cover me!
Tail nozzles!
They're not activating!
Aims! John!
Watch close, you
Dianna Counter elitists!
Rett team, Militia pilots,
listen to me!
The bombs stored at the Lost Mountain
are terrible things called nuclear weapons!
When it comes to fighting...
...the Rett team sees it through!
All Zenoa team members, fall back!
Evacuate from the
Lost Mountain at top speed!
Gallop, there was a Zenoa team...
We intercepted it!
No, Miashei!
Fall back!
Gavane's Suicide Squad
is fighting for their lives!
One nuke is powerful enough
to wipe Nocis off the map!
Aren't you dead yet?!
Kane getting killed
was a miscalculation!
What do we do, Aims?
You do nothing!
Suicide Squad, retreat!
Nukes are terrifying for their
power, also for their poison!
We have to assist Commander
Gavane to secure the bombs!
Don't even joke about that!
They spread a poison that lasts
for one or two centuries!
Rett team members!
As Moonrace, you should know
how terrible nukes are!
Mottke! Bury that Militia
mobile suit!
I'll take out
the Mustache myself!
You're not running?
I will!
I'll slice up this
stubborn person first!
Don't mess with me,
mustached doll!
You're not getting your way here!
Get away from here!
Boss!
W-Withdraw!
I can't pick him out from all the
underground metallic readings...
Gavane Goonny!
Get clear!
The Zenoa team isn't sending us
any solid data.
Could they be tactical nukes?
I think there's various levels.
All we can do
is say our prayers.
Why won't you let me fight?!
Gavane's still fighting!
There's no turning back.
We're doing as Mr. Horace says.
These things are terrifying bombs.
We're in danger ourselves.
Gavane's fighting out there!
This is stupid!
We ourselves might be destroyed
by those stupid weapons.
Do we really have to
leave this quickly?
It might already
be too late.
Think the commander
made it out?
Sure, this is our commander
you're talking about!
If everybody had put on normal suits,
they'd be protected from the radiation.
There it is!
That's...
It's turned into day!
Is this it?!
That can't be a bomb!
This is a bomb blast?
The Gallop must have been
constructed with nuclear warfare in mind.
It almost looks like
dawn breaking...
That's pretty close.
That is definitely a nuke.
A dawn at midnight is an anomaly
that must never be.
No way... We've been trying
to return to Earth.
How could there be tools
like that here?
Why would anyone build
something like that?!
I don't want to turn over the
remaining nukes to Lt. Cmdr. Phil,
so dispose of them for me!
You're giving these
to your enemies?
Nuclear weapons
don't discriminate!
I'm being followed,
so I'm giving them to you!
Loran!
Please don't go off...
Which direction is the place
that the blast happened, Loran?
Gavane! Don't I look pretty in
the wedding dress you gave me?!