Translators: philly, tofu, treehugger
Timers: Piyo., pottie
QC: Piyo., pottie
This is a free fansub.
ix.subbers.net
Turtles Swim Faster Than Expected
Cast
Ueno Juri
Aoi Yuu
Director and scriptwriter: Miki Satoshi
[Diary of my life]
Everyday I feed my turtle.
Everyday before my 23rd birthday,
the only thing that needs me now
is just this turtle, that's all.
Yes...
I receive daily phone calls from my husband who was sent overseas.
Suzume,
have you been feeding the turtle?
Yea, I am.
Alright, okay.
What is "okay" about that? I was about to ask that when he hung up.
Hello?
Suzume,
did I tell you to look after the turtle?
You already told me.
I have the urge to throw it out like this, but...
in the end, as usual, my heart drew me towards it,
and I would continue feeding him everyday.
Hello.
Kujaku?
On the phone is Kujaku, my childhood friend since I was born.
We lived in the same town, but
it's been a while since we've met.
Then it's at 1 o'clock?
Don't be late.
Good afternoon.
Coming!
Plumbing service!
What is it?
Over here.
Okay.
Sorry for intruding.
Hoohoo!
I got it!
Do you have these piling up?
This brand does clog up the pipes.
Oh is that so?
Yehh...
They fill up the turtle's stomach, they'll also clog up your pipes.
Ah...
Is that why?
Hey you...
if one day you find your toilet blocked,
what would you do?
Hmm...
Squid meal.
Squid?
There's such a thing,
inside the squid is stuffed with rice and sweet filling.
Ahh...
I found one before.
No way.
Yeah, really really!
Inside,
there wasn't much filling, but
it was only part of it.
You can't be serious?
Honest! It's true.
But it's really hard to believe it.
It's hard to believe, but it's true.
I can't believe that.
What!
Are you doubting me!
I mean...
Then!!!
Then...!!!
I'll show you the evidence!
Fine!
I don't know why I became so hot tempered.
For him to show me the evidence of a squid meal clogging a toilet,
I went to the plumber's place.
I thought that it was impossible to be shown evidence of a squid clogging a toilet here.
Now do you see?
Yeah...
Eh..
Got it?
Well....
That's good.
I'm leaving now.
Ah -
Shall I show you a fine mannequin that was thrown out?
I'll be LEAVING now.
Hmmm...
To get home,
you'll have to walk back.
I didn't think I'd actually walk home...
but I ended up walking back.
This 100-step stairs...
today I'll set a new record.
Alright!
If this flight of stairs take less than 30 seconds, something good will happen.
Ahhh!! Help me, someone!
Are you ok??
Hm?
Huh?
[Spy]
[now recruiting.]
[Comprehensive interview]
What's this?
I waited in the coffee shop that I was supposed to meet with Kujaku.
But she didn't come.
To kill time, while making a liver out of a straw,
"Is my existence unimportant?" I thought to myself.
She couldn't see me?
What are you doing, Kujaku-kun?
Eh?
You'll be late?
How long?
Two hours?!
What's with that?
Excuse me, customer.
Customer,
here!
What the...?
As Kujaku said, she'll be two hours late,
the one who will be waiting is me.
At the park, the old lady sitting at the bench today seems to be feeding ants.
If I remember right, she has been sitting there since I was in high school,
she's been sitting there for at least 7 years.
Come to think about it, whether I am at home feeding the turtle now,
or feeding the ants in the park,
they are rather similar.
Probably the same kind.
It's sad to think that at this rate, if I'm like that old lady at the bench...
people would forget about me while I die and not grieve over my death.
Should I go overseas for holiday?
[Fujihara tofu store]
*gasp*
I'm so sorry.
Don't mind, don't mind.
Again, the store owner is going on an overseas holiday.
Huh?
Always going overseas,
isn't it meaningless?
Yehh...
Why...
open a tofu store next to a pastry store?
If there's water everywhere,
the pastry's surface
will deflate!
So, why?
Here,
want to eat some?
Ginkgo nuts.
Please excuse me.
Hey!
Heyy!!
Heyyy!!!
Ginkgo nuts!!
Ginkgo nuts!!!!!!!!!!!
While running and trying to shake off that man, I got lost.
There, I discovered a strange thing.
What's that?
[Eternal Salon]
Out of desperation and curiosity,
I came to this salon.
May I help you?
Ke?!?!
Would you like an oriental style?
Eh?
Oriental style.
Ah,
well,
I was wondering if I could have this style.
Sure.
Did you understand, old man?
Thank you.
Ah,
after getting a new hairstyle, my mood will change too right?
Well, I don't know..
doesn't that depend on the individual?
Why did I end up in a salon in the first place?
It's Kujaku's fault that I'm here and having to sit for 2 hours.
On the same day, Kujaku and I
were born at the same hospital.
[Oogitani Kujaku] [Katakura Suzume]
During our stay in the hospital, under the influence of Kujaku's mum,
having heard her name her daughter 'Kujaku' (peacock)
mum named me 'Suzume' (sparrow).
Henceforth, we have been together through anything,
our inseparable relationship continues till this day.
The problem is...
-no matter what I do, Kujaku always wins over me.
-Yah! It's done!
What decided it all was our bags- the seals on them.
By the way she sticks on her seals,
was totally cool,
whereas I was always unfashionable and dull.
Certainly, the way we stick on the seals
reflected our lifestyles.
I'm sorry, but...
I'll be dancing.
Huh?
It'll be a little dance practice.
I have to do it no matter what.
Ok...
I...
have nothing to do in the salon...
so I'll be dancing.
Thank goodness.
I was wondering what I should do if you didn't permit me to do so.
Oh..
#That is why you are shining brightly and sparkling, why do I think of you all the time
I don't know why I think his dancing is quite good...
but I'm relieved..
Oh, I remembered!
When I was in high school, I was in the horticulture club.
Kujaku was going out with a big-scaled guy.
Alright ~ fight!
She participated during high school pro-wrestling competitions.
I can't win against her with my sense of style,
so using my creativity,
made a fan that produces north-wind sounds.
Yahh!
I was briefly reported about,
and received 1.2 million yen.
[Female university student invents an interesting fan machine]
I went shopping using 100 000 yen,
saved up 100 000 yen...
and I gave the remaining a hundred thousand yen to Kujaku.
All right!~
Heyyy~~~~
I went to the horse races,
I won 2 million yen...
And then,
I was proposed to by a common man,
and I accepted it.
Kujaku is single...
hoping that in the future, she'll be able to live with a French man,
with a Eiffel Tower view outside.
Kujaku?
Yes?
We will be here forever, right?
Yes...
And this is the current Kujaku,
living her life dynamically.
What's with your hair?!
"Eternal Salon"
She made it this style here.
It's strange, isn't it?
Huh?
Lame~~~~~~~
Shut up.
What's with that?
I picked it up.
Eh, why?
Because I'm lucky.
Could I borrow it for a while?
I like Eraku!
-Why...?
Somehow I want to eat ramen.
Sounds good.
Eh?!
Do you know any nice ramen places?
Over there.
It's narrow.
That place is really nice!
Being together with Kujaku...
we went to my favourite ramen shop in town.
[Ramen Sultana]
Here.
Welcome.
What the hell is this?
Such mediocre ramen..
There's no taste or flavour to it.
Is that so?
I like it though~
You're too low-classed.
What's your favourite number?
Six.
What do you like in your sushi?
Kingfish.
So low-classed...
What's your favourite saying?
Um...
Perfection of Wisdom (Buddhist saying).
Ha.
You laughed at me.
That's because.....
IT'S NOT FUNNY!!!! MAKE TASTIER RAMEN!!!!
Even though I haven't seen Kujaku for a while, I really like being with her.
She said as a photographer she has to go to Cambodia.
Suzumu, aren't you coming?
I'm going by bus.
And as for me,
I'll be feeding my turtle everyday.
*sigh*
Eh?!?
This is no good...
no one can see me.
Right now, the only thing who will acknowledge my existence
is this dog.
If I continue like this...
I'll gradually become smaller and vanish.
Is there no hope left?
When I thought about this...
something struck me.
Ah!
[Spy]
The spy poster
what was that all about?
Was it just a prank?
Or was that an invitation to an evil scheme?
Ah,
hello.
We talked on the phone and he told me to come over in three days.
Thank you very much.
All right!
I thought to myself, if anything happens to me...
it'll be fine if Kujaku comes and rescues me. With that kind of naive thoughts, I asked for her help.
[Kugitani]
What is it?
Ah.
Ehh...
I talked to you on the phone a few days ago.
Sorry for being so rude to you before.
That's ok.
Look,
I'm bad at living my life, aren't I?
So...
Ehhh?!
Here..
Sit.
Eh?
It's soft.
Ah..
Thank you.
You're really good at finding
that poster
It's wonderful
you pass as a spy.
Yea.
Excuse me,
what is a 'spy'?
Spy means spy.
What are you doing, E-chan?
Yes...
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Today, because of the adverse stock-market factors, I had some work.
She's E-chan.
She's my wife, but
she's a spy accomplice.
Nice to meet you,
I'm Etsuko.
Ah!!
Heyy -
why are you sitting on Azuki panda!
Hey, don't get mad.
Don't let her sit on it.
It was near me, what's wrong with letting her sit on it?
Then why did you have to give her Azuki Panda?
Oh well, that's true...
Excuse me.
This is...?
It's Azuki Panda.
Don't you think it's cute?
A
Azu
Azuki
Azuki Pan
Azuki Panda
Azuki Panda-chan~
You can sing well.
I can indeed.
Excuse me...
Ah,
here, we have someone...
who is interested in becoming a spy.
This is Katakura Suzume-san.
Oh.. may I call you Suzume?
Sure.
You have money, don't you?
Well..
not really...
Suzume-san...
is it ok if you become a spy from today?
We'll leave things to you.
Ehhhhh??
5 million yen.
Funds for your (spy) job.
*gasps*
Nonono
I haven't thought about this yet.
Hey,
what do you mean?
Are we being made fun of?
I am not making fun of you.
But I just wonder what's going on...
Heyy, haven't you explained it properly to her yet?
That's right.
Geez what are you doing?
Because...
Actually...
we are
spies from another country.
But!
Currently you will be recruited as a Japanese spy.
To sum it up,
the spy said you'll be a spy, did you hear that?
Do you find that interesting?
Yes, it's interesting
Even if you say all of a sudden that I'm to be a spy....
Could you try standing up?
Okay.
She's fine.
She has the potential to be a spy.
I thought so right from the beginning.
I have been doing this business for a while,
but the way you're so ordinary is really quite unusual.
-To be ordinary is an amazing thing.
-It is amazing.
Anyway, will you be able to take this job?
You didn't say anything about it...
Eh?!
Can you
do that?
No.
So ordinary..
Damn right.
Nononono...
Hey?
If she's too ordinary, won't it conversely make her unique?
It'll make her a prodigy, won't it?
Oh yehh, that's true.
-Hahaha
-Thank you very much.
Excuse me,
If I become a spy, what kind of things would I be doing?
There's nothing much to do now.
What?
If anything comes up, I'll contact you.
When will that be?
I dunno...
There haven't been anything for 12 years.
Speaking of which...
No way...
Anyways, from now on you'll be receiving special training.
Never forget for a second that you're a spy.
I don't get any of this.
Special training?
What's that?
To live normally.
To live normally...?
That's right.
So to speak.
We're to live as we usually do.
Then why do you have to push me?
Aren't I right, Shishimi-chan?
-It's "Suzume".
-For the time being,
here's five million yen
for joining our organisation.
I shouldn't take it though...
Anyway,
won't you use this money to do something about your hair?
Does it look weird?
Of course it does!
Gee whiz.
Even Azuki Panda-chan is laughing at you.
Hue
Hue he
Hue he he
Hue he he he
Hue he he he he
Hue he he he he he
Hue he he he he he he
A
Azu
Azuki
Azuki pan
Azuki panda
Azuki panda-chan~
So that's how I became a spy.
For the time being, before they contact me again, I'm to live as per usual.
This is apparently spy activity.
Once again, I'm living my usual life everyday
but the only difference is....
Hue
Hue he
Hue he he
Hue he he he
Hue he he he hee
The five million yen cash in the fridge
is because I became a spy.
I began to feel really excited.
This feeling is like
back when I was in primary school,
when I pushed a tyre down
these 100 steps.
When I think about it
feeding my turtle and spy activities have similarities.
Hey,
have you fed the turtle yet?
Yepyep.
Wow...
did something good happen to you?
Nah...
I get excited thinking about doing spy activities wherever I am.
I just want to live as inconspicuously as possible.
Hue
Hue he
Hue he he
Hue he he he
Hue he he he hee
But what do they mean by 'normal'?
How would I put out the futon in a normal fashion?
Was the way I did it previously considered normal?
Or is it the total opposite?
What about hitting the futon?
To hit while it's air-drying...
... or not?
Or after I take it in?
Thank you very much.
Somehow, my life has changed,
and I returned back to my old hairstyle.
I bought myself a gift too.
To commemorate myself becoming a spy.
[Glasses, Watches]
Yes?
It's Etsuko.
What are you doing?
Take off your sunglasses and go to the family restaurant ahead.
Yes...
Hello.
That's a worry.
What?
Why did you buy that sunglasses?
Ahh... well, it gives me the feeling of being a spy...
Shhh!!!
Ah, I don't understand at all. Who are you talking about being like a spy?
Oh, I see.
Why did I say that, I wonder?
I don't know.
By doing something like this,
you will be caught by one of those around!
This person seems to fit the spy description.
Shall we execute her?
We'll make her weep.
Yes.
Stop it..
please....!
Why did you make her cry?
Ah, no...
I'm sorry.
It's a lie.
Don't cry!
Ah.
Ah!
Ah, what are you doing?
I'm sorry, sorry.
Why are you doing that for??
It's fine, it's fine.
How is it??
Ah.
Wipe your tears with this.
What...
Hey?
Why were you crying again?
It's all because you said that.
No way.
It's fine.
Anyway,
before the commander comes,
just live quietly.
Yes, yes.
In a way that you don't stand out.
It's not good to be conspicuous.
Excuse me.
Menu!
Frankly speaking,
you're the one being most conspicuous here.
Here you are, the menu.
This menu too,
it looks like it'll be delicious too.
Hey, hold it there.
From there,
please choose an order that will be hard for that waitress to remember.
When the police comes later,
and ask what did Suzume order, she should not be able to answer.
This is the first time I look at a menu this way.
No matter what food I order, it seems like it'll be remembered.
What should I order, I wonder?
May I have your order please?
I'll have roast chicken meal.
Yes.
I'll have curry with vegetables meal.
I'll have lasagne please.
Yes.
Sorry about the wait.
Here is your lasagne.
Um...
The order for roast chicken meal?
Mine.
Um...
The order for curry vegetables-
Mine.
Hehh...?
Then the next practice.
Choose ordinary items and buy a total of 3000 Yen in total.
Why 3000 Yen?
It's not too cheap,
and not too expensive.
I see.
When you're done, we'll have your receipt.
I got it.
Shopping at 3 in the afternoon,
what would be considered normal for a housewife?
Thinking about it deeply is difficult.
[Camembert cheese]
[pass]
That was Kujaku.
That girl...
what is she shopping for?
Here it comes!
Artichoke!
That is quite a conspicuous item.
You may be just shopping, but
this is spy activity for me.
Hue
Hue he
Hue he he
Hue he he he
Hue he he he hee
Suzume.
Oh, hey.
Kujaku is shopping too?
What did you buy?
Nothing much.
I see. It doesn't look like just anything to  me.
What?
Want to come over to my place?
Hn, yeah sure.
While walking, I left the receipt hidden perfectly behind.
By doing such a spy-like activity,
Kujaku didn't notice it the slightest.
It's Etsuko.
60 marks.
Pass.
The way you handed over the receipt was especially well done.
And so this is how my first spy activity ended.
Even though it's not much different to the way I was living yesterday, why am I so tired?
Here, tissue.
There are still many prizes to be won.
You get three tries to get it right.
Ah.
I'll take that.
Just once, alright?
Yo!
Oh.
You came just at the right time, replace me here for a bit.
Alright.
Why I do not complain to Kujaku, there is a reason behind it.
One day,
the town I lived in had a black out.
Being in the park, Katou-senpai, who lived in the same neighbourhood, appeared in his pyjamas.
That appearance left me feeling "puan~" (breathless)
His hair, still wet from the shower, was wonderful.
You know...
Hm?
Once more, I want to see Katou-senpai's picturesque appearance.
When I said that, Kujaku...
for my sake, thought of inflicting an electrical outage,
by going to the neighbourhood's transformer substation,
and cutting the power line with pruning shears.
Thanks to that, I was able to feel "puan~" (breathless) again,
but electrocuted Kujaku's hair became frizzy.
As Kujaku was thought to have gone for a perm,
she was fiercely reprimanded by the teacher.
Sorry..!
Because of this, I owe Kujaku.
Please come again.
Ahh...
Finally!
Eh?
Nononono,
I thought, finally, someone like you has arrived.
I see..
Well you see, humans...
have their luck already decided.
You look like you have got luck in you!
Luck can be used on a big-scale, or small scale, it's different.
Oh no.
I was told not to be conspicuous.
If I get first prize here, what should I do?
Ge.
I'm being watched.
This should be a time where everything's quiet...
Well, shall we have you turn the wheel soon?
I can't win.
I can't be conspicuous.
Please let me lose.
Oh no,
you missed, you missed, tissue tissue.
Isn't it alright to want the tissue?
That's strange.
You have two more tries.
Huh?
What are you doing by yourself?
Oh, where were you?
Got a problem?
Hey,
did she get a grand prize?
No, she didn't get it.
What are you doing!
I'll be going to France and living with a guy!
Then do it yourself.
Um, anything's fine, I'd like you to spin it quickly.
Alright.
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Now we have the prize winners for seine fishing and the barbecue competition!
What is that...
Why do I have to get the second prize of seine fishing??
Because,
you won it.
Besides, is seine fishing a holiday...
or is it work?
If you don't want to go, then don't talk back!
What the hell is with you...!!!
I'm going now.
Go, go to seine fishing!
Just go!!
Go to it!!
After that,
I somehow met up with Shizuo-san and Etsuko-san.
They told me a lot about society.
From bacterium research,
when one is delivering various dangerous substances,
because she was scared of accidents while driving,
she became a normal aunty taking the train.
[STOP]
Amongst the many Stop signs,
sometimes,
"pots"
instead.
Pots.
Using a hundred quail eggs to make a dish,
it isn't delicious.
What is this?
If you left plastic bags outside for a long time,
it becomes like this.
It's art.deco!
By putting Burmese rosewood into water overnight,
it became quite...
a disgusting thing to look at.
Even if it all seems like a perfectly normal life,
there are a lot of things that I don't know about.
I didn't know it...
this espresso is delicious.
Isn't it?
I knew it, I think the most delicious espresso in Japan is from here.
Ramen is only just moderate though.
I'm sorry about that.
Rather than ramen, why is your espresso delicious?
Just water is fine, isn't it?
Then perhaps the ramen will be delicious.
That's true.
I wonder why.
Think about it yourself.
It's fine.
Isn't it?
Yeah...
How about making this into a cafe?
No way.
Then fine.
I'll just come to drink espresso.
If you don't eat ramen, I won't serve out espresso.
Just saying...
why does this ramen taste so terrible?
Can't help it.
It's not the ramen, you just criticise too much.
Look who's talking.
How much?
Thank you.
It costs 630 yen.
Here you go.
Thanks for the meal.
Thank you.
So it's her, the new recruitment?
Yup,
she's an extremely normal spy.
She's called Shishimi-chan.
It's Suzume.
I see.
Nice to meet you.
Hm?
The owner of the ramen store is a spy?
Yup.
How many years has it been?
As a ramen owner...
14 years perhaps?
And he hasn't been discovered.
Neither has he improved.
It's not like he doesn't have the talent to make it though, a better taste.
An inconspicuous ramen flavour?
Yes.
An inconspicuous flavour.
It's amazing.
To make it delicious would be easy,
but,
if it's delicious and gets popular,
it will stand out.
To make mediocre food that is also edible is difficult indeed.
Everyone says the ramen here is mediocre too.
It's amazing isn't it?
Mission has been hugely successful.
Kind of.
But if that is an act,
you can actually make delicious ramen, right?
But of course.
Ahh..
someday...
according to my own liking,
I want to try making delicious ramen...
So the mediocre ramen had such deep meaning to it.
Why are you crying?
Ah.
Mail!
Shizuo-san, who is it from?
Etsuko-san, it's better if you checked.
Shut up!
What?
Etsuko.
I got it.
Suzume,
that's it for today.
If anything happens,
we'll contact you.
I don't know what happened,
but it was no mood to be asking questions.
After a few days,
I couldn't get through to them on the phone.
[Kugitani]
Even when I went to visit, no one was in.
A while later,
Etsuko-san contacted me.
Hello.
Plumbing service!
You're late!
Be careful!!
Oh.
Be carefullll!!
I'm sorry!!
Hey!!
Sorry.
Although you're a plumber, you sure repaired it well.
Well, I somehow did it.
What?
What...
is it some sort of hobby, repairing doors?
Cut it out.
So what do you need repaired?
Well,
it's the toilet...
can you do something about it before my wife comes back?
Well, without looking at it first, I don't know anything.
Don't be so cool.
I'm back.
Oh!
Why are you so surprised?
Ahh!!
Ahh~~
You're here, turtle girl!
What?
You know him?
Just a bit.
He's the plumber.
What business do you have with a plumber?
I don't know.
Heh? You requested me here!
Well..
the toilet is clogged up.
What did you do?
I was just being normal...
would you take a quick look?
Alright.
Well, excuse me.
Excuse me.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
Ah, over that side.
Got it, thanks.
Excuse me then.
I....
I...I....
I've never seen something like this before!!!
What is it?
Sir!!
It's not from anyone who eats little at all!!
You're exaggerating.
What did you eat?
Just normal food.
Heh??
But it's too big!!
No way...
E-chan, go take a look.
What?!
But this plumber could be telling lies for all you know!
That's not it.
Really?
Yes.
Well, can you take one look then?
Then I'll just have a look...
do you have a cigarette?
Why?
To base the size on something.
Eh?? If you look at it, you'll know.
Really?
Yes.
It's way too exaggerated.
Isn't it, Suzume-chan?
Well...
So?
Hueh??
Wait a second, Etsuko-san!
No, I don't want to go see it!!
You did a good job.
I have been in this job for a long time,
I don't think I'll ever see a situation like that again.
Be careful from now on.
She's right.
What am I meant to do to be careful...
well?
What's wrong?
I lost my slipper in there somewhere.
Oh well.
Sir, what is your current job?
Eh?
Is something wrong?
No, not really, but...
I mean..
it's a working day and you're home.
Ah.
I was fired after some restructuring.
Ah..
is that so?
When he gets a job, he gets fired almost just as soon.
The knife hidden under the table..
I just saw something I shouldn't have seen.
After many days of restless thoughts,
something bizarre happened.
Welcome.
Ah, Katou-san.
Just one person today?
Mmm..
He is Katou-senpai.
My first love.
The reason for Kujaku's electrocution.
My childhood's most remembered memory.
Katou-senpai.
On top of that,
last week on Saturday...
I kept it quiet up till now, but
Katou-senpai liked Suzume before, didn't he?
Ehh...
that's a lie, isn't it?
No, it's true, it's true.
No way.
Because,
I heard it from the person himself.
Eh, why did you ask something like that?
Eh?
Because it's interesting.
What is this...
Hey,
if he still likes you now, what will you do?
It wasn't anything of my concern what she talked about,
I was surprised.
The Katou-senpai whom I saw after such a long time...
was with a strange son and a strange wife.
Your seat is right there.
I want to piss.
You just did just now didn't you?
Suzume,
do you want to do some acting classes?
Hey, are you listening?
Heh?
Ah.
What kind of acting?
I don't know that yet.
But once you start getting into it,
you'll have to keep attending it, so...
Wait, what are you doing?
Tip of chicken wing Nazi.
Oh.
It is too.
It's a Nazi.
Isn't it?
Yeah...
Excuse me.
Beer.
Yes.
This is the first time we're like this.
Ahh...
Well...
that is true.
Hey...
Within your body,
ever since you were born,
is there ever a place that you have never touched before?
Ehh..
no there isn't.
Um...?
Wuah!!!
Eh? What is it?
WUAH!
Eh, what what?
I saw something amazing.
Wait, what is it?
Don't look!
Ah, you know..!
Shoo, shoo!
To people you don't know, you shouldn't bother them.
-Wooooooooah
-Wooooah
-Woooooah
This isn't a joke!
Look!
Thus so,
my fleeting childhood love's memory was totally ruined.
Regardless of it now,
3 days ago,
I met up with Katou-senpai unexpectedly.
Hey,
even until today,
I get the feeling that I'm missing something very important.
Yeah...
That forgotten thing... can I get it back, I wonder?
You too,
do not know what that forgotten thing is?
Yeah...
Hey...
You...
liked me before, is it true?
Crap... that Kujaku must've said unnecessary things to him.
But the problem is with Katou-senpai's receding hairline.
Hey,
if you were born again, what do you want to be?
Heh? Hairline? (Hairline: Haegiwa)
What?
Ah, no..
Hyena...? (Pronounced: Haiena)
What are you talking about?
What happened to your hair(line)?
Hey...
Should I take some responsibility?
He's already lying to me.
I'll put my energy into it, I think I'll be a responsible man.
Yeah...
What do you think?
Want to be with me?
Geh?
Eh?
I have to go.
We'll talk later.