Hey, bestie!
- He asleep?
- Yeah, he crashed.
I closed his door.
That means we can play music!
Look what I pilfered!
You're amazing!
But it'll wake him up!
It's not The Gypsy Kings!
This is mellow.
Now it's almost empty.
Add some water.
They'll never know.
No talking!
The beginning's the most beautiful part.
I wish we could go to Amorgos.
- We'll go!
- I promise.
But we're not free diving!
- You've never tried!
- I know myself.
Plus, I have tried!
I swear! In the bathtub.
Know how long I lasted?
Can't we just enjoy the music?
TWO TICKETS TO GREECE
Everything okay, Blandine?
We're not intruding?
Where's Gaspard?
In his room.
And who's she?
- My best friend.
- I'm Magalie.
Are you kidding me?
Gather up your little things and take off.
Get out!
- You said you were going to a movie.
- We changed our mind!
Now we have to apologize
to the babysitter! What's she doing?
Taking myBig Blue CD.
Now tap into your mischievous side
and let out whatever comes up.
Let's take a deep breath,
lift our arms to the sky...
Very good... And let go!
What's going on, Blandine?
What's wrong?
Sorry, I don't think I can.
It's your first class.
Don't throw in the towel so fast!
Sorry, I know myself.
I can't. And I feel like
I'm surrounded by retards.
Let's keep those remarks to ourselves.
There are no retards here. Just people
like you, here to release their stress.
To stimulate joy in their life!
Too bad for her! She can go.
We'll keep laughing.
We're all together,
and we'll have fun!
I hope you just paid
for the first class?
She made me pay
for the whole quarter.
Okay. Tell me what it cost
and I'll pay you back.
And stop worrying about me, Benji.
- That's not what I need me get better.
- Right!
- What?
- Nothing.
Come on, what is it?
If I don't push you
to do stuff like that...
you do nothing.
- You stagnate.
- I stagnate?
- I did go back to work!
- What a feat!
Honey...
That is progress!
I think I'm getting back on my feet.
Six months ago, you couldn't
get me down the stairs. But now...
- Isn't that true?
- It's true.
So stop fretting about me.
I'm fine.
- How was the chicken?
- Okay. But the rice tastes weird.
Really?
We'll see how you feed yourself now.
I never could live with roommates.
Even at your age.
Yeah, so?
I say that because
you think I'm alone.
I think it's a question of temperament.
Some people...
- What's this envelope?
- Oh, right!
Dad's wedding invitation.
Tell me it's for you!
He's not forcing me
to go to his wedding?
I got one, and so did you.
What? He's polite.
Whether you go is up to you.
What nerve!
The guy's shameless.
If you weren't invited,
you'd make a fuss, too.
There...
you're way off the mark. Because...
what upsets me
is that it's a provocation.
He knows I'd never set foot
in his shitty little hick-town wedding.
- It's on Lake Annecy.
- Annecy's no paradise.
- Okay?
- Salomé was born there.
Salomé... Salami!
- Look at these hideous doves!
- Would you prefer crows?
And those tacky intertwining letters.
Mom, you're not getting back
on your feet.
- Take the rack. It's practical.
- The what?
The laundry rack.
It'll come in handy.
That thing's gross!
It's not made to be pretty.
What's in here?
CDs! These are yours.
Sure your new place has heat?
It's cold now.
Mom, I checked. It works. Okay?
Womack and Womack...
Bangles...
Never heard of these guys.
Who's Magalie Graulières?
"This CD belongs to Magalie Graulières."
Let me see!
Mom...
She was my friend in middle school.
Pint-sized, but a big mouth!
As sassy as they come!
The funniest girl on earth!
Why'd you lose touch?
We had a fight over something stupid.
At that age
you swing from love to hate.
Then she moved away and we lost touch.
- You'll keep in touch, won't you?
- Sure.
Benji...
- Excited?
- Big time!
If the landlord drops in
and sees this mess, you guys are out!
- What did you cook that's so caked on?
- Pasta.
Forget the sponge,
we need a scraper.
Stop!
Give me my cell phone!
- I don't guess you have one?
- What?
A scraper.
Or a thermal stripper.
Mom, who cares?
We have to go, I reserved.
- Don't be mad. I think I'll go home.
- What?
On Saturday, it'll be packed.
And with the road work,
there'll be a detour.
No way are you dumping me!
- And I don't feel well.
- I know you. No more hunger strikes!
Drop the sponge, we're going!
Come on!
Mom!
I can't wear these gloves.
We're going for Indian food?
Yeah.
We eat that stuff every day at work!
- Will you stop.
- What?
Can't you be little more fun?
I'm loads of fun!
Can't we just pick another restaurant?
No, it's happening here.
- What's happening?
- I'm leaving, you have a date.
What date?
You're dining with Magalie Graulières.
I tracked her down on Facebook.
She's inside. So don't keep her waiting.
Benjamin...
No way! You can't...
- I'm not going!
- Yes, you are.
- What'll I say?
- Talk about old times.
You'll laugh.
I'm sure you'll thank me for it.
Good evening.
- Are you Blandine?
- Yes.
Your friend's already here.
- May I take your coat?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- Will you follow me?
Yes.
Magalie?
- Your earring's gouging me.
- Sorry!
Oh, yeah!
It's so great to see you!
You haven't changed.
Back in school,
those kids would call me "ma'am".
No, why?
Okay, your cheeks are gaunt,
you have bags under your eyes.
Who cares?
It'll happen to us all!
But I see my old friend Blandine!
That's sweet.
I hear you're blue
and you've lost your lust for life!
That's what he said?
Let's just say
his dad and I split up...
Well, he's the one who...
- I mean...
- Don't sweat it!
Separations are never easy.
So there've been some ups and downs.
He did emphasize the downs.
I don't know why
he's so intent on shaking me up.
But it's given us a chance to reunite!
That's true.
Benjamin...
I thought his telephone voice was...
pretty hot!
Then I saw his pictures on Facebook...
Cute guy!
He's my type!
What are you drinking?
The house cocktail.
It's not bad.
But it needs a bit more booze.
This almost tastes like water.
- Want one?
- No.
I'm already a little queasy.
Plus, I have to drive home.
- Now I live...
- In the 'burbs, I know.
Okay.
You live in Paris?
In Montmartre.
- How great!
- Just a tiny attic studio.
A 7th floor walk-up.
But it keeps me in shape.
So my gams...
are great!
Not to mention my glutes!
Tight as drums!
I had a dentist there.
- I don't know why I said that.
- No, that interests me.
What do you do for a living?
I guess my son told you about me.
No.
I'm an electro-radiology technician.
So, super serious!
So you totally gave up blading?
Blading?
Rollerblading. You were a fiend!
It was fascinating!
No kidding! You could've gone pro!
I don't know...
been a teacher or an artist.
There are figure skaters,
choreographers.
I imagine.
I opted for something more traditional,
with regular hours.
And what do you do?
Me?
Let's say I'm a music journalist.
- So you write for a newspaper.
- Yes.
Well, not at the moment. But yes.
I've written articles,
reviews for various magazines.
But it was getting monotonous,
so I'm taking a break.
My problem is I'm really into old stuff.
For example, at the moment,
I'm into disco.
Drag balls, New York... Very New York!
And now all they want me to write about
are chicks with Auto-Tune voices.
Or pseudo-singers
in those rigged TV talent contests.
Mainstream's really gonna kill us!
I couldn't take it anymore!
So a little restful detox!
So what's good to eat?
When Benjamin asked me to find
something in the 'hood, I chose Indian.
- Good choice.
- Because I'm vegetarian.
Very good choice.
Chicken tikka masala!
Always a safe choice.
And for me...
Yeah!
Sorry, it's my roomie.
Didn't you say your place was teeny?
Yes.
He's a pal of my girlfriend's.
He came here for a job
and needed a crash pad.
- Did she know your place was small?
- Yeah!
She mostly knew I needed dough.
And the guy agreed.
We couldn't have separate rooms,
since it's a studio.
So he slept in a comforter on the floor.
Which broke my heart.
So we slept head-to-foot in my bed.
One thing led to another...
- That's sweet.
- Yeah!
But... he has a boyfriend.
A boyfriend?
In Bayonne, he has a guy.
And in Paris, me.
So you have some of my CDs.
JustThe Big Blue.
That film!
We were such fans!
- Yeah!
- The Jean-Marc Barr posters!
The dialogue we memorized!
We were young.
We were hicks!
That song with the dolphins singing!
That's strictly
for the Discovery Channel!
Remember how we wanted
to run away to Amorgos!
- Amorgos?
- The island inThe Big Blue !
We had it all planned!
The boat from Marseille to Athens...
Why didn't we go?
We were minors.
And we got into a huge fight.
Remember Nicolas Fiévet!
- Let's not rehash all that!
- No, there's a statute of limitations.
But at the time, it destroyed me.
Maybe because it was my first crush.
And I wrote such a gushing letter.
You even offered to give it to him.
You probably thought I was terrified.
So when I found it folded up
and stuck in your notebook,
it was...
Not cool.
No, not cool.
So what happened? Your folks got
divorced and you left with your mom?
Yeah, exactly.
Like lots of kids.
So did you ever go to Greece?
I'm going this summer!
- With Benjamin.
- Great!
He moved out, so we decided
to go on vacation together.
We fly to Santorini,
then take a ferry to Amorgos.
I'll finally see that monastery on the...
You're not taking your son
to a monastery?
If you're going to the Cyclades,
go to Ios or Mykonos!
They have amazing parties
on the beach, in villas!
When I went, I booked a room.
After two days, I gave it up.
I was never there!
Your biryani dripped.
Shit!
Eating Indian-style is an art.
What a drag,
I have to return this top.
- It's machine washable.
- No way! Look!
Now I buy things to wear one night.
Less waste, more eco-friendly!
Be right back!
My cock's getting impatient!
- Get it out?
- Not really.
I'll see if they have anything...
Is that my phone?
Read me the text!
I don't know how it works.
It's not hard!
Don't you have an iPhone?
What a jerk!
Look, it's my roomie.
Cute, huh?
And that impatience
is out of this world!
We're talking top drawer!
I'll tell you about it.
Sanjit, honey!
Got any stain remover?
...3202.
And?
It's two numbers short.
Right, the 89.
...893202.
Okay.
Great!
It's in my address book!
We'll do it again
and you can introduce me to Benjamin!
Okay.
There's a party over there!
Look! Let's crash it.
They're in costume.
We won't get in.
Oh, yeah...
- See you soon!
- That's a promise.
Not in 30 years!
Or we really won't recognize each other.
- Get home safe!
- You, too. Ciao!
Wait!
Excuse me!
Hello.
- I don't have the code.
- Good timing!
- I'm Mitch!
- Nice to meet you! Magalie.
So? How was the reunion?
An evening with the biggest freeloader
on earth...
Great!
I'm thrilled!
Thank you!
- I'm about to have breakfast.
-Then what?
Then I'm.... supposed to see Magalie.
Great! What'll you do?
- A flea market.
- A flea market?
She likes them, too.
What an awful chignon!
He's a good actor but always the same.
- Have a nice evening.
- Thank you.
Goodbye.
Look what I bought today.
Homer
The Odyssey
The perfect occasion to reread it.
Shall we have a drink?
Thank you.
- Why didn't you tell me sooner?
- I was afraid of your reaction.
And I wanted to find a solution.
- A solution?
- I can't go, but you're not going alone!
Now you're scaring me.
I asked Magalie and...
she said yes!
No way am I going to Greece
with that nutjob!
What about the nutjob
who claimed you were best buddies,
when you never called her back!
You kept hounding me!
I did it so you'd leave me in peace.
Wow! The chick's all alone
and wants to be left in peace.
That "chick" is your mother!
I'm sorry, but...
If I never saw her again,
why would she agree
to go on this trip with me just like that?
Is that normal?
You know what, Mom?
I don't give a shit.
Now you have two weeks
to kill each other or patch things up.
But I really don't care which.
Little Blandine Bouvier,
please come to the information desk.
Your mommy's waiting for you.
Magalie?
Blandine!
- That's your little girl?
- Yeah!
Is this a joke?
- Think I've got nothing else to do?
- Lighten up!
I do that in the supermarket
all the time.
It cracks me up!
So, no comment?
What do you think?
Debbie Harry! Blondie!
You really need to check in.
They're about to close.
Just so there's no problem...
Did your son fill you in?
I'm really broke at the moment.
But I'll obviously pay you back.
That's imminent!
- Don't worry.
- A down vest? For Greece?
There's AC everywhere now...
And it is sleeveless!
Come on!
Best Hospitals and Clinics 2019
Duty-free!
Duty-free items!
Come here.
What are you doing?
I'm collecting souvenirs.
To make a travel journal.
And you wanna put the barf bag
on page one?
It says "Greece" on it.
Mind your own business, please.
You haven't changed!
I remember,
you used to keep a diary.
I kept one until 2017.
I must have about forty of them.
So why'd you stop?
I'm sorry.
He really screwed you up.
You'll see! After this trip,
you won't even remember his name.
Or you could end up like her.
A widow crying over her husband,
sacrificing herself.
And the worst... I don't think
she's ever been with anyone else.
What?
Are you kidding? You, too?
Stop! Stop!
They'll think a reactor's on fire!
Shush!
Hold on, I'm trying
to wrap my mind around this.
This is impossible.
My friends say I could be a life coach.
I find that absurd.
But now I have no choice!
There! "Blandine Bouvier"!
Ms. Bouvier?
Look! I'm not lying!
"Reservation to Ferry Terminal
in a Mercedes van."
Who cares? We're in Greece!
Demis Roussos!
Be careful, Magalie!
It's sublime!
SANTORINI
How about a little brewski?
I never touch alcohol
before getting on a boat.
Well, I do.
Excuse me,
can I have a beer, please?
In a pinch,
I can use your barf bag!
So...
Are we gonna mention
what a big fibber you are?
We're not gonna
pretend nothing happened.
Why'd you tell Benji we were "besties",
when you never called me?
And I left you umpteen messages.
Nine. I counted.
To get him off your back?
And why'd you avoid me?
'Cause I'm a little over-the-top?
I know that.
Lots of my friends say I'm loud.
One even calls me "Tinnitus".
Let's say, you're a bit much,
and I can't do much of anything.
It'll come back to you.
But I want you to tell me
when I'm too much. Okay?
That means
"Thanks very much" in Greek.
How'd you react
when my son suggested this trip?
It made me laugh.
But I didn't say a word.
Then I thought
I was being given another chance.
We were given another chance.
That's what I thought, too.
To Hélène Boucher Middle School!
- Isn't that our boat, there?
- Could be.
What time is it?
- I'll see if the ticket office is open.
- I'll go!
- I'll give you some cash.
- I can pay for that!
Please, please, can I help you?
Yes... Heavy, it's heavy.
Ok. Madame, where are you going?
Here? Yes, yes... We go together.
- What did he say?
- No idea.
- What are our seat numbers?
- 374 and 375.
Can I have the tickets
for my journal?
I think we're further down...
Can I have the tickets?
Yes.
Where does it say "Amorgos"?
These aren't tickets to Amorgos!
Sure they are! Stop stressing.
I'm stressed
because it doesn't say "Amorgos"!
- What's this destination?
- Let me explain.
They just check the tickets
when you get on the boat.
- Then they never look at them again.
- So?
So it's no use paying
for where you're actually going.
So what did you pay for?
For the first stop.
We'll just get off later.
So it's a scam?
A tiny one.
That's exactly why
I didn't call you back.
I'm too old for these schemes
and living dangerously!
Blandine, stop now!
Everyone does it.
It's even recommended
in the Routard guide.
Right! I have the Routard!
What did he say?
I don't know. I don't speak Greek.
- You must go now.
- No, no... We continue.
Tickets please!
Yes... Give! Give! Give!
What a memory!
With all the people on this boat!
Impressive!
- No. You have to go.
- No, no, let me explain.
- It's a mistake. We go to Amorgos.
- No, look, Kérinos. Kérinos here.
Yes, yes, but... We want Amorgos.
Sorry! My English terrible. You know...
I say to the lady of thickets Amorgos,
and, I don't know,
she undestands... Kerinos. Sorry!
Innocent!
Where's the ferry schedule?
It must be that.
How cute!
It's illegible.
- Let's see.
- It's illegible!
Yes, but...
It's high season.
Ferries come and go all the time.
Chill out!
Hold this!
Kerinos...
It's so beautiful.
Page 401...
"At 15.2 sq. km., Kerinos is
the largest of the Lesser Cyclades.
"Today a semi-desertic island,
"it played a major role
in Cycladic civilization.
"Famous figurines, now exhibited
in Athens, were found here."
Awesome!
What else?
That's it!
Any addresses?
Where to eat or get ice cream?
Okay.
What'll save us is the "semi".
If it's semi-desertic,
there must be one place that's lively.
Yes. But if we go on the theory that
the port is always the liveliest spot,
then this must be
the epicenter of activity!
I'll call a friend.
Well, her boyfriend.
He's Greek. He knows these islands
like the back of his hand.
He can fill us in!
Hold on...
I can't see a thing in this sun.
Do you have a signal?
KERINOS
Blandine!
I don't feel like talking.
- Wait, Blandine!
- Leave me alone, please.
Take it easy! Nobody died!
Look, the weather's gorgeous!
- We're on a beautifully paved road.
- But where does it go?
Where does this road go?
We don't know where we're going!
We may wind up back at the sea
and have to walk back!
We'll have tried!
And we'll sleep under the stars!
What? What do you think we'd have
done, if we ran away at 15?
We'd have been wild and free!
Hippies on the run!
Sleeping in the open air!
You see?
We'll pay tribute
to the kids we once were!
Devoured by mosquitoes and snakes?
Some tribute!
In any case, I get it.
For you, nothing's a problem.
Everything's great.
Right now...
I should be in the swankiest hotel
in Amorgos, sipping a cocktail.
Lounging in my suite.
Or in a bathrobe in the spa!
Yeah.
I understand. Blandine, you know,
hotels know that people miss their boats.
Tomorrow, we'll get there,
explain that to them, and it'll be fine.
And if I may...
Luxury hotels here
are a load of shit.
The spas, facial scrubs,
hydro-whatever jets...
Remember you said,
"Tell me when I'm too much"?
I'm telling you.
Okay.
No problem.
Got the message.
Sorry, we don't understand.
Didn't you take German
as your first language?
You're demented!
I never took German.
As first or second language.
Remember?
We had Ms. Brouillet for English.
The crackpot who made us sing
the songWords by F.R. David.
Oh, right. I remember.
Everything okay?
Get some pretty pictures?
I offered to help.
You said, "Hands off!"
Because
you tried to take off the wrong tire!
Exactly!
She still can't understand
that I don't understand.
Please! Magalie, no!
The geriatric shift!
Good evening!
- Are you French?
- Yes.
Birgit said you were lost.
Yes. We weren't supposed
to stop here, but...
- You're in luck! I have one room left.
- Great!
Want something to eat?
The kitchen's about to close.
Gladly!
Excuse me...
Who are these people?
An archeological group.
They're from Dusseldorf, Cologne...
They stay for months.
- Great!
- It's very small here.
The only tourists we get
are archeologists or surfers.
- Okay!
- Take a seat!
Thank you so much!
Just our luck!
We got the archeologists!
Although, Indiana Jones...
But these guys look even older
than the rocks they dig up.
And that music!
It's gut-wrenching.
They'd be better off playing nothing!
I warn you...
tomorrow we're up at dawn
to catch the first ferry.
What's the matter?
I just can't stand that music.
I'll never make it through dinner
listening to that.
Impossible!
- Come on!
- We have to eat now!
Who cares?!
No boat till Thursday?
It doesn't stop here every day.
It's very small, you know.
I'm not staying
till the day after tomorrow!
- What about the fancy hotel I paid for?
- Wait, wait...
Excuse me,
we don't have to take the ferry.
Maybe some fisherman
could take us in their boats to...
No, here...
there are very few fishermen.
You know...
It's very small. We got that!
Calm down, Blandine.
It's not her fault.
Nobody asked you!
Your bullshit got us into this mess!
I'm really not into these vibes.
Go back to the dance floor!
Excuse me, does the room have AC?
Success! I found it!
You did?
I know what we can do
till the boat comes.
We'll go see the surfers!
- Would you rather dig with the Krauts?
- I'd rather not be here!
Elena explained everything.
There's a famous spot where they camp.
Surfers come from the world over.
Isn't that tempting?
A hunky Australian surfer
for Blandine?
- Please taste this baklava! It's lethal!
- No.
What do you think?
Isn't that a great idea?
Elena's even lending us her truck.
And making sandwiches!
It'll be so much fun!
We'll be queens!
Why not just go to the beach downstairs?
And do what?
Make sand castles?
- Plus, it's dangerous.
- Really? May I know why?
Yes. Elena explained it to me.
A very rare marine phenomenon.
A vortex or something.
You can be swept out to sea
by tidal waves.
Like in Hossegor. Or Reunion.
I almost drowned there once!
And I'm the fibber?
Before we left, I reread my journal.
Not all of it!
Just the parts about us.
I don't know if you recall,
but you convinced me
that your father invented Wite-Out.
Yeah...
So...
are we on for tomorrow?
Holy cow!
It's magnificent!
We're lucky to have
this stopover in Kerinos. Look!
I came forThe Big Blue,
and I find myself in Point Break !
That's the problem with surfers!
They prefer big waves
to two pretty patooties, like us!
Think I'm still pretty?
No...
Come on! Obviously!
Look at that face!
Why do you doubt yourself?
When you have a son who's 20
and his father dumps you
for a women
who's about the kid's age...
you wonder
if you're past your expiration date.
"Past your expiration date"?
That's taboo!
- Yeah, but...
- No!
You're stunning!
Look what a great body you have!
It's true!
This is the start of a new era.
Your erotic potential will blossom.
I can feel it.
I can!
- Are you kidding me? 100 SPF?
- Yeah.
I didn't know that existed.
Get a load of this guy!
American, for sure!
Florida or... California!
- That's 100% Californian!
- You speak French!
Yes. Wild!
Cool! French girls!
I'm from Brussels.
- Brussels, California.
- Okay, okay.
We're from Paris.
Well, she's in Meudon.
So you're on vacation
here in Kerinos?
- A forget-it-all vacation. And you?
- I'm here with two buddies.
We came to check out this spot,
which isn't bad.
Not bad at all.
- Can I join you?
- Of course.
- We're Blandine and Magalie.
- Nice to meet you. I'm Maxime.
I'm taking it easy.
I hit a rock yesterday.
That must've really hurt.
No big deal. I disinfected it.
I won't bore you with my little booboos.
You're not boring us at all.
On the contrary!
Doesn't your friend speak?
Yes...
Tell him about your passion.
Blandine's like you, she's into sports.
- Rollerblading!
- Wow! You're a skater?
No, when I was a teenager!
A long time ago.
It wasn't that long ago!
So, a Belgian surfer?
Do you have...
big waves back home?
No, that's why we come here.
But it's so deserted here.
Aside from catching waves,
what else is there to do?
Cruise chicks.
- There are just goats.
- Oh, no!
Steamy!
Maxime,
is it true what they say about surfers?
That you're incredible in bed. You're
so patient, waiting for those waves.
So you take your time.
You're not instant jackhammers.
Is that true or not?
Indeed.
There've been
several scientific studies.
It's funny you mention it.
Because I was a guinea pig!
Maxime!
Be right there!
Maybe we can elaborate
on that next time.
Sure!
See you soon!
You're completely...
You were a huge,
huge hit with him!
Stop! You'll get my phone wet!
- I have a big problem.
- What now?
My bank wired 602 euros
to the electric company. It's weird!
So, a forget-nothing vacation.
Could your neighbors
be tapping into your meter?
I do that sometimes,
when I'm broke.
I hook into my neighbor's meter.
That's not really
Mr. and Mrs. Duchesnay's style.
So... Wanna know
what his buddies are like?
How are they?
I think we'll really have fun.
So what shall we do?
Join them now or tonight?
It seems the waves are lousy now,
so they wanna look for another spot.
Let's stay here.
Or we'll look like groupies.
You're right.
Keep them hanging a bit.
Please hold for an advisor
to respond to your request.
That cold water feels great!
You're up!
They won't answer.
It's unbearable!
What if I cut your hair?
Please!
A short bob would look great on you!
With bangs or without? Look
at me! Look at me!
No bangs, no bob.
And please get dressed.
Don't be such a prude!
I'm not a prude!
I adjust nude bodies at work every day.
It's just that...
If I could,
I'd traipse around naked all the time.
There's a hike in the Austrian Alps
my friends and I did.
We were all in the buff.
It clears your head!
We should do that for our next vacation.
No?
I'll stop torturing you!
So...
What'll I wear?
- What do you think of this?
- Very pretty.
We look like we're in
a Cindy Lauper look-alike contest!
Have a little confidence!
You look fabulous! Hold on!
Let's ask Elena to slip us a bottle.
Pull out my iPod!
Open the disco playlist.
Look for Candi Staton.
Young Hearts Run Free.
That's totally us!
Young hearts run free!
I love that!
That's for you! "Love only breaks up,
to start over again!"
Huh? Listen!
Hi, girls!
I fucking love vans!
Look, they built a fire.
How great!
You're the only adult on earth
who gets excited by a campfire.
No mystery there.
You're not excited by anything.
We're gonna sit on rocks,
freeze our butts off...
You are such a fucking pain in the ass!
I mean, really!
It's no big surprise that...
- No surprise that...
- Nothing.
That my husband dumped me?
You were already like that in school.
Uptight.
We had to beg you
to do the slightest thing.
That's funny because you were a leader.
We all followed you like the pied piper.
Look where that got you!
I have no idea,
but maybe you'll tell me.
Let's join the Beach Boys,
since that's all you care about.
Oh, no!
Go on, tell me.
Since you seem to know me so well.
- Chickening out?
- Listen...
Magalie, I...
Let's not lie to ourselves.
This vacation was a bad idea.
Forced marriages have never worked.
Just because we were friends eons ago
doesn't mean we're still...
inseparable.
I agree.
But that's no reason to be contemptuous.
I don't judge you, even if
your life's shit and you stay there.
No, I'm sorry but...
You're in no position
to give me any lessons.
With those pop tune loops
that make you feel like you have a job.
Sorry, but...
Not you!
So you feel superior
in your white coat and Dr. Scholl's.
I earn my own living.
So I can be independent
and not mooch off other people.
Hold on!
Have I ever mooched off you?
Have I ever asked you
for one red cent?
I'm paying for everything.
Okay, you win! You can go
to your shitty posh hotel all alone.
Really?
- Hi!
- And what you plan to do?
I don't know, I'll stay here.
Or go to another island
and see my friends.
I may have no money, but I have friends.
I make friends!
I'm interested in others.
Cocktail hour!
That was a great spot
we found today.
A lot more wind than the first.
There were also sea urchins.
One bit my foot.
I really saw stars!
I'll move to the south of France,
open a tapas bar...
By the sea, of course.
That's a must.
Can you take me back?
Already?
- I don't feel too well.
- Okay, we'll take the van.
What did I do with the keys?
Be right back!
- You leaving? Want the truck?
- No need.
Don't you wanna put on some music or...
- Whose ukulele is that?
- Only Maxime can play.
I'd like to try.
Thanks.
I had to look in all my pockets.
We can go, if you want.
Okay.
Thanks a lot.
Want me to come up and help you pack?
No, I think I can manage alone.
Don't worry, it'll be okay.
With Magalie. I'm sure it'll work out.
I'll be going.
Just 'cause we're on vacation
and the moon's sublime
doesn't mean we should kiss.
We're not like that.
No.
We don't fall into those clichés.
This time, I am going.
That's it?
That's already a lot for me,
I assure you.
Wait, I'll give you my number.
- Huh?
- Yes.
If you ever feel like
hopping on a train...
or have a yen for a Belgian beer...
Call me!
Elena!
Go away!
Blandine?
What are you doing here?
Can't you hear? We can't get in.
What do you mean?
A goat's blocking the door.
I've tried everything.
I even did that thing
fromManon of the Spring !
I won't do it now,
but it was very successful.
The result:
the whole herd showed up.
I beg you, do it again!
- Elena!
- Forget it, she's sound asleep.
My battery's almost dead.
Why didn't you bring your phone?
I don't like
to spend hours on that shit.
Especially not for online banking.
If it's just to tell me
I'm overdrawn again... No, thanks!
Okay...
What are you doing?
I have to stay awake.
Since it'll die
before the alarm rings.
You plan to sit upright all night?
I don't wanna miss the ferry.
- Okay.
- But maybe you're staying.
No, I'd rather be pampered in your spa.
And with Gaëtan...
A total bore.
You and Maxime?
- Very sweet.
- Yeah?
But... let's say we're worlds apart.
A guy who says, "I've got
the hots for you"... That's beyond me!
When he got back,
did you feel like he was disappointed?
Well, I mostly felt bored stiff.
And I thought...
you were right.
We should've stayed here.
We could've discussed Merkel's policies
with the old geezers.
Elena would've made us
a nice lamb moussaka, golden brown.
Aren't you a vegetarian?
Yeah.
No more.
You know,
you shouldn't believe everything I say.
Me either. I...
I can speak without thinking.
No, I was unsparing.
I said horrible things to you.
I'm ashamed... I apologize.
But your banjo song was spectacular.
Ukulele.
An unusual instrument.
I was with a guy from California
for two years. A real one!
He taught me.
- I forgot you had such a pretty voice.
- Really?
That wasn't in your journal?
I'm a little offended.
Excuse me!
- Amorgos...
- Amorgos?
- Amorgos finish.
- What finish?
Too late. Amorgos 20 minutes before.
Now Mykonos.
Magalie!
We missed Amorgos!
We fell asleep and missed Amorgos!
Does everything make you laugh?
Everything makes you laugh!
Tomorrow!
There's a boat to Amorgos
tomorrow at 1 p.m.
Great!
MYKONOS
Stop petting that disgusting cat.
- You'll get mange.
- You're phobic!
Look how cute he is.
You're such a cutie!
What is that?
He's all scabby!
Disgusting!
- Fuck! Get lost!
- Here, clean your hands.
- What's that?
- Hydroalcoholic hand gel.
Okay.
- And your friend?
- She's on her way.
- What's her name?
- Bijou.
Her real name's Lavinia.
Thanks Mom & Dad!
- So she prefers Bijou.
- And why Bijou?
Why not?
She's an artist and makes jewelry.
How'd you meet?
Here, three years ago.
At the Cavo Paradiso.
It's a well-known open-air club.
The cover charge is a little steep,
but great vibes.
The last time I was in a club
was with you, as kids.
She knocks me out!
Sweetie!
- Honey bunch!
- I'm so happy to see you!
Bijou!
So you weren't even planning
to stop in Mykonos?
I'm hurt!
And that ring's not one of mine.
Eagle eye!
- Like it?
- It's gorgeous!
Then it's yours.
As a peace offering.
I say that...
but I can't even get it off.
Shit!
This calls for desperate measures!
- Stop, Maggie! Forget it.
- It's my pleasure.
Then you get one of mine.
Which one! The blue?
- Pretty, huh?
- Superb!
Except...
I can't get mine off either!
Shall I buy tickets for tomorrow?
- Let me introduce you. I did it!
- Put it on me!
There!
- This is Blandine
- Hello, Bijou.
Hello!
This ring's spectacular!
- We were in middle school together.
- No way!
Yes!
Here!
There, miss!
It's magnificent!
- What's your name? Blandine?
- Yes, Blandine.
That's kind of a bummer...
Mind if I find you a new name?
So what's the plan?
Amorgos tomorrow?
- Yeah.
- You know, we have a boat.
We can take you there!
Here's what I suggest...
Spend the night at our place.
Take a dip in the pool,
we'll make a nice dinner.
And tomorrow we'll take a little cruise
as far as to Amorgos!
- How's that?
- Beyond our wildest dreams!
Thank you!
- And we lose a third night at my hotel.
- And keep quiet!
The only snafu is my car died,
so I had to rent a quad.
There's my pal, Léonidas!
I'll ask if he can take you, Blandine.
She knocks me out!
If you like Jacuzzis,
it's right over there!
I think we have a fan here!
And everything you see on the walls
is Dimitris' work.
And like me, you have the right
to find them completely hideous.
Does he know you don't like them?
I've never said it like that.
But I've never gushed either.
If you knew what they sell for!
I think you're tough.
This one, I really like.
Yeah... Let's say it's the least ugly
(moche).
What is "moche"?
"Moche"...
Strong and beautiful.
So...
You are very "ugly"?
Sorry!
I know,
it's not too appetizing but...
it's the best way to tenderize them.
- All settled in?
- Yes, thank you so much.
It's magnificent.
- Have you always lived here?
- I've lived all over the place!
- I meant you and Dimitris.
- Well, I'm a freeloader.
At first, I had a room in Chora.
Then, soon after we met,
he asked me to move in with him.
I admit, I didn't hesitate.
Yeah!
It's funny, because
I wanted to divest myself of all that.
Luxury, big mansions...
royal families, all that!
She didn't tell you?
I was born in a castle in Kent.
But at 18, I chucked it all.
I traveled the world barefoot,
ashamed of being rich...
But then, over the years,
I started to like Ibiza, St. Barts...
And here I am!
In fact, we never change completely.
- I think I fixed the turntable.
- Fabulous! Dimitris!
Can you do this?
I'm just so tired...
- You are so tired...
- Yes. No, no, no.... Just do that!
Yes, yes, yes!
No, no, no... Okay, okay, okay!
- Driving me crazy!
- He's the octopus!
What music do you wanna play?
This!
Super! I learned French
listening to those records.
Gimme a break!
But before we listen to anything,
we need an accessory
that's indispensable.
Yes.
Come on, girls!
- Here.
- No, thanks.
- You don't like it?
- No.
- Yes, my love?
- Have we got any opium?
No, the joint's fine. Thanks.
-So, how's Amorgos?
- Amorgos...
Amorgos...
In fact, Amorgos got complicated...
It's sort of inaccessible, in fact.
As an island!
That's Benji?
- That's Benji!
- Hello...
Bijou!
We're "Benji's Angels"!
Your son's handsome!
Get in line, right behind me!
Or a threesome...
Stop! That's enough!
You, get out!
Go on! Leave us alone!
Wait, Bijou!
Can we roll another joint?
- Did I hear that right?
- What?
- That's why you're relaxed! You're high!
- Not at all.
My eye!
You've been toking giant doobies!
No, it was just a teeny puff.
Well, it did the trick!
It's great! I love seeing you like that!
You look 10 years younger!
Cell phones are off limits here.
- Sorry, I'll hang up.
- Thanks.
Where are you?
-So how's the weather?
- Where are you?
I'm...
at the maternity hospital.
Salomé had a baby girl.
A little girl... Nice!
What's her name?
Her name's Ruby. With a Y.
That's nice.
Perfect for a TV reality show.
You can't help yourself!
Coming!
I'll try to show her to you.
Don't move!
It's frozen!
The image is frozen...
I understand!
You shared intense experiences,
you had a kid...
It's hard to turn the page.
But it's been two years now!
Time to move on!
What do you think, Maggie?
You're preaching to the converted.
Yesterday, she had the chance
to move on with an ultra-cute surfer.
- And?
- And nothing. Nada! Curtain!
For two years,
you've been playing goody-goody?
I haven't been playing at anything!
I haven't felt the need to...
No, sorry...
Maybe you're afraid
of making a fool of yourself.
But don't tell me
you don't want to!
That's impossible!
Sex is vital!
It's as if I said,
"I'm gonna stop eating.
But I'm fine, I don't feel the need."
Yes! Exactly! Really!
Listen to her.
Bijou's a virtuoso life coach!
Make the most of that!
Every piece of advice
is worth its weight in gold.
It's true!
To me, you're a mentor.
Is there a feminine version
of the word? "Mentress"?
- Did you just say mentor?
- Yes.
Mentor is a Greek word.
Yeah! He was in the Odysseus.
He was in charge of Telemachus.
And the whole palace.
Thank you, Dimitris.
I should explain.
To Dimitris, everything is Greek.
When he does that, just nod.
- Yes! Okay!
- Do you understand?
Yeah!
Darling, we have that salad now, please.
The salad?
Yes...
So, where was I?
Right, you!
I'm not gonna let up!
Excuse me, but...
aren't joints supposed to relax you?
You're more excited than before.
That story of yours makes me crazy!
I won't let you waste away!
Waste away...
Look...
If you'd like to get back in the saddle,
I can easily ask Dimitris.
And it's my idea,
so I won't go into a jealous rage.
I love it!
She's kidding?
Not at all.
If I can do you that favor...
No, Bijou!
Don't ask him anything!
He's not your type?
No big deal.
I just said "Dimitris" because he was
at hand. But we could easily ask...
Léonidas, the cab driver. He's single!
Now you're sounding
a little like a "madam".
What?
No! Hold on!
I'm just trying to help
and you call me names?
- Then it's your problem!
- Exactly.
Can I have some wine?
It's good, the Retsina.
Very good.
Well, I'd be interested in Léonidas,
if you'd put us in touch.
Someone's sensible!
Blandine!
He can be so conventional at times!
What's the matter?
When I went to rent the quad today,
I was early.
I wasn't gonna come back home,
so I waited with the salesman.
He was in his 20s,
very cute, and so we...
It's a way of passing time.
But I have principles!
I think you should be honest.
No use hiding it!
There are two schools of thought.
And I decided to tell Dimitris.
And did you hear the tantrum he threw?
The guy's sick!
Plus, what does he have to fear?
I'm not gonna hook up with a kid!
Drink up.
I think it's touching.
It means he loves you,
he's attached to you.
Love isn't possession!
It's the 21st century. Shit!
That, I can't tolerate!
You know,
we could take the ferry tomorrow...
No!
We said we'd take you, and we will.
He may throw me overboard but...
- How is it?
- Delicious!
Alley-oop!
Buck naked!
Maggie's not back?
I don't think so.
She said you were a doctor?
No, I'm a radiology technician.
Okay.
- But you work in a hospital!
- No, in an office.
Good night.
Blandine...
Yes?
X-rays...
Do you know how to read them?
Yes, that is part of my job.
- You did see I was missing one?
- One what?
You see? If you'd stop being
so modest and looking away
to avoid seeing me naked,
you'd see I only have one breast.
What did I do with those things?
It was either that
or kick the bucket!
I had the works!
Mastectomy, radiation, chemo!
They didn't let up.
- You poor dear.
- No, I'm clearly still having a ball.
The guys I meet
turn out to be very understanding.
And it's a real plus for archery!
So last week,
we stopped in Athens.
And I had a mammogram
on what's left.
I didn't tell Dimitris.
I said I was shopping.
But now they want me to have a biopsy.
So?
So...
There is a suspicious mass
in the upper quadrant.
So they didn't make a mistake.
I ask because I was hoping these
Greeks were idiots about this stuff.
Yes, but as Dimitris would say,
they did invent medicine.
But it may just be fibroids.
Or a benign tumor.
That's what the biopsy's for.
You're sweet to reassure me, but...
I know the old song.
Even I could see the spot.
It's huge.
They'll start bombarding me again...
What a fucking pain!
I don't want to.
But no big deal!
I won't let it beat me.
I'll get treatment and I'll get better.
And you!
Accept this divorce and look alive!
Okay?
Because we're fighters!
We're amazons!
And I'm a bitch.
Why'd I do that to Dimitris?
I guess, when this happened again...
I felt that screwing around
would make me feel alive.
That I'd be invincible.
I understand.
Magalie's back!
Tell her we're in here.
Oh, Blandine!
It was really...
such a blast!
I've always found Léonidas chocolates
nauseating, but him...
I could wolf down four boxes in a row!
He taught me to play backgammon.
Bijou!
Did you know Léonidas
was a backgammon champ?
He plays in tournaments and everything!
We sat on his balcony and started
to play. He destroyed me, of course!
But he said, for a beginner,
I had a certain savoir-faire!
Wait! You know,
they're having a party next door!
This is horrible!
I can't take it anymore.
My ears are bleeding!
Here goes!
Enough!
Oh, shit!
- Hello, you need something?
- Yeah! You know what's in here?
No... I don't know.
This music will make you
the best DJ in the world!
Really? Okay!
- Which song?
- Put Candice Staton.
Candice Staton? Alright!
What are you doing, guys?
What happenes?
What? But look,
everybody loves this music...
Put Lost in Music by Chic.
It's a classic one!
What can I say?
You weren't too cool.
- But neither was he.
- Bullshit!
They're your neighbors.
I got you in deep shit!
I hate myself.
I'm fucking ashamed!
All my psychoanalysis down the tubes.
In two seconds, I turn into that asshole!
What asshole? Oh, right!
Anyway, I don't blame you.
Saw you!
Your iPod still works! That's cool.
Yeah.
Wanna talk about last night?
God, no!
Let's move on.
To clear my head,
I went out afterwards.
Really?
I went to Cavo Paradiso.
I felt like dancing.
I wanted to be allowed to dance.
Good choice!
The music was insane!
Great!
You didn't just dance.
- What?
- You have a hickey!
Really?
Yeah, well...
I was pretty drunk. I let loose.
Tell all!
I don't really remember much.
Did you go to a hotel?
No, just to a nearby beach.
Okay, a power nap.
Blandine!
We're gonna make a detour
to an inlet we know. Okay?
Great!
Things are better.
- Yeah.
- What did you say?
That he was "ugly".
I said I felt bad about it.
That I was sorry and I loved him.
It's good to be
conventional sometimes.
And I told him about the biopsy.
We're going to Mykonos
to do it tomorrow.
That way, if I have to
go through all that again...
I can buy a nice wig.
- We don't know that yet.
- No, just in case. You never know!
This time, I'd like to go '60s!
Sort of a beehive.
A little Divine, or B-52s!
That's it! Divine!
What?
Not "Blandine", "Divine"!
We keep the "ine",
but lose the bland side.
From now on, I'm calling you "Divine"!
Enough, okay?
See you...
Sorry! Bye, bye!
You're taking me away from my friend.
Why not stay with us
instead of going to Amorgos?
During the dictatorship,
they sent political enemies there.
Creepy Amorgos!
But Blandine promised herself...
We promised!
True! We promised we'd go
to the island inThe Big Blue.
- The one with Rosanna?
- Yes.
I never saw that film,
but she's so nice!
I'm not surprised.
She's Yoko's best friend.
- You know Rosanna Arquette?
- Sure. She's great!
Way into Ayurvedic massages
and energy crystals,
but we've had a lot of laughs.
Didn't you go to her place in Santa Fe?
Do you know lots of celebrities?
Yes, but I never recognize them.
Someone had to tell me that
the Yoko in question was Yoko Ono.
To me, she was just
a Japanese woman in a big hat.
I love that!
Let's go over there.
This side's for the rich.
Yeah.
The water's amazing!
I'm trying to learn Greek,
but it's impossible.
Really?
Shit! I'm so bummed out.
- What's wrong?
- I got a job.
So?
I just got a cable music show
that starts in the fall.
What a drag!
I had a feeling they took a shine to me.
It could be fun!
They're already talking
about a full-time job.
I know the drill!
"Magalie, I'll take the lead."
"I expect you to be proactive!"
All that crap!
- But you were looking for a job!
- Not like that. I'm freelance!
And freelance includes the word "free".
You're right.
- Let it go.
- Okay.
We'll see! Yeah! Let's see.
Yeah!
- She's winning all the time!
- She's winning?
Amorgos!
Blandine, Amorgos!
AMORGOS
Geeze...
That movie's their bread and butter!
Look!
They have cups,
key rings, place mats...
It's Disneyland!
But with a bit more charm!
Thank you.
Girls, your van is here.
- Sure you don't want anything?
- I'm fine.
It's pretty with the belt.
Let's take a beautiful selfie
before you go.
It's really nice!
Lots of teeth!
- I don't wanna leave you!
- No!
One last picture with Bijou!
Here!
Is that Maxime?
When were these taken?
- Who's Maxime?
- The surfer she turned down.
- Really?
- So?
He was at Cavo Paradiso last night.
He's cute!
Let's go!
He was the guy on the beach?
What do you care?
You blew him off.
You had your pick,
and the one you screw is Maxime!
What's the problem?
You said he wasn't your type.
Then why'd you hide it?
You'd have admitted it.
I admit it. Happy?
Let's go!
Why do you always
have to ruin everything?
- Take it easy! Calm down.
- Why didn't you call to tell me?
Didn't you think
I'd be happy to see him?
Didn't I say I needed time?
That I can't do it on the first date?
If I saw him again,
maybe I'd see him differently.
You're mad at me
for not waking you up at 4 AM,
to see a guy
you claim you don't give a damn about?
- Is that it?
- In fact, you're vicious.
Yes, you're vicious.
You only think of yourself.
You're selfish!
This is exactly what happened
with Nicolas Fiévet!
Wow!
- That's the cherry on the cake!
- Who's Nicolas Fiévet?
He's a kid she's accusing me
of stealing from her in middle school.
- That's what this is about.
- You gonna pretend it's not true?
That I made it all up?
And I never found my letter
in your fucking notebook?
I never went out
with Nicolas Fiévet, okay?
I never even considered it.
If you found your fucking letter in
my notebook, maybe I couldn't deliver it.
Back then, my life was complicated.
I couldn't always do what I wanted
or what you asked.
While your biggest problem
was a love letter to Nicolas Fiévet,
I had other nightmares to deal with.
Get it? No, you don't!
You were blind.
In your tidy little world,
with nothing out of place.
Where a letter
is inevitably delivered.
And I'm the one who's selfish?
I should apologize?
When you were so unfair.
I staged a sit-in outside your house.
Remember that?
I begged you for hours
because I needed you.
I was in pain!
And all you said was, "Get lost!"
Because with my...
In any case, we'll never make it,
you and I. We won't make it.
I'm coming with you.
Hello...
Hello!
Bijou? She's making necklaces
in the backyard!
Divine!
It's so nice you came back!
Celebrate with us tonight!
I just got my biopsy results.
- It's benign.
- That's great!
I'm so happy for you.
I'm so happy for my hair!
- You looking for Magalie?
- Yes.
She went back to Paris.
She was very sad.
So she called her new boss
to start early.
You can't blame yourself
for not knowing, if she never told you.
But we were so close, so...
inseparable.
I thought we told each other everything.
And she meets you in a club...
I don't want to be rude but...
She tells you her father beat her
and she escaped with her mother.
I swear, we were constantly together.
She was always at my house.
And I was never at her house.
That was a sign.
I should have suspected something.
She's right, I was blind.
You couldn't see anything.
She couldn't say anything.
It's complicated, you were so young.
Maybe Magalie was happy
to forget her problems with you.
You helped her, too.
Why not tell me now?
It's not easy.
You were on vacation...
- You were on vacation, too.
- Listen...
Magalie renewed your friendship
because your son called,
saying you were in very bad shape
and in a deep depression.
She just wanted to bring you some joy.
Some joy.
Here...
A present!
Thank you so much!
A star is born! Welcome to Ruby
& congratulations to her parents.
Blandine
I'm here to see Magalie Graulières.
One sec...
Do you have an appointment?
Yes, I do.
- Magalie's not here.
- Oh, no!
Not here, she's downstairs now.
That's what the receptionist said.
But the sign says it's a kids' channel.
You know Magalie!
Good luck.
Wait!
No, please... Cut!
Please, bring me an apple box.
I feel like a dwarf!
I'll never make it!
I'm struggling!
I don't know if Lucas is here?
From the top! Can we do it
without music? Great!
Let's go!
Léontine! I'm cooing!
That's your cue.
Hello, Gladine, the pigeon!
Hello, Léontine!
- I'm happy to see you.
- I brought binoculars.
That's what binoculars are?
Great!
We can see the Paris rooftops.
I don't have to fly to the Eiffel Tower!
This is so great!
Excuse me!
Can we take a break?
We'll pick up in 10 minutes.
Be right back!
- What are you doing here?
- And what are you doing here?
I was bored to tears
on their dumb music show.
I met some people from this show
in the cafeteria.
I came to see one of their tapings.
I loved it, so here I am!
Excuse me.
You okay, Léontine?
I'm not sure I can do the next song.
No biggie! I'll do it.
What did we say?
Rule number 1:
Nothing's obligatory.
Thanks, Magalie!
- I'm sorry.
- No, I'm sorry.
I just barged in...
I'm sorry for...
not measuring up.
- I don't know if Bijou told you...
- Yes, she did.
I don't agree
with what you said in Amorgos.
I do think we can make it.
Absolutely!
I'm sure of it.
I missed you so much
I bought a disco compilation.
No, don't ever do that!
Those things are shit!
They're made using algorithms.
I'll make you a compilation
and it'll make sense.
Because...
Disco's not just music.
It's a protest movement.
It's choosing to dance to forget.
Choosing lightness.
Choosing to be carefree.
Let me be sure I have my iPod...
In case the DJ's lousy.
We're safe!
Who's throwing this party?
A friend of a friend
of a friend of a friend.
We'll see soon!
By the way...
Remember my
electric company problem?
They made a mistake.
No way?
What a relief!
I was losing sleep over it!
I even told my new shrink.
I couldn't deal with the stress!
Thank you!
Now I can breathe again!
Look!
Holy shit!
Be right back!
Excuse me, what size are you?
Hello.
Hello. Your shoe size?
Nine and a half. Why?
Would you like
to make someone happy?
Blandine!
TWO TICKETS TO GREECE
Revised and Synchronized by
FAST TITLES MEDIA