- Subtitles -
Luís Filipe Bernardes
I don't want any of you newspapermen
trying a hidden camera stunt on me.
This isn't a public exhibition.
And you folks who have never seen
anything of this kind before,
remember, no talking.
No matter what anybody says or does,
you keep quiet.
Even if John Allen himself should
talk to you,
don't dare answer him.
It doesn't seem quite fair no to talk.
We ought to try to make his last few
minutes as pleasant as possible.
Oh, shut up!
I'm not worried about him.
He'll faint dead away
as soon as the show starts.
- All set?
- Yes, sir.
Well then, we'll start the parade.
Why doesn't he want us to answer
John Allen if he talks to us?
Why did you come up here anyway?
There ain't gonna be any legs in this show.
Well, you see, I'm taking a lot
of sociology courses at college.
So Prof. Summers, he teaches us, you know,
thought it would be a good thing if
one of us could report to the group...
...the actual process of an execution.
So he selected me and got me
a pass from the governor.
College boy, huh?
Well, you'll get your belly
full of it up here alright.
Doctor?
You tell me, will you? Why can't
we answer John Allen back?
It's because Allen is living
on his nerve now.
If he talks at all it will be
to keep up his courage.
He really doesn't expect an answer.
If you gave him one, it would likely
throw him off.
And we'd have a devil of a time
with him, hysteria and all that,
fighting to keep out of the chair.
I don't know about that. He seemed
pretty cool when I talked to him.
- When was that?
- Yesterday.
What did he have to say?
Does he still persist that we're
burning him at the wrong time?
- Yep.
- There's something in what he says, too.
I don't know about that.
Look, doctor, when that current's
turned on, how long will it take before...
- ...it's all over?
- You mean before I'll pronounce him dead?
No, before he actually is dead.
Will he pass out as soon
as the current hits him?
- No.
- He won't?
I thought it was all over
just like that.
Not with a powerful fellow
like John Allen.
His body will be paralyzed,
but his brain will continue to
function for... maybe two seconds.
Gee!
Those will be the longest
two seconds he ever lived.
Long enough for him to relive
his whole life.
He's due now.
...and whosoever liveth and
believeth in me shall never die.
He that believeth in me,
though he were dead, yet shall he live.
I know that my redeemer liveth
and that he shall...
...and stand at the latter day
upon the earth.
And though after my skin
and bones destroyed...
John!
- John Allen!
- That's me. What is it, big boy?
- My drill went dead. Is the plug in?
- Wait, I'll see.
Yeah, it's in. What's wrong?
- Got a screwdriver?
- Wait a minute.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
- What time is it?
- Near five.
I don't want to be late quitting.
I ain't giving this outfit no free overtime.
Anyway, not when I have
a heavy date on.
Say, listen, Bud, I don't think I'm gonna
horn in on your party tonight.
Getting stuck up all of a sudden,
are you?
Me and Annie ain't good enough
for you anymore.
Oh, it ain't that and you know it.
It's only that...
Well, I don't know who the dame is
Annie's gonna bring along for me.
- I ain't so keen about a blind date.
- Ah, she'll be alright.
Annie knows you're particular
about dames. She'll get you a good number.
Yeah? Well what about that truck horse
she picked out for me last time?
- I gave her the devil for it, didn't I?
- A lot of good it did me.
I was stuck with her for
a whole evening.
Boy, all that dame wanted to do
was eat. Eat and dance.
I felt like I was handling
the rear end of a fire truck.
I told Annie that.
She knows better now.
Now you call her up and tell her it's
cold turkey with me for tonight.
A can't do that now, John,
Annie's got a dame all set up.
Well, what's this one to be like?
I don't know, but she ain't
gonna be no fireman's delight.
This baby's gonna be alright.
She's got class, Annie says.
- Works in a laundry
- Well I hope she's got class.
Hey, listen now, I ain't promised
you no Peggy Joyce.
Oh, that's all right. I ain't
expecting anything much.
After all a laundry is where
you send your dirty clothes.
Hey, you know, Bud...
Working this way, 20, 25 stories
up in the air, you know...
It kinda gives a fellow ideas.
You know, you meet a guy
or a girl down there...
...and they think they're hot stuff,
they amount to something.
Well, there ain't nothing wrong
in them being that, is there?
No, nothing wrong,
nothing like that, but...
I don't know... when you get
up here and look down on them...
Well, you get a different slant
on the whole thing.
You know, they only seem like...
like just a crawling bunch of little flies.
Look at them, look at them
crawling down there.
A banker, and a lawyer,
and a fancy dame.
All the rest of them thinking
they're doing big things.
Making speeches, and getting
into the papers and...
cheating and hating each other.
I'll betcha God gets a big laugh
out of this old world.
Hey, listen, if you're gonna talk
carelesslike about God,
don't pick out no six-inch
girder to do it on.
Don't it ever hit you that way too?
Look, John, you and me's been bunking
together for more than two years now,
...and I ain't never heard you pull off
anything like this before.
- You got me scared.
- It scares me too sometimes.
You're in a bad way.
Better take some aspirins.
First thing I know you'll be going sour on me.
You'll be clipping some of them coupons...
...and getting yourself a study
book to carry around.
That mightn't be a bad idea at that.
Oh, no, not while you're
bunking with me.
- I ain't gonna live with no lily.
- Well, don't you worry.
The girl I'm gonna fall for
is gonna have real class.
I ain't seen no poodle dogs
chasing you.
Yeah, well she's gonna have
an education.
A girl you can learn something from.
Ain't no use in both of
us being dumb.
Hey, what do you want to go bothering
your head about that education bunk for?
Ain't you making 62.50 a week?
Well, what more do you want?
A guy told me that $62.50 is more
than what a college professor makes.
Do you want to be a college professor, not
have any dough to blow in on a good time?
No, it ain't the money, Bud,
it ain't that. It's only...
Gee, I don't know, there's...
There's so much in the world
I don't know.
One thing you sure don't know is
when you're well off.
Yeah, I guess you're right, Bud.
I don't know why I should be wanting
them kind of things.
You know, it's being up here
so close to the sky...
...makes a guy think crazy.
You leave the stinking racket
to the guys what gets paid for it.
You know, like college professors.
You and me, we ain't got no time to think.
We got work to do.
- Oh, you said it.
- There's only one thing we gotta think about.
When we get our arms around
a dame, how far can we go?
Hello?
Oh, hello.
Yeah, sure.
I did? How much?
Thirty-eight bucks? Oh boy!
Yeah, sure!
Where's the payoff?
Don't worry, I'll be there on time.
John! John!
Hey John, can you top it? I pulled
a winner, Peach Blossom in the third.
- Yeah, how much did you make?
- Thirty-eight bucks.
- Gee, not bad.
- Not bad?
Thirty-eight bucks without
lifting a finger.
Say, where would I be if I could
pull one like that every day?
You lost over thirty-eight
on the ponies last month alone.
Aw, that don't count. The bookie's
paying off in front of Tony's place.
I'll phone the girls to meet us there,
we'll go out and throw the works.
Say, you ain't gonna blow in
the whole 38!
I sure am. You don't spend easy
money fast, no more will come to you.
Oh, yeah, but it seems crazy to spend
all that jack on a couple of dumb dames.
I ain't gonna spend it on the dames.
It's on us.
A couple of ties for you
and a silk shirt for me.
I seen a beauty the other day,
I'm gonna get it. Blue silk it was.
What's left of the thirty-eight
goes to the girls.
Why did I only have two bucks
on that night?
If I'd had 20 smacks on them
I'd have made... let me see...
- I got 38 for two, that's er...
- 380.
Three-eighty, that's right!
Can you imagine it, three-eighty.
Yeah, you might just as soon
have lost your twenty.
Not me, I've hit my stride,
I'm on a lucky streak now.
Last time you hit a lucky streak
I had to pay all the room rent.
Oh, what a guy. No wonder
the girls don't like you.
Oh, they like me well enough.
Say, didn't that fire wagon
slobber all over me?
That's because you were
feeding her good.
If Annie's got you a thin one this time,
I'll bet she won't even give you a tumble.
Yeah, well that will her tough luck.
I ain't wasting any time on losing any sleep
over any dame that comes out of a laundry.
You know? You know, John,
you oughtn't to razz a dame
you ain't never seen before.
After all, she's taking just
as big a chance as you are.
Yeah? Say, now look here.
Any time I take a dame out
she knows what it is to be out.
- I satisfy.
- Oh, yeah?
# Oh, boy, I'm lucky G-boy, #
# I'm lucky, this is my lucky day #
Boy, 38 bucks and nothing to do but
spend them, and am I gonna spend them.
I betcha that bookie won't
even show up.
Oh, he'll be here, he can't
afford to pull a trick like that.
I've been laying bets
with this guy for months.
Yeah, well, how many times
have you won?
Take it from me, John, a guy don't
get rich slaving away for wages.
It's the guys that...
Gee, that's a hot job.
I didn't notice.
Aw, lay off of that fly stuff,
you're down on the level now.
You know, I'm sorry I dated
Annie up tonight.
With all the extra coin
coming in I coulda...
No, Bud, that stuff is alright
when a guy is on the loose.
- But what about you and Annie?
- I ain't married yet, am I?
- You're engaged.
- Don't tie me down yet.
Till the preacher makes me say love,
honor and obey,
I can still have a little fun.
Gee, she had a nifty leg.
I shouldn't have let her get away.
Hey, Bud!
Hello there!
Say, I pulled a fast one
on you this time, didn't I?
- Sure did. How Much you got coming to you?
- Thirty-eight smacks is what you said.
- That's right, and here it is.
- Come make my hands filthy.
Say, how about something on the nose
of Letonia tomorrow?
Uh-uh, I'm blowing this.
I got a three-horse parlay that looks
like anybody's money. It pays 55 per 10.
- 55, huh?
- And it's a sure thing.
The last time Buddy played a sure
thing I had to pay all the room...
Aw, forget that.
You oughta come in on this thing too, fella.
It's tips like this that make a fella rich.
No thanks, I'll save my money
and stay poor.
Alright, it's up to you. This one can't miss,
Bud, I got inside info on it.
I know, straight from the
horse himself.
Say, Bud, if I was you, I'd sink
the whole 38 smacks on this streak.
- Let me see, 38, that'd pay me...
- 210.
210, that's right, can you
imagine it? 210!
That's a lot of money to make
without lifting a finger.
Yeah, well it's a lot to lose too.
I won't lose, I told you I was hitting
a lucky streak and this is it, I feel it.
- How much will it be, the whole works?
- Yeah.
Well, how about the silk
shirt and my tie?
Tomorrow night I'll buy you a dozen
ties, I'll dress you in ties, I'll...
Say, wait. I just remembered something.
I can't play anything
on the ponies this time.
- Well, what's the matter now?
- Nothing, it's just that...
...I got something else I gotta
do with this jack.
Well, what more can you do with it
than make it grow five times?
Now, this is how that parlay shapes up.
In the second place...
Nope, no, I ain't gonna play it.
See me tomorrow and maybe I'll lay
something on them then.
Alright, it's up to you.
It's your loss.
Don't forget what I told you.
I'm certainly glad you've decided to
quit playing Santa Claus to them bookies.
- Now, if you sock that dough away, you...
- Look, John.
You hang around here till Annie
and the girlfriend get here,
and you tell them that, er...
Tell I was here, see, and I, er...
I got took sick kinda suddenlike...
...and I had to go home, see?
What'll I tell them that for?
Oh, no, Bud, I can't do...
Well, there goes the 38.
- Hi, girls.
- We don't know you.
Oh yes, you do. I'm the guy
who just said hello to you.
You got anything special
on for tonight?
Yeah, we were just gonna get
a bite to eat at the Astor.
Come off, come off, you got the Astor mixed
up with the Owl Dining Car, ain't you?
- The Owl ain't so bad at that.
- You said it.
How about letting me sit across from you
and squirt grapefruit in your eye?
Like they do in the movies.
- I ain't particular.
- That goes double for me.
Now remember, don't try to pull
no Astor stunts on me.
I don't come from the Bronx.
A couple of drinks in a speak, dance
and maybe a movie.
A little party afterwards.
That's the program for the evening.
- Are you on?
- My name's written over everything you said.
- Atta baby.
- Hey!
Who's the smiley lieutenant
down there?
He's got a little business to attend
to first then he's going to join us.
I'll be right back.
Well, looks like we eat.
Boy, it's all fixed.
Say, Bud, I don't want to go anywhere
with those two tomatoes.
Why not?
- I won't be able to shake Annie...
...and that other dame.
And I ain't playing no papa to
two girls, I ain't no Turk.
Ah, you can lose them.
Look, if you get into a jam with them,
tell them you gotta make a phone call, see?
Then step into some corner drugstore,
and while they're waiting outside...
you sneak out the side door, get it?
Hey, what's holding up the party?
Just giving the boyfriend a few tips
on the love racket.
If he's that green, what kind
of an evening am I going to have?
- Bud, here she comes now.
- Who?
Annie.
- Look who she's brought with her.
- The firewagon.
Say, I thought you told her...
I'm gonna beat it!
Look, John, you can't do that.
What am I going to do with the girls?
Push them off the pier. I ain't gonna
play fireman again tonight.
I'm sorry but the heavy sugar's
coming down the street.
- The party's off.
- It's off?
That's a hot way to treat
a couple of ladies.
Well, looks like we don't eat.
- Hello, honey.
- Hello, Bud.
What's the idea?
- What's the matter with her?
- I thought you said the laundry.
- Listen, she's the best I could do.
- I don't believe you.
I think you're trying to put
something over on me again.
Where's the boyfriend?
He ain't here and he ain't never
going to be here.
- What's the matter?
- He's sick.
- When did all this happen?
- I'll talk to you later.
- Ain't I going to have a boyfriend tonight?
- Not unless you go down to the firehouse.
Firehouse, what for?
What's the use of us standing
around chinning?
- Ain't we going anyplace?
- Yeah, I feel hungry.
Yeah, we're going someplace.
- We're going down to a drugstore.
- Drugstore? What for?
I gotta make a phone call.
- Hey, what's the matter with you?
- Say, where do you think you are, home?
- This is a dance hall, ain't it?
- Sure it's a dance hall, and that's all it is.
I got a right to dance and you
gotta dance with me, I paid for it.
You pay to dance with your feet,
not your hands.
I dance my own way, come on.
And I dance my way.
Say, what's the matter here?
Ask him. He just bought the place.
Paid a dime for it.
I paid a dime for you and I want
a nickel change.
What's happened, brother?
Oh, I tried to dance with
the girl nice and...
Come on, sure, I'll fix you out.
Alright now, let's forget about it,
Shirley, come on, get in line.
Atta girl.
I want one ticket.
Alright, right this way, brother.
Yes, there are nice girls all over.
Here you are, Shirley, here's a nice
fellow for you. Dance with him.
Say, big boy, you sure are
a swell little hoofer.
You ain't so bad yourself.
I'll improve, if only I can get
some practice.
Say, um...
Do you girls have to dance with
everybody who has a ticket?
Why not?
Well, it must be sort of tough letting
every guy paw you.
They don't paw me, not if they know
what's good for them.
Yeah, I guess you do learn
to take care of yourself.
Is this your first time up here?
Yeah.
I came up here by accident.
A big accident.
What's the gag?
Oh, you wouldn't understand.
It ain't important anyway.
You know... you don't seem like
these other girls.
You seem more refined like.
Go ahead, where's the rest of it?
- Rest of what?
- The story.
I'm different. I don't belong here,
and you're gonna take me out of it.
No, I'm not, why should I?
Don't you want to put me
in a show?
Ain't you got a friend that knows
a big producer?
- Not me.
- You're the first guy that ain't then.
Say, do they all try to pull
that stuff on you?
All. Except the ones that try the little
apartment on the avenue line.
Well, you wouldn't fall for that
sort of thing, would you?
I'm still here, ain't I?
Not that I'm going to stay here.
I got ambition. And someday
I'm gonna get them, see?
I hope you do.
Well, how about the next one?
- I'm willing.
- Where's your ticket?
Well... I only got one.
Do you know any more Scotch stories?
Come on, let's dance it out anyway
and I'll get a ticket later.
I can't. Gotta have a ticket.
Well, you wait here for me
and I'll go get one.
Get a handful of them so's we can
dance a lot together.
Huh?
Alright.
- How about this one, baby?
- I'm waiting for a guy.
Yeah? Since when are you
reserving him?
Oh, alright. You needn't get
sore about it.
Say, where's the blond girl
that was here?
She's out dancing. Dance with me.
No, thanks, I'll wait.
- Hey!
- Fresh guy, huh?
What's the matter here,
what's the matter?
You try that again and I'll
break your neck!
More trouble.
Just because he paid a dime to dance with
me he thinks that entitles him to privileges.
Oh, who wants any
privileges with you?
A dime would be too much for
a bimbo like you!
What are you trying to do,
wreck this place?
You get your things, Shirley,
and clear out. And stay out.
Now wait a minute. You don't have
to take it out on her.
This is between me and that guy.
Yeah, well I ain't going to argue
with her or with you, see?
Get out of here both of you
before the cops come!
Here, take him in the back room.
Well, what are you all standing around for?
Come on, enjoy yourselves.
Everybody dance, music, music!
It was wonderful of you to stick up
for me the way you did.
Oh, that was nothing. That guy
was just aching for a sock.
And he sure got it.
Gee, I never thought anybody would think
enough about me to stand up for me that way.
Oh, I would have done
the same for any girl.
- Oh... I thought...
- What?
Nothing.
Say, do you know...
That's what's the trouble with your job.
You know, it makes the guy
think you're...
Well, what he said you were.
You hadn't ought to work
there anymore.
I don't.
Gee, and it was my fault
you got canned.
Oh, no! Nothing would have happened
if I hadn't slapped him myself.
But then I couldn't let him play
around with me that way, could I?
- No, not if you're decent.
- Well, that's one thing I am.
And they work in a tough joint, but everybody
that knows me knows I'm on the level.
Well, that's the only way
for a girl to be.
But why, why do you work
in a dump like that?
Because I can make more money
that way than any other business.
You see, I got a family
to take care of.
My mother and father, I mean.
Oh.
They're both sick.
I keep them on a farm in Idaho.
You're not handing me a line,
are you?
Alright, if that's what you think!
No, no, only it sounds like,
you know...
It's the truth, that's all.
Yeah... Well, what are you
going to do now?
I don't know.
Gee, I get kind of scared when
I think about being all alone...
...in New York without any money.
Yeah.
What do you do for a living?
Oh, I'm a riveter.
That's where you get such
a big muscle, ain't it?
Yeah.
You make good money
at it too, don't you?
Sixty-two fifty per.
Boy, you and Rockefeller.
Yeah. You know, that's more than
most college professors make.
- Or so my buddy says.
- I'll bet he's right.
The fellows that put up these
big steel skyscrapers...
...are more important than any
college professor.
Oh, no, I wouldn't say that.
I think education is the biggest
thing in the world.
Not that I'm against education.
I got a good one myself.
- You have?
- Yeah, I went a year to high school.
- No kidding.
- I wish I could have stuck it out but...
Like I told you, the folks were sick
and I had to help them.
Yeah, well that sure is tough.
You know, I haven't learned any myself.
I wish I had.
Do you know what I was
planning on doing?
Before I lost my job, I mean.
I got ambition, see?
And I was planning on...
on going to some business college...
...and finishing my education that way.
You were?
Yeah, that's why I was glad
I worked nights.
It gave me the daytime to study.
But, gee, now that I'm out of work...
Hey, my Buddy's girl, Annie...
See, she works in the paper box factory.
Maybe I could get her to speak
to her boss about taking you on.
Oh, no, that wouldn't give me
time to study.
Never mind. I'll speak to Tony myself.
I'm sure he'll take me on again.
Oh, no, no. Say, that would
give all those fellows...
...a chance to get fresh
with you again.
It'll only be for a short time.
It sure is tough on a
pretty girl, ain't it?
Do you really think I'm pretty?
- Why, yeah!
- I'm glad you think so.
It's the first time I ever heard a fellow
say it that I was glad he did.
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
Oh but, I guess at that I won't be
seeing you anymore, will I?
Oh, I don't know.
I haven't thought about it.
But you want to?
Why, yes, I guess so.
It'll make it so much easier for me.
At the dance hall, I mean.
- Yeah?
- If the fellows knew...
...I had a big guy like you looking out for
me, they wouldn't try and get fresh then.
Yeah, I bet you they wouldn't, huh?
And then, when I was studying,
there'd be lots of times I wouldn't know
what things meant.
I won't have anybody to ask.
- But if you was around.
- Oh, no, no I couldn't help you that way.
You know, I don't know
anything about books.
I'll bet you do.
But even if you don't...
...we could study them out together.
That's what we could do.
Yeah?
Say, that would be something like.
That's what I'd like awful much to do
if you let me, mister...
- John Allen's the name.
- Shirley Day's mine.
Well, I'm certainly glad
to meet you, Miss Day.
And I sure am glad to
meet you, Mr. Allen.
Well.
Yeah.
She's got you dizzy, that's what.
I thought you had more sense
than fall for the first dame...
...that sighs at you and tells you
how wonderful you are.
Here me and Annie's been chasing
around trying to get you interested...
...in some nice little home girl.
But no, this one's too fat,
this one worked in a laundry.
While we go chasing around trying to find
a Peggy Joyce for you, what do you do?
You go out and get yourself
hard-tied by a dance-hall Jane.
You was the guy that didn't have
no use for women.
They was all flies, and you got such
a big laugh looking down on them.
- Yeah, but I get a big kick out of Shirley.
- Ah, you could do better with a mule.
You think I'm stuck on her,
but I ain't.
I got my eyes open,
I know what I'm doing.
But do you know what she's doing?
That's what counts.
She ain't after nothing from me.
Oh, no, she's sweet, and pure,
and innocent.
- She really is on the level.
- Don't make me laugh.
- How much has she got out of you so far?
- Not a red cent.
- Have you offered her any?
- Oh, just before she got her job back,
when she was in a jam,
I offered her a ten-spot.
Yeah, but she wouldn't have it.
She's no dummy!
She can add!
Why take a tenner today when
you can get 62.50 every week?
Oh, Bud, the only thing you've got
against her is where she works.
You've got the kid all wrong.
The only reason she works there...
...is because she needs a lot
of money to help her folks.
So that's the racket, huh?
The mother needs an operation.
The kid brother's gotta have
his eyes treated...
Oh, nothing like it.
I don't doubt she makes a lot of money but
I bet she don't make it all by dancing.
Now listen, Bud.
Even when you say that
I don't get sore.
And if I were stuck on her,
I'd get sore, wouldn't I?
- I guess.
- But I ain't sore.
So don't that prove to you
I know where I'm at?
Why are you hanging around her
so much for then?
She's good company, she knows things.
- She goes to school.
- She goes to school!
- Yeah.
- I'll say she's a wise hen.
She's found out you're nuts
about that education stuff...
...and she's trying to hook you
with that bait.
Oh, nothing like it. She went to school
long before I ever met her.
Listen, John, that dame don't
need to go to school.
- She knows everything.
- Yeah.
Where are you taking her tonight?
She's got the night off,
we're going to the library.
A fellow there's giving a lecture.
- She's going to a lecture with you.
- Yeah.
Boy, this is the tipoff.
When a dancing Jane sits through a lecture
with a guy there's only one answer.
She's got designs on him.
Now look here, don't
you worry about me, Bud.
There ain't a chance of her
roping me in.
That's what a lot of guys have said...
...but I've noticed the marriage license
bureau ain't going out of business.
Yeah, well it ain't gonna get
any of my trade.
Not yet anyway.
I'm wise to Shirley. I know she'd
like to tie one on me.
Why not? I'm a good buy.
Yeah, but I'm just a little bit
too smart for her.
Alright, John, but remember this.
When it comes around to playing with a dame
or pounding on a stick of dynamite,
the real smart guy chooses
the dynamite.
Okay!
Now, if you're a good boy, when Papa comes
home he'll bring you a nice big lollipop.
- Make it a red one.
- Right.
Come home sober.
# Gave you my love #
# Gave you my kisses #
# Now that it's over I see #
# You knew you hurt somebody #
# But why did it have to be me #
# You took my love #
# Played with my kisses #
# Somehow it never could be #
# You knew you hurt somebody #
# But why did it have to be me #
# Oh, didn't you know #
# Didn't I show I cared #
# Oh, loving you so #
# Couldn't my heart be spared #
# Heaven above... #
I told you I didn't want
to come here.
I wanted to go to that lecture.
There's plenty of time to go there, honey.
We can take in the second show.
No, there ain't no second show
in a lecture.
Well, it can't be very good they
if they don't run it twice.
- Aw, come on, let's have another drink.
- No, no, no.
If it's the money that's
worrying you, I'll pay for it.
No, it' ain't the money and you know it.
I just don't like the stuff
they serve here.
There's going to be another
act in a little while.
- Let's stay and see that.
- No, it ain't gonna be any good.
Nobody's any good in here.
They're just flies.
- I want another drink.
- Say, you've had enough already.
A girl like you oughtn't to drink
all the stuff you do.
I have to. It makes me
forget my troubles.
What troubles have you got?
Oh, John, if you only knew how
I've had to suffer in that dance hall,
you'd take me out of it.
Why should I take you out of it?
What troubles have you
got there anyway?
- Who makes you trouble?
- The girls. They're so jealous.
And the boss, Tony. I'm beginning to be
afraid of him, John.
What's the matter with him?
I don't like the way he looks at me.
What way does he look at you?
Oh... you know.
Ahh!
Hey there! Another cup of tea.
- And bring the bottle this time.
- Yes, ma'am.
No more for me.
Leave the bottle, I said!
Come on, come on, let's go to
that lecture.
- Not yet, honey.
- But you said you would.
I wanna see the manager first.
- What for?
- To see if he won't take me on.
You don't want to take a job
dancing here like that, would you?
Half undressed.
Wouldn't you want me to?
What difference would it make to me?
Wouldn't it make just a little
bit of difference?
Now look here, Shirley.
- I like you a whole lot, see?
- Yeah?
And that's all.
That's as far as it goes.
Oh, John!
Oh, come on, don't start that again.
I can't stand it, not when I'm drunk.
You know...
I think I'm a little drunk.
Oh, John, be nice to me.
- I'm so lonely.
- Alright, alright, I'll be nice.
Oh, John!
Hey... you know, I like that.
- Wouldn't you like to have more?
- That ain't a bad idea.
No... I don't want any more.
I don't want anything.
Now look here, Shirley.
You're a good kid, see, a good kid.
But you ain't for me.
That's a nice thing to say.
Alright, it doesn't matter.
I know you don't care
a rap about me.
Sure I do, Shirley, I care
about you a whole lot.
- I said I did.
- You never kissed me.
I did. Just a while ago.
I don't mean like that.
I mean kissing me because you must do it!
Because you can't keep yourself back.
Because your whole inside
burns up just for me.
- Oh, shush...
- That's how I am for you.
- Shirley...
- Yes, John?
I know what you mean.
Yeah, that's how I want you now.
- No, John, you don't love me.
- Yes, I do. I do, Shirley.
Will you have this woman to be
your wedded wife,
to live together in lawful state
of matrimony...
will you love her, comfort her, honor
and keep her in sickness and in health,
and, forsaking all others, keep only
unto her as long as you both shall live?
Say "I will", John.
I'll say anything you want me to.
- Only I got to have you.
- John!
I want another drink.
Hey, waiter!
I'm afraid he's too drunk for me
to go on with the ceremony.
- He doesn't know what he's doing.
- Yes, he does.
- Come on, John, say "I will"!.
- Say, where's my drink?
Say, what sort of service...
Hey, waiter!
Never mind him. There's ten bucks
in this for you.
That ought to take place of the
two words he's gotta say.
Will you have this man to be
your wedded husband,
to live together in the lawful state
of matrimony...
will you love him, comfort him, honor
and keep him in sickness and in health,
and, forsaking all others, keep only
unto him as long as you both shall live?
I will.
Got a ring?
Here it is.
- Hm, all prepared, hm?
- For three weeks.
With this ring I do thee wed.
With all my worldly goods I do thee endow.
Come on, John, put this on me.
What for?
Now look here.
If you ain't going to that lecture,
come on, let's dance.
That music's getting me.
There ain't no music here, John,
what's the matter with you?
Sure there is, can't you hear it?
Say, what are you trying to do,
make me out drunk?
- What's he doing here?
- Never mind, I'll put it on myself.
- There.
- Congratulations.
- Now, John, you may kiss her.
- Kiss who?
Oh... Shirley?
You bet I'll kiss her.
I'll kiss her and there won't be anything
left to her, only my kisses.
Let go of me, John, we'll fall.
Not a chance. I've got you now
and I'm gonna hold on to you.
Not a chance.
Not a chance...
Over here, here we go.
Hello, Bud!
Hey, look what I brought home.
- That's Shirley.
- What's the idea?
You shouldn't have brought her up here,
John. You know the landlady don't...
Oh, she'll let this girl in alright.
- That's my friend, Shirley.
- So that's your game, huh?
Gonna get him in a jam
so's he'll have to marry you.
Oh, no, no... I ain't gonna marry her.
I ain't gonna marry anybody.
No, sir.
Hey, look here, Bud.
You better clear out of here, see?
You can't stay here with us.
It wouldn't be respectable.
Yeah! I'll get out.
I ain't gonna let you pull your
old army game in him.
- Who's pulling the army game?
- You are and you know it.
You got him drunk so's he'd get all hot over
you and now you're framing him to marry you.
I don't have to frame anything,
Mr. Wise-guy.
We're married already.
You're what?
- John! John!
- What's the matter now?
Did you let this dirty little egg
rope you in?
Hey, that's no way to talk
about his wife!
- You filthy little rat you!
- What's the matter now?
I can't stay here any longer.
I gotta take her to that lecture.
- Come on, John.
- That's all I'm gonna do.
There ain't a chance she's
taking me for a ride.
- I'm just a little bit too smart for her.
- Take it easy now, will you?
I ain't gonna let you get
away with this.
Oh, what are you sore about anyway?
I ain't taking nothing away from you.
He ain't the kind of man you're
used to playing around with.
- He's s square shooter.
- Well, ain't I?
Yeah, I know your kind.
And so do lots of other guys I'll bet.
Only they was all too smart to let you
ring the wedding bells on them.
But this poor guy. Didn't take you long
to find out he couldn't hold his liquor.
Say listen, brother.
Until you can talk the signature
off of this...
you're only wasting your breath
making nasty cracks about me.
Hm, you got a license and everything, eh?
How much did you have to pay extra to
get this at night? And got him drunk, too.
He wasn't drunk when I got it,
he was perfectly sober.
But he wanted to celebrate our wedding.
That's how he got tanked up.
I don't believe you.
I notice you ain't let up none.
No, you had to keep your head clear so
you could steer him into this, didn't you?
He's a little white angel, ain't he?
It's me that's all bad, eh?
The worst thing you ever did
was getting born.
It's a good thing he's passed out.
If he was sober, you wouldn't
dare insult me like this.
If he was sober you wouldn't
be here like this!
Oh, it's all over, ain't it?
I'll be good to him, honest I will.
- He won't ever be sorry he married me.
- No.
Come on, let's you and me
be friends too.
Not me!
If he had taken you because
he wanted to, I wouldn't interfere.
Since you put this over on him with
your cheap dirty tricks,
I ain't gonna let you get away with it?
Alright then, you've had your say
now listen to mine!
He's married to me, right,
square and legal.
And since I'm his wife and partner
to all that's his,
you just get out of here, see?
My husband's waiting for me.
And I ain't gonna keep him waiting.
Alright, I'll get out.
But get this.
I'll make you sorry for what
you've done to him.
You said you'd bring me home
a lollipop, big boy.
And you did alright.
And a red one at that.
Welcome home, Shirley.
Cigarette?
Oh, Bud, how long are you
gonna keep sore at me?
- I ain't sore at you.
- Yes, you are.
You've been this way ever
since the night I...
- Do you blame me?
- Well, it's my funeral ain't it?
Only because you won't
listen to me.
I can't, I gotta play square.
After all I married her.
Yeah, when you were so cockeyed drunk
you didn't know what you was doing.
Well, whether I was drunk or sober I'm
married to her now, see, and I gotta stick.
No, you ain't. I ain't gonna let you.
- Why not?
- 'Cause you're too good to be tied to her.
- Maybe I wanna be.
- Oh, no you don't.
It's only because you're so fine that
you don't want to do anything to hurt her.
But I ain't fine, see?
And I ain't afraid to hurt her.
I can't walk out on her if that's what
you're after. It wouldn't be fair.
I know her kind. She's a softy.
She got tired of grubbing
for her own keep,
you look like three squares and
flop to her so she hooked you.
I don't think so.
You've only been married
to her three weeks.
Where's all that dough
you had in the bank?
On her back already, ain't it?
She had to have decent clothes.
A riveter's wife don't need
silk lingerie and silk pajamas.
Not a night gown, mind you, pajamas!
That shows you what she's like.
- More rivets!
- You'll have to wait a minute.
Oh, Bud! Why are you so
bitter against her?
Because I... Well...
You're the kind of guy I wished
I could have been myself.
That's why I'm so broke up about
this tramp getting you.
Don't call her that.
That's all she is. Don't you think
I know the breed?
She lied to you about her
parents, didn't she?
Said they was out on a farm in Idaho.
All the time they was living in
a booze joint on 10th Ave.
Yeah, I don't know why she lied
to me about them.
I do. She's lied to you about
other things.
And she'll keep on lying to you
the rest of her life.
She was born crooked.
It ain't in her nature to play
square with a man.
Don't say that! She's on the level
that way, with men I mean.
- I know she is.
- Yeah?
Where'd she get all them glad rags
she was dolled up in when she come to you?
From dancing?
She only made 5c a dance.
There's a limit to how much you can make
adding up pennies in a night.
She wouldn't have made enough to buy them
clothes not even if she was a merry-go-round.
- She's worked hard.
- Sure she has.
And I'll tell you where she did it too.
The same place she still goes
every afternoon.
- She goes to the movies.
- Yeah?
Now look here, Bud. There's a limit
to what I'll stand for.
- You'll stand for all I've got to give you.
- No I won't!
What she's done before
we got married that's out, see?
You and me haven't been
holiness ourselves.
She's my wife now, and you and everybody
else has got to respect her.
- Your wife? Tony's wife!
- Don't say that.
Yes, his wife. Anybody else's wife that
wanted. I could have had her myself!
Shut up you!
Bud!
- You gonna play that all day long?
- Why not?
It's the only fun I can get
around here.
You ain't no happiness boy
these days.
You don't like me to play it
just because it was his.
Oh, alright!
How long are you gonna
keep on being like this?
Makes me sick to look at you.
Why don't you go out
and get yourself a job?
- I can't get one. I've tried.
- You can go back to riveting.
You know the boss would take
you on again as soon as you got better.
No, I can't go back to that.
Not ever since Bud...
I can't climb.
When I get up there...
my had swims.
I get sick, afraid.
- I gotta hold on.
- Oh, rats!
One minute he was standing
there talking to me.
And the next he... he was flying
through space.
His fingers clawing, trying to catch hold
of something and nothing for him to grab.
And then when he hit...
I see, well it's going to be up to me
to go back to work.
No, you don't!
You stay right here!
I'm going to make all the money
that comes into this house!
Well, do it then!
I ain't anxious to go back to the hall
and let the girls give me the laugh...
...for marrying a guy and then
having to support him.
You keep away from that dance hall.
What am I supposed to be doing...
while you're hanging on to
a hunk of steel crying...
"I can't do it, I can't climb,
I'm afraid!"
Were you ever up that high
with only six inches of steel...
...as a foothold between you and hell?
What have you got to live for
if you're so afraid of dying?
By the way, have you got
any life insurance?
Oh, what a guy.
Keep on using that same tonic.
It's all the medicine you need.
Yes, doctor.
I don't think it'll be necessary
for me to come back again.
How long is he gonna be
laid up, Doctor?
Well, that's up to him.
You know, Mr. Allen,
I think your trouble's much more
mental than physical.
It's my nerves, Doctor.
They're troublesome things. Knock you out
when they get the best of you.
- Yeah.
- But you got to knock them out.
It can be done, you know.
Get a grip on yourself.
- Oh, Doctor.
- Hm?
- About your bill.
- Oh, yes.
My visit and the medicine, $9.
Well, what I wanted to say was...
You wouldn't mind waiting
for it, Doctor?
I haven't got the nine dollars
just now.
Is it that bad, son?
- But you said I'll get well soon.
- Yes.
When I get back to working
I'll pay you back with interest.
That's all right, don't worry.
Just get well.
Goodbye.
Oh, Mrs. Allen.
If there's no money, how about food?
Our credit's still good.
I'll see he gets it somehow.
That'll be fine.
But get him out in the open.
- This place is so stuffy.
- It's that maid!
- I'll see about it right away, Doctor.
- Good, good.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
Lizzie! Hey, Lizzie!
- Yessum?
- Come up here!
Can you imagine me living
in a place...
...that even a stranger has to make
cracks about us being dirty?
- You want me, Mrs. Allen?
- I sure do!
What's the idea of passing up this place
when you're cleaning the rooms?
Oh, it's no use starting
anything, Shirley.
Well, there's going to be trouble
anyway, Mrs. Allen.
Mrs. Smith said to me this morning...
...cause you ain't paid your rent for
so long she's gonna ask you to get out.
But she can't do that.
That's a nice one. Put a sick man
out in the street, eh?
Says you owe her fifteen bucks.
But I'll pay her, I'll pay it all back to
her as soon as I get back to work.
That's what I told her, Mr. Allen.
She says herself you was always on time
with your rent when you was living with...
Before she came.
Oh, so that's the story they're
telling downstairs, is it?
Soon as he married me he got broke.
No, no, she didn't say that, Shirley.
Look here, you go tell Mrs. Smith
I want to see her.
I'm gonna give that gossiper
a little surprise.
Oh, I'll tell her, but I wouldn't advise
you to start nothing funny with her.
- Her brother's a cop, you know.
- You go tell her what I said.
Oh, it's no use starting
anything, Shirley.
You'd better start packing
what little's left of our things.
Oh, no, we ain't leaving here.
But she won't trust us
for any more.
I ain't asking her to. I'm gonna
pay what's owed her.
What with?
- Where'd you get that?
- Oh, don't get excited.
- Where'd you get it?
- Borrowed it.
- Who from?
- Tony.
Tony?
It's an advance, I'm going back
to work for him.
But I told you I didn't want you to.
I ain't going back to dancing.
He's putting on a floor show.
I'm going to do a specialty,
a sing and dancing act.
- You're lying.
- I am not!
That's a nice note. You ain't got
a dime to your name.
Then when I use my brains
and my talent to get some...
...you start thinking dirty things
about me.
I know why Tony gave you
that money.
Bud warned me.
- But I wouldn't listen to him.
- Bud, always Bud!
That guy's still messing into with my life
even after he's dead.
You give that money back,
give it back, do you hear?
- I won't let you keep it, I tell you.
- I ain't asking you if I can, I'm doing it.
I could have walked out any time these past
months and left you flat, couldn't I?
I could be living like a queen
if I had wanted to.
But I didn't do it, did I?
I've had offers, yes, plenty of them.
Even since I teamed up with you.
But I turned them all down.
And what for? To struggle
along with you.
Well, I'm through struggling, see?
I'm at the end of my rope and I don't
want to hang so I'm hauling in.
Get the idea?
Alright, then take that money
and clear out of here.
Oh, no, whether you want me
or not, I stick.
There's no use you putting
on an act, John.
You didn't know where the money
came from, you took it...
...and ate what it bought and it
didn't poison you, I notice.
Now that you know, what difference
does it make?
I didn't know what kind of
money it was.
Oh, I don't know what keeps
me from killing you.
If you did, the goose would stop
laying the golden eggs.
- I hate you!
- I don't doubt it.
But I'm gonna do that song and dance
at Tony's like I said I was.
And get this. No matter what you do, whether
you're taking the money or not, I am.
Come in.
You want to see me, Mrs. Allen?
It's Mr. Allen, he's got
something for you.
Yes, Mr. Allen?
Here.
Here's the rent I owe you.
Fifteen dollars is all you owe.
Thanks.
Well, big boy, what do I
look like now?
You look just like what you are.
Yeah, I look like the wife of
John Allen the good provider.
Get those things out of here.
- Take those clothes off.
- Oh, no, I just put them on.
A few jealous cats are gonna see what
it means to make a successful marriage.
Now see here!
I ain't standing for this any longer.
I stood for you paying the rent
because I couldn't help myself.
But if you go out with them things on,
advertise what you brought me to,
you can stay out.
You got it backwards, big boy.
I'm feeding the kitty now, see?
There ain't anybody gonna bring
that kind of money into this house.
That kind of money.
Since when did you begin to examine
a dollar and see who it's father was?
What do you want to stay here for
when you're doing so well by yourself?
I found out that a missus can get away
with things that a miss can't.
That's why all the girls all look up to me
and try to get tips on how I do it.
Yeah, you give them the tips alright.
You'll have them as low as you are
before you're through.
Why shouldn't I give them a hand?
That is, the ones that are worth it.
I've only found one so far.
You'd be interested in her.
You introduced her to me.
- I never introduced you to any girl.
- Sure you did!
At Bud's funeral.
- Annie?
- That's the one.
She's been around a couple of times...
...to see if I couldn't get Tony
to take her on at the hall.
You mean...
- You mean you're gonna put Annie on...
- Why shouldn't I give her a break?
- You can't do that.
- Do what?
You can't... you can't make
a tramp out of Annie!
Who's making anything out of her?
She's tired of working at the box factory.
None of the fellows ever take her out...
...and she wants me to put her
next to some good times.
You can't do that! She was Buddy's steady
company. He was going to marry her.
I don't care what you do
to yourself or to me.
But you can't do anything
like that to her.
- Say, do you think I...
- Leave her alone, do you hear?
- Don't make me laugh, it'll crack my lips.
- Now listen to me, Shirley.
You can do what you want to your own life
but don't go messing into Bud's.
Who's messing into it?
Did I go after his girl?
No! She comes up and makes
a proposition herself.
And anyway, is she any better
than I am?
If it's all right for me to work this way,
why is she too good for it?
Here's a buck in case you run
out of cigarettes or something.
Hiya, John!
- What do you want?
- Ain't you seen the papers?
- What about the papers?
- The horses.
The horses? You mean the ones I...
You sure picked them pretty
this time, John.
You mean the horses won?
The whole layout. Niftiest parlay
I've ever seen.
- In the second Jean King comes up...
- How much?
- How much did I make?
- $388!
- 388?
- Not bad for a vice, huh?
I'll bet that partner of yours sure
would like to have been in on this.
I didn't have no partner!
I was in this alone.
I mean the fellow you used
to bunk with.
- Bud?
- Yeah, that's him.
Remember how he always
used to play for a big kill?
All the boys are talking about this.
They want to know where you got your tip.
No, no. it was not tip.
Yeah... yes, it was.
I got it from Bud, that's who.
- Which Bud?
- Yeah, he made me lay that bet.
He showed me how to play
them horses.
Hey, what are you talking about?
He's been under the ground for months.
- Where's the money, where is it?
- Don't get excited, you'll get it.
Three hundred and eighty-eight.
You'll be able to clear up
a lot of debts with $388.
Yeah, you bet I will.
I'll clear them all off.
Yeah, that's what Bud would
have wanted me to do.
That's why he showed me how
to play them horses.
- Say, I wouldn't talk like that.
- Yes, I've got it all written down here.
Nine dollars for the doctor.
Fifteen for the back room rent.
And then seven and a half.
I've got it all written down here.
Here, give me a pencil,
give me a pencil quick.
I can remember every cent of it.
There... nine dollars...
Fifteen... seven and a half...
There.
And this dollar!
Yeah...
That's a hundred and sixty-two.
A hundred and sixty-two dollars.
Not counting what he gave her.
But this is the only part of it
I've got to clear off!
What are you saying?
- Here, give me the money, give me $162.
- There's three hundred and eighty-eight.
No, I don't want it!
I only want 162!
No... No, I...
I gotta have another ten.
Yeah, I gotta have another ten-spot.
Yeah, that's for... never mind.
Give me 172.
- Take it all.
- I don't want it, I want 172!
That's mine, isn't it?
I didn't get this from him
or from her, did I?
Take it easy, take it easy!
Yeah, yeah...
Yeah, I gotta take it easy.
Yeah, I got a lot of things to do.
Give me a cigarette, will you?
Yeah, that'll steady me a bit.
Light it for me, will you?
Eighty, ninety, a hundred and ten...
A hundred and fifty,
a hundred and fifty-two...
A hundred and sixty.
Sixty-one, two...
There, take that back.
Thanks.
Yeah... yeah, I got something to do.
Yeah, just a minute, just a minute.
- You see this?
- It's a teacup.
Yeah, that's what you think it is.
But it ain't, it's more than that.
I've carried it with me
wherever I've gone.
I've had to hide it so she
wouldn't find it.
Once this was filled with
bootleg liquor.
That's what started it all.
And then it was filled with the blood
of my dearest friend.
My buddy, you understand?
And now it's filled with
rotten money, see?
But I'm gonna clean it all out now, see?
That's what I need the money for.
I'm gonna pay it all back,
I gonna be free!
Yeah!
I'm gonna be free!
- How much are they?
- Only sixty-five bucks.
Well, I ain't asking you for
real ones, Tony.
I suppose I'll have to buy
them for you.
Give me the money.
I got them all picked out.
Oh, you have, eh?
You knew I'd give in, didn't you?
- John!
- What are you doing here?
- What did you come here for anyway?
- You!
What are you trying to do,
spoil everything?
Oh, no, I'm going to set
everything straight.
What is this, a frame-up?
Are you two trying to frame me?
Oh, no, Tony, I ain't in on this,
I swear it!
Trying to pull the outraged husband
gag on me, are you?
- Well, we'll see about that.
- You stay where you are!
- What is this?
- Look!
I've got it all written down here.
Nine dollars for the doctor,
fifteen for the room rent...
- What is this anyway?
- Forty-five dollars more for the rent.
And here's for the food.
I've got it all written down here.
- It all adds up to $162.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
What do you think you're doing
anyway, John?
I'm trying to square things
with myself, that's what.
$162, that's what I took off of him.
Well, I've got the $162 now,
I'm giving them back.
Here it is, a hundred and sixty-two.
You can count it if you want to,
it's all there.
- I don't want your money!
- You can't get out of it that way!
It's yours, take it, see?
- And now, you!
- Tony!
Yeah, it was you who made
a rat out of me.
Made me ashamed so I couldn't
hold my face up.
But I paid him off now.
And as soon as I've paid you I'm gonna
be square with everyone.
- Tony!
- No, I ain't gonna hurt you, Tony.
It was a business deal
with you, see?
- But her!
- Give me another chance, John,
- I'll play fair, I swear I will.
- Oh, no, you can't, Shirley.
Buddy was right.
You were born rotten.
And now you're trying to make
other girls as rotten as you are.
No, I ain't... I won't touch that Annie
girl if you don't want me to.
No, no, it ain't her especially.
She only helped put me
wise to you.
You told me to think about where the money
comes from that I've been spending.
Well, I have thought about it.
- And that's why I'm here.
- Tony, he's going to kill me!
- Yeah, I'm gonna kill you.
- No! No!
If I don't, you're gonna
go on like this.
From Tony to another man
and from him to somebody else.
Always making yourself cheaper
and dirtier.
No I won't, no I won't! If you let me alone,
I swear I'll be on the level.
Yeah, that's what you think now,
but you won't.
It will be the best thing for all
of us if I stop it right now.
Help! Help!
And so, young man, my personal
desire is to be lenient with you...
...in view of certain extenuating
circumstances in the case.
Unfortunately, however, I am bound
by the dictates of the law.
Just why you didn't permit your council
to make any defense for you...
I don't know.
It seems to me you could very well
have pleaded justification.
Or you might have pleaded
temporary insanity.
The evidence of the detectives
who arrested you at the steelworks...
...indicates a least a temporary
mental derangement.
However, since you refused to take
advantage of any of these defenses,
there is no alternative left me than to find
you guilty of murder in the first degree...
...and sentence you to death
in the electric chair.
Is there anything you wish to say...
...before I pass formal sentence
upon you?
All that you said about the
shooting being premeditated,
is quite true, Your Honor.
Yeah, I did it just like you heard.
I was never quite sure when
I'd be able to do it.
But something inside of me
kept hoping that...
...someday, somehow I'd be able to.
Maybe that's why I played the ponies.
Played them without really knowing why.
As soon as that bookie told me
how much I'd won,
I knew at once what I had to do.
No, I wasn't crazy, Your Honor.
I knew all along what I was doing.
Yeah, I was...
What I can't understand now...
is why you're giving me
the chair for that.
You... you've got it all wrong, see?
If you'd have burned me
when I was living off of her,
that would have been the right
time to do it, see?
At first I thought I'd only take what
I needed, what I had to have.
It wasn't my fault I had to have it
and I couldn't get it myself.
But I knew where it was coming from.
And I took it just the same.
That's when you should have
given me the chair!
I sunk as low as a guy can get.
Yeah, but nobody did anything to me.
And then I got that break with
the ponies like I was telling you.
And when I got it,
what did I do with it?
Blow it in on a good time? No!
I went out and I paid off my
debt to him...
...and to her.
Yeah, I did it so I could hold
my face up again.
And for that you want to kill me.
Well, don't you see? You're killing
me at the wrong time.
If you'd have killed me
when I was a rat,
I'd have thanked you for it,
but you didn't.
And now that I've squared everything
off you want to kill me.
Well it ain't fair!
It ain't fair to let a rat live
and kill a man.
No, it ain't reasonable!
It don't make sense.
I won't let you do it, I tell you!
I won't!
You're only gonna make me sick
like I was when Buddy fell.
You're gonna bring that fever
back on me again.
No, I don't want to get sick.
I can't!
I got a lot of things to explain
to you yet.
You're bringing that fever
back on me again.
The blood's rushing to my head.
Oh, I'm getting all dizzy...
My thoughts are all getting jammed up.
Stop it, you!
Stop it!
Stop it! What are you doing?
Stop it, stop it!
Buddy... don't go away!
Wait for me.
I'm coming.
Bud! Wait for me!
All right, Doctor.
- Subtitles -
Luís Filipe Bernardes