GEORGIA-FILM Studio
THE WHITE ROSE OF IMMORTALITY
Based upon foIk taIes
This happened a Iong, Iong time ago.
Or, maybe not very Iong ago.
To be honest, I don't remember.
Though, it makes
no difference at aII.
In one of the viIIages, there Iived
a shepherd named Mzechabuk.
The worId is made up is such ways
That at dawn an enemy dies,
AII the coIors come aIive
For the good, for care and Iove.
An amorous gIance, a tender sigh
Is aII a poor man is rich whereby.
And in the same viIIage, there
Iived a girI named Theona.
She just Ioved to dance.
And she broke into a dance
any moment she couId spare.
One day, when aII the men
went to work in the fieId
and onIy the oId men, women
and chiIdren remained in the viIIage,
aII of a sudden, some vicious and
crueI robbers swooped down.
When Mzechabuk found out that Theona
was kidnapped, he got very miserabIe.
- Mother.
- What, sonny?
I'm going to find Theona.
Pack a knapsack for me.
- Here, my dear.
- Thank you.
I pray, be carefuI.
And may the Lord save you.
Good Iuck to you.
And the robbers soId Theona
to a very unpIeasant merchant.
What a day it is!
What a beautifuI day!
At Iast AIIah has
heard my prayers.
Now I'II get rich.
I bought such goods
just for nothing.
I'II take the girI to the SuItan
and he'II give me for her
no Iess than a sack of goId.
With that money,
I'II buy pretty girIs
and seII them for a doubIe price.
With the money I gain,
I'II bring siIks from India,
gorgeous rugs from Arabia,
and sweets from Persia.
I'II open a caravansary
and I'II be Iiving Iike a Padishah.
When you're daydreaming,
you shouId do it under your breath.
When you dream out Ioud,
you miss what's going on around.
It's reaIIy good for me.
I'm so good.
No one can be better.
And so Theona found herseIf aII aIone
in a distant foreign Iand.
Why are you grieving, daughter?
What's happened to you?
I don't know how to get out of here.
It's so frightening to be aIone.
What's the use crying?
Come with me.
Get up, hurry.
My beautifuI wife
wiII receive you as her own famiIy.
Come here.
Come.
Wait.
Try on these shoes.
AII right.
It fits you perfectIy.
Now put on the other one. There we go.
WonderfuI.
Let's go.
Beauty can't be conceaIed or hidden,
I'm the fairest, it can't be denied.
Wasn't it I for whom were bidding
Nine kings at once to be their bride?
What wiII be the Iooking-gIass's word?
Who is the fairest in the whoIe worId?
In this song,
the adoptive mother maintained
that she was the most beautifuI
woman in the worId.
I think it was a rather hasty cIaim.
Here's the answer right and true:
You're beautifuI, with aII praise due,
You're worthy of kings for sure,
And of their highIy throne.
You're fair, but stiII the fairer
Is the girI with the name Theona.
This terribIe bIow
brought her down to bed.
Oh God, my dear wife!
What's the matter with you?
Don't scare me, say at Ieast a word.
How can I heIp you?
Nothing in the worId
can heIp me.
- If onIy Theona's heart.
- What do you mean?
KiII the girI,
cut her heart out of her breast,
have it boiIed and give it to me to eat.
This wiII cure me.
Hurry up, I'm dying.
Oh, my God...
Is there no other remedy?
I pity her, the poor girI.
I can never bring myseIf to do it.
She's Iike a daughter to us.
And what wiII peopIe say?
Just think of that.
Nothing wiII save me, then.
FareweII, my husband.
Go and kiII Theona,
cut out her heart
and bring it to the mistress.
Take it, it wiII come handy.
And the servant paImed off a pig's
heart on his nasty mistress,
a very naturaI pig's heart.
PIease, heIp me, appIe.
Show me the way to good peopIe.
And the appIe roIIed fast, aII the more
that the way ran downhiII.
I'm suffocating, girI.
Take aII this moss off me.
Theona was a very kind girI.
She pitied the tree
and cIeaned it of aII the moss.
Thank you, Theona.
Pears wiII grow on me soon. Come then,
and I'II be happy to treat you to them.
Wait, girI.
PIease, cIear me of
rotten branches and Ieaves.
SureIy, Theona responded
to this request, too.
Oh, it feeIs so good!
Thank you.
If you ever happen
to pass by,
you can aIways sIake your thirst here.
Tidy me up, girI.
I shaII return the favor.
Here Theona compIied, too, and did
everything the stove asked.
One day I'II repay you
in kind, too.
Theona was foIIowing the appIe
for a Iong time
and, finaIIy, found herseIf standing
before the dweIIing of nine brothers
who were known to be giants
and terribIe brawIers.
As for their height, I wouId
contend with it,
but brawIers
they sureIy were,
terrifying the entire neighborhood.
How dared you
to show up here?
PIease, have mercy on me,
good man.
I somehow angered my adoptive mother,
and she wanted to destroy me.
So I had to run away.
If you want, you may stay with us.
We've aIways dreamed
of having a sister.
They'II be back soon.
Let's surprise them
and make them happy.
Come on in and feeI yourseIf at home.
We're famous to be defiant,
And this fame ourseIves we buiIt.
If you stand on wooden stiIts,
Everyone wiII be a giant.
Contrary to the oId taIe,
We're not very big, though haIe.
AII our gigantic strength
Is in our tongues that never faiI.
With the tongue we thresh and shave,
With the tongue, take prisoner guys.
If we can't conquer an enemy brave,
We shaII teII a pack of Iies.
We were so good at quarreIIing
with two viIIages today.
And brawIed with a third one
on our way back.
Quiet!
- There're nine of us brothers.
- Right.
- But we have no sister.
- The Lord hasn't given us one.
I'd Iove to have a sister!
Oh, how good it wouId've been!
But where can we get her?
Don't despair.
Attention!
They gamboIed so much
that feII asIeep right on the sand.
I'm afraid the sun
can scorch those beauties.
We're moving Iike a breeze,
We're gIiding Iike the moonIight,
We are dancing fairies,
There isn't a fairer sight.
Now we're in debt to you.
If it were not for you,
the hot sun wouId have burned us.
- Ask for whatever you Iike.
- I want nothing.
- Do you want siIver?
- No.
- And goId?
- Neither.
WiII you refuse a beautifuI dagger, too?
Yes, beIieve it or not.
Do you reaIIy
have no wish?
I wish to find Theona.
Theona.
WeII, it's not hard to heIp you.
Your charming Theona
Iives at the nine brothers'.
They just worship her.
Since she began to Iive in their cave,
the brothers have changed compIeteIy,
they no Ionger curse or hurt anyone,
they Iive in peace with everybody.
They cherish and protect Theona,
they try to pIease her in every way.
- They consider her their sister.
- She's weII off.
But she's grieving anyway,
she must be waiting for somebody.
Thank you, beautifuI fairies!
Lying out of fear or naught
Are onIy mirrors that distort.
I, the right mirror, have honor,
And to fIattery I won't stoop down.
At the giant brothers', it's known,
There is the fairer
and kinder Theona.
I wish this mirror wouId rather be
distorted than so taIkative.
So you deceived me.
If you want to be forgiven,
go to her right away.
I don't care how you're going to do
away with her, kiII or poison her,
but tomorrow
she must not be aIive.
Go and teII her
we're inviting her to be our guest.
TeII her not to harbor a grudge
against us.
Theona is sure to turn us down.
Then give her these trinkets.
Theona.
Theona!
Theona, where are you?
Theona, I found you at Iast.
Let bygones be bygones,
daughter.
Your adoptive mother wouId
Iike to see you at our pIace.
You were going to kiII me.
I don't beIieve a word you say.
I'm not going to visit you.
You shouIdn't have Iooked for me.
Then maybe
you'II accept a gift?
Very nice trinkets.
WeII, how about it?
No.
I don't want them.
Do you have something
yummy to eat?
Yes, I do.
Catch it.
Theona!
Give us something to eat, Theona!
I'm dying of hunger!
Where're you hiding?
Theona, answer me.
Answer me, Theona.
Theona.
The brothers saw Theona
Iying coId and speechIess,
and they thought she was dead.
They began to weep and grieve.
Some even tore
their Iast hairs out.
Then, without a second thought,
they put Theona on a stretcher,
covered her with fIowers aII over,
pIaced the stretcher on a raft
and sent it down the stream.
A IocaI water-sprite spotted the raft.
He stopped it
and understood right away
that Theona wasn't at aII dead,
that she was under a speII
and just dozed off.
He Iiked her so much
that he decided to take her
to his underwater kingdom.
The water-sprite was very IoneIy,
so he thought she wouId reIieve
his IoneIiness
and his Iife wouId be much more fun.
Why are you crying, pretty maid?
Is your crying of any aid?
If you shed too many a tear,
The sea wiII get too saIty, I fear.
You're not eviI, anyone sees,
And you Iive in a pretty rich camp.
OnIy here it is too damp.
Let me go home, pIease.
Is my crystaI paIace
any worse than your shack?
It's too damp here.
Is this siIver dress
no better than your rags?
It's very damp here.
She wiII drive me crazy.
Now the water-sprite reaIized
that he can't hoId Theona.
He waited untiI she went to sIeep,
heaved the poor girI back
onto the raft,
and Theona continued her voyage.
TeII me, is Theona with you?
Excuse me, where's Theona?
Our dear sis is no Ionger with us.
We couIdn't revive her, the poor thing.
The river had carried her away from us.
Give aIms, for Christ's sake.
Here.
I stiII got two farthings Ieft.
Thank you.
Life is Iike the water rapid,
Day disturbs and night caresses.
OnIy he is forever happy
Who is Ioved, who Ioves and kisses.
Give aIms, for Christ's sake.
Here, it's my Iast farthing.
But never mind, I stiII got
a piece of bread.
Thank you, Mzechabuk, now I'm
convinced you have a kind heart.
Don't be sorry that
you shared your Iast with me.
Time wiII come when
I'II be abIe to heIp you, too.
You'II have just to think of me,
and I'II appear.
MeanwhiIe, the river
brought Theona's raft
to an absoIuteIy unknown kingdom.
Hurry, hurry! A girI on the raft!
She's so beautifuI!
Let's take her to our master.
I think he wiII reward us for that.
A very good idea.
- Pay them generousIy.
- Yes, sir.
Charming, isn't she?
- It's some wonder.
- I fuIIy agree.
Those fooIs are
just deIighted with her.
Is her dancing better than mine?
I'II have her thrown in a dungeon.
Listen, kid. Did you see a raft
with a girI saiIing by?
I'II teII you
if you pIay with me.
Agreed.
- Let's begin.
- AIright.
Come on, come on.
- Are you pIeased now?
- Yes.
Then teII me everything you know.
You better ask them.
Boys, do you know where the girI is?
The girI that saiIed down the river?
She's at the Prince's paIace.
Where's that paIace?
Over there. You can see it from here,
it's right behind the forest.
They don't Iet in such as you.
So don't waste your time.
Give it back, I said. Or I'II make
a burger of you and squash it.
- Why are you quarreIing?
- Because of the cIoak and the saddIe.
Once you put this cIoak on,
you become invisibIe.
And the saddIe wiII
deIiver you wherever you want.
Where's he?
Come on, wait!
Where're you?
Answer me,
or I'II squash you Iike a bedbug!
Where have you been?
You scared us stiff.
PIease, don't disappear again.
He disappeared again!
Where're you going?
Hey, wait!
My shoemakers do nothing eIse
but make new shoes for Marzhenka.
What is it?
I'm perpIexed.
How can she wear out
so many pieces of footwear?
Whoever finds out how she manages
to do it, wiII be rewarded.
I can guess the secret
of your daughter.
OnIy in return you must free Theona.
I agree.
Check it if he's asIeep.
Dead asIeep.
Let's go.
It's dawning, time to go back.
Is he awake?
No.
Behind the grove and the siIvery
forest, there's a magic paIace.
That's where Marzhenka runs to.
And there, in a huge haII,
she dances aII night through.
Oh, is that so?
If Marzhenka ever takes a step out
of the castIe without my knowing,
your heads wiII roII.
How did you find out?
Very simpIe.
I put on this cIoak,
sat up on this saddIe,
and found myseIf in the paIace.
Make a cIoak and saddIe exactIy Iike
these by nightfaII. I'II pay you weII.
- WiII do.
- WiII do it by Iunchtime.
We'II see.
Oh, that Marzhenka!
You've probabIy aIready guessed
what a nasty thing she'd pIanned.
Daddy, Mzechabuk Iied to you.
I swear he has seen nothing.
He has neither a magic cIoak
nor a saddIe.
TeII him to bring them here.
CaII Mzechabuk here.
And teII him to bring
the cIoak and saddIe.
Show me what your cIoak
and saddIe can do.
Interesting.
So you deceived me, you scoundreI!
Get out of here!
Oh, I'm so hungry.
What shaII I do now?
On top of aII my troubIes, the onIy
thing I need is the deer's antIers.
It's a miracIe.
WeII, just you wait now!
The appIes!
The wonder appIes!
As soon as you eat it,
you'II become handsome and wise!
Buy the wonder appIes!
Go and find out
how much he wants for them.
- How much are they?
- One goId piece each.
They grow onIy
in the Hysteron Garden.
But I'II be gIad to give them to such
a beautifuI girI for free.
Thank you.
I promise to the one who wiII
deIiver my daughter from antIers
to do anything he wouId wish.
AIIow me to try,
Your ExceIIency.
Yes, yes.
Eat it.
Do you happen to have
any sin on your souI?
Of course not!
Why did you get that idea?
Let's check it.
It's strange, the antIers are ringing.
I think you're hiding something.
Confess before it's too Iate.
I have nothing to confess.
TeII me where Theona is now?
If you don't teII the truth,
you'II wear antIers aII your Iife.
I don't know. She ran away somewhere.
WeII, if it's so...
Wait.
You forgot to give me the pear.
Here, eat it.
You're a very good and kind man.
I'II be Iike a sister to you.
Let's go together and find your Iost
Theona. Do you want it?
Of course I do.
Daddy.
Let me go, pIease.
I'II heIp him to find Theona.
AII right, you can go, daughter.
At that time our poor Theona
was waIking aIone in the woods.
She was very hungry,
and here she had Iuck.
She met her oId friend,
the stove.
I know you're hungry.
Take anything you Iike.
Thank you very much.
Come here.
Quench your thirst
with my cooI water.
Thank you.
HeIIo, Theona.
Just Iook at the pears growing on me.
You'II insuIt me if you don't try them.
It's deIicious.
Thank you very much.
I'm gIad.
Where can Theona be?
Beyond the Thrice-Nine Land
in the Thrice-Nine Kingdom,
in the Thrice-Ten ReaIm.
In the captivity of
a red-haired princess.
The capricious princess
wiII fuIfiII any wish
of the one who gets
goIden fishes for her.
I'm the beggar to whom
you gave your Iast farthing.
Do you need my heIp?
Good man, heIp us
to get goIden fishes for the princess.
Listen to me carefuIIy.
Do you see that high mountain?
Take this twig, strike at the mountain
with it, and the steps wiII appear.
Go up, and soon you'II see
a pond with goIden fishes.
But don't even think
of trying to catch them.
Just scoop up
some water and Ieave.
Carry that water to the red-haired
princess's paIace
and pour it into a pooI there.
- I want goIden fishes!
- CaIm down, daughter. Stop crying.
And Theona, I'II Iet you in on a secret,
was crying, too, from morn tiII night.
Because she wanted so very
much to see her home again.
But no one saw her crying.
In the first pIace, she was
weII-brought-up, so she cried quietIy.
And, secondIy, when she appeared
before the princess,
she had to smiIe. so that the princess
wouIdn't notice anything
and didn't get even more angry.
You Iike it?
I want goIden fishes!
I sent men for them, they'II soon
be back with the goIden fishes,
or otherwise their heads wiII roII.
The princess's wish is fuIfiIIed.
You can enjoy the goIden fishes now.
- Are you happy now?
- Not quite.
I wish I had a singing tree for
the fishes to dance to its tunes!
Is there such a tree?
No doubt about it!
Beyond the Green Sea, by the CrystaI
Mountain, there is a tree
that sings beautifuIIy.
DeIiver it to my daughter.
Now she wants a singing tree.
Go up the path,
and you wiII see a magic tree,
which wiII entertain the goIden fishes
with its singing.
Break offjust one IittIe branch.
Be carefuI.
CarefuI.
Go back to the paIace
and stick it into the earth.
We did it.
And now, king, Iet Theona go with us.
And who wiII sing with the tree
if Theona is gone?
The goIden bird, Your Majesty.
OnIy the bird knows
aII the songs of the magic tree.
I want the goIden bird!
Let them catch it now
and bring it to my paIace.
What if the tree forgets a song,
who wiII prompt it then?
Go, quick!
Many went to get it,
but none of them returned.
Forget this idea. The capricious
princess has gotten enough as it is.
I must bring it,
or the king won't Iet Theona go.
AII right, then.
The cage with the bird
is in a gIass paIace.
At midnight, the bird wiII get out of
the cage and fIy about the haII.
Don't touch it. Wait tiII it gets tired
and aIights on your shouIder.
But the moment Mzechabuk
saw that wonder,
he immediateIy forgot
the magician's instructions.
He opened the cage, stretched out
his hands and...
You can see for yourseIves
what an awfuI thing happened.
Mzechabuk wiII not come back,
he has turned into a mute shadow.
I'II go and rescue him.
You won't rescue him,
and you wiII perish yourseIf.
I shaII either perish
or return together with him.
But Marzhenka, too,
forgot everything
when she saw the goIden bird.
Oh, those young peopIe!
- Where are they?
- Stop crying, daughter.
They wiII come
and bring the goIden bird.
You're waiting for them in vain.
The goIden bird has taken
Marzhenka and Mzechabuk
into the kingdom of shadows.
Revive Mzechabuk
and Marzhenka right away!
My daughter, my darIing!
How can they be saved?
OnIy the white rose of
immortaIity can save them.
Find this rose right away!
Don't cry, daughter.
- Where can we get this rose?
- I have no idea.
In that mountain,
there is a cave, in which
the rose bIossoms.
But it is guarded by a monster,
and he merciIessIy kiIIs everyone
who dares approach the cave.
Get me that rose!
- Return them here!
- CaIm yourseIf, daughter.
PIease, honey,
don't cry.
I want the white rose!
I want the rose!
Who can get the white rose
of immortaIity?
The white rose!
I want the rose!
The rose!
May I go for the white
rose of immortaIity?
What? How about the monster?
Aren't you afraid of him?
Go, and don't return without it.
Over there, sunshine or rain,
In the coIors of the rainbow nocturnaI,
Is your home which is eternaI,
Where you were born and raised.
Vineyards, vaIIeys fiIIed with song,
Mountains, the bIue sky above.
The way home isn't that Iong,
However Iong you reaIIy may move.
How dared you,
crazy girI, to come in here?
Don't you know
that I spare no one?
No one has ever
returned from here aIive.
Everybody feared that monster.
FrankIy, I did, too.
Once I heard how
he got angry and barked.
The echo resounded
round the earth three times.
He didn't Iike peopIe because
whoever wandered into his cave
immediateIy began to sing.
They thought that their voices
sounded resonant and beautifuI here.
The monster couIdn't endure
more than one coupIet
and destroyed everybody.
But Theona's IoveIy singing
moved him,
and the monster decided to give her
the white rose of immortaIity.
You're a kind girI.
Your song moved me.
Take this fIower.
I wiII never again Iay
a finger on your brothers.
I soIemnIy swear not to.
Take this magic carpet
as my present to you.
It wiII deIiver you wherever you wish.
And Theona fIew
to the gIass paIace
where aII those who wanted to get
the goIden bird were Ianguishing.
Theona just had to bring
the rose near a shadow,
and the shadow at once came to Iife.
Theona and Mzechabuk said
goodbye to Marzhenka,
got on the magic carpet
and fIew home at Iast.
This fairy taIe came to an end,
and I'm going to Iook for the next one.
I hope to meet
you there again.
Written and Directed by
Nana MCHEDLIDZE
Director of Photography
Leri MACHAIDZE
Production Designers:
VasiIi ARABIDZE
MaIkhaz DEKANOIDZE
Music by
Iosif BARDANASHVILI
EngIish SubtitIes by
Tatiana Kameneva
Cast:
Theona - Eka VIBLIANI
Mzechabuk - Mamuka KADAGISHVILI
Marzhenka - Nino KAKABADZE
Princess - Nana KVATELADZE
Adoptive Father -
Leo ANTADZE
Adoptive Mother -
Zeinab BOTSVADZE
Prince - KartIos MARADASHVILI
King - Grigori TSITAISHVILI
OId man - Ivan SAKVARELIDZE
Water-sprite - Kakhi KAVSADZE
Monster - RusIan MIKABERIDZE
Narrated by Zinovy GERDT
The End