Fishermen chanting.
It's my hometown, Malpe.
A major fishing town on the
Arabian Coast of Karnataka.
A town whose shores are
cleansed everyday by the sea.
But the waves can't reach
everything. Can they?
Fishermen chanting continues.
Boy chanting with fishermen.
Boy starts chanting again.
I met him a few times
during my college days.
I feel he was attracted to me.
Or was he just trying to annoy me?
What would you call that?
Or did he behave the same
with everyone? I will never know.
I would see him around
during my visits to hometown.
Incidentally, we met on that fateful day.
So is it about him?
The article you want to write.
Regina?
Are you here for that interview?
Yes.
Please follow me.
No, No!
It's not only about him.
Then why a series? I mean, is it worth it?
You can finish it in one article.
No.
There are many stories
involved in this incident.
A single article will
not do justice to them.
Madam, Can I get you a chair?
No. Please open the cell.
It's okay. I know him.
Okay.
So what is your idea?
Sorry.
It's okay. I can understand.
Take some time.
Nobody knows what really happened.
Thereis a strange feeling
listening to everyone's version.
You feel it is true,
yet different from the other.
One incident seen through different eyes.
What do you prefer, Tea or Coffee?
Coffee.
Coffee for her and tea for me.
Perspectives. What's true? Who is right?
Everything changes when you see
it from a different point of view.
So how am I supposed
to come to a conclusion?
tell this story with a conclusion.
Instead,
lf every aspect and each
perspective of the story is narrated,
the readers might find their own answers.
Hmmm...
Fair enough.
Ho many articles do you want to write?
I don't know. Maybe 5 or 6. It all depends.
Hmmm... Okay.
Six consecutive articles
for the Tuesday edition.
And I think we can freeze on that.
Sure Sir. Thank you so much!
So this is your first write up.
What will you call it?
I'll tell you everything I know.
I'll tell what I saw.
I'll tell you what I know.
Bastard﻿, What do you know?
Sit quietly. I'll talk.
Regina.
What will you name this article?
Il call it...
"AS SEEN BY THE REST"
A film by Rakshit Shetty
♫ ﻿As time rewinds
to fading memories. ♫
♫ ﻿To the resonance
of the door unbolting. ♫
♫ ﻿Was there a sound?
Knock Knock. ♫
♫ ﻿Whose at the door?
Knock Knock Knock Knock. ♫
♫ ﻿Could it be him?
Knock Knock. ♫
Knock Knock ♫
♫ ﻿He came to tell a secret. ♫
♫ ﻿But walked away
saving those words. ♫
♫ ﻿Troubling me in the
name of memories. ♫
♫ ﻿Was there a sound?
Knock Knock. ♫
♫ ﻿Whose at the door?
Knock Knock Knock Knock. ♫
♫ ﻿Could it be him?
Knock Knock. ♫
Richi was a bully since childhood.
He stabbed a boy to death defending
his friend Raghu at the age of 12.
Raghu disappeared without a trace.
And Richi was sent to the remand home.
And then? What happened?
He was released after
eight years in the remand home.
He returned to Malpe.
And looked for Raghu all over in vain.
But Raghu was nowhere to be found.
Then how did you find Raghu's whereabouts?
I didn't know either,
until I visited Bombay.
I was in Bombay to show
cashew nut samples to a buyer.
He exports cashews to foreign countries.
Raghu was his acquaintance.
We visited a ladies bar for dinner
one night and Raghu joined us there.
What did he do in Bombay?
He was only 13 or 14 years old
when he fled to Bombay.
He took up a job in a little
canteen at the Bombay port.
A few years later he became the cashier
as he was good with numbers.
Gradually, he got involved in
smalltime smuggling at the Bombay port.
Then one day, he made a mess, cracking
the head of someone from the Navy.
He died on the spot!
Raghu had to take refuge with another gang.
He couldn't get out of the vicious circle.
So didn't he feel like
returning home in these 15 years?
He would've never come back.
He had only bad memories of here.
Not that he had good memories in Bombay.
But how many times can a man
run away from his memories?
No, no! I'm not expecting
any money out of this.
I'm just making notes. What was
the name of the ladies bar in Bombay?
I'm a regular to quite a few ladies bars.
It's hard to recall out of the blue.
It's... mm...
It's... Hmmmm...
Roopa Ladies Bar.
So when did you meet him?
Almost a year ago.
We spoke a lot that night.
I told him about his father's death.
He was very upset.
He asked me to meet him the next day
early in the morning at the Bombay harbor.
Chapter 1 Voice of Silence.
When did this happen?
Four years ago. Liver cancer.
His drinking worsened after you ran away.
Mother?
She is okay. Haven't seen
her for a long time now.
I see her once in a while
when visit the market to buy fish.
Is she happy?
I don't know.
She is alone. How can she be happy?
Why don't you come back?
Where? To Malpe?
And do what?
You could set up a business.
It's not that easy.
They'll come for me if I leave Bombay.
Who?
The people I work for.
I know their secrets.
They won't like me quitting.
Why don't you get her here then?
To this hellhole?
She must've learned to live
without me by now. So let it be.
How are others?
Others?
Richi
You remember Shankar Poojary, don't you?
Richi oversees his
legal and illegal business.
Still a bully.
Even after serving time in the remand home.
After you fled, he was sent to
remand home for eight years.
Take this money.
What is this for?
Keep it.
Meet my mother frequently.
Let me know if she needs money.
I'll send in more.
And don't tell anyone about meeting me.
I didn't hear from him for a while.
He then called me two
weeks before this incident.
He wanted to flee from the country
along with his mother forever.
He assured to call back
after arranging money.
Hello.
I'm coming to Malpe.
Arrange my accommodation.
Nobody should know about my visit.
The money is arranged.
A huge deal between the Bombay underworld
and the US mafia was underway.
A red bag crucial for the deal
went missing two days prior.
I had no choice but to steal the bag.
But they won't spare me.
They will try and find me.
I don't know where the
switch is. We visit so rarely.
It's not a big house. But it's safe.
There is some food in the kitchen.
Some bread, jam and eggs.
Can you cook?
Will she come with me?
Of course, She will.
What if she refuses?
What is wrong with you?
How will she say no to her only son?
Mark my words,
She will be ecstatic to see you.
Hmmm.
Well in that case I'll need
your help with her passport.
It will take a month or two.
I can't stay here much longer.
Don't worry about all that.
I'll take care of it.
Keep this money.
I'll send more from Dubai.
Do you have a passport?
Yes!
I've had my share of Dubai dreams.
Okay then, I'll make
arrangements on reaching Dubai.
I'll send tickets for the both of you
after mom's passport is done.
You'll have to accompany her to Dubai.
To Dubai? Will I get a job there?
I have friends in Dubai. I'll talk to them.
Alright. I'll go now.
Get ready by 8 pm.
♫ ﻿If you need anything give me a call. ♫
♫ The phone is right there. ♫
♫ ﻿Hide and seek, ♫
♫ Away from the womb. ♫
♫ ﻿You went beyond the light. ♫
♫ ﻿How high into the sky have you flown? ♫
♫ ﻿That you cannot see your own mother. ♫
♫ ﻿Fingers have dried, ♫
♫ ﻿Holding the food you've forgotten. ♫
♫ ﻿I am worn out waiting. ♫
I called him at 8 pm to
tell that the car was waiting.
He was nervous, perhaps because
he was seeing his mother after years.
♫ ﻿A full grown tree is ♫
♫ eager to see its roots. ♫
♫ ﻿A bird of the vast skies ♫
♫ yearns for its mother's nest. ♫
♫ ﻿If you trace the baby steps, ♫
♫ ﻿I can come home again. ♫
♫ ﻿I wish to go back into your womb, ♫
♫ ﻿To be born again with painless labour. ♫
♫ ﻿The mother's eyes are always Seeking. ♫
♫ ﻿Hearing the child's call, ♫
♫ ﻿I came running. ♫
♫ ﻿Oh my Mother! ♫
After visiting his mother,
he called me around midnight...
when he was
back at the farmhouse.
He was overjoyed.
His mother had agreed to come.
He wanted the car again
at 7 pm the next day.
His mother had called him for dinner.
I called him the next afternoon.
We talked for a bit.
He said that he heard a car arrive.
Gimme a minute. I hear a car outside.
They are coming.
Did you tell anyone about me?
No. I didn't tell anyone.
How did they know?
I think I saw a gun.
I'll call back.
Please connect a trunk call to Dubai.
Operator: Telephone number Sir.
Seven five eight double zero.
Operator: Okay, I'll
call back in 5 minutes.
I visited the farmhouse he stayed at.
I could feel his presence there.
I could feel what he felt.
I experienced his confusion.
I sensed a chapter coming to an end.
The next chapter was in the making.
Tearing the poster, Out came the hero.
Your attention please!
As the Cuban kid always said
Here we meet once again!
Chapter 2
Richard Anthony Alias Richi.
What can I say?
I lost a brother.
Richi was like a son to me.
B@$tarD!
He is an A$$h0lE, a $ON OF A BitcA!
He should rot in hell!
There is a story about him.
When Richi was in the remand home there
was a ruthless cop who beat up the kids.
On his way out of the remand home,
Richi stole his uniform.
And wore that police belt everywhere
he went around town.
Can you believe that?
What a waste!
Thank you!
What a risk!
Old customs of the past,
sacred land, sacred house
God will forgive anyone who sins in that
house, but the householder will never forgive.
Smiles!
I know all about Shankar Poojary.
He may be an important man to these guys.
It's all black money.
They say he ruled the
Bombay underworld at one time.
Bullshit!
Then why did he flee from Bombay?
They kicked him out.
He can't even set foot in Bombay anymore.
He is an exile.
Please find that god
forsaken picture, will you?
I've told a million times
that it is a dummy camera.
You don't believe my words.
What are you laughing at?
Do I look crazy?
You guys are crazy!
- Have you seen yourselves...
- Shut up!
You were saying something
interesting. Continue.
You are harassing me
for a picture I never took.
I'm done with you.
- Please stop...
- Shut up!
She is so cute.
This tea needs a little more sugar.
Please continue.
Shh...
You...
What happened?
Speak baby.
Wait a minute.
Now that you are done talking,
let me have a look at the camera.
Dummy camera huh, What a piece of junk!
Sorry. This not the same camera.
What? Have you lost it?
It's the same camera.
No, it is not.
That camera had a flash as I recall.
How can a dummy camera have a flash?
That is the point.
The real camera had flash as recall.
So it can't be a dummy camera.
Hand over my photo
and I'll stop troubling you.
How can I give a photo I don't have.
Not my problem lady.
You should have thought
before being a nosy parker.
I was just a kid.
So was I.
Yeah right! And I have
memories of cops chasing that kid.
Arrgh, What the hell!
Listen girl,
You're meddling in my life again.
Okay fine. I'm sorry.
I've lost that photo.
Please let me off the hook.
Hmmm...
Please.
Wait, Wait. I'm thinking.
Please!
Dinesha, have you tasted
the fish fry at Rama's hotel?
I swear its the best in Udupi.
I'll try my best darling.
Are you here to meet me?
Yes. You are Richi's father.
Yes.
Can I talk to you for a while.
I wanted some information.
Sure.
How do you know Richi?
We've met a couple of times.
But this is not personal.
I'm a journalist.
I'm writing an article about the incident.
So you know...
Yes. I understand.
If you don't mind,
can we talk in my office.
Sure, sure.
I used to come here as a kid.
Really?
Yes. My parents brought me here
during my vacations in Udupi.
I'm really sorry to bother you with this.
It's okay.
Tell me, how can I help you?
When did you last see your son?
He visited the previous
day of the incident.
Did you break Nikson's nose
in fight three days ago.
What the hell!
Who's Nikson?
I had many fights 3 days ago.
And I keep breaking noses man.
That is my business.
Richi, I'm talking about
Mr. Gonsalves’ son.
Mr. Gonualvas came to church yesterday.
How can I preach at the church
when my own son is...
Your own son?
You should have asked
Mr. Gonzales why I hit his son.
I didn't break his nose.
That B@$tarD got away
before I could do it.
I ain't doing nothing Sir.
And you summoned me
for such a baseless rumor
Now if your point is over, I'll go.
Thank you. Welcome.
Stop bothering me.
I have loads of work.
May Jesus ‘peace be upon him’
bless you and Mr. Gonsalves.
If not his son.
And that was the
last time I saw him.
Stop bothering me.
I have loads of work.
May Jesus ‘peace be upon him’
bless you and Mr. Gonsalves.
If not his son.
Where will we find Nikson?
Why?
I have a job to do.
What job?
I have to break his nose.
Richi, Be gentle.
Will you shut up?
What is this bullshit?
Your father is spreading rumors
around town that I broke your o e
Uh oh! The nose looks fine!
Come here.
Now, this looks superb!
lf the townspeople feel the nose is not
broken well, my reputation will be at stake.
If Richi breaks a nose,
this is how it should be.
No hard feelings bro.
Purely professional.
What?
We regret the inconvenience caused. The
match is postponed due to technical reasons.
What are you laughing at
B@$tarD$? Wanna get shot?
How much shall I buy?
Get a crate for now.
$On OF A BitcA!
Who the hell is that?
What?
I was working in peace by
myself and you butt in like this.
Shit! I don't even understand his
dialect. What the hell happened now?
Use my real name. Will you?
What is that "Loverboy" huh?
The whole town calls you by that name.
I don't like that.
Just call me by my name.
Alright! Where is Democracy?
Dont you understand?
Left a kid all alone in that darkness.
Democracy, come here.
Why?
send him for a bit.
I have a little job for him.
Listen!
Don't waste time chatting with them.
Come back soon.
Go.
Dude, you sent a kid to buy beer!
He can't even lift that crate.
Rayban?
He is asking if your Sunglasses are Rayban.
Yes. Why?
Is it original?
Yes.
Do you have one more back at home?
Can you give these to me then?
Why do you want them?
To wear them.
What is your name?
Satisha.
Don't you go to school?
I go during holidays.
To play.
Ask him, how much has he studied.
How much have you studied?
Democracy for the people,
by the people, to the people.
What's that?
He was caught at school
smoking a cigarette.
It was a beedi.
Oh, a beedi!
A beedi is fine.
Democracy!
Let's go.
I'll go now.
Hey, come here.
Thanks!
Who is that kid?
Vasu's son. He is always with Munna.
So... Where are we heading?
Let's go for a ride man.
What do you say?
Hey Richi.
Yikes! What's that?
Why dude?
Where did you get weed at this hour?
What are they upto this late?
They are painting the
tiger dancers for tomorrow.
Okay. Give mea drag.
Pick up the one you threw away.
Are you going to smoke the whole joint?
When is “Shankaranna's
yakshagana for the ex-voto?
Oh, it slipped my mind.
It's today.
Ugh, What time is it?
11 pm.
It's not too late. Let's go.
What about him?
Look at his plight!
He has drunk too many.
The ASSh0l3 has passed out.
We can't take him along. Let's go.
Okay.
Hey, wait up.
Give me another drag.
How much will you smoke up?
Bhagawata singing.
I hope the act doesn't last till morning.
I don't think so. It might rain.
We have to suffer along with Shankaranna.
Gimme a moment. I'll catch up.
V4 Okay.
Hello, Mr. Artist!
A sword in one hand and a gun in another.
Where are you looting tonight?
Nah, No plans of heist.
How long can you hold
the tide back with a broom.
Spit the fire out of your mouth.
Or it will burn you from inside.
Are you curious about what
happened next, my friend?
When the merchants were sailing on
the waters of Malpe a storm hit their ship.
Shankara, I'm going to sleep.
‘Okay.
When the merchants were sailing in
Malpe's waters a storm hit their ship.
Sire Madhvacharya who was meditating at the shore
saved the sinking ship with his divine powers.
You finally had some time to come!
The grateful merchants offered anything
on the ship as a token of gratitude.
Listen...
Bhagawata singing.
lf Madhvacharya had searched the
ship well, he might have found more than..
the two statues of Krishna and
Balarama hidden in sandalwood trunks.
My friend, there are still such precious
treasures in the depth of the oceans.
Do you know Balu?
Yes.
Where will we find him?
At this hour, I guess he'd be home.
Let's go then.
Not now, Tomorrow morning is fine.
We'll talk later.
I had sent for Munna.
Has he come yet?
He has been informed Anna.
He'll be here soon.
Aren't you giving
attention to these things?
We've 140 boats.
And there are other dealings too.
What are these two for?
It's not about the money,
It's about loyalty.
If we let him off easily,
the others will take us lightly.
I'll take care of it.
Don't overdo it.
Just a simple lesson.
What's funny?
If you send Richi to mow a lawn,
he will mow down a jungle.
He broke someone's nose yesterday.
You $On OF A BitcA!
Are you still high from yesterday?
Come here.
Anna, Munna is here.
Tell him to wait.
Look here, Just a simple lesson.
Don't be a loose cannon.
Walk with me.
Give me a cigar.
Don't give him the cigar.
We'll be screwed if Shankaranna finds out.
Nobody will notice a cigar missing.
It's the same old shit with him every time.
Hey Munna!
Come here.
I'll be back. Wait here.
Alright. I'll send someone with the car
as soon as I get more information.
He'll take you there.
First,
Find Balu.
Balu is one among the tiger dancers.
Last night...
Hey Sudhi!
He was at the school in Malpe last night.
Everyone must've left
for Car street this morning.
Here comes the A$$AQie!
What did I do?
The idiot needs an explanation too.
You are talking too much thes days
Where are we going?
To your dad's house.
Shut up and follow.
Janmashtami celebrations in Udupi
The photo is clicked already.
I don't have spare coins.
Share this among yourselves.
Thank you!
Hey!
What's our share?
lf we have to share a hundred rupees among
the four of us. Should we divide or multiply?
I think we should subtract.
You idiot!
We must divide.
Then... How much is 100 divided by 4?
I have an idea. Let's buy 4 ice candies,
Collect the change and divide it.
Okay.
I want the yellow one.
Democracy!
Come here.
All three of you stand in a line.
I'll be back.
Making a killing, eh?
It's decent.
Business isn‘t as good anymore.
Take this.
That's all?
That girl gave me a hundred bucks.
Richi.
Is this the same camera?
Uh oh! It's not.
I will click some photos
if you care to move aside.
Click mine.
I'm not intere ted.
You were very interested 15 years ago.
I will be really interested when the
police chase you the next time.
I won't make you wait for long.
Okay. Good!
lf you are not developing them
into photos, why do even click them?
Who said that I don't
develop these into photos?
You do?
Of course.
Then, give me my photo.
Why are you so obsessed with that photo?
Well Madam, I don't have
any photos of my childhood.
And you captured the
most important moment of my life.
How can I let that go so easily’?
I've already told you, that pho...
Oh oh!
So I'll have to take your leave now.
But the next time we meet
please get that photo.
Oh! Can I also come with you.
I'm sure I'll get some
interesting pictures.
Shall we take her along?
Not this time darling. Next time.
The police won't chase me yet.
Get the photo.
- Where is he?
- Jod raste
At the junction.
Dineshanna, Where are you headed?
Jod raste.
Wanna race?
Let's see how far can you keep up.
Pedal hard! Fast
Faster, Faster, Faster.
Faster, Faster, Faster
Hey, Why did you stop?
Once more, Shall we?
Music.
I'm so beat after all that dancing.
I'm out of practice.
Gimme a cigarette.
Once more?
Hey, this is our tiger, right?
We don't want to be
hunting the wrong tigers.
Aww!
This tiger is dead!
This tig...
He won't die so easily.
He needs at least an hour to wake up.
Lets dance again, shall we?
We have time till my tiger wakes up.
Raghu Is in town.
Shankaranna sent me to take you to him.
Hey Sudhi. Take the tiger to the harbor
in the rickshaw. I'll meet you there.
I'll take your leave now.
Do you have a paan?
Dinesha, come with me.
Where are you guys going?
To your dad's house.
Shut up and do as I said.
I gave it to hold, not to wear.
Where to?
To meet an old friend.
Hold the gun.
Are you sure he is here?
Yes, Shankaranna said he is here.
No response.
Anna.
Can you please move the car?
Our lorry has to pass by.
Whose lorry is that?
Hey! Go, give him a nice beating.
Go!
Do you think he can pick a fight?
Instead,
You go and give him a beating.
Richi!
After the beating,
Park the car aside.
Open the gates of heaven and
let me serve you, Oh Almighty!
Don't you hear my devout pleas?
Tearing the poster, Out came the hero.
Your attention please!
As the Cuban kid always said
Here we meet once again!
Hey, hey, hey, hey hey!
Down, down, down, down.
Now vou may ask me,
Who is this Cuban kid?
Well,
There is a little story behind it.
When I was in the Bombay remand home,
There was this legend.
The legend of two kids.
A long time ago,
A story about two kids in the remand home.
Some called it a myth.
And people like me,
believed it to be a true incident.
Hmmm, the telephone rings a lot here.
Don't worry.
I will take care of it.
Back to the story.
The two kids.
One was from Cuba,
The other kid,
He was from a village called Mandva
somewhere in Maharashtra.
Uh oh!
What the hell!
Easy man!
No tension.
He is our friend.
Where was I?
Yes.
The two kids.
Antonio Montano,
What was the other one's name?
Vijay.
Yes
Vijay Dinanath Chauhan.
Wanna smoke?
Okay!
Every morning in the remand home,
Everyone gathered at
this canteen for breakfast.
Whenever this Cuban kid
saw the kid from Mandva,
He smiled and abused him in Spanish.
The Mandva kid never understood a word.
But it happened again...
And again... And again.
Now tell me, If you were in his
shoes, how long would you bear it?
Then one day, the Mandva kid lost his mind, put the
Cuban kid on the ground and started punching him.
Daan! Daan! Daan!
Punched until he broke the nose open.
Will you keep staring at us or make
yourself useful and go search?
So...
The two kids were taken to the warden
and the Mandva kid was asked to explain,
Why he beat him up?
The Mandva kid explained what happened.
The warden then asked the
Cuban kid, why he swore at him?
The Cuban kid abused
again in front of the warden.
But this time,
Not with a smiling face though.
But with a broken nose.
Concentrate!
Now this is the best part.
The warden then realized that the Cuban
kid was only greeting the Mandva kid.
Good Morning!
We meet once again!
It is a Cuban tradition.
The Mandva kid was embarrassed.
Then they became best of friends.
That's the legend.
But that's not the point.
My point is,
Let's rewind to the part where
the Cuban kid is getting punched.
At that moment, What is running
through the Cuban kid's mind?
Put yourself in his shoes.
You are getting punched by a kid,
But you have no clue why he is hitting you.
What would be going on in your mind?
Full confusion, right?
Are you confused?
You have a bag. If you don't
hand it over, I'm gonna shoot you.
I don't have any bag.
You do. If you don't give it, I'm gonna
take it anyway, along with your life.
I'm telling the truth.
There is no bag.
ls it? Okay.
We'll find the bag.
And then we'll shoot you.
Got it.
Good!
Now it's time to shoot you.
But the bag is empty.
Huh? Empty?
There must be something.
Have you brought an empty bag?
Alright.
We'll have a look in the
bag once we shoot you.
Now, I'll shoot you.
Before I shoot you,
Why was I telling you
the story of those kids?
You don't know?
How did it start?
Come on. Don't spoil it now.
What did I say when I
entered through that door?
Your attention please.
After that?
Tell me fast!
Are you on mute?
What did I say after that?
We meet once again.
What does it mean?
Exactly! You B@$rarD!
We meet once again.
We meet once again after 15 years!
Richi?
Oh! So you remember Richi!
You B@$tarD, $On OF A BitcA!
Look at your face.
It's a sight to watch.
Look at his face. Sweating like a pig.
So you remember Richi?
How can I forget you?
What? You $0n OF A BitcA!
You've returned to Udupt after 15 years. Why
didn't you let your best friend know about it?
It's not like that. I was
supposed to meet you all.
But...
So I heard you met your mother last night.
Oh, you know?
Are you taking her to Dubai?
Won't you take me along?
Alright.
Take your bag.
You are coming with us.
Sorry. I've promised mom that
I'll be coming home for dinner.
Fine. I'll drop you home
by evening. Now come on.
Come on now.
Get him along.
I'm sorry about breaking the door.
I have a small job to do. If you don't mind
You enjoy the sea breeze. I will finish my job.
Hey Sudhi! Stop the boat.
Hey A$$h0l3!
So you want Shankaranna's money, eh?
So you're a tiger, eh?
When a dog gets high it eats its own shit.
Deceitful B@$tarD!
Are you a real tiger?
Let me hear you roar like a tiger.
Don't whine like a dog.
Tiger! Roar like a tiger.
Louder! I cant hear you.
Roar properly you $On OF A BitcA!
Nah! It's not a real tiger.
It's a dog under the tiger's skin.
Is it enough?
Everything under control?
Just a simple lesson.
Nah! Our tiger needs more.
Our tiger...
needs to earn some more lessons.
Are you confused?
Nah! You are not confused.
Our tiger is not confused. Because...
Our tiger knows why I'm hitting him.
That's the house.
Shailesha, What are you doing here?
Nothing Ratnakka.
Just waiting for a friend.
Chapter 3 Fish Curry.
Fish Auction at the harbor.
She is in her prime now
and not getting any younger.
Ratnakka, how much
did you pay for the fish?
Will you sell it for 180?
I bought it for 200.
How about 190?
Don't you get it? We paid 200!
She has an elder brother,
but he is busy drinking.
Ratnakka, thats my final offer.
Do you think I'm selling peanuts?
Akka, are these new rings?
She paid 375.
Are these fresh?
We would've got it for 340.
She let it pass. I kept pinching her A$$.
When has she ever listened to me?
How was I suppose to know
that the boats would be late today?
Didn't I bargain for a
good price yesterday?
What is she up to?
New job, thus the excitement.
This basket is already counted.
Hey Anita, How many
fish are there in this basket?
Tell me, How many in this basket?
Arrgh! I lost my count now.
Why are you counting?
Don't you want to share?
Who told you that we count and share?
Silly girl! Get up!
Counting! My A$$!
Hello Ratnakka.
How is the business today?
As usual. You want fish?
What do you have?
Lady fish, mackerel.
Don't you have sardines?
No sardines today.
Do you want Clams?
No. How much for the lady fish?
As usual. 5 fish for 30 rupees.
My god! That's expensive. Maybe omorrow.
Will get Sardines tomorrow.
Just 4 left. I'll give all the
fish for an extra 10 rupees.
We are just four people. I've already bought
more and the children don't even like mackerel.
Where will I sell these?
Ratnakka, Do you know
this other girl who sells fish?
She is very pretty.
Who is she talking about?
Must be Sharada.
Yes. Who Is that guy
following her around on the bike?
Oh that guy! He is not from here.
He is from across the mountains.
He works at the harbor.
Following her post
noon is his daily routine.
Akka, Do you want the
head or shall I throw them?
Nobody eats the head.
We feed it to the dog.
Ratnakka, Early today?
Early? Its already dark.
Get inside.
Akka, any fish left?
Sorry. Everything is sold.
Oh okay. I thought of taking
some home if there were any fish left.
♫ ﻿When the tears summoned, ♫
♫ you prepared in sorrow. ♫
♫ ﻿You learnt to draw
with wounded fingers. ♫
Akka, pass the basket.
First, keep the other one down.
Right Right.
Bye Ratnakka. We will meet tomorrow.
♫ ﻿As a Strike of a
matchstick lights up a home. ♫
♫ ﻿As my mother hugs, ♫
♫ ﻿This grown tree, ♫
♫ ﻿Bows in respect, ♫
♫ ﻿For making it feel like ♫
♫ blooming into the heavens. ♫
♫ ﻿The sky meant for this bird, ♫
♫ ﻿That loves to fly, ♫
♫ ﻿Your lap ts that sky to me. ♫
♫ ﻿For this moment of rendezvous, ♫
♫ ﻿For the morsel in my mother's hand, ♫
♫ ﻿We thank you, Almighty. ♫
♫ ﻿Oh my son! ♫
♫ ﻿Oh my Mother! ♫
After that, I never had
the courage to return home.
Your father wanted to see
you once before he died.
How foolish of me. I didn't
even ask you for dinner.
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
I know you like fish curry. I will
cook quickly. Eat a little before you go.
Arrgh! No fish at home. Wait here,
I will get some from the neighbor.
Mom, I have to go.
I can't stay here for long.
You've come home after 15 years!
Please don't speak of leaving already.
Will you come with me?
Who do I have to call my own but you?
I am going to Dubai the day after tomorrow.
I'll take you there. Will you come with me?
To Dubai?
Yes. We can be a family again.
Are you telling the truth?
Will you really take me?
Then I'll come along with
you the day after tomorrow.
You'll need a passport to travel.
It'll at least take a month.
I can't stay here for long.
Mom. Take this money.
My friend will take you to Bangalore
and help you with the passport.
Once it is ready, I will send you tickets.
He'll take you to Dubai.
Why can't you come and take me along?
I can't explain.
Anyway, I'll have to leave now.
Please stay home tonight.
At least have some dinner!
I don't know when I'll see you again.
Alright Mom, I'll come for dinner tomorrow.
I will cook your favorite fish curry.
It's been ages since I had your fish curry.
Fine. I will go now.
Ratnakka, Where is your basket?
Are you ill?
My son has returned.
What?
My son is back.
The one who ran away 15
years ago? He came back, huh?
Yes.
Where was he?
Bombay.
What was he doing there for 15 years?
He was working at a hotel.
Oh. He must have made money then.
He is taking me to Dubai.
To Dubai?!!!
So you won't be coming with us anymore.
When are you traveling to Dubai?
After a month. You need a passport
to travel. It takes a month.
Is it for preparing
fish curry for your son?
He likes lady fish very much.
I'll leave now. I am getting late.
Ratnakka, Don't forget about
us after you go to Dubai.
Oh Shut up! Drama queen.
Will meet you tomorrow.
Ratnakka, where are you going in a hurry?
My son has returned.
The one who ran away 15 years ago?
Where was he?
It's along story. I'll tell you
Some other time. I'm late already.
I'm going to Dubai.
♫ ﻿The moon woke up from his slumber
tonight and floated across the horizon, ♫
♫ ﻿Passing through coconut leaves
and making the landscape picturesque. ♫
Baby! Baby!
My son is back.
Really?
Yes. My son is back
Really? Where is he?
He was here last night but left in a hurry. He
will come for dinner tonight. I will call you.
Where was he for so many years?
He is taking me to Dubai!
As soon as my passport is ready.
To Dubai? Really?
It's getting late. I'm preparing
fish curry. We'll talk later.
♫ ﻿The moon woke up from his slumber
tonight and floated across horizon, ♫
♫ ﻿Passing through coconut leaves
and making the landscape picturesque. ♫
♫ ﻿Like a deep river drifts the boat
ashore even when you lose the oars. ♫
♫ Like a light in the dark of the night,
a voice guides a lost lamb home. ♫
♫ ﻿Like a drop of the morning
dew glitters on the leaf it steps on. ♫
♫ ﻿As if the sky adorned
a rainbow for eternity. ♫
♫ ﻿Like an evening flower cries,
longing for the morning sun. ♫
♫ ﻿Like death himself
stabbed you in the heart. ♫
♫ ﻿Like an old tree falling from a lightning
strike has no land to break it's fall. ♫
♫ ﻿When the thirsting sun is yearning
for water, even the oceans are dry. ♫
♫ ﻿Like a ravaged town
without a caretaker. ♫
♫ ﻿Like a whirlpool stops
a river on its path. ♫
Pass me the toolkit.
Now the spare part.
Hey! Don't throw this
like the toolkit. It will break.
Ya ya. I know all that. I am not a novice.
I'll beat you to pulp, you rascal.
Gimme a minute, Let
me get the water bottle.
Hey! Don't leave me
alone, it's scary here!
Are you listening? Please take me along!
I thought you weren't a novice.
Do you know how dark it is inside?
What if there are ghosts in there?
You folks from Mandwa are dimwits.
Hey! You are up for a
beating if you mock me.
You go first.
Chapter 4 Whispers in the wind.
Come on.
You have two of these. Can I have one?
What?
Hey!
Don't touch my cooling glasses.
Keep them inside.
What will you do with two of these?
I will wear them on alternate days.
And thats none of your business.
Keep them inside.
Can't you wear the same one everyday?
No, I can't. Now shut up!
I like this one a lot!
Hey! you will break it. Give it to me!
These are original Rayban. Do you
have any idea how expensive they are?
Listen, I can't reach it.
Come over here and pick it.
Can't you do any job properly?
Loverboy!
Who the hell is that? How many
times should I make it clear?
Hey! Don't leave me alone here!
Who the hell is that?
What?
I was working in peace by
myself and you butt in like this
Alright! Where is Democracy?
Don't you understand?
Left a kid all alone in that darkness.
Democracy, come here.
Why?
Send him for a bit.
I have a little job for him.
Listen! Don't waste time
chatting with them. Come back soon.
Go.
I'm gonna beat the $h! 1
out of them someday.
Jobless hoodlums!
Drive around the town drunk.
Send that small kid to
get the booze. Filthy pigs.
Democracy!
Let's go.
Whats in the carry bag?
Fish.
Why did you get them?
To put them in an aquarium.
They are dead!
Really? Then I will cook
some nice fish fry for you.
Don't feel bad for them. Take a couple of
extra cooked pieces and parcel them to Mandya.
I'll smash your face, you li'l scoundrel!
Why did those 3 monkeys call you?
Those guys? I was teaching
them Gandhian principles.
What principles?
See no evil, hear no evil, talk no evil. They asked
if they can drink evil. I got them a crate myself.
They even gave me 20 rupees.
You stay away from them.
They are not good people.
And no more taking their money.
Wait till I talk to your dad today.
Shall I wear the other one?
Shut up and sit.
Will you paint me for tomorrow?
What painting?
It's Janmaastami. Think of something
awesome. I should look better than my friends.
Will you paint me?
Why do we come here every
afternoon? You don't even buy fish.
Shut up and follow.
Make way.
Make way please.
♫ ﻿He traveled across
the mountains, ♫
♫ ﻿reached the southern shores, ♫
♫ ﻿enchanted by her smile,
he followed her spellbound. ♫
♫ ﻿He came down the ghats, ♫
♫ ﻿reached the southern shores, ♫
♫ ﻿and stopped the
moment he saw her. ♫
♫ ﻿When she spoke
to the sea breeze, ♫
♫ ﻿he was mesmerized
by the silent whispers. ♫
♫ ﻿She stole my
heart with ease. ♫
♫ ﻿Oh my god! She is laughing! ♫
♫ ﻿The mind's back alley,
will it not hit a crossroad? ♫
♫ ﻿Are you ong ard there? ♫
♫ ﻿The footprints on
the desert sand, ♫
♫ ﻿Is that your shadow? ♫
♫ ﻿He opened his heart ♫
♫ ﻿to write a silent poem ♫
♫ ﻿of lines with no words, ♫
♫ ﻿on a carnival of paper. ♫
♫ ﻿Alas! ♫
♫ ﻿The ink dried! ♫
What fish do you have?
Sardines, Mackerel.
Fresh sardi...
Yes. See.
♫ I know no ways to stop time. ♫
♫ ﻿Hence, I treasure these moments
of intimacy and voice of silence. ♫
♫ ﻿He spent the spring, measuring
sand, enjoyng the distance. ♫
♫ ﻿When she spoke
to the sea breeze, ♫
♫ ﻿He was mesmerized
by the silent whispers. ♫
♫ ﻿She stole my
heart with ease. ♫
♫ ﻿Oh my god! She is laughing! ♫
♫ ﻿He traveled across
the mountains, ♫
♫ ﻿reached the southern shores, ♫
♫ ﻿enchanted by her smile,
he followed her spellbound. ♫
Bye.
Munna, stop.
Hey kid! Get down.
Where are we going?
Drop me till the school.
Hey! What are you staring at? Scoot...
Will you go now?
Stop! Stop!
Get down!
Sit behind.
Lets go!
Are you seated?
Yes.
Why don't you buy a new bike.
This is a piece of junk.
You are finally here.
Yes.
Everyone's here. Get in.
This Karunakara Is missing. Now
where do I go searching for him?
Don't worry. He'll show up soon.
You never now. He has
ditched me on several occasions.
How many painters with you?
Two, including me.
Two.
So, you both.
Narayana and I.
That's four people.
How do we finish tonight with just
four painters? It's the festive season!
I wouldn't call him otherwise.
Hey! You paint boats, isn't it?
I've never painted tigers.
It's no big deal. If you can paint
a boat, this is an easy task tor you.
Please, don't say no. I beg of you.
My reputation is at stake.
No harm in trying. You will get paid too!
Yes yes. Not too much though.
Moreover, we do this in God's name.
Do you have cigarettes?
No cigarettes. Try in the other room.
Oh Dinesha. Come inside.
What are you doing here?
Want to get painted?
Nah! I have better things to do.
You mean we are good for nothing, huh?
This happens only once a year.
Hey Balu. Stand still?
Does anyone have a cigarette?
Are you okay with beedis?
Beedi? Nah!
Jaggu is playing cards outside.
He must have weed.
Really? That like winning the lottery!
ls there Yakshagana at Shankaranna's house?
Yes. For ex-voto.
Which Mela?
Peraduru Mela.
Munna you can sleep now.
We will paint the rest.
Ask the painted tigers to get
the cotton coating in the other room.
Shankaranna has called for you.
Why?
I don't know
What have you done to yourself?
I am a doctor today. Look at the
medicine. You want some?
See, He is a newspaper guy.
And he is a flutist.
Its Vittalapindi. Krishna will
visit us in different avatars.
It coud be him. Offer him something.
He is...
What are you?
I'm a doctor.
You are not a Doctor.
I am. Look I've medicine.
an Ayurvedic doctor.
Yes. He is an ayurvedic doctor.
Never ending energy.
Gives you a new lease of life.
Take it.
Are you coming to the car street this
afternoon to see the procession?
I don't know.
You won't come.
You have time for feelings only.
Come! It will be fun!
What?
Wait for a while.
Okay.
Do you know Balu?
Why?
He has not shown up
at work for many days now.
Have you seen him?
He got painted.
He was at the school when you visited.
An idle mind is a devil's workshop.
Shankaranna is very angry with him.
Why? Is it because he
hasn't shown up at work?
Shankaranna won't lose
sleep over his absence.
Then? What did he do?
Nothing.
What is it? I will talk to him.
Hey, Munna!
Come here.
Wait here, I'll will be back.
Okay.
I'll send someone with the car
as soon as I get more information.
First. Find Balu.
Okay.
What are you hiding?
Learn to smoke a beedi first.
Listen.
He has no control over himself.
Keep an eye.
Okay Anna.
Munna,
Boat 98 is giving trouble. I've told
Richi to dock it by 4 pm. Have a look.
Are the China made engines any good?
Big engines, so good load capacity.
Very few boats have it in Malpe.
I've ordered for one.
If it's good we will order for more.
I'll leave now.
What happened?
They took away Balanna.
Who?
Richi and his friends. They beat him badly.
Balanna was bleeding all over.
When did this happen?
Where did they take him?
This afternoon.
I don't know where hey took him.
Hey! Where did this happen?
Jod Raste.
♫ ﻿Paper, paper. Medicine, paper. ♫
Was there a fight around here?
I don't know.
Have the tiger dancers left from here?
They are at the bus stand.
♫ ﻿I rented out the
Chitradurga fort to the British. ♫
♫ ﻿Bent down the loghthouse to the
ground, to see moon through my lantern. ♫
♫ An insect's cocoon is the silk cloth I
wrap around my waist like a diaper. ♫
♫ On it... On it... On it...
On it... On it... On it... ♫
♫ I drew a colorful
butterfly on it. ♫
♫ ﻿Paper, paper.
Medicine, paper. ♫
♫ ﻿Medicine, paper. ♫
♫ ﻿The rich can construct temples.
But I am poor, what will I build? ♫
♫ ﻿Never ending energy.
Gives you a new lease of life. ♫
♫ ﻿A minister has a
garland around his neck, ♫
♫ ﻿the flowers falling off
leaving just the thread. ♫
♫ ﻿Tie a bell in that thread. ♫
♫ ﻿As I drew my girlfriend's
pigtail on the classroom board ♫
♫ ﻿and was punished to kneel
down outside for a week. ♫
♫ ﻿Frustrated by the teacher's
anger, I smoked an useless beedi. ♫
Did you see Balu?
No. Why?
He is painted as a tiger dancer.
A tiger dancer?
Sudhi took one in the rickshaw.
♫ I rented out the
Chitradurga fort to the British. ♫
♫ ﻿Bent down the lighthouse to the ground,
to see the moon through my lantern. ♫
♫ ﻿An insect's cocoon is the silk cloth I
wrap around my waist like a diaper. ♫
♫ ﻿I drew a colorful
butterfly on it. ♫
♫ ﻿Paper, paper.
Medicine, paper. ♫
Munna, What are you doing here?
Shankaranna told me to repair an engine.
Which one?
Boat 98.
Richi took that boat in the morning.
They must be docking it already.
Hey Munna, what's the rush?
Fishermen chanting.
What are you looking at? Get to work.
Fishermen chanting continues.
Hey Dinesha! It's getting late.
Coming.
Do it quickly.
Do you see any blood stains?
No Anna.
I'm still tired with all that dancing.
Look at Sudhi. Killing time.
Where is that B@$tarD. He had a
lot to talk at Shankaranna's house.
Hey Sudhi, start the vehicle.
All he does is chase women.
Don't get that any closer.
I beg you, just let me be.
I don't want to talk about that.
Please leave me alone.
Just a few minutes.
I won't trouble you much.
Please understand!
The trouble you are causing is more than
enough. I'm an ordinary man. What'll I know?
- Please don't drag me into this.
- I'll make sure to protect your identity.
Arrghhhh! Please leave me alone.
I'm already fed up in life!
First it was the police and then that lawyer. As
if that wasn't enough, now you want my interview!
See, Everyone is looking at us.
What will they think of me?
Arrgh! Bloody crow! All
this mess is because of you!
You are the main reason.
I'm gonna kill you today!
You B@$TarD!
Disgusting crow!
Hey! What are you doing? She is a girl.
How willl you say no to her?
She is just asking for an interview.
Talk to her.
Hey Koraga, Mind your own business.
If you so wanna talk to her,
go give the interview.
Don't tell me what to do.
Come on! Leave me! Come on, Let me go!
She is a girl, you can't say no.
She has promised not
to disclose your name too.
So what if she discloses my name?
I'm not afraid of anyone. I don't care!
Sit down now. Hey kid bring a chair
Please come inside.
Please sit down.
Ask whatever you want now.
I will answer all your questions.
B@$tarD, What do you know?
Sit quietly. I'll talk.
Do you see that crow?
That B@$tarD crow!
It's been following me
since I got that thing.
What thing?
What is it?
Shhhh!
You shouldn't take its name.
It is a bad omen, a curse.
It has ruined all its owners’ lives.
I found it while fishing at the sea.
What does it look like?
It was raining heavily that night.
Five people could not pull the net that day. I joined
and so did Seena. It took seven people to haul the net.
As we untied the net, we found a
huge log of wood in the midst of the fish.
For some reason, I couldn't discard it.
I got it home along with me.
That night the bird was crowing non stop.
It sounded like a brass band inside my ears.
shoo! Shoo! Go away.
Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
Hey! Go away.
Shoo! Shoo!
The crow did not leave with all my efforts. I
realized the crow had followed me from the sea.
It did not stop crowing.
It had its eyes fixed on the piece of wood.
I couldn't bear it anymore and
threw the log towards the crow.
The log split and I see the
most beautiful thing in my life!
Gold. It shined as bright as gold!
It is very precious.
It's in huge demand
outside our own country too.
Do you know how much
they were ready to pay?
In lakhs, crores.
You can't imagine. So much money.
It's a relic. You won't find it anywhere
but in the depths of the ocean.
So where is it now?
I sold it to a guy in Bombay.
That B@$tarD gave me an advance of 10,000 and
promised me to pay 50% of profit after sale.
But then he calls me
and says that it is stolen.
Now how does that matter to me?
Catch the culprit.
Give me my money.
He says he can't until he finds that thing.
Now you tell me,
How do I trust these
guys with so much money?
Shankar Poojary was after it too.
He had sent that Richi, to find out
where I had sent it in Bombay.
But Shankar Poojary told me that...
I was selling his fish in the market.
$On OF A BitcA!
Runs an illegal business
and talks about righteousness.
This Shankar Poojary
has good links in Bombay.
You just can't trust him with anything.
This bloody crow doesn't stop.
I'm going to kill it today.
Chapter 5 Ka.
Trust me.
We don't give Bechappas
(scarecrow) their real credits.
Bechappa has protected our field
day and night from crows and even animals.
What have we done in return?
Not even a yakshagana act in his name.
If you ask me,
We should perform a
Yakshagana act in his name.
The Chronicles of Bechappa.
What do you think, huh?
There is an act on
Krishna & Arjuna's battle.
Bheeshma's Victory too.
Has Krishna, Arjuna or Bheeshma
ever saved us from the crow.
Never! why on earth should
we have acts in their names?
But Bechappa has always been there for us.
What do you folks call him?
Bedaru Gombe.
Not bad.
Same looks but different names.
Hey Balu!
Come on. Let's paint you waist down.
In a minute. Don't get on my
nerves now. Paint the rest of them.
Everyone's almost finished.
You come fast.
Bedaru Gombe
Isn't a very ordinary name?
You should have named
him something strong.
KrantiVeera (Revolutionary)
MahaPrachanda (The Tremendous)
Bedaru Gombe
Doesn't have a ring to it.
Trust me.
You folks over at the western
ghats have no sense in naming.
Have you gone nuts?
A scarecrow is a scarecrow.
What else will you call it?
Don't underestimate our Bechappa.
Do you know how many sleepless
nights I've had due to that bloody crow?
It didn't let me sleep or a week.
I tried to scare it in vain.
Finally I settled down
near my Saviour, Bechappa.
That crow did not dare to come
close to me for those 4 days.
I'm telling you, These crows
are really scared of Bechappa.
Have a look.
He is a foreigner.
That's the guy who is buying it.
Marsellus Wallace.
A rich party!
He was ready to pay in crores!
Take a few more drags.
Oh no!
I can't handle the high.
How much money is a crore?
How many zeros does it have?
You'll see, my Bechappa's
prophecy will come true.
You B@$tarD!
Fantasizing about my
sister in my company, huh?
Tell you the truth,
These folks from the Western ghats
have no control over themselves.
The guilty conscience does not
need an accuser. Look at him run.
♫ ﻿Does the crow see the color? ♫
♫ ﻿Or does it see
the skin beneath it? ♫
♫ ﻿Under the spell
of marijuana, ♫
♫ does one See the
truth or just an illusion? ♫
♫ ﻿Can the crow see the color? ♫
♫ ﻿Or does it see
the skin beneath it? ♫
♫ ﻿Under the spell
of marijuana, ♫
♫ ﻿does one see the
truth or just an illusion? ♫
♫ ﻿Can the betel leaves see
the color of lime put on it? ♫
♫ ﻿Can the dead see the
gruel offered at the funeral? ♫
♫ ﻿Betel Leaves. Gruel. ♫
♫ ﻿Can an illiterate tongue
see fame or revolution? ♫
I'm so beat after all that dancing.
I'm out of practice.
Gimme a cigarette.
Hey Sudhi, take the tiger to the harbor
in rickshaw. I'll meet you there.
I'll take your leave now.
♫ ﻿Can the papyrus see
the scriptures written on it? ♫
♫ ﻿Can the Kanaka's window see
the skin colors peeping through it? ♫
♫ ﻿Did the Dasara pada sung on occasions of
festivities and celebration witness it? ♫
Let me hear you roar like a tiger.
Don't whine like a dog.
Tiger! Roar Like tiger.
Nah! It's not a real tiger.
It's a dog under the tiger's skin.
Have I ever told you the legend
of the Mandva and the Cuban kid?
The Cuban kid smiling and abusing
the the Mandva kid in Spanish,
The Mandva kid dropping him
on the ground and breaking his nose.
Where is it?
Yes. Got it!
When the Mandva kid was punching him, what
was running through the Cuban kid's mind?
Put yourself in his shoes.
You are getting punched without a reason,
What will be going on in your mind?
Full confusion, isn't it?
Are you confused?
Nah! You are not confused.
Our tiger is not confused.
Because, our tiger
knows why I'm hitting him.
Are you confused?
8 years.
All those years for you.
Do you know the life in a remand home?
Hell!
You ran away so easily!
Did you ever think of me?
Now die.
Stop staring and tie him up.
Richi!
Check the bag.
Move aside.
Final Chapter Reasons.
Raghu! Raghu!
Raghu!
Not that way! This way!
Shankaranna is very angry with him.
Nothing.
What is it? I will talk to him.
Hey, Munna.
- What happened They took away Balanna.
- Who?
Richi and his friends. They beat him
badly. Balanna was bleeding all over.
First, find Balu.
Do you see any blood stains?
Shankaranna is very angry with him.
Have I ever told you the legend
of the Mandva and the Cuban kid?
Put yourself in the Cuban kid's shoes.
lf someone hits you without a reason,
What will be going on in your mind?
Full confusion, isn't it?
Are you confused now?
Nobody knows what really happened.
There was a strange feeling
listening to everyone's version.
You $On OF A BitcA!
B@$tarD. Bloody crow!
You feel it is true, yet
different from the other.
One incident seen through different eyes.
I guess, the thing was
stolen by Raghu in Bombay.
He probably had plans to
sell it in Dubai and settle there.
I told you! Its a bad omen, a curse.
It won't rest until it ruins your life.
Perspectives. What's right? What's wrong?
What is the truth? Which one is a lie?
Everything changes when you see
it from a different point of view.
No, no! Richi didn't kill him. I was there. They
were childhood friends. Why would he kill him?
So why didn't Raghu
meet his mother that night?
I'm not sure either. When we were leaving the
farmhouse, he said he had to make an urgent trunk call.
After the phone call, he was tensed.
He left in the evening to meet his mother.
I don't know what happened after that.
He must've returned secretly, probably
because, the Bombay guys found out he was here.
If he is in Dubai, he will surely call me.
So how am I supposed
to come to a conclusion?
In fact, it would be wrong to
tell this story with a conclusion.
Instead, If every aspect and each
perspective of the story is narrated,
I believe you'll find your own answers.
I did not witness this story.
I've chronicled it “As Seen by the Rest"