Give thanks with your heart
and support with your body
A Toho Film
Uma (Horse)
A Shingi Morita Production
Film by Akira Kurosawa,
Music by Shigeaki Kitamura
Cinematography by Hiromitsu Kurosawa,
Akira Mimura, Hiroshi Suzuki, Takeo Ito
Starring Hideko Tamamine,
Chieko Takehisa, Kamatari Fujiwara
Roles
The Onoda family: Grandma = Kaoru Futaba,
Father = Kamatari Fujiwara, Mother = Chieko Takehisa,
Ine = Hideko Takamine,
Ine's older brother Toyokazu = Takeshi Hirata,
Ine's younger brother Kinjiro = Toshio Hosoi,
Ine's little sister Tsuru = Setsuko Ichikawa
The teacher (Yamashita-sensei) = Sadao Maruyama,
his wife Kikuko = Sadako Sawamura, ETC.
Military equestrian supervisors
Jun Maki and Shoichiro Ozaki
Script and Direction = Kajiro Yamamoto
Good horses are made through the care of those
who raise them. They will be increasingly needed in future
as weapons for our military - Army Minister Tojo
(Horse Inspections)
Lot 37, military approved.
Bidding starts at 200 yen.
Opening bidding at 200, 200 yen.
That's cheap!
10! 210.... 20... 220, 30! 230 ..
250! 260!
Plus 1 yen! OK 301 yen...
304 yen...
307 yen!
320 yen!
One more!
and one... and another one yen...
And one more...
335 yen!
Too cheap!
I must get more money for it!
Bid higher!
Come on Zenzo 335!
and another! 338!
340...
450 yen!
I have 450...
Surely it's a mistake. He must mean 350!
No, it's 450, No mistake.
Hooray!
Army bids are always welcome!
Everyone else finished bidding?
I'm done. The price is too high.
All done at 450. Army purchase.
Nice horse.
450! Great price!
This one's for the military.
Oi!
Thank you very much!
Keep back! Keep back!
What's a girl doing here?
Get out of here and go home.
Eh? It's fine. Let her stay.
You're Ine, Ine Onoda!
That was Mr Sakamoto's horse.
- You stay close down here.
Next up is lot 48 from Tamayama,
Army grade 19.
Well worth buying!
A lovely horse! How much am I bid?
Starting at...
200! 200 yen!
(and 5!) 205!... (and 20!) 220!
204!  (and 4) 245! (and 50!) 250 yen!
Ine! I'm angry!
Where on earth have you been all this time?
I went to the auction.
That's more or less what we figured!
And just when your father and I
are utterly exhausted too!
Why so late?
You're inconsiderate,
running off like that.
I'm so disappointed with you.
I don't know what to say
But Mum...
How dare you! You know
what happens to kids like you?
But Mum...
How dare you! You know
what happens to kids like you?
I shouldn't even let someone like you
back in the house. Get out.
Go on... GET OUT!
Don't say that.
I'm desperately hungry.
That's not my problem.
Complain if you like,
but after I've eaten.
You cheeky little brat...
- Don't get angry with me!
How dare you!  You little...
Mum no!
- You little wretch! Come back here!
Ine! Ine!
Come here.
Right then.
You're not coming back in this house.
Well?
Papa! It's started raining.
Ine! Come and help!
Hey! Be careful!
Look where you're going!
OK.
Look!
Ine, you clear away.
It may be a stable
but it's all straw and no horse!
It would be much more fun
if we actually had a horse.
You're always going on about horses
but what would we do with one?
You know mum...
We're the only ones
around here without a horse.
Have you forgotten the one that died?
That was just bad luck.
We couldn't do anything.
It wasn't bad luck.
Horses always cause problems.
They're expensive and they eat up time.
Then they suddenly up and die on you!
You don't know it but we're still
struggling with the debts from that.
I've never heard of keeping a horse
lead to anything good.
Horses are not something we want to raise.
You say that because you hate horses!
Kyuzaemon's horse was sold
for stud today... for 1200 yen!
And Zenzou's colt was taken
for a cavalry horse at 450 yen.
Prices are going to go up higher too.
Nobody can lose money they were saying.
That's true, dad, isn't it?
Whether it's good or bad,
you can't raise a horse without money.
That much I know.
Mum, bake this for me.
Chestnuts?
Yes.
They're early this year!
What are you doing?
What's it to you?
How dare you talk to your father like that.
I'm making a bathmat.
You'll damage your eyes
if you keep at it like that.
But my teacher said
it might be good enough to show
at the prefectural competition.
If your ruin your eyes
don't say we didn't warn you.
Well well...
It's Zenzou.
Come in.
Have you finished dinner?
Come in. Come and sit down.
Make room!
Don't stand by the door.
Come on in.
Come and sit down.
I brought some sake!
Wow!
Hey Kanjiro...
Listen to this!
They gave me 450 yen for him
as a cavalry horse!
That's incredible.
What an incredible price to get.
That's something to give thanks for.
Congratulations.
Wow...
Getting 450 yen is superb.
I thought he'd sell well
but I never expected that much.
Well I did!
The horses I raise are always reliable.
I know how good they are.
You look like
the smiling merchant god Ebisu!
You look utterly delighted.
Yes, I hardly know what to do with myself!
Help me celebrate!
Thank you so much.
Right then, let's drink.
Have a drink.
I still have work to do tonight...
What? But I want to celebrate!
Come on, have a drink.
You too, Granny.
Thank you.
And for you.
Thanks, but I don't need it.
I can't drink.
Oops! My mistake!
My mistake, my mistake!
(Sings a festival dance song
without clear meaning)
(SONG again)
That's funny!
That's great for the barefoot dance
at the Bon festival!
Who was saying how no good
ever came from raising horses?
Just look!
(Children's song: mentions Spring, then Summer)
You've almost finished.
If it's good I'll send it to
the folkcraft show in Tokyo.
Your snow-boots are scarily large!
Who on earth could fit into these?
Maybe the statue at the temple
is big enough to wear them!
Toyokazu, yours is a bathmat.
That's right
I see.
Looks like you made the pattern
with a yahazu (hooking tool).
That's a clever idea.
Teacher!
There's a horse!
What a beautiful animal.
Is it your family's?
Yes.
She's called Hanakaze
(written with kanji: flower+wind)
Oh, a mare!
Her stomach is swollen...
That's right..
She'll foal next spring
She's a fine horse.
Is she a thoroughbred?
No way. Anglo-Norman stock,
but bred in Japan.
Because of that Norman heritage...
I plan to raise her foal for the military.
That's a good idea. Norman stock have
strong legs and are well-suited for military use.
I must be going.
Good luck and work hard to raise your horse.
Come on then.
Toyokazu!
Was the horse bought at the last auction?
No, she's on loan.
So you mean
you're looking after her for someone?
Yes, but the foal she's carrying
is promised to us.
It will be hard work to look after
a pregnant horse through the winter.
Be careful.
Teacher...
I actually don't like horses.
(Bridal song for ceremonial journey of bride to new home)
Well, well! Hello.
Hello...
- Have a drink!
Come on!
Hello.
Please drink a toast.
Here we go...
Have another!
- No I...
Come back here!
Don't let him escape!
I said I don't want it.
Good isn't it! Have another!
Drink with us!
Alright then...
Do you still feel cold?
- Yes, I'm cold.
So cold, so cold.
The chills won't stop...
Damn it. I'm so bloody angry.
On the slope...
I was behind the cart...
I stooped to pull...
and I suddenly fell backwards...
I know...
God damn it!
Damn them, he's so important to us
and they've ruined him.
They've ruined my husband.
A curse on them! Damn them to hell.
I hate them, I hate them.
There were many crows cawing
(an evil omen) outside this morning.
It's the horse's fault.
This is what happens!
Here!
Ine, don't feed the bloody creature.
But...
Father was in the wrong for getting drunk.
It's not the horse's fault.
Do you mean the horse is
more important to you than your father?
Good evening!
- The doctor's here.
The doctor's here, the doctor's here,
what kind of doctor I wonder...
but in this little village
the doctor's just a useless quack!
Stop that!
You're in a bad way.
Yes but first...
thank you for coming so far...
No problem.
I want you kids outside.
Ine, take the kids outside.
Toyokazu!
I don't want to! I don't want to!
Come on hurry up!
-  I don't want to!
Come on. I know what to play...
Riddles!
- I don't want to!
Shush!
OK, here goes...
When it stand it's like a cat...
when it sleeps it's Grandma... what is it?
Upright = a cat?
Lying down = Granny?
That's easy! It's the Chouchin lantern!
When you stretch it it moves like a cat...
When you squeeze it shut
it's as wrinkly as granny!
He's right!
OK. You're right.
Let's have another one.
What did the doctor say?
Dad needs an operation straight away.
Why does he need it?
Well I don't know...
Come on, let's play hide and seek.
- I don't want to.
Right then! Hide-and-seek!
(Play janken to decide
who hides and who seeks)
You're it! You're it!
- Ready?
Are you ready yet?
No, not yet.
Ready?
Not, yet not yet.
No, not yet.
Ready?
There's a whole bucket of fresh blood...
- That's bad.
When he put some medicine on it
lots of white, bubbling slime came out!
Is dad going to die?
Don't be silly.
It's not bad enough to die from.
I don't think so anyway.
Shaman-style Chanting (folk healer)
(talks of driving away this persistent ill)
(talks of gratitude for
receiving the benefit of healing)
on and on in
a garbled pseudo-religious babble.
This way!
Granny!
I'm hungry.
- You must wait.
The doctor expects him to be
up and about in 2 or 3 days.
We'll be in trouble
if he doesn't get better quickly.
Yeaah? He's not really a doctor.
You can't believe what he says.
Well, as far as I can tell....
He's been cursed.
There is an evil spirit.
What kind of spirit?
Well...
An evil spirit...
Hey! I'm hungry!
- Me too! - Make us something to eat!
Be quiet. He's praying for your father.
Mum will be home soon
and we'll eat but until then stay quiet.
What kind of spirit?
Well...
An evil spirit... I think it's four-legged.
Four-legged?
So that must mean...
Maybe it's the horse?
A horse? Oh yes, it's the horse.
What a ridiculous tale!
To blame the horse
is utterly ridiculous.
Dinner! Make dinner!
Roast us some yams!
Wait. When mum
comes back we'll eat properly.
It's horrible, we're 300 yen
in debt to the farm union.
What can we do?
Ine, why are you still waiting here?
Why don't you go and get firewood?
Don't you realise
it's cold and I'm half frozen?
Here!
You're alright beside the fire
but think of your frozen mum.
There's nothing for the horse to eat.
I can't stand you sometimes, Ine.
Do you know how much of a disaster
your horse has caused this family?
We're in a real mess.
It's as if you've brought a curse
of bad luck on us with that horse.
And there's nothing we can do!
How dare you look at me like that!
They say if you glare at your parents
your face will end up end ugly.
But.... I really don't understand
half the nonsense you say.
So you're going to talk back to me?
I have no idea what you're on about!
How on earth can we get out from this?
We're in debt...
I can't buy anything at all for New Year.
What on earth am I going to do?
Here!
Never mind about feeding the damned horse...
We humans have to eat too.
Kinjiro and Tsuru are hungry.
Ine loves that horse more than
her sweet little brother and sister.
The Union said they'll wait.
And the chairman gave me some eggs for you.
Eggs? From the chairman?
I'm embarrassed... but really grateful.
He's a really good man.
Will you have some egg?
I need you to get well quickly
or it will be hard for me.
Where've they gone?
I'm sure I put them here.
That's strange!
I had them at the union...
they wrapped them for me!
There were 8 eggs...
Did someone take them? Eh?
Surely it can't be you grandma...
Kinjirou, it was you!
- It wasn't me.
If it wasn't you then open your mouth.
If you lie a demon will come
and rip out your tongue!
I told you it wasn't me.
How odd...
Recorded Delivery!
Recorded delivery?
What's that mean?
I dunno...
Hey, do you think it's the debt collectors?
Surely not...
I need your hanko seal here.
- My seal?
Don't accept it until you've had
a good look to see what it is.
If it's from anywhere bad
make them take it away.
He says its definitely for us.
Really? Where's it from?
From Tokyo.
Tokyo?
Hurry up and stamp it.
Where did I put my hanko...
I had it when I was at the union...
Here you are.
Quickly then! Show me what it is.
- Hang on and I'll open it.
Give it here!
Wow, it's typewritten!
Respectful greetings.
Allow me to come straight to the point.
At the recent Exhibition of folkcraft
in the Mingeikan in Tokyo...
as part of the North East
Farming Villages exhibit...
What's a "Mingeikan"?
Shut up and let her read it!
The bathmat which you exhibited
received a lot of positive attention...
And we would like
to sell them here in the shop.
We therefore humbly request
that you send us
100 of them by March 1st.
As a deposit I enclose 30 yen.
Check in the envelope!
Here...
It's a money transfer order!
A bank draft!
It's for 30 yen!
Mum, Grandma... look!
A bank draft!
Wow, 30 yen. 30 yen!
That's amazing!
Dear...
I've given you a cheap price! Come again!
Thank you!
(market trader calls)
(market traders)
(Stall holder cries prices)
Happy New Year!
First have some mochi (rice cake)!
Thanks. What a treat!
What a treat!
It's ready! There's anko (sweet bean paste),
so come straight away.
OK.
Come on. Come on everybody.
(shouts to exorcise bad luck)
(Calls in good luck via folk Buddhist
tradition see Setsubun or Mamemaki)
Found you! Found you!
(Children join the game)
As it's New Year
here's some rice for you!
It's frostbite! I've got frostbite!
Frostbite?
I have a charm to cure that.
Pain, pain, fly away up the mountain
1, 2, 3... Gone!
Is that better?
No!
You're a pain!
You've been complaining for ages.
I've got frostbite.
So don't play snowballs!
Go to bed. Go to bed.
You wear me out!
(Folk tradition where monsters
called Namahage/Yamahage/Suneka visit)
Where are the naughty kids?
Who's bad?
Who's the bad one?
Yes, we've got one. Here he is!
This one?
You're not going to be bad again, are you?
I won't, I won't!
Will you do what your parents say?
I will, I will!
Have you told lies?
I didn't. I didn't!
Are you sure? Really sure?
OK I did.
When did you lie?
I took some eggs and ate them.
So it was you!
What a bad boy!
And was it you
who took dad's machete and lost it?
I didn't touch the machete.
Are you lying again?
I'm not lying.
I don't know about the machete.
You really don't know
anything about the machete?
He promises he won't do anything bad...
So please forbear from harming him!
OK, this time and this time only.
OK let's go.
Kinjirou, Tsuru, come on, off to bed.
Go on.
Thank you very much.
Please accept a drink.
Thanks.
Have a drink!
And you too! Come in.
OK I will.
Thank you very much.
Zenzo you bastard!
Snow, snow tumbling down, tumbling down.
Snow, snow tumbling down.
Snow, tumble.
Mum? Mum!
Now what is it?
Come and look!
What is it?
Hana isn't eating.
So that's what you want.
It's ridiculous.
Please come and look, mum.
She's got no energy and just lies there.
I'm afraid...
Come and take a look. Please!
Stop going on and on about it.
I can't at the moment.
Just like a person, when she's hungry....
a horse won't eat and won't get up.
It's nothing to get worked up about.
You're really unsympathetic, mum.
What will we do if the horse gets worse?
Ine! How's Hana doing?
Her muzzle is dripping... maybe it's a cold?
Yes. Maybe.
She seems bad.
Nasal discharge...
Dad?  Yes?
I think we need the vet to take a look.
OK.
Shall I go and get him tomorrow?
Yes, we should get the vet.
Of course it will cost money...
Maybe a cold is not such
a serious thing if you're a horse...
You go to bed. I'll stay up with her.
No. I'll stay with her.
(chants to drive off evil spirits)
Chanting mumbo-jumbo won't do any good.
She needs the vet.
You're a kid and you don't understand.
Vets cost money.
Money...
and we haven't got any.
So you're saying
we should just let her suffer?
Well, for better or worse it's not our horse!
If the owner doesn't want the horse to die
THEY should do something.
It's nothing to do with us.
I know that's logical... but...
Never mind about "logic"
You always say such cold-hearted things...
I feel so sorry for her
I can't bear to watch.
Hello?
What the hell are you doing?
Oh, it's you Mr Sakamoto.
You shouldn't be here doing this!
Get out of here. Go!
- I'm sorry...
You're still troubling the farms
with your ignorant ways?
If you do anything illegal
you'll get arrested again!
Get out of here!
I'm going. I'm going.
I won't take any payment from them.
So please don't tell anybody.
I'm going. Goodbye.
He's incorrigible!
If he gave you some
rubbish potion to give to the horse...
Don't feed it to her.
No good will come of it.
Please could you look at the horse?
OK. I wonder what's wrong.
She's not eaten properly for 10 days.
She's got equine distemper.
It's commonly called "strangles".
It's a recurrent problem.
Large horses don't often get it...
But no matter what you do
sometimes horses develop it.
Fortunately with this girl to look
after her carefully she'll be fine.
She'll be fine. Just keep feeding her
as usual and she'll get through it.
If it was anywhere other than here
she might not survive.
How is distemper treated?
What should I do?
Well... it's supposed to come
from a lack of UV light.
So getting her out
in the sunlight is the key.
It would be best to give her
green hay if you could.
I know that's nearly impossible
in the middle of winter.
But you might find some
around one of the natural springs.
Ask the youth groups or even the police
to keep an eye open as they move around.
She needs it urgently.
But don't try to go up to Inosawa.
She certainly won't.
In this snow
even a man couldn't get up there.
There'll be something closer to hand.
But this kid is a handful. She's tough.
She may well try.
What should I do?
I'll ask the youth group guys to help.
- Thank you.
I'll come along with you.
There's nothing I can do here.
I'm so sorry to trouble you.
Thank you so much.
(prays)
Ine!
Ine! Ine!
You idiot!
You idiot. You utter idiot!
Mum! Mum!
Walk her round and round every morning.
- OK.
I'll do it over and over again.
Her legs have strengthened a lot.
She'll be able to have her foal safely.
Yes.
When is she due to give birth?
- Maybe around the start of May.
Come on.
Spring is here. Spring is here
Both here in the fields
and up in the mountains
Flowers bloom, flowers bloom
They bloom in the village,
in the mountains and in the fields
Dad! Dad!
Come quickly! Dad!
Come on out! Quickly!
Never mind that! Quick!
- Hang on! No need to panic!
You're ridiculously calm!
OK. I'm coming.
Hurry!
You're too anxious. It's good to get on
with a thing rather than worry about it.
Never mind that! Come on! Quickly!
There there...
It's so painful to watch.
Her breathing is so laboured...
and so much sweat on her muzzle!
Dad! Rub her stomach!
OK.
There there.
I can't bear to watch.
Mum, how can you not feel sympathy for her?
Because she'll be fine. Stop making
such a fuss. Try to calm down.
Is it so hard to give birth for people too?
Silly girl!
When I had you
you were my first so it was really hard.
There there, there there.
Mum! Please come and look.
It'll be fine. Keep calm!
You're so heartless.
Why won't you even come and see?
Dad! Is she OK?
I've told you already, she's fine.
Now go away.
Mum, mum!
God, you're a pain.
Can't you keep quiet?
Granny! Pray to Shourai (deity usually calling
the souls of the dead back at the Bon festival)
Yes, we should pray.
Even Shourai has to sleep. There's no point
waking him in the middle of the night.
Maybe there is!
Stop complaining and pray.
Pray for a safe delivery.
Ine!
Has she given birth?
Did you say she has?
Yeah, she's just this moment started.
Don't peek.
She'll panic if you do.
He says she'll be very panicky
and we should keep away.
Ine! Come here!
OK.
What is it?
One of the legs isn't out...
That's bad.
It must be stuck.
- What should we do?
Ah!
It's finally out!
Hooray!
It's about the size of baby deer!
How ridiculously long its legs are!
Look! It's legs are all rubbery!
What's that covering the hooves?
Keep quiet!
Stay back!
But you and Kendo are here...
It's incredibly heavy.
So cute, it's so cute!
Show me!
You go to bed.
It's so cute... yeeeah, so cute.
Won't she tread on the baby?
I told you, it'll be fine!
Bring some cloth!
I need to wipe the little guy.
Here!
That's better!
Come in and help me.
I'd be delighted.
Careful!
Give it to me!
- Here you are!
Good girl!
There we go.
Keep still!
There there!
It's enormously strong!
Toyokazu, fetch some hay!
You want me to get it?
Here you are!
Wow mum... it's rare to see you so keen.
Well I know everyone gets
incredibly hungry after giving birth.
Here here!
That's right...
Come out!
Now it's dry it'll stand
and try to suck its mother's milk.
Look, look. It's going to stand up.
Stand up!
Almost...
That's it...
Maybe not quite yet...
It's legs are still not steady.
Here it goes...
Almost!
Shouldn't we help?
No no, it has to do it by itself.
Yes, I suppose so.
He's going to try again.
Stand up, come on!
That's it! Go on!
That's it... that's it... nearly...
Keep trying... you're almost there.
Almost there... come on... you can do it!
Hooray! It's done it!
Well done!
That's it!
Look, it's doing a poo!
So it is!
So wobbly!
It's so cute!
It's like watching a drunk.
It looks like Mr Sakamoto on the way home
after he's been out drinking.
Look at it staggering!
That's funny mum, really funny.
it's going to drink!
How cute its mouth is!
It's poking its little red tongue out!
Wow!
Look, the sun's already up!
What a long night!
So it is!
The foal grew day by day,
cuter all the time.
Come here you!
Wait, Kozuo (little rascal).
Hoi (used to call horses).
Hana!
Kozou!
Hana!!
Come here!
Good!
I've been waiting,
but I've brought you something nice!
It's salt!
Here you are! Eat! Eat!
Delicious, isn't it?
You're getting bigger every day, aren't you?
I'll bring you something nice next time too!
Where on earth has Ine gone?
You can never tell what's in her head.
Ine's up at the Oogata ranch.
That's so like her! She never listens!
There's no need for her
to come and see me off.
Here it comes now!
The steam train's coming!
Do your best!
Careful! It's dangerous!
Ine!
Hi, are you back for o-bon
(Bon festival holiday)?
Yes, that's right.
Are you enjoying your job in the factory?
Not really, but who would?
I'll come and visit you tonight.
- OK.
I'll tell you about the factory!
And we'll talk about films!
Great, see you later!
Please take a seat.
I'm so sorry I haven't been able to pay.
I know how tough things have been
for you so I didn't press you...
But I'd like you to pay what you owe
at the end of the half-year. - I see!
I know it's the Bon festival...
but I can't do the books
unless you pay last year at least.
I'll manage to pay somehow.
- Try and come up with an idea.
I hear you're going to sell your foal.
I was shocked when Mr Sakamoto told me.
There's nothing else I could do.
It's a a terrible world we live in
where you have to do such a thing.
No matter how much you can get
I advise you not to.
I don't want to sell it...
But with the half-year rent bill,
I have no choice.
I'll be leaving now!
Thank you. I'm so sorry
we can't offer you anything.
I'm so sorry we can't offer anything.
Please forgive our rudeness.
To sell a good foal
just for the rent is a waste.
You'll lose compared to what you'd get waiting
until he's a colt and selling him to the army.
I know.
So think it over carefully.
What about Ine? Will she agree?
You're really upset, aren't you?
I know there's no help for it
and I'm trying to accept it.
Come on, hurry.
Don't just stand there. Quickly!
Good evening!
Aren't you going to the dance?
You all look really pretty.
Come on Hana, come on in.
All of you!
Ine said she wasn't going to go,
but we came to try and persuade her.
Thank you for coming specially.
Can you wait just a moment?
They want you to go to the dance.
Why don't you go?
It's so kind of them to come and ask.
They didn't have to.
Go on, please, for me!
I'll dress you!
Take this off...
and let's sort out your obi (belt)!
They're waiting for you!
Come on... put this on!
Here, let me do it!
(obon dance music)
Dad...
Dad! Dad, wake up!
Dad!.... wake up!
What is it?
Hana's gone! Where's Hana?
Hana! Hana!
She's gone looking for Kozou!
- What shall we do!
I've no idea where she is!
Dad!
I'll go to the cotton factory.
Ine...
I'm going to the factory.
Why?
They'll advance me on my wages.
And we can use the money to buy Kozou back.
Are you still on about that?
I've made up my mind.
Idiot!
I know you love that horse but...
What if the work makes you ill?
What will be will be.
I've made up my mind!
Ine! Ine!
Please don't do that!
Just calm down. Calm down!
I'm going to get a job!
You little brat I'm going
to beat some sense into you!
You...
You stubborn little bitch...
Don't worry. It's OK. It's OK.
I'm going. And that's that!
Come on!
Please take good care of her!
Take care, all of you!
See you later!
Ine, eat this. It's mochi
made in blessed water.
It'll stop your stomach getting upset.
Take care of yourself! Yes, take care!
I'm fine. Don't worry. I'll be able
to ride to collect you next o-bon!
OK I'm off. See you!
Sings FURUSATO
Those hills where I chased rabbits
and by the brook where I fished
I recall these in my dreams,
oh my home town how could I forget you?
Grave marker for Grandma
How could I forget you, oh my hometown?_
Funeral tablet.
This is Grandma's first o-bon.
And she was so well.
She even promised to ride a horse to come
and meet you on your return this o-Bon.
I''m going to pop in somewhere on the way.
Are you going to the dance tonight?
Yes, I'm going.
Hana, there you are!
I've brought something nice for you!
Where's Kozou?
Wow, is that you?
Are you really that little Kozou?
Wow!
What a beautiful horse you've become!
Hey! You!!
What?
You're supposed to be back at the cotton factory!
Oh!
Have you quit your job?
No, I haven't.
You don't understand what calamity
you will bring on your family...
If you don't return and your father
is held responsible for the debt.
You need to think carefully.
I'll go back to the factory.
But I want to stay here another week.
There you go again! But sensei
has told you and we've told you...
I don't want you here any more.
Get out!
I said get out!
Just a moment!
Why do you want a week?
I want to say goodbye to Kozou.
He'll be sold at
the horse market in a week.
I see. Mr Onoda, I'm sorry to pry
but is all the money for the horse...
Is it going to be paid to you?
Yes, it is.
The foal is mine.
Won't that money
solve your problems?
No!
At first I thought so but...
There are quite a few
other debts that I have to pay.
Sensei...
I...
With the money from selling Kozou...
Just maybe those debts...
Colt market for cavalry, farm or heavy work
Hey, hey.
Hey!
What?
How much do you think we'll get?
Well, not less than 400 yen.
I wonder if we might get 500.
If we were able to sell him for 500
Ine wouldn't have to go back
to the factory.
(prices being called)
and another 50 is 350.
50, 50.
Please take care of him.
352, 353.... 355 yen.
If there are no further bids,
going at 355 yen...
I don't like to see your tears.
Wipe your face!
Next horse please! Quickly!
Let's go look at the auction. OK?
Number 46, quickly please!
Military approved.
I'll start the bidding at 300, 300 yen.
300!
You're expensive!
Come along. Place your bids.
He's a lovely horse.
300.
300! Am I bid 300?
305!
and 5... and 5, 320
and 25!
300+25= 325
300 + 35, 335 yen
60!
and 1... 367 ... and 1... 368
And another
380, I have 380
150 What? That makes it 450.
I said 150.
What on earth are you on about.
The bid is 380.
Oh! I thought it was just at 80.
What an idiot.
380, 380
380, 380...
Any further bids?
For 380, 380
380 and at 380... for 380...
Come on! Bid higher!
Higher! Come on!
Hang on, here's a new bid.
380 and...?
85, plus 85. 385
395...
400!
400 and 5 ... 405
550 yen.
What? But we're bidding at 450...
I say 550 yen!
Understood!
550, 550.
No way. No.
No. No.
So at 550 yen for the military purchasers...
Wow! Wow!
Amazing!
That's great!
I'm so pleased!
I'm really pleased!
Thanks for coming to see us off,
but you should go home now.
OK, but Kozou's leaving us...
Work hard! Take care!
Ine!
Let's go!
Let's raise a horse
for the military next year too!
Yes, yes. Ine, you don't need
to go back to the factory.
Quiet! Don't speak!
The End