Go away!
CJ Entertainment
presents
a You Cinema production
executive producer
Lee Kang-bok
produced by
Yoo Hee-sook
starring
Lee Eun-joo
and
Jeong Joon-ho
UNBORN BUT UNFORGOTTEN
associate producer Suk Dong-joon
screenplay Han Hyun-geun
lighting directors
Bak Hee-joo _lm Jae-gook
editor
Gyung Min-ho
directed by
lm Chang-jae
What these people
wanted was time.
Those of you out there,
I'd like for you to think about
the amount of spare time
you have in your lives.
I'll see you again next week.
Good-bye.
Good work everyone.
You did great today.
So what's the topic
for next week?
We have on ready,
but it's a bit complicated.
How about dinner?
I already have an appointment,
so maybe next time.
I talked to the station chief,
and he seemed interested.
Really?
I hope I'm not being
too much of a burden.
Not at all.
If things work out,
it could turn out well.
But I want to
finish it on my own.
You should've bought the CD.
It's obsolete,
and I barely got a copy of it.
I think I'm pregnant.
Are you sure?
Was it on that day
that worried you?
Soo-jin,
how about you get some rest?
Resting won't matter.
I'll take care of it on my own.
Sir, here's what you asked for.
Right, thanks.
When did you get here?
Why couldn't I
reach you last night?
I called so many times
about today's shoot.
Sorry.
I was out drinking all night
with my friends.
What's that on the screen?
Is it a suicide site?
Oh, this?
It's nothing special.
You transferred from violent
crimes to cyber-investigation.
Are you more satisfied now?
Well, no matter what department,
I'm always catching criminals,
So I think
nothing differently of it.
What's the case about?
Which case?
The one you were looking at.
I better go.
- Officer Ju, I'll be back.
- Okay.
- Going somewhere?
- Pardon?
Remember, we agreed for me
to follow you all day today.
Seems as if the uterus expanded
and pressured the bowels.
See here how the pelvis widened,
and smashed into the bowels?
But the belly doesn't
swell down this easily.
I think it's very strange.
But she was definitely
ready to give birth.
So are there any signs
that she did?
I can't be sure of it right now.
But I plan to conduct another
thorough examination today.
Do you feel better?
What a strange case.
The site I'm investigating
has a very strange homepage.
Think it has anything to do
with her death?
Well, I'm not exactly sure.
But I think it's
related to her death.
Do you have any suspects?
I'll have to investigate further.
She wasn't pregnant.
We lived together
until two weeks ago.
And there was nothing strange
about her body.
We went to the
public bath together.
So when did she move in
to that apartment?
About two weeks ago.
There must be some reason
why she moved there.
Was there anything you
heard or found strange?
After she looked at
something on the computer,
she turned as white as a ghost.
She said she was going to die.
I asked her why.
And she said
she saw herself dying.
What are you doing?
This place is great!
You can't tell who's who!
What's going on?
Somebody call an ambulance!
She's one of the girls
who said she saw herself die.
What's wrong with it?
This is the end.
I swear I saw her stomach
swollen up at the scene.
But it strangely turned fuzzy
on the screen.
Really?
Her autopsy results
fit with the other death.
Medical responses are clean.
But there are no clear signs
of external wounds.
That's strange.
Why are these
serial murders occurring?
Oh yeah, the air time
will be scheduled soon.
Is that so?
Wow, it makes me nervous
thinking this will be on TV.
Just a sec.
Hello?
Good.
When it's done,
we'll put it on Ei-suk's show.
On "Looking at the World"?
Why?
Don't like popular shows?
No, sir.
What's the title?
There's nothing definite yet.
But I'm thinking about
calling it "Cybercop, 25 hours".
Sounds good to me.
Let's go with that.
- Is there anything you need?
- No, sir.
Make it real fun.
Thank you, sir.
Aren't you scared
that a person died there?
Will it be as bad as the club?
Anyway,
it's all part of the job.
Won't have anything to shoot
since it's cleaned up.
But you never know.
Wow, making a documentary
sure isn't easy.
Soo-jin.
I have to go ask something,
so please wait here.
So many people
moved in and out of that place.
They said they heard
strange noises at night.
Now that someone died there,
who'd want to move in there?
Gynecology Clinic
Mari Women's Clinic
When was it open?
Lm Su-young's Women's Clinic?
But this address
is for Mari Women's Clinic.
Know where that
record I mentioned is?
Oh that.
It'll be hard to find here.
I'm sorry.
This album was hard to find.
I hope it can be
of some comfort.
Han Soo-jin
Seoul, Shindang District, 35-1
Hello?
It's me, Choi Jin-suk.
Is something wrong?
It's nothing.
So why did you call?
You've clicked on that site,
haven't you?
Pardon?
We need to meet and talk.
Until now, all the victims
have clicked on this site.
You're saying that anyone
who clicks on it dies?
That's it.
After I clicked on it...
Don't!
If I click here,
the main site pops up.
Shall I not?
I swear it was there before.
If what I saw was real...
What was in there?
It was like a very
bright white room.
This picture...
It looks like the portrait
in that apartment.
Detective Choi,
what brings you here?
How have you been?
I came to see
the server operator.
Has there been another ICD
problem with that closed site?
Not that I know of.
I guess
someone else is using it.
- Really?
- Maybe so.
I'll see you later.
It's strange.
I swear I erased it earlier.
Now it's been erased.
Look at that!
What's happening?
Is something bothering you?
Nothing really.
I think the captain is
trying to tell me something.
Tell you what?
You know,
that ghost site case.
It's been handed over
to violent crimes.
He's probably implying
that I take my hands off.
How long have you
been on the force?
Pardon?
Think a detective
chases the criminal?
This may sound strange.
I've always been
chasing criminals until now,
but this case feels like
it's drawing me in this time.
Don't worry.
I'll handle it on my own.
Jung Ei-suk speaking.
Yes, sir.
Yes, I understand.
I'll come right up.
Until the rumors settle down,
the two of you be careful.
Since I don't want
to see Soo-jin get fired.
I'll solve it on my own, sir.
Soo-jin.
Know why you were
reprimanded before?
How long do we have to hide
from everybody?
The news anchor position
will be mine soon.
Just wait a little longer.
But...
Wouldn't it better to
bring it out in the open now?
Be a little more patient.
You can do that, right?
Was it your idea that
I get taken off your show?
The reason why
you couldn't get on it
was because people
would talk behind your back.
I'd never request such a thing.
Because I love you.
You trust me, right?
Say something.
Yes.
I trust you.
She said she was going to die.
I asked her why.
And she said
she saw herself dying.
That Mrs. Oh Young-ae
who lives upstairs
has clicked on that site before.
But strangely enough,
I heard she wanted
to move in to room 1308.
Most people would stay away
from a place someone died in,
but she's the opposite.
Who are you?
Hello.
I saw you once downstairs.
Do you remember me?
I came because I have
some things to ask you.
Come in.
You know about the
Mari Women's Clinic site, right?
People who clicked on it died.
So why are you here?
You clicked on it recently,
haven't you?
So you think maybe
I'm the one who made it, right?
Since I'm still alive?
It's not me.
I know you tried to
move in to room 1308.
The only reason why
was because it was vacant.
The power of a strong curse
is flowing all the way to here.
It's passing on to me.
Sounds like it's coming
from the pipes.
That would be a relief.
What were you looking for
by clicking on to that site?
After I logged on,
I felt something strange.
A feeling mixed
with hatred and sadness.
Felt like it was
trying to say something.
One thing is certain.
The hatred gradually
became stronger.
That portrait.
It's the site's background.
It all happened 15 days later.
17th, Han Soo-jin
31 st
Did you meet Oh Young-ae?
She tried to say something,
but I'm not sure what it was.
Soo-jin.
Yes.
All the victims died 15 days
after they clicked on the site.
It's now been a week
since you logged on.
So a week later, I...
Stay strong, Soo-jin.
I'm going to move
in to that apartment.
She kept insisting on
moving in to room 1308.
You don't see anything, right?
Doctor,
please check once more.
I'm sure something is in there.
If people are
oversensitive or stressed,
they tend to be confused.
I'm sorry,
but can I try it?
Doctor.
It's there.
It's there, doctor!
I just saw it.
I even heard
it's heart beating.
It's probably
because you're tired.
Eat well and rest for a while.
I'm telling you I saw it
with my own eyes!
Please calm down.
It's okay.
Are you crazy?
How about going home now?
I didn't come here
on my own will.
I feel like something
drew me here.
Aren't you scared?
I can handle it.
If there's a way to live.
What should I do now?
Just rest.
Is somebody there?
- Who are you?
- Please put that away.
Are you a tenant?
Yes.
Aren't you scared
to be here as a woman?
I thought I heard something.
Well, I didn't hear anything.
Looks like room 1308's tenant
hasn't picked up her stuff yet.
Sunyoung Art Instiute
I'm sure it's
Yoo-shil's self-portrait.
Is there any way to find her?
Yoo-shil was a very gifted girl.
Winning a prize at the teen art
competition is an amazing feat.
Being an orphan
and a bit autistic,
all she was
interested in was art.
Where is she now?
It's been a long time
since we've spoken.
So then...
Yoo-shil's friend
was my daughter, In-mee.
They were very close.
She might know
what happened to Yoo-shil.
Miss Ahn In-mee?
You're Yoo-shil's friend, right?
- I have some questions.
- I don't know anything.
I need to know
what happened to Yoo-shil.
What for?
My life is in danger.
If Yoo-shil falls for something,
then she can't separate from it.
She'd stay up
for several days painting.
She gets really attached
to something she likes.
But when she started dating,
she often postponed her work.
Who was the guy?
She didn't tell me.
She painted this picture
to give to him.
She was so crazy about him.
He probably told her
to have an abortion.
Even though I did the same,
she said she
wanted to have the baby.
Then one day I got
a call from the hospital.
They said Yoo-shil needed
someone to take care of her.
I thought she'd lock herself up
in her place, so I visited her.
But she wasn't there.
So then Yoo-shil...
This is Yoo-shil's last present
she sent to me.
Now it's only a relic.
Where was the hospital
she checked in to?
Was it Mari Women's Clinic?
When I was opening this clinic,
I hired the nurse
who worked here before,
but she had quit.
I think she went
to another hospital.
She was pregnant
for eight months.
It was probably that long.
It seemed premature.
Enough for it to be
dangerous to give birth.
She only had two months left
till her delivery.
Oh yeah, there was
a bruise on her abdomen.
If she hadn't been treated,
then it would've been
very dangerous for her.
But she insisted
on having the baby.
Was anybody with her?
She had a friend with her.
It was pouring hard that day,
but I remember her
because she was so strange.
What was strange about her?
The child died.
When we conducted the surgery,
it was already dead.
But she wanted the remains.
She insisted on it persistently,
so we gave it to her.
The girl who painted
that self-portrait.
She went to the same hospital
as the other victims.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm okay.
What in the world
is behind that site?
I think it's a message
sent by someone.
I'm looking for the person
who's operating that site.
I think that's the most
crucial thing right now.
Even if there is someone,
he or she is being
ordered by a spirit.
That's a common statement
mentally-ill criminals say.
- "Someone told me to."
- People believe that what
they can't see doesn't exist.
But we can even feel
the air invisible to us.
Air is something
that can be proven.
But that spirit
is something that can't.
I don't believe in God,
but I do believe in spirits.
That's my belief in life.
You said you saw
yourself die, right?
Soo-jin,
is it true that you're pregnant?
Can you explain this?
This company doesn't need
to know about my private life.
Just answer the question.
Is it true about you two?
Sir, we told you it wasn't.
You keep quiet.
Whether it's true or not
is my problem.
It has nothing to do
with this company.
Give me time.
So are you going to
announce your marriage?
I'm not planning to marry,
and I'm not in
the position to do so.
You're better off
asking Ei-suk.
Soo-jin.
This has to be solved somehow.
If a scandal like this gets out,
this will look bad on us.
I'll talk to the people upstairs,
and give you three days.
Until then,
I trust you'll solve it, Soo-jin.
I really don't get your attitude.
Have you ever tried to?
Know how scared
and desperate I am?
Your baby is
growing in my belly,
and I can't just do anything
to this baby.
You had a chance to solve it,
but why didn't you?
Your idea of solving
it is useless now.
It's me who can't now!
That general manager
is ruthless.
You should've denied it.
I told you to say
what we talked about.
I didn't want to lie
disgracefully like that.
Think that innocent way
of thinking will work?
Why'd you make
things complicated?
If it doesn't work out,
I'm through.
How could you say that
when I might die?
If I lose that anchor spot,
that's just like dying.
I'm not done with you yet.
How'd you get into this place?
It's related to that case.
How the hell does
that matter to us?
One of the victims
died in this apartment.
So we came to a
place someone died in?
- Let's go.
- No, I can't leave!
Where did you
get that painting?
It was here before.
What are you doing?
I don't like how
this painting looks.
- Throw it away!
- No, just leave it!
Think it'll comfort her?
A spirit knows the
minds of the living.
She's probably
resting in peace now.
Officer Ju.
Can you make out this picture?
Over here.
Well, I'm not quite sure.
I guess it's all over, right?
What are you keep looking at?
Can you make out this picture?
Of what?
Well...
I'm not too sure.
If we ask In-mee,
she might know.
Her phone's not working.
It wasn't over.
I guess I'm next.
I've abandoned you already,
but if you were born
inside of me again,
I would be so happy.
Finding comfort wasn't
the only thing you wanted.
An amulet to fight off all evil
You wanted to be born again,
and be loved instead.
Ahn In-mee
Can you check this part?
Can you turn off the lights?
See this skull?
This painting is called
"Holbein's Ambassadors."
If you twist the
figure's angle like this,
a very unfamiliar and distorted
image appears.
Can it be a clue?
I hope so.
It's been a while
since I used this program.
It looks like a person's face.
Doesn't he look familiar?
Really?
Think sorry is enough?
Why'd you screw around
in the first place?
I'll take care of it soon.
This isn't just
a personal matter, you idiot!
Get out.
Until now,
I thought about how I'll die.
I'm going to die
like the rest of them.
I was so scared,
I had forgotten about
the baby that was in me.
I must not have what it takes
to be a genuine woman.
The baby that was mine.
My irresponsible self who
couldn't be responsible for it.
I can't even forgive myself.
If I could,
that cute baby,
the baby I threw away,
I'd like to have it.
I want to have it and love it.
I need Cho Yoo-shil's diagnosis
sheet when she checked in.
I think it's a crucial clue
to this case.
I need to know
her boyfriend's name.
Please, Nurse Jung.
Hello?
Hello, Miss Jung?
Pretty and nice.
This is probably
what everyone wants.
But in my opinion,
I wish we could all do
the best at what we do.
Thanks for watching
"Looking at the World".
In return for all
your encouragement,
I'll repay you with a more
invigorating and fair show.
Thank you.
Ei-suk?
What the hell
are you doing here?
What are you doing, huh?
It's not too late.
Let's go to the hospital, okay?
There's no use.
You have to
get rid of the baby.
I just got my last warning
from the station.
Do you want to ruin my life?
Don't come any closer.
What's all this?
Why do you need it?
Why are you trying
to ruin my life, too?
Why?
Why? Why?
Why are you doing this to me?
Die!
It was you?
Yoo-shil's boyfriend was you?
Thought you could hold on
to me because of that kid?
It's your kid.
Don't talk like that!
My kid?
Fine.
I'll have to check for myself.
What are you doing?
This isn't happening.
This is impossible!
Soo-jin!
Soo-jin, wake up.
The baby...
Where's my baby?
- Baby?
- My baby...
Soo-jin, there's no baby.
Please calm down.
I heard it for sure.
A baby crying.
I bore it.
I'm telling you I bore it.
I'm sure I bore it.
What are you talking about?
I bore it.
I'm sure I did.
I'm sure.
I'm sure I bore it.
Where's my baby?
Who?
Mister.
Can you buy me a drink?