Daddy William!
Don't let them take you away!
Momma needs you, we need you.
Now go home, child.
Ain't nothing you can do.
I belong to Legree now.
When you coming home?
Never, child!
Now you go home,
tell your mama I love her,
and you, too.
Now get!
Now that's a fine young filly.
Let her be.
Now why should I do that, boy?
Run, child!
Not if you wanna live, nigger.
Daddy!
Hey, boy, I'm gonna fuck your daughter!
Don't let them hurt me!
He gets all the fun.
Let's move them out.
He can catch up later.
Come on, nigger.
Hey, get up there.
Move.
Move!
No!
My land, childrens,
ain't they any other place
for y'all to sit except on the stairs?
Morning, Eliza.
I see you're busy already.
Master going out?
- These aren't Master Shelby's
boots, they belong to the guest.
Guest?
Ain't nobody told me about no guest,
that's for sure certain, and Mr. Shelby
always tells me when they's company.
Well, his boots are here.
May I come in, sir?
- Yes.
I brought your boots, sir.
All right.
Help me on with them.
What's your name?
Eliza, sir.
You've done a
good job on them, Eliza.
Thank you, sir.
Are you always so shy?
Is anything wrong?
No, sir.
You have a man, Eliza?
Oh, yes, sir.
I should think so.
He's a lucky man, you're very pretty.
I suppose he'd like to marry you.
We are married, sir.
That's nice.
- Only I don't live with him.
Our neighbor's his master.
He's hired at the hemp mill.
So he works for old Mr. Wilson?
What's his name?
Harris, sir, Jim Harris.
Do you know him?
No.
Now can I go, please?
You're very pretty, Eliza.
How'd you like me to buy
you and take you home?
Are you afraid of me?
No, sir.
Or of the South, perhaps.
It's nice down there.
But I'm very
happy right here, sir.
Come back here later.
I won't do it.
Annie can just bring his water up to him.
I'm not going up there.
I'd rather throw myself in the river.
Child, you supposed to be a Christian.
Stop talking like that.
They want us all to be good Christians,
but they talk about it
one way and do us another.
What's got into you, Eliza, honey?
You look like you seen the ole
devil himself this morning.
I never gave thought to
what the devil looks like,
but I bet he looks a
powerful lot like him.
You wanna see me, Mr. Morrison?
You think I rode 10
miles for the fun of it?
Where's Harris?
What do you want with him?
Is it all right with you, Wilson,
if I sell my own slave?
Does it have to be Harris?
He's the best man I hired from you.
I know what I'm doing,
Wilson, so don't butt in.
But you'll want to see this
machine he built over here.
He invented it himself.
It does the work of six slaves.
I don't know anything about machines
and I don't wanna.
I'd rather use slaves,
they don't get rusty.
That's all I need, ain't it,
for some uppity nigger to
start inventing things?
You keep your place, hear?
You have no right
to do that, Mr. Morrison.
I didn't rent you any brains, Wilson,
just a pair of arms.
I asked for good
workers, and I got them.
He's the best man I have.
Don't take him away, I'll buy him myself.
Legree's my friend, he
paid a good price for him.
He'll teach him what it means to work.
Go on, inventor.
Get moving!
Don't take him away
from me, Mr. Morrison.
I'll pay more than you're
getting from Mr. Legree.
Forget it, Wilson, he's going to Legree.
I can do what I want with my own property.
I'll pay you $1,000 for him.
Nothing doing, I told you, he's sold.
1,500, Mr. Morrison.
2,000!
You'll never see him again.
Run!
Tomorrow, there'll be a reward notice
on every tree from here to Kentucky!
Have you been comfortable
with us, Mr. Legree?
Now that business is out
of the way, yes, ma'am.
Where's your son?
What's his name again?
George.
Please?
- Oh, thank you.
He knows I hate unpunctuality.
He's probably with Uncle Tom.
He can look at a watch,
can't he, wherever he is.
Well, time's not
important when you're young.
He'll be old enough
for college next year.
College, that'll be
pretty expensive, won't it?
Well, with a big,
beautiful estate like this,
you can afford it, I guess, hmm?
With plenty of hard work, Mr. Legree.
How well I know, madam.
I've a plantation of my own down river.
Down river?
Near Natchez, ma'am.
1,000 acres of long staple cotton.
That's the only crop you can make money on
because of the climate.
Swamp fever.
We lose a lot of slaves.
But that's life there.
Excuse us, please, for being late.
We were listening to the singing.
I don't believe you've met
the children yet, Mr. Legree.
This is our Virginia.
The reports didn't do
you justice, young lady.
How do you do?
May I offer my congratulations?
How do you do, sir?
Did you enjoy the spirituals?
Yes, it was just lovely.
They like to sing.
Good thing, too, helps my business.
It helps them work harder, is that it?
Naturally there's more
profit in a happy nigger.
For instance, take this case
I heard of the other day.
There was this man, trader I know,
bought a woman with a child,
but he didn't have any use for the baby,
so he sold it.
Stupid thing to do.
The mother killed herself.
$1,000 wasted through mismanagement.
The baby always goes with his
mother, that's what I say.
It's just awful, isn't it?
What can you do?
The man had a law on his side.
Laws like that should be abolished.
You planning to be a lawyer, boy?
I haven't decided on a career.
I do know what I don't wanna be, however.
What's that, young fella?
A slave trader, Mr. Legree.
- George!
A slave trader has to earn his living,
just like everybody else.
Aren't there other ways?
I guess that depends.
You're young, you're nice and gentle.
So, for you, life should
be easy and beautiful,
like yourself.
As his life is ugly.
George, how dare you.
Apologize, do you hear?
I'm sorry, Father, but I
will not apologize to him.
George.
Come back at once!
- Go after him, dear.
Do you think I should?
Certainly, my child, go ahead.
Going away to college
might do him some good.
Nice evening.
Well, I won't stay any longer.
Master, made him my master.
What right does he have to own me?
I'm a man just like he is.
I'm not some kind of
a machine or an animal
to be bought and abused and sold.
I'll never be an animal again.
What will you do?
I don't know, go to Canada.
They're good people there.
No slaves, only freemen.
I'll make lots of dollars,
I'll make thousands and
thousands of dollars.
I'll buy you both back.
Yes, you and the baby, too.
Be careful, Harris, you're hurt,
and it's so cold and the river's frozen.
Don't worry about me.
I'll come back for you.
I'll be all right.
Take care of yourself.
- I have to go now,
I have to run before
Morrison gets after me.
I'll wait for you forever.
Forever.
No, Mr. Shelby
wouldn't say that.
Shelby wouldn't do that.
They said they wouldn't do that.
What y'all hanging 'round for?
Get to work.
There's a bad man with a scar
hanging around the place.
That's Mr. Legree, he's
a guest of the master.
That's just it, Mr. Shelby's
gonna sell some of us.
What you talking about?
That fellow Sambo who come with him...
- There's Mr. Shelby.
Morning, Mr. Shelby.
I'd like to talk to
you alone for a minute, Tom.
Yes, sir.
All right, get to
work, everybody, go on.
Go on, put your arms into it.
That Sambo of Mr. Legree,
he's started a lot of talk
about how you wanna sell some of us,
and they've gone half-crazy.
I beg of you, Tom,
please don't make things
any harder for me than they are.
Well, I'd never do that to you, sir.
Why, ever since we were little boys,
we been looking after one another.
Tom, suppose that
this isn't just a rumor,
that I've been obliged
to have sold some of you.
Then, then I knowed it
must be hard times for sure.
Why else would you be fixing to sell
any of us off the plantation?
I knowed lessen you had to,
you wouldn't never do nothing like that.
Where you going?
I'm getting my other shirt.
But, Tom, there's no
question of your going.
Why, you're as much a part
of the Shelby plantation
as I am myself.
All us is part of the Shelby plantation,
like one big ole family.
Mr. Shelby, if you are gonna sell anyone,
please, sir, I want you to sell me.
It say here in the Bible,
no one has greater love than this,
to lay down his life for a friend.
If you don't want me to do it for you,
then I'll do it for Master George, sir.
Don't listen to him, sir,
don't listen to what he says.
Please, sir, don't let him go away.
They ain't nothing about
going in the Bible.
Know what it says there?
Tom, stay where you at.
- The Bible don't say one word about that.
Then put it in!
What's the matter, George?
I'm gonna horsewhip Legree.
He's a guest, your
father will be disgraced.
He's already disgraced himself.
But I beg you, please,
don't start trouble.
Virginia, it's not a
question of starting trouble.
But I'm not gonna just be idle
while something like this
is happening to our people.
I must speak to George for a minute.
Will you excuse us, Virginia?
Have we anything left
to talk about, sir?
Yes, all the things I've
been keeping to myself
in order to spare your mother and you.
Does watching
our people being sold
like a bunch of animals
spare our feelings?
I've been doing everything I
possibly could to avoid this.
I've borrowed money
from all of my friends,
I've sold most of your mother's jewelry.
In heaven's name, what else could I do?
Stop being hypocritical.
How many times have you said you despise
slave traders like Simon Legree?
You're talking of things
you're too young to understand.
Too young?
Isn't it odd how that's
always the argument
when you know that I'm in the right?
George, I will overlook
your lack of respect
under the circumstances.
I even understand how you feel.
It affects you just as it does me.
Those are the ones
who are affected by it,
those people out there.
Come here and look at them.
Hey, man, go on, move.
See what they're doing?
They're lining them all up.
They're being herded like animals.
Unfortunately, he has the right
to choose the ones he wants.
And if Uncle Tom is chosen?
I've been talking to Uncle Tom.
He has to be one of the
people who...
The sheriff.
I'm sure it'll serve its purpose.
You're free, Eliza.
I always felt like I was free
with you folks, Miss Shelby.
That's not the way they do things
in the world outside now, Eliza.
And don't forget, for little Harry,
this document I gave you is useless.
You have to be very careful.
He belongs to Mr. Legree
in the eyes of the law.
You could be accused of
kidnapping your own child.
I haven't much money.
Here, Eliza.
Here, here's $20.
- Oh, no.
I saved every cent of
the money you gave me.
I don't need anymore.
- Go on, take the money,
Eliza, you're sure to need
it before you're through.
Tell old Jim to harness the
fastest horse in the stable.
Just leave him at the ferry.
How can I ever thank you?
Write me when you've
found your husband and you're safe.
And now you better hurry up.
Mr. Legree's a very dangerous man.
Go on, get in the wagon.
Sit here.
Gimme your ankle.
Number eight.
Get in the wagon.
Nine.
Over here.
Where's number 10?
Get in.
Who's that, sir?
The child, the maid's little boy.
What's her name, Eliza?
We've been looking for them.
Nobody's seen her or the boy, sir.
Where's the child?
Eliza and the child are both gone.
We've looked over the whole plantation.
Where have they gone?
You could ask Mrs. Shelby.
Eliza belongs to her.
It's important.
I don't understand
how you can ask me to.
I was under the impression
I was dealing with a gentleman.
What do you mean by that, sir?
The child Harry's vanished.
The terms of our agreement
gave me the right.
He's undoubtedly with his mother.
- And where's the mother?
Someplace in the woods,
I should think.
In the woods?
Woods, yes.
At least, I think that's where she is.
She's gathering mushrooms.
Where is the boy?
That, you must ask
his mother, I'm afraid.
You helped them to escape, of course.
Sir, how dare you address my wife
in that tone of voice!
- Do you think I'm so easily fooled?
Mr. Legree!
- Let me tell you this...
I give you my word of honor, sir.
I have no idea where those two have gone.
I'm not impressed.
What about horses, have you horses ready?
We'll be glad to arrange
for horses, Mr. Legree.
Thank you.
And you want the
horses saddled for you
right after you finish dinner?
No, thanks, before dinner.
If that man ever comes
into my house again...
Give him the oldest,
slowest ones we have.
Nice, slow ones.
Which way we go now?
That's a better road,
but this one's shorter.
You go that way!
Here, take us across.
We've got to cross right away.
Impossible, the ferry's not running.
Well, isn't there some other boat then?
The river's full of ice.
You can't get across.
But I must.
You're mad!
Stay here, you can't get across there!
Seen anybody come by here?
Nobody.
What's this wagon here?
Must've come unhitched somewhere.
Are you out of your mind?
She's not my property.
But they're getting away.
If you kill her it'll cost me $1,000,
and you'll be a murderer.
Yes, but, Mr. Legree, I thought...
Think with what, you idiot?
Come on, your black brothers
are there waiting for you.
If you're black, nothing
you do for him is right.
Hold it.
He's gonna go right on
hitting you if you don't talk.
You better tell me where that
no-good brother of yours is.
Hello, Morrison.
I've come to fetch Harris.
You can put him in there.
No, I can't, he's run away.
You must be joking!
I wish I was.
I've got his sister there, though.
I'll beat it out of her where he is.
- His sister?
And I had my troubles today
with his wife and son.
I might just as well see what the rest
of the family looks like.
She's a pretty one.
What's her name?
Casey.
Pretty name, Casey.
How'd you like to come with
me in place of your brother?
Know how to cook?
Good, I'll take her with me.
You got the best of our deal, Morrison.
You're getting off easy.
Well, what's a few
dollars between old friends?
Have a good trip.
Get out, get out, come on.
All right, get in line.
Come on, old man.
You, too.
Come.
Go on, gal.
Get going down there.
Go on!
- Poor Casey.
Shut your mouth, go on.
Good day, Mr. Legree.
Come on, get a move on.
Boat won't wait for you.
Captain, nearly ready, sir.
Take the lap first.
We'll hit the currents on our way.
Aye aye, sir.
- Carry on.
Hurry up with that loading, there!
Look out for the lambs there.
Come on, old man, stop gawking.
Get a move on.
Why do they put all those
men in chains, father?
Are they criminals?
No, it's not that.
They're slaves and their
owners have chained them.
But why must they be chained?
Well, because some owners
are wicked and cruel.
Come, come.
Hurry up, keep moving.
Don't fall asleep there,
you can sleep later.
Go on, move, hurry up!
Get in there.
How do you like it here?
Here.
Actually, I bought these
things for Lucinda.
She's the singer in my hotel,
but you're much younger and prettier.
There, choose what you like.
It's all yours.
Take a look in the mirror.
Here's something else.
Wanna smell it?
How do you like it?
Smells good, huh?
If you like, I'll make
a real lady out of you.
How can you make a real lady out of me?
I'm a negress.
Leave that to me.
What I say decides who's
a nigger and who isn't.
You, sit over there where you belong.
This man gave you
money for clothes for us.
What'd you do, drink it?
Mr. Legree got all kind
of clothes on the plantation
off all the slaves that died.
Get out, what is this a funeral?
What do you think they're all
saying about you up there?
If you behave yourselves,
you'll be treated well,
and, if not, look out.
Do we understand each other?
Well, answer.
Yes, sir.
- All right.
Now, let's hear you sing a song.
Sing whatever you want to,
sing one of those spirituals.
All right?
Why don't you sing?
Sing, I said.
Excuse me.
Did y'all like it, Miss?
Yes, your singing was very beautiful.
Why must you wear these?
So we don't run away.
Well, I think it's awful.
Oh, that's how things is, child.
You better go now, before
you get some trouble
for coming down here.
Will you let me visit you again?
If your mother says you can.
Oh, she's at home, but my
father lets me do anything.
Does he?
Oh, I'm glad you came, Father.
Please, break off these chains.
I can't do that, dear,
I'm not their owner.
Who is?
First, my Lord, then Mr. Legree.
Well, I'll talk with the Lord.
And my father will speak
to Mr. Legree.
My name's Evangeline.
But they all call me Eva.
And I'm Thomas, but
they calls me Uncle Tom.
You must call me Uncle Tom, too.
All right, Uncle Tom.
I'm going, but I'll see you
again tomorrow. Bye.
Good day.
Excuse me, sir.
Do you own those people downstairs?
I own them, yes.
Why must you eat alone?
I prefer to eat alone.
It gives me time to...
I must ask you to forgive her
for disturbing you, sir, but...
Not at all.
It was a great pleasure to make
your daughter's acquaintance,
Mr. Saint-Claire.
You know my name.
Yes, we're practically neighbors.
I own a plantation down in the Bottoms
and then, some time ago,
I bought the tavern,
so I know most of the townspeople,
by sight, at least.
If there's any way that I can
be of any service to you...
No, thank you. I don't think
there's any likelihood of
the occasion arising for
us to do business together.
But, Father, you
could do business with him.
You can buy all those slaves
and take off their chains.
Sorry, dear, you see, I can't buy
all the slaves in the world, even for you.
But at least buy Uncle Tom.
Excuse us.
Brought this food for you.
Here.
Tomorrow, I'll eat with you in the cabin.
Looks like the fine, respectable people
on board this boat don't
exactly approve of me.
You know why they don't?
Because of you!
Did you hear what I said,
did you understand me?
Answer me when I'm talking to you!
Folks here don't like
you, and it's my fault.
That's better.
How come you didn't put these on?
Aren't they good enough for you
or are they too good?
Take off those rags.
Casey,
take that thing off.
Do as I tell you.
Drink.
Didn't you like our song this morning?
No, because this time
it's a goodbye song.
I'll think of you when I
sings that song, Miss Eva.
And when I do, you'll feel it,
and then our thoughts
will be together again.
But I'd like to keep
you with me all the time.
And then maybe you could
be happy again, Uncle Tom.
I've felt very happy
while we's on the river
In the morning, when
it's time to get off,
Mr. Legree will put you
all back in chains again,
and it makes me even sadder.
Oh, Uncle Tom!
Why aren't you eating?
Go ahead and eat.
Your friends won't starve.
That would be foolish.
You can't get any work out
of them if they're not fed.
Ah, well, young lady,
what brings you here?
Is this Mrs. Legree?
Well, suppose she is, what then?
Then I would like something from her.
Please, would you give me
Uncle Tom as a present?
Ah, Uncle Tom.
Can I have him then?
A present?
No, I'm afraid not.
Can I buy him from you?
You couldn't pay
what Uncle Tom is worth.
Why don't you?
You know he's a very old man.
He won't be much good on the plantation.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
He may be old, but he's strong as an ox.
Uncle Tom isn't an ox.
Besides, he made me a baby doll.
Man overboard, Napoleon.
Accident?
- No, he jumped.
Whatever is the matter?
Leave me alone.
But your leg, it's wounded.
I don't need nobody help.
You can't stay here, it isn't safe.
No.
Then you'll die.
Don't need nobody help.
Wait.
Please.
Giddy-up.
Gotta get away from here.
Gotta get away!
Away from here.
Sit there.
Well, come on.
What you looking at, boy?
Find out what the lady wants.
Bring me a beer.
Nothing, thank you.
Why don't you want a drink?
Cause they're all staring at you?
Does it annoy you?
It doesn't bother me a bit.
Then why aren't you drinking?
I wanna get that dress, I told you.
Haven't you got enough already?
Did you promise it to me or didn't you?
There.
But hurry.
- Thank you.
There she is again!
Dressed up like a circus horse.
Excuse me.
Henry!
Legree's got his nerve, ain't he?
Well, I'll say one thing for him,
he sure picked a pretty one.
Where is she?
Casey, you're here.
I came as soon as I could.
Were you worried?
Lonesome mostly.
I've good news for you.
Harris sent word he's coming.
He is?
Eliza, he's free, and Mr. Wilson
has paid him for that invention.
Harris knows then, about you
taking his place and being here?
Yes, he does, now you can't stay here.
Where else is there?
Somewhere that Simon
Legree would never dream
that you were hiding,
with him, in the same house.
He'll never look for you
there, that's for sure.
All right?
And I'll come back in a
couple of days to get you.
Oh, Casey!
- Everything's gonna be
all right now, Eliza, you'll see.
It happened about two years ago.
Poor Jed got caught in one of
them freak lightning storms.
I wouldn't believe he was dead at first.
Then after a while, I just felt nothing.
So I took this job teaching,
and I've been living in this big house
all alone ever since.
What about you?
Where'd you get the name Napoleon?
I'll bet I know.
Your ma wanted you to
be important someday,
so she named you after a famous general.
A man as big and strong as you
will get to be important someday, I know,
especially reading and writing
the way your friend Tom taught you.
My leg's getting better now.
I gotta be going.
They're gonna be looking
everywhere for me.
You can stay, they won't look here.
Simon Legree's men were
in town the other day,
and I heard one of them
say you must've gone north.
They won't find you here.
I'm a slave.
I belong to Legree.
I don't know why you're
taking these chances, but...
I don't want anything
to happen to you,
not on account of me.
But I don't want you to go.
You're the first good
thing that's happened to me
in an awful long time.
With you here, I find myself smiling,
listening for the birds,
watching the flowers,
becoming aware of all the beauty in life
instead of that ugly,
dreary existence I had.
Please, stay.
Tell me you feel something for me, too.
Ma'am?
My name is Melissa.
Say it.
Melissa.
That wasn't so hard, was it?
You're a kind person.
I got feelings for you like
I ain't never had before.
But they's wrong.
You're white and I'm black,
and they won't let us have these feelings.
It don't matter none what we want.
Why can't they leave people be?
It isn't fair!
Everyone should be equal.
There shouldn't be this color barrier.
Why won't they let us live in peace?
Napoleon...
I need you.
I need you to hold me,
to need me,
to love me.
I don't care about anyone else.
Napoleon?
Are you all right?
I don't know what I'd do if
anything happened to you.
I had a beautiful dream.
We were in Paris, and
everybody accepted us.
Wasn't no color barrier.
We were so happy and peaceful.
No one to bother us.
Maybe it could happen.
Maybe.
Napoleon, tell me it could happen.
I'm so scared.
Dear, Miss Melissa.
Sometimes I don't say things
too well, but I will try.
I guess I love you cause, I don't know,
I never loved anyone before,
except my ma and pa.
You are the nicest
person I have ever known.
Maybe someday your dream will come true.
I hope so.
But right now, I can
only bring you trouble,
and I don't ever want to hurt you.
I hope you will find happiness,
and that you will think of me always.
I know...
I will never forget you.
Love, Napoleon.
Well, looky here.
If it ain't my old friend Napoleon.
Where you been, boy?
Here, boys.
I want you to meet Mr.
Legree's fucking nigger.
That ought to teach you, boy.
Want us to cut his balls off?
Nah, Mr. Legree wants
to make an example of him.
Too many of them other niggers
thinking about escaping.
We gonna do something
real special to this one.
This motherfucker cunt, he's gonna pay.
If we ain't a-gonna kill him,
maybe we can have a little fun first.
I ain't said we ain't gonna kill him.
We just gonna make it interesting.
Now, you boys can have
all the fun you want,
but for your sake, I just hope
you don't catch nothing from this nigger.
Couldn't be nothing worse
than we got from those sheep.
Shit, that tar's blacker
than the nigger.
Well, it looks like
the soup's about ready.
I ain't never seen
nothing like that before.
I heard about it once.
Tore the skin right off,
just like being burnt alive.
Well, boy, how you feel now?
You know, I was always your friend,
and as long as you done your work,
I ain't never hit you much.
Tell Legree to fuck himself!
That wasn't nice, boy.
Now I guess we gotta do what we gotta do.
Don't pass out now, boy.
The best is yet to come.
Fuck you!
Crown the nigger boy.
He's coming, he
mustn't find out I've been away.
I know you doesn't cry, Harry.
What if he does, Casey,
what if somebody should come?
Here, take this.
Now, honey, you be quiet, hear?
Don't worry, nobody can get up here.
I took care of that.
10 new hands.
These ought a stop your complaints
about being so shorthanded.
Yes, sir, only yesterday,
we lost three more.
I guess they were so scared, hearing
the hounds coming after them,
that they ran for the swampy ground.
Idiot, we'll speak about this later.
I hope you all heard.
None of the three who tried it escaped.
Here, nobody gets away.
This isn't a showplace like
Saint-Claire's was, is it?
Go ahead and complain if you want.
Course, nobody will listen.
You can be as happy as
you like, it's your right.
Your only right.
Should I shut them up for you, boss?
No.
Don't you like music?
What brings you two here?
That man leading the singing,
didn't he belong to Pierre Saint-Claire?
I gotta have tea.
- Sambo, shut them up
and bed them down for the night.
Right, boss.
- Go ahead.
He could cause trouble you know.
He's always caused some trouble,
but what can he do out here?
I like the singing, it's pleasant.
Sit down.
What if he escapes?
Nobody's gotten away
from here alive yet.
John here hasn't been that lucky.
Last night, 15 got away.
And right before picking time!
Don't you have dogs and guards?
Sure.
We got back four of them.
And the rest?
They're hiding in the monastery.
About time we burned a
couple of their sheds again.
Seems they need another lesson.
The situation since then
has changed considerable.
The monks are getting help from the north.
Getting help?
Abolitionists.
And most of them are the
ones folks call Quakers.
Lot of do-gooders.
I seen them in Ohio.
Even so.
They can shoot.
- What?
Rabbits, huh?
They're peaceable, don't
hold with war or killing,
but some of them will kill when it comes
to defending something,
like right or justice.
Right, justice, what are they?
Words, just words, that's all.
I'd think things over.
An evening full of surprises.
What's the occasion, come in.
Read it yourself.
What, about the
committee they're sending?
We know that.
You don't know nothing.
Lincoln has won, he's gonna be president.
This some kind of joke?
By a slim majority, but he won.
Well, gentlemen, now what?
Succession, what else?
Lincoln will keep his campaign promises
and free the slaves.
It'll give him five
million more supporters.
It's going to cost us dearly, gentlemen.
Not my slaves, Mr. Lincoln.
Were you delighted to hear the news
that the gentlemen brought from town?
What news is that?
You're not going to say
you didn't listen, are you?
I was in the pantry getting whisky.
I must've missed it.
Seems they had a
couple of runaway niggers
and they're scared to death.
- And you?
Are you scared?
My niggers are more afraid
of me than I am of them.
Here, brought you a little present.
You can at least say
thanks to me, couldn't you?
I thank you.
Nice necklace.
You could even strangle somebody with it.
And lose the $1,000 you paid for me?
Extravagant, huh?
But that's the way I am.
Harris!
Was Legree there?
- No.
Did you see my wife and child?
No, only your sister.
Have you told her about
the ship we've chartered?
It won't be able to wait for her.
She knows, yes.
And she knows I'll pay any
price this brute asks for her.
I don't think money
will induce Mr. Legree
to give up your sister.
If I know Mr. Legree, he will all right.
I've been waiting for you.
He says he saw you with someone.
Who was it?
He says he saw him come
in but he didn't leave.
He's lying.
You hear her?
You're lying!
Get outta here.
Give me your hand.
Now who's the man?
Where'd you hide him?
- What man?
Is he here, in my house?
Answer me!
Oh, my arm, you're breaking it.
I'll break your neck
if you don't answer.
Up in...
- Where is he?
Up in the barn in the attic.
Keep an eye on her, Sambo.
Yes, boss.
Where are you at, boss?
I'm coming.
Some of the boards are rotten up there.
They better be replaced.
Sambo, see to it.
Why do you look so concerned?
Nothing happened, you see.
A miss is as good as a mile.
I must say, that is quite a trick.
Black witch!
You really wanted to do me in, didn't you?
I'm sorry I couldn't oblige.
From now on, you're gonna be
out in the fields, working.
Sambo, do you hear?
Tomorrow morning, put
her to work in the fields
in that dress she's wearing now.
Bunk her with the others.
Basil.
- Evening, sir.
Well, you been thinking?
Don't you think it's better
with me, in my house?
Casey!
Move!
Tom!
There's a saying
I remember hearing once.
I never...
understood it before.
It's very, very important.
- Don't try to speak, Uncle Tom.
I must tell you, Casey.
I must tell you.
I haven't very
much longer.
The saying is, God helps those
who help themselves.
Only one thing wrong, that's
a saying for white people.
No.
Listen to me,
God sees black and white the same.
He will help you.
You must run away.
Yeah?
Mr. Legree?
Yeah, I'm Legree, but who are you?
You don't remember me?
I'm sorry, no.
I owe you some money, Mr. Legree.
A debt?
Come in, excuse us.
What debt?
It concerns my sister, Casey.
You took her from Mr.
Morrison in my place,
and my little son Harry, who you
forced Mr. Shelby to sell to you.
You've changed a bit since then.
Nobody would recognize you.
What do you want?
I invented a machine
that does in one day
what 1,000 slaves do in a week,
and it does it much better,
and I bought my freedom from Mr. Morrison.
Mr. Wilson paid me a lot
for my invention. I'm rich.
As well as free now, Mr. Legree.
Very interesting.
Then you're free to get outta here.
Go on.
Name the price
for my child and my sister.
I haven't got the boy
and Casey's not for sale.
If you haven't got the
child, so much the better.
I'll pay you whatever
you ask for him anyway,
and for Casey.
She wants to stay with me.
I'll not give her up.
You don't even believe
that yourself, Legree.
Mr. Legree, Harris.
I'm busy, get out.
- You listen to me, Mr. Legree!
If I don't get...
- Just a minute, please.
I'm sure we can discuss this
matter without violence.
I'm willing to be reasonable about this,
and I need more cash right now.
We can talk this thing
over like gentlemen should.
Who's the one let this
fancy nigger in here?
Carl, Henry.
Get outta here.
- Let go of me!
Come on, get outta here.
Here's your hat!
No, sir, I don't want
any fancy, play niggers
strutting around any place where I come.
We keep them in their
place and their place
ain't in here with decent folks.
And just who are you to
decide who comes in here?
I belong here and they don't,
and that's why...
- Are you better than they are?
Better than they are, and
better than any white nigger.
Stop, hold it!
My niggers are running
away, could be yours next!
This concerns us all.
I count on everybody to help.
Come, Eliza, we have to get Uncle Tom.
Come.
Uncle Tom?
Come, Uncle Tom.
Hold on to me.
We have a long road ahead of us.
No.
I'm going on a different road.
My road is a long one,
and I must go all the way
by myself.
At the end, I'll be free.
And now you must go, Casey, go.
Goodbye, Uncle Tom.
Come on!
- Hurry up!
Hurry up, get over there!
Push it, push it!
That's it.
Come on!
Open the gates.
Help me, please.
Thank you.
Hurry, they have wounded.
Quickly.
Get them inside.
Gently.
You have to go right now.
And your family, what about them?
You'll have to go without
them if they're not here.
These men can't wait.
The ship...
is ready.
Boss, this way.
They've been spotted.
Come on, let's go.
You sure?
Yes sir, Casey and
another woman on the road.
Casey?
- Yes, sir.
Which way they going?
- Over toward the monastery.
That where the others are heading, too.
Come on, let's go.
I think those brothers need a lesson.
Faster, faster!
They're closer.
We're gaining on them!
Faster!
Eliza, Casey!
Eliza!
Is the boy all right?
Casey, take him, please.
- Sure.
It's all right, honey,
You'll be all right, my darling.
You're safe now.
You better hurry.
They're nearly on us
Close the gates.
No one can harm you here.
You'll be all right now.
You're safe.
All of you.
And my son, my son, he's
gonna be free, Eliza!
He'll be free!
They've run to ground.
Let's smoke them out like varmints.
What about it, boss?
Yeah, go ahead.
- Yes, sir.
Let's go!
- We'll get them outta there!
Stay here.
- I'm coming, too.
Come then.
- All right, darling.
There's gonna be fireworks!
- Here you are.
Come on, I'll cook them there.
You said it, let's go.
Casey, oh, Casey.
Let's hope they
honor this white flag.
Have you thought it
over carefully, my son?
Sometimes a person can think things
over so long, they never get done.
Pray for me, Father.
- Bless you, my son.
Open the gate.
A message!
I have a message.
I have a message for the planters.
Give the slaves back to us.
- And your cotton?
Your beautiful cotton, my son.
Are you aware that they
opened the levees as they ran?
You really ought to see to your fields.
And you really ought not to lie.
Legree!
They're drowning our cotton fields.
The sluice gates are open.
We're coming back later.
Let's go, to the field!
We'll still be here.
Come on, let's go.
Legree wants us to round up some niggers
that escaped and been causing trouble.
What kind of trouble?
Opening levees and ruining crops,
killing and everything.
Let's go!
Come on!
The gates, the sluice gates!
Come on, close the sluice gates!
There's one of them still here.
There.
You, damn you, you were their leader,
the one who caused me all this trouble.
Leave him alone, Legree.
How much do you want for him, Legree?
Dead niggers cost nothing.
Uncle Tom.
Thank you
for coming, Master George.
I knew you would
some day.
You...
You sure you seen something?
I seen something, and it was black.
Well, I ain't seen nothing.
Let's go.
Now y'all gonna get a
taste of black justice.
You been making slaves out of us,
you been hunting us down,
you been raping our women,
you been taking our respect.
May God damn you to hell for
what you did to my daughter.
No!