Story by
VÄINÖ LINNA
What would you do with the marsh?
I would try and clear it.
Put up a croft.
A croft? In raw marshland?
That swamp won't sustain you
for years to come.
If you grant me permission,
that would be all I need.
Why not, then.
That has been done before.
Can I have the entire marsh?
-Go and do your will's way.
What about the rental agreement?
Later, later.
But remember that your work
is worth nothing without blessing.
Why do they need to be so long?
-For the wall, of course.
We'll put this in writing. It will
stay in effect as long as I live.
Good day. -If the manor doesn't need
the bricks, I'd like to buy them.
We don't have a name for it yet.
Sure we do.
-What is it?
It's Koskela!
UNDER THE NORTH STAR
I've never seen such grain.
A right thug he is.
Hands like a lumberjack's -
and balls so large that
he could go courting right away.
Would you just look at
that tiny fist.
How are you, Akseli?
-I see he has a name already.
He's had one for long now.
Akseli Johannes.
Now he's dead.
-Right.
Directed by
TIMO KOIVUSALO
How did he die?
Around three this afternoon.
He had asked to be seated and
said he cannot breathe on his back.
They lifted him, but he went limp
and died in their arms.
Better for him to be at peace.
He was in such pain.
Right.
-What are those?
His son, the judge, wants me to
drive the coffin to the churchyard.
These are his brother's old clothes.
-Take it off! It's not a toy.
All right, go eat.
He was so good to us.
May he rest in peace.
But what's next for us?
-What would it change into?
Anything.
A clergyman wouldn't demand
the impossible.
Who knows... Priests and preachers,
they're all the same.
Should I massage it?
-No!
It will only make it worse.
Will the new Pastor
come and live here?
How so? -Because father
is afraid we'll have to leave.
He's not going to come here.
God will let us keep this place.
Now go to sleep.
May we eat these right away?
-Change your clothes first.
Keep the wrappers. Father will make
a wooden filling for them -
and we'll keep them
in memory of the Pastor.
Is he going to Heaven
from the grave?
Yes, on the last day
when the dead will rise.
When is the last day?
-When Jesus comes.
When will Jesus come?
-Only God knows that.
Thirteen years
and such large fields already?
It's not all good land, you know.
But if the Pastor would continue
the lease... -Not to worry.
Let everything remain
as it is for now.
This is bigger
than many farmhouses.
He even has five head of cattle,
the bastard.
And the rent is next to nothing.
That's no business of mine,
entirely up to the Pastor.
The rent is cheap, but the farm
has been built up from marshland.
Inherited crofts are different.
All this in 13 years.
Quite an accomplishment.
Mister Pastor... the contract...
When would be a good time?
I'll let you know,
let's let it lie for the moment.
We'll get back to that later.
Jussi Koskela has made himself
a little fortune in a short time.
That's all fine and easy.
Just look at the Laurilas.
Living on other people's land
and sucking it dry.
That's not really my problem.
But it's the congregation's land
that is being exploited.
No wonder
the parsonage is losing money.
My predecessor's heirs recommend
that I continue the lease -
and we will certainly do that.
It would be very good for us.
It's our home, like.
The contract will be temporary
for now. -But... Why?
It is hard, when you
don't know for how long.
I don't mean to worsen the deal. You
can live there while I'm in office.
But I don't want to
bind my followers.
The rent will remain the same.
So we can live there?
You will have the right to live
in the croft and use its lands -
as long as the parsonage's
economy doesn't suffer.
But that does away with...
Whatever contract we make -
we are bound
by the parish council's decisions.
Of course. But if the Pastor says...
I consider this a binding agreement.
We have a real lord and master now.
But he gave us
the right to live here.
Unless the parsonage's benefit
states otherwise.
It wasn't any better in the old one.
And the rent-work...
They can't come up with so much -
that these three couldn't do it in
a couple of years... Mummy's men.
Are you from the parsonage?
-Yes, I am.
But where is my husb... the Pastor?
We meant to come together,
the Pastor told me to explain.
There wasn't enough room
in the carriage. -How unfortunate.
Wait, you son of a bitch!
God damn it!
Is there an elementary school here?
-Yes, in the church village.
There are plans
to build one in Pentinkulma too.
Are the people patriotic here?
-I really don't know.
Daddy!
Ani!
Finally!
Ilmari.
Wait, here's something for you.
Thank you, but I'm doing rent-work.
It's not necessary.
Right, right. Koskela is your name?
Well, that's what they call me.
In the books it's Antinpoika.
Lauri, you should make Koskela
this man's official family name.
Certainly, my little patriot,
right away.
Give it!
Give it here!
What's this thing with the name?
I hope it's no scheme that the
contract is under a different name?
Let him hold it for a while.
-No, because it's mine.
Give it right away.
-No!
You need to get involved here.
Did you hear your mother?
-I found it, it's mine.
One more time: will you do
what your mother tells you?
Kill me... if you want to!
Not so hard...
I've never seen a brat like that!
You must stop the whippings.
It's just too terrible.
He had bumps
as wide as a finger.
The world doesn't mind, it
strikes you down without mercy.
Just try kindly first.
Sometimes I praise him
for a job well done -
and he's quietly pleased
even though he doesn't show it.
No reason to praise him for working.
Work is a thing of nature.
We came to see Halme talk,
since we didn't even need tickets.
He took our son as an apprentice.
Our Valenti might become
a master tailor.
Halme is a wise man.
This nation has slumbered
for centuries, but now it is waking.
May the ideal of the fire brigade
elevate them from that slumber.
Let it flood like a spring brook,
ever stronger, growing and rising -
in all our hearts, for the benefit
of our northern fatherland.
We are pleased to see -
that our gentry
is advanced in their views.
Especially the poor are elated. They
have not been entirely forgotten.
I wish to thank Halme
for these words.
The fire brigade idea was his,
and thanks is due to him.
Why the Hell should we thank him?
Well, Halme is a good speaker.
You can tell he reads The Workman.
The poor don't have any use
for a fire brigade.
There's no such rush that a worker
couldn't gather up his scraps.
Goddamnit, how they try!
Rocks are left in the field
so that it would be hell to work!
Go tell your father
I'm sitting and smoking.
Why would he want to know?
-I don't know.
I guess he needs to know,
since he's put you to spy on me.
I must sharpen this sucker
to earn more money for the boss!
I'm only going to say this once.
Don't scare my boy.
You know I am a man of my word.
You really are, especially
when it comes to rent-work.
But when you got the house
from your father-
you gave us a lifelong lease
on the croft.
I did, but with the condition
that you behave!
Will you be decent,
or do I have to say it?
Say what you want,
but I'm not leaving.
Good Lord.
Let's meet them outside
so they don't have to wait.
Did you clear all this alone?
-Well, it's fair to say I did.
We ought to get Koskela a medal
from the farming society.
You said it.
We shall do that right away.
No need.
This is little compared to...
This is well worth a medal.
You must get along quite well now.
The land feeds us...
But we work hard.
Our wilds have always been
cleared like this.
That is why Finns
are tougher than any other nation.
You little settlers.
Come here now.
Thank the nice lady.
-Thank you.
It is good to think of you
continuing your father's work.
I trust you'll give your
contribution when the time comes.
They are doing better than us.
How many tax days does Koskela do?
Two with horse and one on foot.
Isn't that rather little?
Couldn't we increase their days?
It doesn't feel appropriate.
-What's inappropriate about it?
That is the reason we're losing
money over the parsonage.
They can do a couple of days more.
A cuckoo!
Six times, did you hear?
What a lovely country we have.
We must speak kindly to them.
How many days did you have in mind?
-Shall we say... six?
I heard a cuckoo. Six times!
Only six times?
He could have sung more
while he was at it.
What would Koskela say,
if I asked him for a little help?
What kind of help do you mean?
Would Koskela object strongly
if we added his tax days?
Not a lot, just some help days
during the summer.
Say, six women's days.
If the Pastor says so,
we must accept...
It's not a command,
it's a request.
The contract states
that we both must agree.
We can do as much as we can.
As long as we can live there.
The lady is in control, and the
man cannot keep his own head.
We're not done for yet.
And Akseli is already
as strong as a grown man.
My back can still support
one family of gentry.
It would be fine
without their army of maids.
Could you do a bit more,
that strip over there?
It's all in the bank.
Where is it going?
-It's going to hit us.
It will go to the parsonage.
-I can see it's coming, can't I?
It's Osku's turn!
Who hit you?
Well? Who was it?
Arvo Töyry,
you tell me what happened.
He fought with Akseli Koskela.
I see. Sit down.
Akseli Koskela, on your feet!
Look what you did
to this boy's face.
Do you hear me?
Apologise at once. Apologise!
You little brat!
Am I supposed to turn
you vermin into people?
Osku, stop it!
Leave your sister alone. Elina is
the only one here with any manners.
A pair of skis for our godson.
No need to fight anymore.
Mind you, the only education I got
was a beating now and then. -Thanks.
Well, thank you.
Dear neighbours.
You must have heard of
the emperor's manifesto -
overturning our country's
constitutional rights.
We are gathering names
for a people's petition.
Please, would you sign it.
-Of course. It's important.
Although Finland is
a grand duchy of Russia -
the Emperor cannot betray
the will of the Finnish people.
I don't know about signatures.
I never learned that skill.
Surely you can write, Mr Laurila.
Sometimes I can, sometimes I can't.
I don't care for constitutions.
The constitution secures your
freedom. -It hasn't done so before.
Besides, the lands will soon be
divided up according to Russian law.
That is a lie meant to divide
the people. How can you believe it?
It's as believable as anything.
-Are you implying that I'm lying?
We're not implying anything. Our
constitution is master Töyry's word.
We're talking about the fatherland.-
Indeed.
The fatherland doesn't beg for
what it needs. It demands it.
Goodness me.
Welcome, welcome.
I knew the gentry were coming,
by the bell ringing.
Didn't even have time
to clean the house.
We have quite a few animals now...
Sit down, please.
-Thank you, no.
I'd like you to sign a petition.
-We'll thank the emperor in church.
We don't want to thank him.
The emperor has broken his vow.
Has he gone and done that too?
Wouldn't you like to sign after all?
If the madam wants our names...
Writing to the emperor, oh my.
I am theoretically
in favour of this petition.
There is only one mistake.
The workers' stewards
have been entirely surpassed.
But the issue at hand
is not at dispute, is it?
You will sign, right?
Yes, of course. I'll sign the
petition as an individual.
The bosses don't care what the lower
classes think about the fatherland.
You won't get to go another time,
so you know.
You kids will not be
running off at will.
Yes... Is your back hurting bad?
Why would it be any better?
Well, what did you do?
-Played games and made a bomb.
Uncle Otto made one into a pipe
and lit it. -Well, some folks.
Just blowing up
their way through life.
It's a new century.
-So it is.
But don't go emptying that meat cup.
I believe we need to eat
in this century as well.
Akseli Koskela is driving
a mowing machine!
On the parsonage fields.
Many don't know
a thing about machines.
The parsonage is losing money.
-We must cut our expenses.
We have too much staff.
We can give up the parlour maid,
but that's a drop in the ocean.
We should live less extravagantly.
This is inappropriate for my office.
I'm the only priest in the church of
Finland with a two-horse carriage.
All that was bought
with my parents' inheritance.
There is one way, but it's not easy.
-What?
The parsonage has a tenancy
almost as big as the parsonage.
We could reclaim some of its lands.
That will not do.
We must do something,
you know that.
I could take away a tenancy from
anyone else easily, but not Koskela.
I've begun to admire
him during these years.
He fears rain on the parsonage
fields as much as his own.
Why won't you understand?
-I understand!
But I expect my husband
to support me and my children.
How will we pay for
Ilmari's studies?
Give me strength.
The world took away my joy
And left me with a bosom of woe
Should the kantele still be playing
No joy will ever live in its sound
This is becoming ridiculous.
-Ridiculous? I've run out of tears.
Let's talk.
We're a husband and wife.
I'm alone with my children,
who have no future.
Ellen, let's stop this.
I've been thinking it over.
Do you really believe I'd think it,
if I didn't feel it is justified?
Maybe we can reach an agreement.
The parish council
has been thinking -
that the parsonage should get some
land back from Koskela. A little.
About four hectares, no more.
That's a good third of the croft's
land and half of the best land.
But you will be left
with a whole lot.
It's also good for you
to cut down on your work.
I just thought...
There's nothing I can do,
if you want to take it.
Crying won't make it any better.
I just feel sorry for father.
He didn't sleep a wink last night.
Staying up won't make it
better either. The land's gone!
Easy to say. If you had done
all this yourself like father...
But if it is God's will...
Don't drag God into it.
God doesn't need our marsh.
It's that damned priest that's
taking them. -Hold your tongue!
You'll have to accept God's will
at some point in your life.
Any crime is explained away
with the help of God.
But I won't bow to land-robbers.
-Come on now!
He is a servant of God, after all.
He's a servant to the Devil.
And to the greatest Devil there is.
Have you stopped working altogether?
-Not yet, but soon.
I can't stop.
Now I'll have to work twice as hard.
They can take all they will.
-Why bust your back for others?
Don't go causing trouble.
We'll all be kicked out!
Good morning.
It's turned out beautiful again.
Why won't Akseli answer?
It's not part of our rent-work
to say good morning.
Take it easy.
We must keep up!
I must hurry,
or the bosses will go hungry.
He's not angry about the lands.
He's just a difficult person.
He's a good workman. As good
as his father, if not better.
If we continue the contract, I want
the tenancy to go to the middle son.
He's easier in all respects.
I'm here on the master's errand.
There's a meeting tomorrow
at the firehouse.
What's happening?
-Great things.
The country is on strike,
they're demanding a new parliament-
and that the lands be dealt anew and
the tenants freed. -Strike here too!
Leave the dungforks alone!
-Take it easy tomorrow.
People of Finland! We are caught
in the middle of great events.
The Finnish people
want back their rights.
There is a strike on
against Russian oppression.
If we're on strike,
why are the masters here?
This is a national strike.
I ask the Pastor to explain more.
It's a national strike.
All classes of society are involved.
Also the officials are on strike.
We have no reason to strike here,
but we must show our support.
If the bosses are on strike now,
what did they do before?
They have the most at stake: their
offices, their future, even freedom.
A strike won't do here.
Animals must be fed and cows milked
in any case.
May I enquire when will the crofts'
contracts be legitimised?
This is no time to
stir up class hatred.
There is hope of
general suffrage at last.
We don't need to strike here.
We would only be harming ourselves.
A strike must not to be used
to create chaos and anarchy.
Why are the factories on strike if
the strike is against the Russians?
The bosses against the emperor, the
workers against the factory bosses.
It just happens to take place
at the same time.
The goals are national.
We want oppression to end.
There are many types of oppressors.
To my amazement,
there is discord about the strike.
The old parliament
must return to power.
But it must immediately pass a new
election law and disperse again.
Are you sure this 'cash parliament'
will make the reform?
Us radicals, Mr Halme and myself,
guarantee it.
We will go on strike again
unless a reform is passed.
Dear madam. In that case, I think
only one radical would be on strike:
Mr Halme.
It's best just to see how it goes.
These are big issues, you know.
People like us need to be careful.
Halme should have started a strike
without the bosses.
We're on strike for the tenants.
The priest should stay away.
We're in for rough times.
The hotter the situation gets,
the more tenants will be evicted.
They couldn't do that.
Where would all the people go?
Do you think the bosses care?
They wouldn't give a damn.
Finland's roads are still
littered with beggars.
We need to do something. -You go
to rent-work tomorrow and be nice.
If we get the vote, we'll give
the lords a run for their money.
I must start reading them books
and newspapers myself.
Akseli.
I'm building a grain store
at Kylä-Pentti. Come help me out.
Dig the pit.
I'll pay you a little money.
The bosses took a clear victory.
The strike is over.
They are assembling at the
municipal hall. Shall we go?
We'll celebrate another time,
and the gentry will not be cheering.
If we had started
a strike together...
In Helsinki, the Students' Guard -
threatened to shoot
at the Red Guard during the strike.
They're ready to spill blood when
squashing the workers' demands!
We must retaliate!
Violence is a foreign tool
to the working man.
The working man will use
any tools necessary to gain power.
What are people up to at Pentinkulma
village? -They're ignorant.
You must found a
Workers' Association there.
That I'll certainly do.
Halme speaks about socialism, but he
hangs around the gentry too much.
We should educate the baron
about the rent-work.
The tenants won't be freed by
running around in a fire brigade.
Join the Workers' Association's
Board of Directors, father.
Where does that enthusiasm
come from?
I didn't know you read books.
Think about it. If we get the vote,
we must get people to vote.
And if we get the majority, the
tenants' condition will be fixed -
and no more goddamn rent-work.
What is that? I have enough
to keep this household going.
It's not for the household,
it's for you.
Oh, you poor boy.
Buy something for yourself.
What ever do I need?
I must put in a little praise
for my own work with that suit.
It's not common to feel pride -
when clothing this
rickets-stricken nation.
Higher tailoring is a form of art.
It's a joy to see it on you.
But your understanding of socialism
is skewed. -What's it like then?
Its purpose is not to burn and
destroy, but to create and maintain.
Thereby a fire brigade is important.
Bosses or no bosses.
-I see.
Stop messing with that lunatic!
God damn this life.
One lunatic is not enough, but the
others have to be a bunch of devils.
Is Elma hiding behind all that hair?
We don't have time to groom
our children, like some people.
Pretty girl. No use to keep hair
all over her face.
What good is the Association,
if we can't get any help from it?
Let's try one more time.
-We have to leave for sure.
This plot will be a shop
for his brother.
It's no use going there
and shooting off your mouth.
So there are no outstanding rents?
-Every damned day has been paid for.
It's clear as day. I have the right
to issue an eviction.
But is it absolutely necessary?
I will not tolerate
back chat from my tenant.
I'm going to chat back as long as
you keep up your game.
You wouldn't have coped without me,
and you know it.
What has the world come to, coming
in folks' homes raising trouble?
We don't want to order you around.
But Laurila has
some rights to his croft, no?
When did you become a juror,
Kivivuori?
I've said all there is to say.
That land is mine.
You're out in the spring.
Others need not interfere.
Laurila has the right
to seek our assistance.
He is a member of the Association.
Socialism gives him the right.
We know nothing of the
disease of socialism in this house.
If you're not out by the due date,
the coppers will empty the croft.
Right it is then! There's your ten
marks for that one seed of barley!
Keep it, and go to Hell with it!
And I won't do any more work,
I'm on strike!
Then the eviction will be
implemented sooner.
You'll only get me
on the road feet first!
There's the front door, use it.
The Workers' Association
will not sit still for this.
I'm making a flagpole for the cause.
Soon we'll fight the oppressor
behind Emma Halme's red underskirt.
Although Anttoo is bound
to lose his case.
What good is it then? -It shows
people the tenant's position.
It's nothing less than serfdom.
Come, Akseli. Let's go courting.
-Why would I want to come?
I think Akseli has plans
about our girl here.
He's begun to lift up her skirt
a bit. -You're terrible, father.
Look at the girl, gone all red.
What is the purpose of this group?
And who has authorized this?
The group will follow
the destruction of a comrade's home.
The authority is that which is
granted to us by the law of Finland.
This is an illegal demonstration.
Do not approach
the site of the eviction.
If you do,
the consequences are on your head.
We will not interfere
with your work.
What are you doing here? -I'm a
reporter. This is a public eviction.
All right. But don't get involved.
Do you wish the order
to be followed?
I've said what I've said,
and I'm sticking to it.
Anton Kustaa Laurila, I urge you and
your family to vacate this building.
If you don't leave,
the troopers will have to act.
Kill all of us right away.
But I'm not leaving. That's final.
Anttoo, if you promise to leave
in three days, I can wait.
You'll have to drag me away
piece by piece, you bandit.
For the last time.
Get up from that chair, Laurila!
The chair stays under my arse!
Unhinge the doors and windows,
destroy the stove.
Ma'am, clothe your children.
-Let them freeze!
They have no place in this world.
Let's all go to Hell together!
Bring rope and handcuffs.
Take this man outside!
Jesus shit!
We're going to Hell, all of us.
Goddamn!
I won't tolerate this.
Come what may, let's go!
-Stay still!
My God, comrades, keep calm!
You devil! Driving children
out into the cold!
Laugh it up, you had your will!
I'd like to tear your eyes out!
Your ass is like two stale cookies
in a sack! But have a look at this!
Ugly!
-Take this!
Antti, no!
Break up that screaming bunch!
This is a peaceful
and legitimate gathering!
Comrades, return to the road.
Let's go already.
Akseli, take the flag to the road.
They are whipping us!
Go on, this is no use anymore.
The group will break up.
Comrades,
let's march to the firehouse.
"This tenant farmer was torn
out of his home with violence -
after slaving for his master
year after year."
"The flag of socialism flew high on
the steely arms of a young hero..."
What a hero. Carrying around a flag.
What good did that do?
The croft is empty
and Anttoo is going to prison.
What is he writing?
-Arms of steel...
Subscribing to papers like that.
Some flibbertigibbet
is making a fortune.
Writing rubbish by day -
and drinking away
people's money by night.
Arms of steel...
Good day. Sofa there.
You people make trouble
with the police. -Dear sir.
The trouble was caused by the
police, not by the demonstrators.
This concern me: my men
off work without permission.
Another thing, to you the firehouse
is like a Socialist House.
Dear sir, considering that the house
is located on your property -
and built out of your wood, you
naturally have authority over it.
If one more time my men go off work
and walk on road with song and flag.
Then those men away!
As the great Tolstoy says...
-Tolstoy not do my men's work!
Magnus?
Wait!
Dear sir.
Despite our long hours,
we have all night to assemble -
and we will find a space
for that purpose.
I'm sorry that we disagree.
Goodbye.
The battle is escalating.
The baron is placing all his might
against the Association.
We will not be getting reforms
through peaceful means.
Leave the collar longer, so he can
steal hay from the next horse.
Well, let's grab hands
now that we started.
Is it real gold?
The chain is gold, but the watch is
silver and only gold plated.
Are you going to go
courting tonight, Aleksi?
This one's ready in mind and body.
-What are you doing, boy?
I'm teaching her to fear her arse,
so she'll be a little shy with it.
What good-for-nothings.
They embarrass me every time.
What lip.
Where have they learned it?
Dear youths. The perils and joys
of adult life await you.
But if you hold this sacred moment
as your guide -
your lives will be blessed,
whatever lies in wait for you.
The body of Christ...
The blood of Christ...
That fence
will not stay there forever.
Halme said that with
80 socialists in the parliament -
old evictions will be nullified.
-Don't believe everything he says.
He's just organising
one work party after another.
We have our own work, you know.
Come learn a few steps, Aksu.
Take the girl for a swing.
We were going to build the people's
hall. Let's dance when it's ready.
That's man's talk.
Those two are just messing about.
Let us dance then, mother.
Terrible. Behave now.
Our Janne is marrying Sanni.
Right, they're starting
a thirty-year war.
It doesn't need to be war.
You're like Osku.
You never say anything nice.
I don't like you at all.
-I can't help that.
I'm as good as I'm going to get.
I'm just my own simple self.
I didn't... You are always so crude.
-That's just me!
I don't want to act
any better than I am.
Let's have more red, Valpri!
You've had her for sure.
-No way.
I've just squeezed her about.
-Don't talk rubbish.
I'd walk you home,
but I don't want Osku to know.
I don't like Osku,
I like them different.
If you don't tell Osku,
I'll walk you.
You're one...
What of me?
I'm just the normal kind.
Say nothing.
Everybody knows how you are.
I must go home.
Don't hurry. We have all evening.
-It's cold.
Let's go to the sauna to warm up.
-It's not warm.
You should have been a fiddler
with fingers like that.
Who would have known at school
that we'd end up being a couple.
Don't fuss now.
What are you doing?
The others are mowing!
They're behind in the work.
They have to work during the break.
Get up and go to work.
-I have to take a breather.
I said go to work, right now!
Man and horse, both as lazy.
It's like he reads
People's newspapertoo, isn't it?
I will not let this lie.
-I see.
I will.
You spoke to the steward
against the manor.
You do bad rent-work.
-Mr Baron, sir.
Rent-work is piecework. It's enough
that the contract is filled.
And when it comes to speaking;
go get your book, son.
Doesn't it say all Finnish
citizens have freedom of speech?
I don't want your books,
I want your work.
You don't take care of croft,
only People's hall.
Your rye still green,
while manor's rye very ripe.
Even God knows
who needs the rye first.
Up when you speak to me!
Take off cap!
No manners, like hooligans.
This day next year, you out!
-Mr baron.
We call a hooligan someone who
raises trouble in people's homes.
You don't enter a house without
permission. Not to brawl anyway.
Dear ladies,
I apologise my excitement.
And you, who is
man of the house, fired.
Too much is too much.
Magnus Gabriel came to see how
Finland's agriculture is developing.
Now we'll show him.
Are you that far ahead?
I didn't even notice.
I hired that young man
to do my strip.
Do you intend to beat the steward?
The baron's minion
will be beaten down today.
What has the baron ever done to you?
-Not to me. But to you.
So you're mowing for my sake?
-Yours too.
For the manor's honour! Parsonage
boy goes too much in front.
The boy hasn't read
The People's Newspaper.
Some teach their horses to do that.
-Your every word nasty!
Leave the worksite, don't come back!
-Not even for rent-work?
You go this year without rent,
then you away. That's it.
Remember what you promised me.
You all heard it!
My word needs no witness.
Go away!
Damn, boy.
You'll get your due reward for this.
I'd like a word.
-We need to have that word then.
Right... About Elina and me.
What about you?
You know well enough.
-How would I know what you're up to?
We've been thinking...
I'll marry Elina!
I see. Marrying.
Marrying them is fine, but I've had
to clothe and feed her for years.
Sure you can have her.
What would you pay for her?
-What do you want?
The boy is asking for our daughter.
I promised her for a bottle.
What do you think, mother?
-Elina...
In a year's time, our girl will be
supporting a little arse on her arm.
The girl came to see
where to put her spinning-wheel.
We'll help you as long as
we are of any help.
I'm not afraid of you, but shared
households are just like that.
We'll build an old-folks cottage
for us so we can get along better.
Akseli!
You keep your mouth shut, goat!
According to the new law, contracts
will have to stay in force for now.
That's how Elina's parents' eviction
was cancelled.
Akseli is the eldest, but remember
your younger sons too.
Right, so it is.
But Akseli has been responsible
for the rent-work for years now.
I wouldn't turn back on him now.
-That's for Koskela to decide.
So we will draft the contract
in his name. -If you wish so.
Yes. Well, yes.
What's bothering you?
Has something happened?
Is it true that
you have been with Aune?
Who told you that?
Aune said she could have
had you if she had wanted.
Is it true?
Where did it happen? Tell me!
In the sauna at the Leppänen house.
What did you do with her?
Tell me everything.
I did screw her.
It doesn't get any better.
You too!
Take that to her.
Put it on that tart's finger.
Take it!
-Don't go.
If you leave, I'll kill myself!
-You won't do that.
I'll kill myself for sure!
We can't help that now.
Then let's not talk about it.
This marriage
pleases me to a great degree.
I have known you since
you were a little boy.
I wish all the best for you
as you enter manhood.
Bear in mind that marriage -
is not just an earthly union
taking place hear on Earth.
Your astral beings
have come together -
before either of you had
a conscious thought about it.
The People's Hall is the right place
for your wedding.
Socialism is, should I say,
a witness to your marriage.
Congratulations.
Did you see how the Pastor's wife
chattered when she congratulated us?
She can be so sugary
when it comes down to it.
You see, the gentry doesn't show
anything in their faces.
Educated people know
what to look like and when.
What do you say
if we build a proper kitchen?
The hall would be left
as a Sunday room.
Why not.
And then we'll panel up the walls.
-But only halfway.
I want real wallpaper
above the panel.
Sure, why not.
I baptise you, Vilho Johannes -
in the name of the Father -
the Son -
and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
WAR EXPANDING IN EUROPE
You can't take anything
for granted anymore.
At least we'd have
the burial plot booked.
I'm sorry,
but I cannot give you a discount.
It would be fair that a man who has
cleared over ten hectares of land -
would get the last yards for free.
But you won't need it
for many years to come.
You'll drive me to the churchyard,
like my predecessor.
I think that will not happen. I'm
starting to be in such a bad way.
Why did I have to be born
into such small circles?
People of my age elsewhere
are doing great things.
But after all,
war is against human nature.
War, if anything, ishuman nature.
Aino is doing the laundry.
My name is not Aino.
What is it then?
You should know, sir.
I do know. It's Aino.
No it isn't.
What's wrong with your finger?
I cut it with a sickle.
Let me blow on it.
You're a terrible man!
Don't, you wouldn't like me anyhow.
If Aino is nice,
I will surely like her.
Please believe me,
my name is not Aino.
Halme asked me to tell you
about the Tenants' Bill.
The tenants' rights have been left
untouched for another five years.
The bosses' secret wish
has been drained empty.
But I wouldn't applaud
the emperor yet.
You give thanks for presents,
not for justice.
Do you mind if I go by
the Laurila house? -Go right ahead.
It can't stop anyone walking on the
road. -Why don't we go together.
I'm not going anywhere
with Koskela's golden boy.
People might talk.
It's yours, you were with me
at the time. -So were many others.
You can't be sure it's mine.
-But it is.
I can bring five men
to court against you.
You'd be left with the expenses
and the shame. So keep quiet.
I'll ask you straight:
have you and Oskari been involved?
We have been involved.
Then, before Almighty God,
has it been only him?
I don't mean to offend,
but we need the truth.
I didn't do it with others.
Oskari was my groom.
But there were others?
Sometimes, a little,
but mostly with Osku.
Oskari was one, all right.
There may have been others too.
But he certainly was one.
-Why blame Oskari alone then?
It's not my fault alone.
It's all good at the time.
But now everyone is denying it.
I asked the steward for permission -
to hoe the plotside
for a little more land.
So we'd have
them potatoes at least.
I'll help out as best as I can.
Although Oskari can't be blamed.
The baby is not guilty of anything,
that's for sure.
It is Osku's all right!
But I won't chase after one man.
This village would go upside down
if you knew about my men.
There are some
that I've left for others.
There are fine ladies
with men that I've had.
God told me
to come here and find out.
I don't care for a man who makes
his mother do his dirty business.
I could marry gentry too.
-Don't speak rubbish.
I'll help the best I can, although
Oskari cannot be blamed.
Good evening.
We'd have them potatoes at least.
You will need to
keep quiet about this.
I'll take a training course
for officers in Germany.
If you speak about this, you'll
endanger me and many others.
No need to talk,
I've made up my mind.
Everything is planned for.
The less you ask the better.
What about afterwards?
I don't know yet.
Why is Halme coming here
in the middle of the day?
You're as beautiful as ever.
Dress up. You must come with me
to the People's Hall at once.
Nicholas ll is no longer
the Emperor of Russia -
and much less
the Grand Duke of Finland.
Revolution has broken out
in St. Petersburg. -Hell no!
Do you think I came
all the way here to joke?
Hellberg called from Helsinki.
All right then.
No Savior from on high
than the people itself.
Make way for Koskela.
Come, Koskela.
Let's go up front, Akseli.
Go up to the front, Elina.
Go sit beside your husband.
A beautiful flower has risen
out of the mire of this trade war:
freedom for Finland's poor.
Comrades, the power of the spirit
rises above cannons and swords.
So how about the land-lease law?
We can't give a direct answer
right now.
But I believe soon the lords
will have to give us all they can.
We'll put poles around our farms
and say: "Hand off, it's mine."
I think we should thank
master Halme somehow.
Some applause.
He's been so busy for us.
-I second that!
Shut up!
Our Preeti is being seconded.
Thank you.
However, cheering an individual
feels out of place -
when we're celebrating
the downfall of a dictatorship.
But it tells me your faith
in the cause has grown stronger.
I thought
maybe I could do this work as well.
A strike is fine -
but I don't understand
stopping others from working.
There is a shortage of foodstuffs.
The poorest workers are
the first to suffer from a strike.
People have been starved to death
in this country before.
But you're a farmer too, Akseli.
Farming would be different
if I had land of my own.
There's been trouble
in the manor's fields.
I have to go and sort it out.
Akseli can certainly go
if he has to.
Those in favour of the strike
have the majority.
Anyone opposed to the strike,
raise your hand.
So, we're demanding
an eight-hour workday -
and the Workers' Association's
Board of Directors -
will represent the proletariat.
All those in favour?
The motion is passed.
Let's get busy.
And what we begin, we also finish.
Nice May weather we're having.
It's nice to plant God's crops.
Did you want to see me about
something? -Not the Pastor.
But your men haven't heard that all
places of work are on strike.
If they want to work,
leave them in peace.
The Pastor can work all he wants,
but the scabs will have to go.
Why is Kivivuori on strike?
You are your own employer.
You pay your dues for the
manor in cash. -Sort of, yes.
But I've shortened my working hours,
and I expect all bosses to join me.
The Koskela boys too.
Think about your good parents.
Shame on you.
We have nothing
to be ashamed about.
We haven't taken anyone's land away.
Them as well. I see.
Remember, no trouble.
Don't shame the working class.
But the scabs can go to Hell! -They
have brought in students to work.
The demonstration is fine, as long
as the workers are left unharmed.
It is a grave wrong
to use scab labour.
Who the hell threw a stone?
Akseli!
Jesus Christ,
they're shooting at us!
Akseli! Do something!
No stones and no guns!
I say this to every
troublemaker here:
if you want me to take part in the
negotiations, the fighting must end.
Are we supposed be nice while
we're being shot at and stoned?
Violence undermines our chances!
Both parties are committed
to ending the strike.
Right, but you get up at four every
morning and work until night.
You can't treat people
like animals forever, you know.
They're having a singing rehearsal.
Musical people.
They're shouting out
in their hunger.
We have been threatened with
violence, lest the unrest cease.
We've had to work two weeks
with stones raining on us.
The rights of the working class
cannot be trodden on any longer.
Will you give them voluntarily -
or will they have
to take them by force?
That is the kind of talk that makes
the people go rowdy. It must end!
Believe me, violence will not
bring about a solution.
The ghosts of our past
are demanding justice.
Let us give it to them,
for ghosts don't die from shooting.
Nobody has said
anything about shooting.
This is not going anywhere.
Our side, let's meet
in the council room.
Halme can surely speak.
He should have been
a school teacher...
I think Yllö took them back there
to soften them up.
Anything we get-
is thanks to that screaming
bunch of rag-tags out there.
The Koskela baby
is eating a sweetbread.
I could buy one too if I wanted.
-Go right ahead.
I'm not as indulgent
as the Koskela baby.
We have decided to
satisfy your demands.
We did so only to secure the peace.
The workers' leaders seem to be
unable to control their own people.
Let's start drafting an agreement.
I have it here. Just sign it.
You were mighty sure
of your victory, Kivivuori.
I have always believed
that justice will prevail.
Dear comrades.
I'm sorry if my voice breaks down
when I say these words:
Long live free
and democratic Finland!
The masters agreed to the terms.
Soon the land-measurer will come
and divide the fields anew.
Right after the parliament
has made the decision.
Then I have work for you boys too.
I'll make a new cowshed and
put a siding on the main building.
How will you buy rye?
I'll show you how to buy rye.
Dear comrades.
I must inform you that
we have been betrayed once again.
Why are you making all that noise?
-Should I sneak around in my socks?
What is it?
-They've broken up the parliament.
They arranged this
with the Russians.
Those bourgeoisie senators
and the Governor General!
Right after the Left
took the majority in the parliament.
But isn't there a new election?
-Of course.
But do you think they'd ever
let us take the majority again?
I wish I could come face to face
with the likes of them.
Goddammit!
We're setting up
a protective organisation.
We're gathering money to buy arms.
Perhaps that's the only way.
The Russians have stopped
obeying their officers.
We must get rid of them.
And I'm done shooting in the air.
I don't have a lot right now.
I can maybe give more later.
Ninety-two.
Unless there are changes.
The election was false. The old
legal parliament has to regroup.
This one has been chosen
by the people. It is legal.
Fake votes. That's the only way
the Right would get the majority.
That's how the people voted.
I don't know much about politics -
but the people are in charge, right?
-And they will be.
The bosses have taken a bad road,
and there will be grief at its end.
If you refuse to accept the people's
decision, you are free to revolt.
The country
is practically independent now.
The security guard's main task
is to defend the working class -
from attacks
by non-socialist guards.
I don't think it's a good idea.
It will lead to war, we know that.
I suggest organising independent,
unarmed security forces.
I propose that this suggestion
be turned down.
I second that. Permission to speak?
The guard is voluntary.
Kivivuori doesn't have to join.
I won't join. I'm not a warmonger.
-Am I a warmonger?
Sure feels like it.
Only intellectual acts
are constructive.
Power in the hands
of the working class -
if it emerges as violence -
is no better than
bourgeoisie violence.
That's eloquent,
but doesn't help the workers.
I believe that the working class
will eliminate arms from the world -
and cannot allow them
to pick them up.
I resign from armament -
and trust that the cause
is stronger than its shadow.
Kivivuori and Halme
are scaring us with war.
Setting up a guard
doesn't mean war -
unless the non-socialists
resort to violence.
Non-socialists don't have
the exclusive right to carry arms.
I second Hellberg's proposition.
The worker gets nothing
unless he has power.
I want the minutes to state that I
refuse to participate in the guard.
I'll leave it to the hotheads who
think they can control their army.
How are you, Lieutenant Koskela?
-I don't see the humour in this.
You won't be joining
any of those killing guards!
People have turned into wolves.
-I'm not killing anybody.
Thank God I bought
those burial plots in time.
To bring a child into this world,
not knowing what will happen.
We'll see if he is born
onto a proper farm.
We must forget past conflicts.
The argument was over the means,
not over the goals.
Our country is now free, but
it is still threatened by anarchy.
We've declared our country
independent and untouchable -
but at the same time,
wild forces are invading our homes.
Law-abiding Finns must be allowed
to defend their homes.
Is father inside?
-Yes. Did you get them?
Yes.
-Show us.
Don't start waving them around.
-Let's just take a look.
Looking good!
When you hit someone with one of
these, it's over. -Let's hide them.
Have you got bullets too? -About
40. We can practice tomorrow.
Töyry's boys have shotguns.
These take more in the magazine
than a shotgun.
Who is it?
-Messenger from the headquarters.
Come in.
I have an order. It starts now.
What's going on in the main village?
-They just started to gather up.
Are the butchers on the move?
-They say some left yesterday.
If things go wrong at the church,
I want to know immediately.
Otherwise we're in a world
of trouble. Be careful.
For the leader of the second platoon
A. Koskela.
The platoon is to
undertake its mission.
Resistance must be crushed swiftly.
Mobilise all men without delay.
In the name of the working class.
K.A. Ylöstalo
After reading, burn message.
What was it?
-Just a messenger.
We've been told to assemble
at the Workers' Hall.
Just go to sleep.
-I haven't slept a wink in a week.
There's no need to cry about this.
Shall I fix you something to eat?
-Why not.
I'll go wake Aku and Aleksi.
Don't do anything bad to people.
For the children's sake.
I don't need to speak long.
You all know your tasks.
I have word from the headquarters
that the revolution has begun.
There is no time for speeches.
We must do our part.
I'll go out and confiscate arms
with my team.
Road patrol duties
will be set up later.
When you meet people,
don't overreact. But be firm!
Where are your boys?
I never would have believed
I'd see you on affairs like this.
Let them go, this doesn't
depend on three men.
Did they take your guns?
-Yes, the few that we have.
We aren't used to
running around with guns.
The working class
has seized power in Finland.
From now on you will follow
the proletariat's orders.
By what authority, if I may ask?
The same authority
that you used to have!
I will obey a legal government only,
and Koskela will too, eventually.
You meant to kill the workers
quickly, but your guards failed you.
Do you believe those blatant lies?
I pity you.
Your no-good leaders
have betrayed you.
You are the last
to speak about betrayal.
Your have betrayed people
all your life!
You've never kept your word.
Not even a written one.
You should be ashamed,
if you know how to be ashamed!
But your days of
living off us are over.
If you think I can be scared
by brawling, you are mistaken.
Rule of that sort will fail.
And when it does, we must be firm.
Why you men come here?
You have homes.
We're looking for the manor's arms.
We must inspect all rooms.
You don't find?
You should obey the
proletariat's orders from now on.
We are not giving them for fun.
Why don't you come with us.
We must organise a headquarters,
and Otto is staying away.
You could help us with the new laws.
Thanks you, but I'll settle
with my meagre dwelling.
We haven't spilled any blood, so you
should have no qualms about it.
I cannot take part in this.
Violence is obnoxious to me
in all its forms.
Looks like they succeeded.
She put a lot of lard in Aku's cup.
Smart girl.
You go to hell.
And what are you smirking about?
You should be wrapped in blankets
and made all over again.
Well maybe just a taste,
though I just ate at home.
But just a taste.
He'll give me land or money.
He has made me suffer so.
Maybe just a taste...
I could well put a bullet in him.
Your case will be handled.
Don't try to jump the queue.
But how will that bastard make up
for my time in prison?
We can't help that anymore.
But don't take your own action.
Don't touch the people!
Where are you going?
-Laurila.
Do you want to see Anttoo? -No,
but they have a nice daughter there.
Stay on your own side.
Don't go, let's talk about things.
Don't hit me, goddammit!
What have I ever done to you?
You grew up in the parsonage woods.
Acting almighty.
I don't like you people at all!
-What are you barking about?
I won't push myself on any woman.
Goodbye and farewell.
-Go on!
Password?
Come out with your hands up...
or I'll shoot.
Sorry, could you tell us if
this is the road to Vammala.
No, it's not the road to Vammala.
Then we're lost.
A Red Guard road patrol told us...
Have you got a pass?
Go that way.
That's my orders.
You're on the move without a pass.
I will have to take you in.
Akusti and Elias, go to headquarters
with these boys.
Why are you walking them around?
We should have shot them.
We won't be shooting anyone
without an investigation.
They can be telling the truth,
for all we know.
Plenty of people on the move.
Playing cards, are we?
Some poker, but the bets are small.
-We don't have that much.
Please bear in mind -
that the building belongs to the
Association, not the Red Guard.
I expect the lodgers
to keep the floor tidy.
We're sweeping the gentry out of
this land, not sweeping floors.
Who said that?
Elias.
Take a broom and sweep the floor.
If anyone talks back to him one more
time, he's going to answer to me!
I came to ask
if I could use the telephone.
It's your telephone, go right ahead.
We could use you here, you know.
I might help you in some matters
of a civilian nature.
You need a pass. You can get one
at the people's hall.
How can Aleksi Koskela
be a part of this?
I have my orders.
Maybe I'll run and get one for you.
Or if you would...
-Don't you have any manners?
He's doing important guard work
and doesn't have time -
to listen to uncivilised people
giving him abuse.
I will not accept
an illegal travel pass.
Write away,
she can take it or leave it.
Taking that paper would mean
acknowledging your authority.
My conscience doesn't permit it.
Your conscience has permitted
many things. I don't value it much.
Let's make her wash pans
with the girls.
I'll wash latrines if I have to!
No task is too menial to ensure
the rights of the Finnish people.
I offered you a pass, but if you
don't want one, you can stay home.
You have never washed
your own latrine -
so stop bragging.
Spare us your speeches!
Lauri, escort the lady
back to the parsonage!
I've decided to stay home
and help Anna with the housekeeping.
Just you go in and have coffee.
You could get killed.
Well, that is the last reason
that would keep me away.
That's reason enough for me.
I don't intend to be hanged.
I gave up my position
in the Association too.
I don't want to discuss things that
are decided with mob justice.
I have marched together with
the proletariat for a long time.
I cannot turn back on them now,
even if I disagree on some issues.
Let's return to the Workers' Hall
for an equipment check.
Those two men you sent
to the church village.
What did you write on the paper
you gave them?
How and where they were caught,
nothing else.
They have been killed.
Don't blame it on me.
That paper is at the headquarters.
My conscience is clear.
This makes it
difficult for me to return...
I wrote they'd been apprehended
hiding beside the road -
that they had avoided patrols
and had no papers.
They were not dangerous men.
-Blame those who shot them.
Pentinkulma headquarters,
Koskela speaking.
I see.
Valenti, come take this down,
there's a message.
Yes?
We're going to the front.
We can expect
a lot of running and crying.
I wrote my goodbyes, as you're not
speaking to me any longer.
You don't need to reply.
You can go to the front, and I
won't cry if the butchers kill you.
You never say a nice word.
Always shooting off your mouth.
I'll be fetching suet
from Pentti house tonight.
But I will not see you off,
so don't expect it.
Is this your new guarding post,
or why are you standing there?
You wrote that you'd be here.
Did you think...
Jesus, what are you thinking?
Don't play games.
Why did you write then?
I just wanted to say goodbye.
Now give me a kiss for my trouble.
Don't spit at me.
You deserve a spanking!
Don't think you can play me
for a fool. That's a mistake.
If just for once.
Even once. But always.
I don't know what I should do.
-You know.
Just a kind word once in a while.
Don't go to the front. Run away.
Let's leave together.
They don't ask questions now.
-I have to go.
Will you come back to me?
No matter what?
Of course I will.
You can do
whatever you want with me.
Don't worry.
I'll write to you soon.
Father says that we're going to
get more land from Töyry.
Mother promised me new clothes -
when the proletariat is in power,
and the poor are allowed to buy.
I know that Akseli doesn't like me,
or any of you at Koskela.
Don't say that. That's in your mind.
You don't care for me.
-What's the matter again?
You sound so dull when you say it.
How cheerful should I sound?
Swear it.
Let's put our hands together
like two horse dealers.
Don't laugh. You mustn't laugh
when you're taking an oath.
Say: "I like you."
-I like you.
"When I come back from the front,
I'm going to marry you."
When I come back from the front,
I'm going to marry you.
Let's be very dear to each other.
Eat out of the bark box first.
It's older.
What have they done to the world?
-Both sides are to blame.
Shall we wear our neckties?
-Why would we do that?
We're going to Tampere, right?
-We're not going there to have fun.
Don't be so happy.
You're putting your heads
into the wolf's mouth.
This is the final battle. After
this, all weapons will be destroyed.
Don't joke about it. Who knows
whose final battle this is.
Come say goodbye to father, boys.
Be good little boys while I'm away.
Men don't miss anyone.
-Right.
Mother's crying in the bedroom.
There's no conductor
to check our tickets this time.
This is our very own train.
We can stop wherever we want.
If we had bullets, we'd shoot
every time we pass a station.
Mark my words, we won't go
any further than Tampere.
The newspaper said that Mannerheim
has gone to an unknown place -
to assemble a new army,
after his old one ran away.
I shed tears all night, thinking
that destiny will tear us apart.
I hope we'll see each other again,
though I fear otherwise.
Don't go to the veryfront, stay in
the back. No matter how they ask.
Think only of your faithful friend
waiting for you back home.
We'll get some land somewhere, and
a small cottage where we can live.
If the parsonage lands are split up,
you'll probably get some of theirs.
I'll learn to sow and cook and all.
Every evening after work
I go home and think about you.
When you return,
you can keep me for a long time -
and do what you wish with me.
With love, your special friend.
My country-dwelling comrades,
tenant farmers and farmhands!
With the authority vested in me by
the northern front -
I bid you welcome to Tampere.
You will join forces with
your factory worker comrades -
in the common fight-
against the butchering horde
of oppressors and enslavers!
When the noble Red Guard marches -
the poor rejoice and the
butchers' hearts tremble with fear!
In Varkaus, the butchers took one in
ten of our men from the line -
and shot them right there,
civilian or not.
Ylöstalo,
come over for negotiations.
When are we going to get
the clothes? -What clothes?
They promised that we'd get
clothes for the poorer folk.
We haven't promised you anything.
Come with me, Akseli.
Silent boys, these two.
It's best not to lose this fight.
It's easier to have
just one way to go.
Not a step back,
that is the way to the grave.
What is it?
Butchers!
Osku.
What is it?
-We must push on.
Charge!
What is it? Go on!
Go on yourself, dammit!
Goddammit!
Charge!
Don't gather on the road.
Osku, secure your front,
and let's move.
They have machine guns. Come on!
-Osku!
Do you think I can help it?
Remember, the order
to charge concerns everybody!
I did charge.
-And me.
All of Ostrobothnia, Savo and
Karelia are in White hands.
I must admit I was losing hope.
The Whites are approaching Tampere
as fast as an automobile goes.
This is some piece of news. Indeed.
How could I doubt? How could I?
It's hell up ahead, boys.
Charge!
It looks easy enough on a map.
Goddammit!
Boys, help me!
Someone save Arvi!
-You do it!
Where are you? Help!
Where are you hit?
No good.
Line up!
They're flanking us.
Keep the positions, men.
Keep cool, boys!
-Don't fall back!
Line up, soldiers of the revolution!
I have always enjoyed
my visits here -
but this time
I'd rather have stayed away.
I come with awful news.
Your son is among
the company's deceased.
I see.. I see. That too.
They put one in the poor house
and one in prison.
Someone should
send them to their God.
He's no master after all.
-The butcher is having a big sleep.
Ostrobothnian farmers have forced
their farmhands to the front.
The bosses never
fight their own wars.
I hear there's heavy fighting
in Vilppula.
Maybe they'll push through there.
Nobody is going to push through
if they trust that the others will.
So what are we going to do?
I don't know.
Ylöstalo has sent out an orderly
for instructions.
If we're staying here,
we're in for a hell of a night.
Our clothes are wet and it's
damn cold. Go ask him what's up.
It's gone wrong all the way.
They've taken one village somewhere,
but nothing else.
We've been told
to hold these positions for now.
If we're spending the night here,
we need warm food. -Right.
Why don't you get us some.
Damn it.
We all must participate in the work.
Also the manor. -I need no advice.
I taught new farming methods,
I brought new cows!
I don't need your advice,
I don't start with you.
I recommend you sign this agreement.
-Leave! I sign no paper.
I'll send some men over there
from regional intelligence.
Are these men up to their task?
-They're good boys, all right.
I don't want to see
any kind of blackmail happening.
If the man doesn't sign
the agreement, he'll be arrested.
We hear you've made some hiding
places. We'd like to see them.
You go ahead, look.
-Let's talk a little first.
Stand up, this is an interrogation!
When the gendarmes interrogated me,
I had to stand for three hours!
Where are the manor's arms?
-I gave them away.
So you've armed a
counterrevolutionary organisation.
That's a serious crime.
You'll sign an agreement where
you'll refrain from such action.
This is your pledge of allegiance
to the people's delegation.
I can give no pledge.
-Sign the paper.
I can not.
-Sign it, you damn bloodsucker!
Please, leave old people alone.
Have mercy.
Please leave, madam.
Sign their paper, please.
I can not. Don't ask it of me.
Sir, you're under arrest.
Get dressed,
you're coming with us.
Let's stretch our legs.
Throw the body in the ditch.
The ice is partially melted.
It'll sink all right.
Your interrogators
have murdered the baron.
Answer me truthfully:
was this your intention?
You worry more about the
gentry's safety than the revolution.
Killing an old, harmless man
is not my idea of revolution.
Listen, Aatu.
I never ordered any killing.
We're fighting for survival here.
Attacks have been
thwarted on all fronts.
However much you come down
on the baron's murderers -
you won't be spared if we lose.
Those to be killed have been named,
and you are one of them.
I am too, and so are
Ylöstalo, Silander, and Koskela.
Come on now.
I can do that.
Vilho. Go ask grandma to come here.
Fear not, for God has set an end
to Satan's time as well.
Fear not, for Satan can only claim
our bodies, not our souls.
The courage displayed
by the deceased -
is an example of the ultimate price
of justice and truth.
Anxiety and fear have visited
our homes frequently as of late.
May God forgive these people,
if he can.
Maybe he can do that,
which we petty people can not.
The Pastor made
the Baron's funeral -
into a counterrevolutionary
agitation rally. We don't like that.
That subject was unavoidable
in this case.
I've condemned the murderers.
Surely you have no objections?
You should stick to the Gospel
instead of interpreting the law.
This is the second time you have
brought politics to the church.
We must place you under arrest
for the time being.
The bosses used to put
the poor into the poor house -
so it is only fitting that the poor
put the bosses in the same place.
I'll come with you.
-No need. There's nothing to fear.
Don't worry. I'm not worried.
-I'll come see you in the morning.
Bring a Bible. The small one.
Maybe I could put in a word
for the Pastor.
I thank you, Koskela,
but I don't think that's of any use.
But the child needs baptising.
Maybe I'll have a word.
-They wouldn't listen to you.
But thanks anyway.
Stand there, listen and shut up.
Do you remember them contracts
you had me do -
though you knew that
one man can't do them in a day?
Don't. Please, don't!
You shut up, you cow!
You! Harness a horse and take grain
to the church village headquarters.
Is this an order from
the headquarters?
We're as good a headquarters
as you're going to get!
Aku!
Is it bad?
-My leg doesn't hold.
Don't leave me.
They'll just kill me.
We must delay them so that they can
take the cannons and supplies out.
Go help Aku get to the rear.
Where's Ylöstalo?
He's organising the retreat.
All hell has broken loose.
They're giving us up so the
commanders can escape in time.
Finland's best forces are leaving.
I won't stay behind to be killed.
We must keep the positions.
Keep the positions!
Run, you bastards.
Run all the way home!
Stand on the carriage and shout
"Long live the revolution".
Long live the revolution!
Let it rip, with all your might!
Have mercy, for the love of God.
Don't you start whining, you cow.
Do you remember when
my wife was near her due time?
You complained that
she's no good at working.
Now you'll bark
at the squirrel, bitch!
Bark at the goddamn squirrel of I'll
drop your husband like a grouse!
Shoot me if you want to, but be man
enough to leave a woman alone.
A revolutionary soldier
doesn't abandon his comrades.
Remember the wounded.
Healthy men, off the sleigh!
We want the horse to carry
the wounded! -Ease down, dammit!
If you leave the wounded, I shoot
first the horse and then the man.
Come with us, father.
You'll be safe there.
They can come back.
Those people have given up
their right to live.
Don't leave one seed of their
families to haunt this land.
If I'm not there on that day, you
take care of it. -They're done for.
Let them have their fun now.
It'll soon be over.
But you keep your heads down.
Many of you think that
this is no use. I understand that.
I have a family,
and would like to go to them too.
But have you thought about what's
going to happen then?
"Others will take care
of the front." Who?
There are no others, our company
is no different from any other.
There are rumours that the butchers
want the commanders, not the men.
If that were true,
I would turn myself in right away.
It's better that a few of us die
instead of everyone.
Believe me,
the butchers will not stop at that.
We're not fighting for the workers'
cause anymore, but for survival!
I'm not much of a speaker.
Make up your own minds.
There are no hospitals anymore.
You can take care
of that wound at home too.
What will I tell them at home?
-Say what you think is right.
Try to explain.
Take that, I won't need it.
You should make it all right.
You have nothing bad
on your conscience.
And try to take care of them.
Bye.
I'll try to get us permission
to visit home when we retreat.
I didn't want to tell Aku
so they won't wait for us.
What is that strange glow?
Fires have broken out.
Jesus Lord.
The Whites will break through
tomorrow afternoon at the latest.
We'll have to be gone before that.
Maybe the boys should go with you.
I'm not telling them to do anything.
But their lives aren't in danger.
I think they should stay back.
The boys have nothing coming
to them. It's different for me.
I could try anyway.
Talk to the Pastor.
No way! Don't beg
in front of that man for me.
Do that for the boys, not for me!
-Ease down, son.
It's time to swallow your pride.
Aku, someone's asking for you.
-The Laurila girl is hanging around.
Them people better leave as well,
after what they did to master Töyry.
Are you leaving?
-It won't work.
Let's take a horse and cart.
Why would you leave?
They leave women alone.
Mum says I have to.
But she and father will stay.
Uuno and I have to leave.
Otherwise we'll all get killed.
Father doesn't want to leave.
They're going to find him.
There must be some way
to sort this out.
You'll come back when it's over.
Don't think of us when you're
out there. It'll be easier for you.
It's hardest that you are here
thinking of me.
I would be okay alone,
but I'm in charge of the refugees.
What will I do
with a caravan like that?
There's no hope
anymore anyway.
What will happen now?
We'll try to break through
to Russia.
But I'll be back when I can.
I don't know how to live
without you.
Shall I wake the boys?
-Don't.
It's better that way.
Name him Voitto (= Victor).
Goodbye.
Don't cry now,
we must stand firm.
Where's Aku?
-By the drying barn.
Well... Bye then.
It's about time for Elma to leave.
You must be at the church
by midday.
You'll have your own
horse and driver.
I'm too weak for that road.
If I fall here,
at least I'll fall in my home.
Well, goodbye then.
Goodbye. I wish you luck.
Let's go to the headquarters!
-In the middle of the night? Why?
Headquarters' orders. If you
don't go, you'll die right there.
Do you remember all the old stuff?
Now is the time.
I haven't done any wrong
that I know of.
You've been waiting for this day
like a steed for summer-
but you won't see
the butchers celebrate.
Stop!
Our Father, who art in Heaven.
Hallowed be thy...
Because of you and your bad deeds
the innocent are punished.
This authorises the confiscation.
Be at the church by eleven.
Do you have to do the confiscation?
People are staying behind.
We have to. Otherwise
the refugees will go hungry.
We need horses and food.
Don't you weep, old woman.
Are you on guard?
I'm just checking out what happens.
Give that rifle to Oskari. Don't
keep it under any circumstances.
And say that you were
forced to join the Guard.
Goodbye now.
Try to make it as best you can.
Who are you, old man?
Me? The name is Kivivuori.
Are there Reds in the village?
-They left yesterday.
If you're lying, you'll die.
Go see for yourself
if you don't believe.
We've been waiting for you so much.
I'm the pastor of this municipality
and would like to bid you welcome.
Where's Uuno?
-He's gone, you know that.
We'll find him, no matter what. And
you'll soon walk through the gates!
Shoot me now!
Why walk me around?
You'll have some time to think.
Walk!
All right.
Put on some clothes and go.
Did you come for me?
-Didn't I say that already?
You know I oppose violence.
-Is that so? Let's go now.
Did Akseli leave?
-Yes. He's gone.
There is a new rule on the land now.
Remember that, Elina.
Boys, come with us.
-They haven't done any harm.
If there's nothing...
Everyone will be investigated.
I don't know about the boys,
but Akseli better stay in hiding.
Hurry up!
Vilho...
Keep that for yourself.
What is it? Butchers?
They say we can't go through Lahti.
Line up, everyone
who is able to fire a rifle.
Put that gun away.
-I can go as well as you.
If you weren't such cowards,
we wouldn't be in this mess.
Come on, take guns!
Come on! What are you afraid of?
Charge!
Is everything all right?
Ilmari!
So, the following night
three men arrived at the manor.
The men weren't looking for guns -
but they took the baron with them
and murdered him on a nearby bridge.
What do you say to this?
You know my principles, gentlemen.
Questions like that
serve no purpose.
Do you admit
calling the local headquarters -
and asking for these men
to be sent to the manor?
I made that call, but I didn't...
-Do you plead guilty to this murder?
The accusation alone is insane.
Take him into the hallway.
I didn't accept the permit, and they
threatened to make me clean toilets.
Who threatened you? -Akseli Koskela,
he was the main boss here.
He was in charge of the looting. And
he sent two young men to be shot.
We made a grave mistake.
We practically pushed suffrage
down their throats.
Well, live without honour,
die without honour.
They'll die without honour,
no doubt about that.
For mutiny against the legal order -
participation in
murder and looting -
and unlawful
deprivation of liberty -
you are sentenced to be
executed by firing squad.
Why don't you let me die
for my cause?
Do you have to disgrace me
by calling me a murderer?
That is a nonsensical accusation.
Haven't you given enough
agitation speeches?
I will die soon,
because you want it to happen.
But control your anger -
for in three weeks' time
you'll be wishing you had.
Gentlemen, you are the ones
to blame for this rebellion.
You're only shooting the ghosts
of your own ignorance and greed.
I've told you that you cannot kill
ghosts by shooting -
but you didn't listen.
So have mercy on yourselves
and give lenient sentences.
Gentlemen, behind my
veneer of insignificance -
lies a great witness:
the inevitable order of life.
The coming decades
will make you believe these words.
Per aspera ad astra.
About Jokinen.
It would be fine to shoot him -
but there's no-one else
to run the machine at the sawmill.
This winter's logs are still uncut,
and there's life after this also.
Fine, if it's like that.
We'll give him forced labour.
If I find another man,
shoot him then.
Is that a wagtail? This early?
It's not a wagtail,
it's just nodding.
Off the carriage. Hurry!
Mother!
Run, girl, run!
What do you want, Kivivuori?
I came to discuss the sentences
and the court as a whole.
What's there to discuss? -A lot.
Like the composition of the court.
Some of you
are obviously plaintiffs.
Can you find one law-abiding citizen
who's not a plaintiff?
In that case you should wait
for your heads to cool off.
Kivivuori should stop
distorting the law and leave.
I've kept myself well clear
of the rebellion -
and resisted it more strongly
than you ever dared.
I would be better suited
to be in the court than you.
I told you to leave!
Well, do as you will then.
You'll fill a lot of graves,
but you won't be killing socialism.
At least you'll get your whim.
In my opinion, the younger
Koskela brothers are good boys.
They've been led astray
by their older brother.
They hardly would have joined
the rebellion without him. -Right.
Right, about the Koskela boys.
For their father's sake as well,
he's a very good man.
Yes, he is.
Since the court disagrees,
we'll have to vote.
We got the bullet.
Both of us.
Tell them back home,
but don't let them come see us.
But if it isn't Valpri?
Your armband has faded badly.
I almost didn't recognise you.
Ylöstalo, Kalle Armas!
He went to the municipal building.
Jäger Lieutenant Ilmari Salpakari.
I have the honour of offering to you
our municipality's greetings.
To a Finnish Jäger,
from a thankful nation.
Thank you.
That's ugly.
The road is cut off.
-They say there are Germans ahead.
What do we do?
-We must try and break through.
Don't cry, dear child.
One must be tough in this world.
One must not break down.
You know they don't mean any harm,
Mr Pastor.
I tried all I could,
I gave a good statement on the boys.
But the hatred is so strong.
The murders...
-But not our boys.
I realise this is very hard for you.
I could try to put in one more word.
But you should go yourself.
They listen to the father better.
What's the matter with you?
-Nothing.
You're not crying for nothing,
are you?
How is that your business?
Go to hell, I can cry if I want to.
The sentences will now be carried
out, under my supervision.
Halme, Aadolf Aleksander.
-Present.
Laurila, Anton Kustaa.
Daddy! Daddy!
Koskela, Aleksis Johannes.
Koskela, August Johannes. -Present.
Ylöstalo, Kalle Armas.
-Present.
Move!
Daddy!
Daddy... Daddy!
Let me help.
-No! I can do it.
Silence! No singing.
You can't order us any more.
So the socialists
are singing hymns now?
Halt!
Halme and Ylöstalo, stand there.
You can turn your backs if you wish.
Ylöstalo, take your place.
Goodbye, comrades.
I take refuge in God's mercy
as I die. -Attention!
But I am innocent before man.
-Fire!
Silander and Laurila!
I have something to say
to this pair.
Bury me standing, so you'll need
to waste less land on me!
Fire!
The Koskela brothers!
Which way shall we stand?
Face forward.
Goodbye, and don't be afraid.
Attention!
Fire!
I crossed master Halme's hands.
Although they kind
of told me not to.
When you go to Koskela house,
don't speak of the boys' bodies.
Just say they looked peaceful,
like sleeping.
You know what to say.
They looked like they were sleeping.
No bullet holes or anything.
I took Aleksi's good overcoat.
I'd buy it from you,
if you don't need.
You can have Aleksi's other jacket.
It's so hard to see it
on someone else.
Master Halme was the same as ever.
They boys were
kind of smiling even.
Is it my turn? We don't have
anyone else left to shoot.
I want to speak to Elina.
Elina Koskela gets special tasks,
since she's the headman's wife.
The commandant's orders.
We do this every Saturday,
and it's never been funny before.
How indecent can you get?
Go home, Elina.
Commandant Salpakari
ordered this.
I don't care if it was Mannerheim.
It's indecent all the same.
Would it be possible
to bury them in hallowed ground?
Not just yet. People have objected
to burying them in the churchyard.
But we have the grave
that we bought.
Yes, you do have the grave.
But let's wait for
the hate to subside a bit.
The boys never hurt anybody.
As I understand, they weren't
accused of hurting anyone.
They were accused of
armed rebellion.
Listen. I still have one
very nasty thing to tell you.
Akseli hasn't paid rent
for the tenancy -
and the congregation's board have
taken it as a termination of lease.
I see.
It doesn't concern you, only Akseli.
Right.
Charge! Forward!
Osku, get down..!
Osku!
Osku.
There you are.
We want this man first.
-Is he well known?
Very well indeed,
he's Akseli Koskela!
So, Koskela, many people
back home are missing you.
You cannot have him.
He's important for our intelligence.
You should be next to
Halme and your brothers.
Where are they then?
They're in the ground.
And you will be soon, too.
But we're taking Laurila back.
We have some unfinished business.
Where are the church villagers?
-We don't know.
We've been in our own group.
We'll find them all right.
And we won't forget you either.
Don't remember me badly, sister.
You're a company commander.
Why haven't you reported yourself?
Nobody asked.
-Follow me.
Koskela, Akseli Johannes!
Tell me, how many murders have you
got on your conscience? -None.
No bloody wonder.
That's because
you have no conscience.
Which do you prefer:
will we send you home to be shot,
or would you rather die here?
Here.
You're one of the
most wanted men back home.
I can see it in your eyes
that you're a bandit.
Stand to attention!
I'm an officer!
Don't touch me!
Number one.
Water Water.
Where are we?
Give these to Valenti.
I'm doing cleaning work for a
sergeant major, he gave me bread.
Don't insist.
Just ask once in a while.
Goodbye.
They're making the Reds white,
goddammit.
Has the prisoner been an agitator?
-Yes, a leading soul.
For revolution?
Against the legitimate government?
-Yes, a leading soul.
Read the statement
from his home municipality.
"We view the prisoner as completely
useless and a menace to society -
and unable to function
as a member of organised society."
"We demand the hardest penalty
there is, the penalty of death."
"A. Yllö, civil judge,
A. Mellola, sawmill owner-
Hjalmar Pajunen, farmer."
For partaking in murder and looting,
treason and high treason -
the prisoner is issued
the death penalty -
and sentenced to lose
his civil rights for all time.
As this verdict was
the result of a vote -
it will be reviewed
by the state criminal court.
In addition, you are free
to petition the said court.
If this is my last letter,
I bid you farewell.
It's better that you don't know
the date and time -
but I'll remember you when it comes.
Your husband and father
Akseli Koskela.
If you write to me, you need to
label the letters "condemned".
They're going to kill him. They are.
I'll go too, I won't be left alone.
Don't, for God's sake.
Think of the children.
I have some news.
We've been able to undo
Akseli's eviction.
I see.
I heard a rumour -
that some death sentences will be
changed into life imprisonment.
What would you say about that?
-I'm too tired to think.
I've heard rumours before,
but I didn't want to say anything.
But now I can tell you
that it is true.
Here's a letter from him.
Don't start bawling right away,
but he's been saved.
It's a long time all right,
but I'm sure it will be reduced.
What do I care about years?
He'll live!
Subtitles: Topi Oksanen
Broadcast Text International