I want to see a bear bear
Bears Bears Bears Bears Bears
Child child child child child
I have to look at the bear
No Bears
How the
Dad's body is getting cold
Increasingly stiff
I
To make Daddy warm
In order to remember the warmth of my father
Dad touched until the dawn
But
Only my hands warm
Father
Ice cold
Become stiff
Rarely do you cry so
wave-like feelings
Good morning.
And skipping ah
I am sorry
Although the Kanazawa how you do your freedom
But it is best to go to school
The third year you will regret it
Takano predecessors you regret it
I yo
Because did not go to class?
Total sleep because the class
Feed
Stand up
I do not do it just a kiss
Do not joke
I'm serious.
Do you like me
No ah
Not like you
Why
Just want to try to kiss feeling
The second class began to take on yo
Welcome
Waiting
Nothing to wait a little while
What you say to me
I ask what need points
Blue Mountain
Good
How the
About things today ...
I ...
That was my first time too
Takano predecessors ...
I ...
From before the beginning of ...
From before the beginning like you
I actually
It is the woman's body produces interest
Is no one indifferent
You drink it fast
You really honest
I am very distressed
Na big sister
Today it free
Look what you have to say things
Go without a drink
I treat
Little girl has such a great tone work
I have something to ask of you
Only the mother we do
Daughter no matter what the final compromise could
Will treat you as an adult to deal with is not it
It can be said to wash their hands ah
Waiting
THX
My dad's a good annoying
Decent always say injury
Why would not a little bit rational
I do not know what you would do so uneasy
I am also disturbed by it
By the way what you want to please me
I'm going to look at hospital
Surgery requires an emergency contact person
So tell me about address
Who
I am me
Been asleep ah
A little nap
Wait
What happened to you so long
Good Fana you
Why should I hide from me
Why ah
You take the tram into an earlier than my back right
Why
We do not always meet
But
Every time we meet
You will touch my body
So do not met
If you keep it that way
Even if I am happy you will not do
But
You told me it would only demand on the body
Other than that I have no interest to
I'm not your favorite type of girls
So this kind of thing to go on then
It will become no feelings of
But
It has always been the way you want me to take the initiative
From the outset
So you should refuse my offensive ah
But
If I refuse your quest
We can not say even if all of it
Then you take off it
I like your image before you take off it again
You do not want it
Off fast ah
Shirt off
Cold
Why not refuse ah
Clearly tell you is why do not refuse to play play ah
I
Can not help but eat your
I do not cherish your
Crying
I had a dream
What dreamed
An exclusive one canned oranges
Always wanted to try again
The first time wages finally did get to work
It seems not eat enough of it
Sequelae ah
Brothers and sisters more than one
What will leave sequelae
And sister, who more who less often because it fights
Next Saturday
My mom to come
To do
She wanted to see what my apartment
And so
You do not come oh
How the
I go back
Tomorrow Sunday ah
Bye
Really go ah
Akwan
I
As long as you want me to say
I heard you
If I could come in handy if a little
That my body is yours
You forget it
I take the 4:00 tram back
Do not go
In any case, either
After that we no longer see the ah
I can not stand such a
You lift the other end
Small quarter?
He left me one night
Me
It is also a heavy smell of disinfectant
And so ...
But the body can actually live it is no problem
It is hungry friends
These ones
Eat it
Sister
You have
Men do
There ah
Considered to have a
You will do him like a baby
Ah Wang a meow one
Why do women spoiled it
Who knows
Because that he will cherish you?
Absolutely not
Why keep up his contacts ah
Because I like
What kind of love
So you can do like spoiled
We are free to baby
Contact sports like
What treasure count it
What I say will cherish cherish him
Do not know much
So
Like this relationship Maichun
It is not the same
But just like that ah
I bought a hand bag ah what clothes
Because older than me
My age more than doubled it
That right
He says what cherished things are not touchable
Marriage should not to walk right field
More fool me not just talk
Even the feeling is not necessarily true
Even if you have children to no avail
Have anything to say it
I have nothing to say
Not so
Do not ambush me please in this place
No
Today is not your duty
I changed with others
Stop following me
You have to
When a father
What
What ah
Really!
Ah
I do
I feel like you are in a lie
Really I did not come of holidays
Almost two weeks
I fought for you money can always be right
I would like to be born
He wanted to raise
To late
It's okay
Not work
What does not work
Be sure to take the bike bus
I want a child like you
I am only responsible to pay
The fish bones shaved
Then easy to eat smaller share
You do not like  Lung Tang Yang  it
Lung Tang Yang
after 竜 Tian Yang げ the smell of fish, \ N the meat by soy sauce and mirin marinated \ N-stick frying potato flour from
I just like to eat
Article mackerel does not do what how the line
I'm your mother ah
Ready to go out to work
Irritated now a skilled work
Eyes a bit see
Was pinned too can be hard to do
Stay at home is always a person
Anyway, for a person looking for a relaxing meal points
But needlework'd make more money ah
What work
Pharmaceutical factory dormitory
Warden Boyle
I would not want to live there
How to do it at home
So slightly
Some took a change of clothes and bits and pieces of the past
If dry tired I'll be back soon anyway
From the married when I have eaten so much bitter
Not wronged himself
When did it start
Next week
So ah
To the
Not tell you not to come today Well
I know why I come
Why
Let me see your mother
Quick to cook it
Good
You go back
I'll put the oil quickly cut fish
Faster
Oil will burst
Fast say ah call you back
You see this oil is not wasted
You open letter to me, ah
Really all you write
Is
Really really
Yes it is
When you come back late at night
I also went to the bus station to pick you up for what
In the evening
Even if there is something to buy
What will not let you go out to
Spoil what your parents pay
In the end what you want
What's on your mind
What do you think
I am sorry
This is simply not the answer
Good answer me
So I said, ah sorry
He did not say to make you an apology
I do not want to apologize
Put his body to like people
What is wrong with you
What "to"
You take a look at himself wrote it
Read you gave me to read ah
Are you fine
At the beginning of this "may make you uncomfortable reading
"It must be because I have consciously
"I know for you is a very annoying presence
"But at the same time for you
"Even if only part of my body is necessary
"So we formed a relationship between us
"Now even if you live in Tokyo
"You still need me do not you
"You told me how you can
"I just want to stay by your side
"Even if I saw for once a year
"As long as you are willing to follow me conventions
"I would rather meet."
I went on to finish
"You seem to be afraid
"I probably would want to see me
"But even so I do not mind
"Only a tool to satisfy your desire does not matter
"As long as you I have any trace of demand
"That
"My body does not matter how kind
"So do not worry
"To reassure you reassure me
"Marriage trouble etc.
"I will not let you have these troubled
"My own thing I resolved
"Even if you do not a bride
"I can live a life
"Be sure to let me see you."
The ashamed of you or that you regret
My mother my whole people do better
Those are just my truth
In the end you know what
I feel it does not matter
I am simply not like you do whatever they want
Lose is you ah
This is not something to eat do not suffer
I am willing to let him sleep me
You say I done
I have not done in this life so nasty thing
How do I know
Where you did not make love to me
Little bastard
You do
What is the difference with Maichun
Saying only satisfy his desires tool
Not that prostitutes do
Even if you can not play like this ah
No
We are not playing
You play a kid how to do
Contraceptive what we have to do
Fool
Fool fool fool
Do such things bother
Watching you sick
Out
Give me out
Get out ah
Come
Guess you will come
Sit down over there
Have something to say soon
Frankly have poured Come
You can blame me hate me
So I also lighter
Then we end it
I would not say hate you
Because I like you, ah
Do you like to paint it
Ah
Why draw
I only draw the
I can prove that there is still alive
Painting is my only property of
I
When I heard that might make you pregnant when very painful
You may be more painful than I
I do not want to have a second time
Time
You said the money was only responsible
Indeed it makes me cold spine
I can only say that ah
Because you know
Children not born
Are you ready to go back a few
5:58
It would go faster
I would like to stay here
Go back to it
Do not disturb my life
Into my heart where people live
Are you ah
So I ...
So I was very painful ah
Painting me
You still go back is better
I do not care, ah
Do not cry
Do not
I'm back
Where were you so late
I am sorry
What did you do have to apologize to do it
No apology does not matter what it
Then you just track what apology
People do not see things right
I say you ah
Now is not the most important thing period
Strange things are going to do how to do
I asked you a good review bar exam
I also had a young man wanted to do the
The results are said no way because I'm a woman
So I hope you can not even mom mom's sake
But also with good dreams
Mom will try
I do not want people to think that our family
What it could not pay because there is no father College Students
Stomach growling
And the man doing the wretched thing was hungry right
Shame
Think of all terrible light
I brought you not to let you sleep with men
In order to live up to now in the end what ah
Mom me so hard
All in vain
If your father is still the case
You'd rather know me
I want to leave the house
Darn
Back to being scolded might as well not go home
It is not because of your own doing a good thing
Now it has to go to bed for casual and men while away from home
You do not shame not smell of urine
Darn
Husband you can be good ah
He died as early as possible
Now her daughter grew up
I was worried she does
She began doing inexplicable things clean
I am in the end how to do ah
I do not think so painfully alive the
Not as easily die here Forget
Husband
I also want you there ah
Each time was scolded her daughter
I have always been scolded ah
I obviously raising her so hard
Husband
To whom can I complain it
Mom
I
Woman ah
I am also a woman ah
I do not intend to repeat
But the home environment also can not improve it
I decided to run away from home
I can not say anything
You just do your mother's good daughter very good
My normal way
Meet me now to show that you are not normal
I Normal
You even admitted that no university
So you understand me Well
What I want to understand ah
So my feelings
Do
Lying is also OK
As long as you say, "I know what I know you."
I can tenacious and fight my mom
So I can stick to it
I say no
I say sorry
I need someone to understand me
I do not want to be treated as a stupid woman only know to go to bed
Time has come to me to go back
Do not follow me
Wait
Well I do not follow
I let you go ah
Do not
Enough you quickly go back
You do not say I did not know back
He went out
Like playing marbles of
Akwan
Where have you been
I play marbles up
Win yet
100 yuan earned a lot of stuff too
Very powerful thing
Your mom back yet
Grace
I
In a time when you come
Find your chest changing color
At that time I felt doing incredible things happen under
No change ah
My sister also said it will not change it several times
And she will say that kind of thing do
She asked me chasing
And then
What your sister said
That you are not there other men
I can not help it
I am here besides trying to break up as soon as possible
Without any other ideas die
No matter how
So say too much
My sister was afraid I was forced you
And
And what
In the end to say something
It's nothing
Anyway, I just started sleeping mind play play chant
Not because they like me
Just interested in a woman's body
Said that
Net say the last thing to solve the problem
I can not stand you
What do you want
Come back home
Go to return tomorrow morning
Do not
Let me go back
I was wrong
Not bad for you
I do not like your sister's man
In the end told me how to do ah
I do not know
So more irritable
Until your mother Why ignore me
I do not like it
I hate her man
Do you prefer she did not recognize it
Right
I
You have not been admitted
Not anymore
Why
What changes do
Why ah
Woman is really easy ah
Do not bite me
That we live with it
The original odds because we are not together
Because we are not serious
I like you
I'm sorry to delay your work
It's okay
Akwan please me
Let me apologize to you
Because after listening to what your body
I say black is evidence nipples fucks
He said you angry yet
Because it is not black
I'm sorry
I used to say I have been a man very hurt
Women really trouble ah
Akwan then you really worry about the
So I want to tell him to let him give up on you
Kuan also said I did not like you
So I think you two are no longer meet but also to Hello
Now you very smooth ah
So he brought me to apologize
What man is really headstrong
Labour you bother
Oh, do not bully him
Sorry about to be closed down
Thank you, patrons
Obviously such a dazzling night
The tree will not sleep around
Beat It
The quilt spread it
Incidentally, turn off the lights ah
Not to sleep ah
Why
I wanted to say
Why should I tie
You can sleep dead
There shrine shrine yo
Ah already drink enough
Stop the  ginger ale  What's the
ginger ale
The same  Japanese pronunciation "ginger ale" in the first half and \ N "shrine"
Tengteng
For a long time I did not do the rice may be a bit musty
To
Nothing good to eat
People eat
Not work
I do not like rice
Good good good
I do not want to eat
This is always a good meal after eating it
Do not say a thing
Did you know
I slept with others
Are you kidding me
Is it true
I see you had never been seen before
To me you do not care to show their talent right sex
No
I lie to you
Just kissed it
Next came true
Pain
I am really sleep it
Who What When
Do you like the guy you
That's okay with you, right
You do not like me
You are looking for comfort of the bar
I'm not wrong
Now I cherish you
While the former did not like you
But now I love you ah
Not like it is now
I'm from the outset, with your love
I do not do that with a few others
And what you did just what
You take my body to do
Said Tuesday it does not matter to tell you the
Why be angry with me now
You know what idiot
Hit me ah
Enjoy playing it
I like you just hit your
I hate it
I hate the person you sleep
I hate course
So, now you look back before you
Sure
You will feel hateful
Into this room yet
Just on that bed and he has done it
How do
It does not matter how it
It appears to be really ah
This
What is not as usual
Takano seniors
I
From before the beginning of
It would have been like with you
who made me cry ni de mo love Connecticut woman ru ru na ba ni na me cry Mizuho-do
Should women become everyone love
inter メ ku ni na ~ te
will increasingly fall
private ga ~ te
I can do
who made me cry kara wa moo suspected female ni na me cry ba ru ru na Mizuho-do
Should everyone become disgusted woman
strong ~ te ku ku na
will be more powerful
private mo い ru
so I can
na ta-do っ Mizuho shi chi ga ka い の
Which would you rather have me
wa っ ki shi te ri na ki ゃ ku me cry
Please tell me clearly
ta ma ra nai ~ te Juan ~ te
I can not afford softly sigh
private weep made me cry ku ka mo shi nai
I might cry
private wo see Ba ​​~ te
see through me
core body の ma de hold ki shi Circular te
will I hold deep into your arms
Ann made me cry ra gi ku ru
make me feel at ease
~ te ga na ta
sometimes you would be so
ko と の と san ordinary man zu ー で の Polyster
like other men
escape げ Yui ki te
escape me
virtual shi ku Connecticut made me cry ru
makes me sad
mo na ta い ru
sometimes you would be so
private chi mo-do っ と い nai ra
which I do not need you
Tonight must Circular na ku wa chi ゃ
Tonight must decide
love shi te ru ~ te Juan ~ te
I love you softly sigh
one weeping made me cry ku ka mo shi nai
weep alone
love shi te ru ~ te Juan ~ te
I love you softly sigh
private weep made me cry ku ka mo shi nai
I might cry