Nothing!
Keep looking.
Where's Yukihira?
Don't know.
Figures.
Yukihira, where are you?
I found what you wanted.
Copy
Nishimura?
You're under arrest.
Nishimura!
Stay with him.
Yukihira, give me back up!
Copy.
"Drop your weapon"?
Drop your weapon!
Sorry. I get impatient.
And I wanted him alive.
Look after Nishimura.
So tell me...
how'd you know the chip
was in a wine case?
The company chairman
is a wine buff.
He gives it to all his clients.
I got his secretary drunk.
That's all you had?
And a drinker's hunch.
Drinker's hunch, huh?
Shall I use it to predict what
you're going to say next?
Shoot.
"Luck is the only reason
you're still alive today."
"We don't need loose cannons."
Right?
You're in Public Security now.
Our motto is different
What's that?
"All's well that ends well"...
or something.
So? You find it?
Don't rush me.
Are you even working?
Like there's no tomorrow.
This is very important
to me, Kaoru
What makes you so sure
there is a hidden file?
I'm sure It's there.
Evidence of internal corruption.
You're not worried you're
digging too deep?
Why do you say that?
You know something?
Hurry or you'll be late.
Sorry Maki, go on ahead.
Maki?
The sitter.
See you later
Bye, Mom.
My ex is in New York
The sitter's driving Mio to school.
Bad idea. I advise against cars.
What're you talking about?
Can you find it or not?
Not
You know! 'm not good at
this kind of thing.
If only we had Hasumi.
What?
It'd be nothing for her.
Whatever. I'm coming over
Somebody call an ambulance!
Hurry!
Mio!
The world doesn't play fair.
If you want justice....
it's an eye for an eye
Fire is best fought with fire
UNFA! R: the movie
You must have some idea, Yukihira.
Who wants you dead?
I don't know.
You don't know.
A lot of people, no doubt.
Wherever you go, you leave
a trail of bodies
Yet you always come out unscathed.
You're a piece of work
I truly pity the child that
has you for a mother.
Why?
Forgive me, Mio.
Again.
It's all my fault.
Phone call, Ms. Yukihira.
I'm Yukihira.
I have a call?
Hello?
The parents of that sitter who
died in your stead called.
From Kanto Hospital.
I'm on my way
Take good care of her.
Of course
Don't worry.
Hey!! It's party time!
Hurry, please!
What's happening?
I don't know. Just evacuate.
Let's get you out of here.
Mio, I need you to hide here.
I'll be right back
Listen up, people.
Your attention, please!
We've taken over this hospital.
You over there!
Cooperate or you'll be dead
Secure the perimeter!
100 meters, no one gets in!
Get me hospital schematics!
Party time.
Our daughter's gone because of you.
I'm so sorry.
Why wasn't it you?
You should be dead!
Why?
Why'd you come?
I'm your boss
I think it's time...
I resigned.
I was so occupied with a phone
call this morning...
I can't recall my daughter's face.
Or if! even said good-bye.
I just don't remember.
A large crowd of onlookers has
gathered around the hospital.
At 10 a. m, the Toyosu
Police Hospital...
was occupied by an armed band.
Their exact number is unconfirmed,
their motives still unknown.
Police are on the scene.
What is it?
A standoff.
Brief me on the Toyosu Police
Hospital situation.
Number of hostages?
You're not sure?
Yukihira!
What's wrong?
My daughter's there.
What?
I'm sorry.
It's Saiki. Inspector Yukihira's
daughter is in the hospital.
We're nearly set up.
Heard any demands?
Not yet
They're eerily silent
Are the schematics here?
Schematics!
Yes, Sir!
This is the Toyosu Police...
What's a medical examiner doing here?
My services may be needed.
It's bad luck.
Sorry. As I was saying...
the Toyosu Police Hospital
is a state-of-the-art facility.
Every thing is run out of the central
control room underground.
It was built to resist a terrorist act.
With reinforced walls and
bulletproof windows
And monitored by a secure
police network.
One item hasn't been made public.
The basement including the control room...
is a fully-equipped shelter
Shelter? What do you mean?
In short, what we're facing gentlemen...
is a building that can double as
a highly defensible fortress.
Chief Yamaji!
What's the status inside?
Hostages? Demands?
Why're you here?
Mio's in there.
Please... let me do something.
It's not your jurisdiction.
I know but...
Let us handle it.
Sir, the hostages are being freed!
Why?
Mio.
Mio!
Sorry.
No pushing. Single file, please!
A girl, 8 years old, Mio Sato.
Seen her?
Mio Sato?
Not on my list yet.
Thanks.
If you're not injured, we need your names.
Got a profile yet?
From their attire and speech,
just a bunch of addled punks.
Should be quick
It's the Commissioner.
You're kidding
Yamaji here.
All have been accounted for, save two
whose whereabouts remain unknown.
And the perpetrators inside?
Still unconfirmed
I need to speak with you, Sir
Yukihira,! 'm busy!
- Hold it!
- Let go of me!
There's that female detective
we keep hearing about.
What about the two still missing?
One is a nurse. The other is a young girl.
The daughter of Inspector Yukihira
Her name is Mio.
Have you heard any demands?
We've been trying to make contact
but they haven't responded.
They could be after drugs... or just crazy.
Their objective is...
Director Shinozaki.
The Police Director?
He's there for a check-up
under secret guard.
Only a few know about it.
I want you to make his rescue your
top priority from here on out
His life's at stake, as is the honor of
the Metropolitan Police.
Prepare a SAT insertion
With all due respect, Sir,
isn't that a bit risky?
Yes, but inevitable.
Civilians are out. We 're lucky the only
hostages are police related.
Now hold on!
You need to leave.
What're you saying? That you'd kill
my daughter to save face?
Is that what police do?
Women.
Your orders, Sir?
We haven't the luxury of time.
Send in SAT.
Understood
Yukihira here
They're sending in SAT.
Mio's not out yet.
Please, I need your help.
I beg you.
Listen, Yukihira..
! 'm truly sorry but...
there's nothing I can do.
Sir...
results of Yukihira's car
bomb analysis
Thanks.
I'm borrowing the car.
Okay.
Same method.
The police have decided to
go in with force...
sending in a Special Assault Team.
Stand down!
We've penetrated the central entrance.
B Team...
C Team....
Rendezvous at the
first level lobby.
Copy.
Yoo-hoo, SAT boys!
It's a trap!
An intense firefight has broken out!
Listen!
Mio...
Mio!
Don't
1st Squad, come in!
Commander Hikawa!
Get me headquarters.
We've lost communication
with 1st Squad.
They were prepared.
Who are these guys?
Yukihira!
Welcoming committee here.
Open the gate.
Welcome. We're honored to
have you here, Instructor.
The insertion has been completed
Good work, Commander Hikawa
Thank you.
Status, Mr. Toda?
All secret police have been killed
All hostages have been released,
except for the Director
But we had to take the life of
one nurse who was witness.
Toda...
no more slip-ups.
Yes, Sir
Let's get to work
You're on.
Sir, still no movement inside.
Forget it, Yukihira.
It's crazy.
You can't fight these guys alone
I'm not going to fight them.
! 'm going to save Mio.
Yukihira!
I've never tried to stop you before.
But I am now.
Listen to me!
I've never been there for her
Never.
Open up.
Roger
I'm disengaging all security systems
to unlock the BSL4 Lab
Re-engaging security systems.
The antiserum, Sir.
Stay cool!
Evacuate.
Evacuate!
Don't move!
The suit's torn!
Help!
Help me, Sir!
I'm exposed!
Don't move. Just sit tight.
Irrigate!
Do something, please!
What do we do, Sir?
Sir.
Won't you inject me with the antiserum?
When we're finished.
But, Sir!
I promise to return.
I understand.
I'll wait
Stop!
Yukihira!
! f you're going,
you need to calm down
Otherwise, you'll only endanger
yourself and Mio.
Got it?
Why'd you warn me about
the car this morning?
Bad traffic.
Is that all?
Yeah
They're making contact!
Hook me up.
Yamaji here.
Get me Saiki of Public Security
Saiki?
What for?! 'm in charge.
I'll negotiate only with him.
What's our move?
Call Saiki. Get him over there.
Wait.
Hold this
Aren't you glad I came?
Voice analysis?
Working on it
Focus on people I've been
involved with.
Someone with an axe to
grind against you?
Most crimes are money or
grudge inspired, right?
A friend of yours, huh?
Let's find out.
Patch me through
Incoming call
On speaker
Who's there?
Saiki.
Here are our demands.
Wait a second
I don't like talking to strangers
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?
I don't plan on staying.
Okay Then why me?
I hear you're the least tainted
Fine
What do you want?
8 billion yen's worth of illicit
police slush funds.
8 billion?
Money that "doesn't" exist
So it shouldn't be missed.
You have 2 hours
Or the Director dies.
What 8 billion?
Did you find the hidden files?
Sorry. No luck
But you're talking about
a government secret right?
How'd you hear about it?
In clues to my father's death.
He was looking for it.
There's no such slush fund!
It's a ruse by the perpetrator.
You're absolutely sure, then?
Don't make me repeat myself!
Slush fund or not...
how should we proceed?
Shall we prepare the ransom?
We can't produce what doesn't exist.
Commissioner?
Give an order, Sir
Don't comply. Send in the second
SAT squad.
Negative.
They took out the entire first squad.
They'll be ready.
We don't bargain with terrorists.
Then you'll kill the Director
He, too, would choose death
over acquiescence.
Almost sounds like you want him dead
You're next in succession, Mr Irie.
That's insubordination.
Watch yourself.
Forgive me.
Roger
2nd SAT team's coming.
From the sewer system.
We'll take up positions.
They're sitting ducks.
Chief Yamaji...
have you seen Yukihira?
Not since she left.
I didn't expect you to oppose
the insertion.
I hate waste.
Waste, huh?
So what's Saiki like?
Why do you ask?
No reason.
The "all's well that ends well" type.
That's all I know.
It's not like you to
not know anything.
Second SAT team.
It's under the command of
company leader Kojima.
Takeshi Kojima, huh?
- Any sign they've emerged?
- Copy Team 2!
Team 2 immobilized Sir.
Hey!
Yukihira...
The first SAT team's alive
You don't suppose they did this.
I think they did.
It was an ambush.
They knew what was coming
Go right!
This way!
They'll catch up to us
I'll draw them off.
Don't be an idiot.
Mio's waiting for you
Thanks, Kaoru.
Kaoru...
Thank you.
Don't worry. My mommy
will come to get us.
I know she will.
Mio.
Field command.
Yukihira's calling
Yukihira... where are you?
Inside the hospital.
What happened to
the second SAT team?
Wiped out.
The first SAT team killed them.
Say what?
The first team took out the second
in an ambush.
That would mean...
Someone inside is tipping them off.
Someone inside?
Who's the traitor!?
I'm in the basement
Proceeding to room 602...
my daughter's room.
You alone?
Saiki?
Be careful.
Gotta go.
Sir!
Voice match
Who is it?
Kuniaki Goto.
I should've guessed.
Former SAT commander who
became police academy trainer.
January 1997.
He retired soon after blowing
the whistle on...
an internal embezzlement scandal.
He then spent 8 years in prison for
what he says are trumped charges.
He's out for revenge.
Who's the traitor?
Yukihira...
Can you hear me?
It's me.
Kaoru?
Yeah.
You escaped.
Yeah... I got lucky.
Where are you?
You find Mio?
She wasn't in her room.
Where are you?
Basement.
Gotcha. Meet me in
the first floor lobby.
Kaoru's the traitor.
Aren't you glad I came?
Kaoru's worthless
Let's go
Why's Hasumi with them?
If she's in on it then...
Let us handle it.
Send in the SAT team.
Understood.
You worried?
About what?
Yukihira?
She'll live, I guarantee you
There are no guarantees
in this world.
You came up with Goto, right?
So?
Nothing.
No one earned the loyalty
of his men like Goto.
They called him the greatest
SAT leader ever.
You find me suspect?
No, but there's no doubt
about a traitor
And you've another acquaintance
in there.
Anna Hasumi
We've got contact again
Time's up
We don't give in to terrorists.
No ransom.
We're not paying the ransom.
Then the Director dies
I'm sure he would concur
I wonder about that.
Tell them that.
It's a death warrant.
Tell them!
Well?
We won't pay
The Director would agree.
I see.
In that case...
Holy God!
You won't see that money now!
So you acknowledge its existence
Without the Director,
you have no bargaining chip.
Deposit 8 billion in a specified
account within 30 minutes
Or we release anthrax
into the city.
Say what?
You have 30 minutes.
Anthrax? Is he bluffing?
The hospital has a bio weapons research lab.
Mr Kimura?
Yes, Sir
There is an anthrax-like bacillus
that turns skin black
The immune system has no chance.
! t can spread by contact,
through airborne droplets.
In short, from person to person.
So how dangerous is it, exactly?
If all of the stock were released...
it would kill 80% of the Tokyo
population inside a week
Is there a vaccine or antidote?
There's antiserum enough for one
person inside the lab.
And another supply stored elsewhere
for government leaders.
That's all there is, I'm afraid.
Mio!
Mama
I waited for you.
I knew you would come.
Mama, will you help that
poor man?
Poor man?
Where are you?
The infection ward.
Infection ward?
Here.
Mio's inside.
With an apparently infected man.
I see a torn hazmat suit.
What?
What sort of symptoms?
What's his skin like?
His skin?
Black and splotchy.
Anthrax.
Come again?
The pathogen the terrorists possess.
They're threatening to release it
if demands aren't met.
Bioterror?
And your daughter?
How's Mio?
She's...
What?
infected
Tell me, what does this mean?
It means she'll die in hours
without the antiserum.
Get me some immediately.
Impossible.
Who's that?
The Deputy Director.
We can't spare its use on a civilian
under the current terrorist threat.
Well! 'm not going to let you
kill my daughter!
Inspector Yukihira....
Commissioner?
I want you to find the serum
and prevent the bioterror.
Or everyone in Tokyo will meet
your daughter's fate.
That's right Yukihira.
The police cannot accommodate terrorists
Help us... no, help the people of Tokyo.
There's no time. With you inside,
you're our only hope.
First, secure the anthrax.
Do that and I guarantee your
daughter will be saved.
Promise me.
There's a leak
I don't trust a word you say.
I'm sorry...
for everything I've put you through.
That's okay
When we get out of here...
I'm going to quit my job...
and take care of you.
I won't leave you alone again.
Things will be different.
I'll be a good mom
Okay?
You are a good mom.
You've always been a good mom.
Mio...
I love you very much.
Look.
Happy birthday, Mom
I completely forgot
It's today, isn't it?
I wanted to give it to you this morning.
Don't quit your job.
Go stop the bad guys
Mio...
hold on.
I'm going to get you out of here
I know.
Okay, where's the poison?
Why?
I'm going to stop them and
save my daughter.
But who can you trust?
No one. Not even you.
But give me direction.
And I'll know soon enough
if you're working against me.
That's the girl I know.
Can you leave Mio?
She'll be fine.
She's tougher than I am.
It's probably in the basement.
I've entered the Director's
retinal scan data.
I've got his password.
Next is Deputy Director Irie.
Anthrax in place, Sir.
Nice try.
Yes?
Ten minutes left.
What's your decision?
We're putting the money together.
Good. You won't regret it
The people come first.
You mean "you" come first.
That's enough
You all right?
Why're you here?
Thought you might like some support.
From one loose cannon to another
Hurry. We've little time.
How do you know it's here?
So this is their ventilation.
Yukihira!
Found it.
- Let's dismantle it.
- No!
If we're not careful, it could be us
that poisons the city.
What's your experience?
Five minutes.
How's it coming?
Have they found it yet?
I take it you know who! am by now.
Deputy! Irie?
Kuniaki Goto.
Correct?
Yes.
Been a while.
Why?
I spent eight years in prison
for a fabricated crime.
Time I spent waiting for this day
All because I planned to
expose police corruption...
by you...
Goto!
You and the Director owe me.
Hurry and deposit the money.
Or shall I disclose everything I know?
You're going to make it.
How about you?
Yeah Let's hang in there, okay?
Still suspicious of me, are you?
"Access granted"
"Transfer funds?"
No deposit, Sir.
Why not?
And the anthrax?
Signal's stopped.
Something's wrong.
Open the shelter!
Opportunity knocks!
Let's move!
B Team, move out!
Here comes the cavalry.
Yukihira!
Plug your ears!
Copy
Five men down Intruder fleeing
with the bacteria.
I think it's Yukihira.
You okay?
Natsumi Yukihira...
Let's make a trade.
Give me the bacteria.
And I'll give you the serum.
You can't go!
The serum
Even with it, the moment you go
in without a biochemical suit...
you'll be infected
I don't care as long as
Mio is saved.
You'll bleed to death before
you get there.
Let me tend to that.
I'm sorry to have to say...
so long.
Your mother...
will be here soon.
Good-bye
Let's go
Your car explosion.
Any idea who did it?
Were you investigating something
on your own?
I'll take that as a "yes"
I caught wind of some
hidden files...
detailing internal corruption.
And you plan to expose it?
I'd think twice.
Why?
There, you're set
Six years ago... I looked into a
secret slush fund at the MPD
I got within an inch of finding
positive proof.
And then it happened
My fianc? got into my car
and it exploded
Like Mio.
Luckily, she survived.
But...
she was badly burned.
In place of me
You did this to her.!
Give it up
It's not worth it.
Yukihira!
The bacteria.
For the serum.
Want to save your daughter?
Hurry.
She's dying
Yukihira...
the bacteria.
What?
Mio's life is most important now.
The antiserum.
5-9-2-8.
Access code to the infection ward.
Go to Mio
And you?
I'll stop him
So where's the traitor?
What?
So who're you after, huh?
The police? Yukihira?
I couldn't care less for either
I just wanna get rich.
People betray you. Money doesn't
Now! 'm free.
See ya
"Fund transfer completed"
It can't be.
Find Hasumi!
With the Director and Deputy's
security data...
all doors are open.
Don't scare me like that.
Your beloved files.
Now give me my 4 billion
Is that you, Saiki?
Secret files?
Right here.
Let's see.
You turning on me?
I wouldn't say that.
Just following the plan.
How so?
The "plan" calls for me
to have that.
Isn't that right?
! thought we were going public
with that... force the top to resign.
What about our plans to create
an ideal police force?
Isn't that what we did this for?
What we sacrificed our own for?
Forgive me, Goto.
Justice demands a price.
Saiki...
Drop your weapons!
It's all over!
Seize them!
This what you wanted, Yamaji?
Well... is it?
Hold it!
Gotcha.
Mio!
Mio, hold on!
I'm here now. Everything's
gonna be fine
It's all right.
Thank God... Mio.
Mom.
Mio?
Don't do this.
Hang in there!
Don't leave me.
Look at me!
Please!
Mio, look at me!
Open your eyes!
Please!
Come on, Mio!
Open your eyes!
Don't do this to me!
Please...
Mom?
Mio.
I waited for you.
I knew you'd come back.
All's well that ends well.
! s that it, Saiki?
How'd you know to come here?
A drinker's hunch.
Oh, that's right.
How're you holding up?
I'll live.
The government's antiserum?
It arrived in time.
By your plan, I'd be dead from
anthrax by now
Or would I?
There are no absolutes in this world.
No plan is ever perfect.
But the truth is...
it all began with your father's
investigation
His partner followed up on it.
And I executed it
Someone high up the police ladder
had my car explode 6 years ago
Same with yours, too.
Police were killing citizens they're
supposed to protect.
And failing to expose corruption.
What you did was no different
than terrorism.
I had to break some rules
to get the rule-breakers.
I tried doing it strictly by the book.
I filed reports and petitions,
haggled with superiors.
I repeatedly conducted in-house
probes on the sly.
And yet nothing ever changed.
You wanted 8 billion yen?
I wanted the secret files
you were looking for.
To go public with?
To cut a deal with government officials
and those incriminated by it.
What kind of deal?
Individually, people have limited power.
Destroying them in public would
accomplish little.
Goto's methods were naive.
Rolling a few titular heads won't
cure the rot inside.
Organized crime requires an
organized response.
Otherwise...
you can't even protect
the ones you love
I disagree.
So would your fianc?
She would've wanted you
to stay the course
To remain on the side of justice.
To hell with matching strengths
She would rather have seen
you fight your way.
With you gone, the plan ends
nearly perfectly.
You'd better shoot.
Because I will.
Your way...
only breeds more vengeance.
Saiki...
Ryoko Shinohara
Kippei Shiina
Hiroki Narimiya
Sadawo Abe
Mari Hamada
Rosa Kato
Masaya Kato
Ren Ohsugi
Susumu Terajima
Yosuke Eguchi
Produced by Taizo Tani
Chihiro Kameyama, Yoshishige Shimatani
Planned by Hironori Hata
Kenji Shimizu, Minami Ichikawa
Executive Producer: Hirotsugu Usui
Producers: Hideki Yoshijo, Hideki Inada
Screenplay by Shimako Sato
Music by Norihito Sumitomo
Lighting: Masamitsu Hanaoka
Recording: Kunio Ashihara
Editor: Junnosuke Hogaki
Production: Kyodo Television
Presented by Kansai Telecasting Corporation,
Fuji Television Network, Toho
Directed by Yoshinori Kobayashi
Turning to other news...
A non-profit organization that
provides financial relief...
to families of crime victims in Japan...
announced it received
an 8 billion yen donation...
from an anonymous source overseas.
Officials are still trying to determine
who is responsible for the gift.
2007 Kansai Telecasting Corporation,
Fuji Television Network, Toho