♪ (SOFT GUITAR) ♪
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(ELECTRICAL HUM)
PROFESSOR VASQUEZ:
Oh, my God.
It's working.
SIMON: No, it's too sporadic!
We're gonna lose it!
PROFESSOR VASQUEZ:
Give it more.
Turn the knob,
turn the knob, Simon!
SIMON: What?
PROFESSOR VASQUEZ:
Oh, my God.
Look! Look!
It's working!
We did it!
(LAUGHTER)
Simon!
Simon, we did it!
SIMON:
Let there be light, huh?
(LAUGHTER)
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC) ♪
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(MAN COUGHS)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
Heyyy!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Ah!
Beep, beep...
(RACKS GUN)
Beep, beep, beep, beep.
(GUNSHOTS!)
Agh!
(GUNSHOT)
Beep, beep, beep.
♪ (SINGING IN SPANISH) ♪
♪ (SPANISH GUITAR) ♪
(CHEERS & WHISTLES)
(LADY SCREAMS)
♪ ♪
(MAN SHOUTS IN SPANISH)
(METAL CRASHES)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(MOUSETRAP SNAPS)
Agh!
(COUGHS)
The chili.
(LAUGHS)
Phew!
Ah.
♪ (SPANISH GUITAR) ♪
(GRAVEL CRUNCHING)
♪ ♪
PEDRO:
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Simon Orwell.
MIT?
A student?
Why would he be here?
Maybe for this...
hmm.
Pedro, don't touch that.
PEDRO:
Por que?
Because you don't know
what it is or what it does.
PEDRO: But it's not
even plugged in.
(BOTH SPEAKING SPANISH)
(HIGH-PITCHED BEEP)
Hey, Simon Orwell.
HAROLD:
Well, I hope you're hungry.
Harold Finch.
Ah.
So where am I?
Well, I assume that
you know you're in Mexico.
And beyond that, you're at
the Tres Llaves Orphanage.
I run the place,
and Sofia here helps out,
and Pedro keeps
the place running.
I'm at an orphanage?
What are you doing here, amigo?
Came here to see someone.
Got a little caught up
on the way
when someone shot at me
in your beautiful country.
Shot at?
You guys happen to know
a professor around here?
Professor Vasquez?
Ring any bells?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
How do you know
Professor Vasquez?
Do you know Armando Vasquez?
You want to give him that
for me?
Professor Vasquez
is dead, Simon.
No.
Very suddenly, last week.
No, Professor Vasquez
is not dead.
He e-mailed me and asked me
to come here a few days ago
and give him that...
I...
I'm sorry.
He was my friend too.
He gave a lot to this orphanage.
We had big plans.
What happened?
He was poisoned.
We don't know that.
He was poisoned?
I have to make a phone call.
I'm sorry about
your loss, Simon.
Simon, we get supplies from vans
that come across the border.
There's one here now.
I can make arrangements
to get you back
as long as you have
your passport.
You don't have your passport.
In the passenger seat.
I guess I forgot to grab it
when people were shooting at me.
You can take your chances
with U.S. Immigration
at the border
without your passport.
Otherwise, you're gonna have to
go to the American Embassy here,
and that'll take weeks.
There will be a van leaving tonight before nightfall.
While you're here,
mi casa es su casa.
Good luck.
It's Pedro, right?
Amigo?
Thanks.
PEDRO:
De nada.
If you need anything,
you can tell me or my sister.
Who's your sister?
Yeah, Sofia.
We're one big happy family here.
(SCREEN CREAKS, THEN SLAMS)
♪ (SPANISH GUITAR) ♪
(PLAYFUL CHATTER)
(PEBBLE CLATTERS)
Nice shot.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
So, you're the gringo orphan?
Apparently I am.
That's quite a shot
you've got there.
I'm Juan.
I run the place.
You run the place?
Yeah.
What about Harold?
My helper.
Helper.
So, bomb?
Not quite.
It's a pipe dream.
Dr. Harold talks
a lot about dreams.
He says the more impossible,
the bigger the blessing.
Well, that's quite the blessing
because it's definitely impossible.
Anything's possible.
With God,
♪ all things are possible. ♪
So, what does it do?
Well, it's
supposed to be a tuner.
Tunes music, right?
♪ (JUAN HUMMING) ♪
Electricity, actually.
Ohhh.
(CLICK)
SOFIA:
You have to pay them.
HAROLD: I told you I'm not
paying those people a dime.
Harold, we can do nothing
around here without the cartel.
They control everything.
Harold!
God has always provided.
(SIGHS)
Now, about this stray.
Harold, I am
uncomfortable with this.
Who knows what kind of
business he is wrapped up in.
Listen, do you know
that Pedro told me
that the men who were
chasing him were El Noche's men?
HAROLD: You know,
Vasquez used to tell me
about this brilliant student that he had
who had been able to take
his research further in months
than he'd been able to
in years and I think...
Harold, Vasquez is dead.
The project is too.
Okay, can we... please,
can we focus on the now?
Simon is this student.
It's not dead;
it's very much alive.
Brilliance does not know
good from bad, Harold.
And I don't like
the looks of him.
(SIMON CLEARS THROAT)
I'm sorry, was I
interrupting something?
Oh, no, no.
Come on in.
SIMON: I just want to say
I think I'm gonna,
you know, take
my chances at the border.
It's a risk.
I am going to
call Enrique, okay?
Just sit for a minute, please.
What's up?
HAROLD:
Let's talk.
Red rope?
I'm okay.
Come on,
everybody loves red rope.
It's red rope!
Okay.
It won't kill you
quite as quick as tobacco.
That was my vice of choice
back in my NASA days.
The whole place
could have burned down
and nobody would've noticed it
back in those days.
You worked at NASA?
During Apollo.
That's how I met
your Professor Armando.
So you went to NASA,
and now you run an orphanage.
That makes sense.
Well, I did quite a few things
since my NASA days.
Oh, yeah?
I've started a few businesses,
conducted seminars
for Fortune 500 companies.
Motivational type stuff?
The whole "Be all
you can be," right?
Well, there's a little bit
more to it than that.
I know plenty of people
who are highly motivated
who have no clue
as to what they're doing.
So what is your secret
of success, Mr. Finch?
Well, I like to start out
by asking people
to write down
three goals in life.
(SCOFFS)
Well...
I feel like
I'm a fifth grader right now.
Don't laugh.
What's your first goal?
Find my passport
and get out of here.
That's a goal in life?
Come on, you can do
better than that.
"Find my passport," okay.
What's your second?
That's it, really.
Just get my passport
and go home.
That's all you've got?
Yep.
Okay, well...
That's it, that's all I got.
All right, it's a start.
Before you go,
I've got something
I want to show you.
(CLICK)
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC) ♪
He never gave up.
Watch.
♪ ♪
He did it.
Huh, he did it.
Yeah.
And then he overdid it,
every time.
Whoa.
Yeah.
He said he needed
some device to tune it.
You wouldn't know anything
about that, would you?
He called it Ilimitado.
Unlimited.
Dr. Harold,
pardon.
The van is here.
They found another one.
♪ (GUITAR) ♪
Martinez.
Harold, how are you?
Who do we have here?
Oh, hola.
AGENT MARTINEZ:
I just found her.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Think you have
some space for her?
Of course, of course.
Hey, what do I have there?
It's for you.
(LAUGHS)
Cómo estás?
AGENT MARTINEZ:
Hi, Sofia.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
That's Agent Martinez.
She's a federales,
a good friend of Dr. Harold's.
She finds children everywhere
and, well, she prefers
to bring them here
than taking them
to the state orphanage.
SIMON: That's how they
all wound up here?
Not all of them.
But enough.
Mira.
It's getting late.
Why don't you help me
unpack the van.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ ♪
You know, Sofia is close
to the town mayor,
Enrique De Angelo.
He knows some people
at the U.S. Embassy
and says he might can help
your passport situation.
Might take only a week.
You can stay here if you like,
as long as you obey the rules
and pay your way.
Oh, yeah?
Maybe finish
the professor's work.
The professor's dead,
and I just want to get across the border before I am too.
Well, the border
shouldn't be any problem
as long as you don't
have any priors.
No, of course not.
In that case, good luck.
It was good meeting you, and...
fill this out, will you?
Good luck, señor.
Vaya con Dios.
♪ (SOFT GUITAR) ♪
(KNOCKING)
Simon, what's up?
Hey, uh, I think I'm gonna
go look for my passport
in the morning.
Would you mind if I just
stay for one night?
Sure, sure.
Hey, do you mind taking
a look at something for me?
Maybe you can help me out
with something here.
Solar lantern kits from China
for the kids to build
and, you know, put together,
and they're gonna sell them
through this charitable outfit in El Paso.
You know, it'll help them
with their work ethic.
The only problem is,
once we assembled them,
the doggone things
wouldn't work.
Chinese-made lanterns
assembled by Mexican orphans.
No wonder there's a problem.
Yeah.
Well, here are the schematics
that you might want
to take a look at.
Once you get through with that,
maybe you want to revisit
the professor's device.
Harold, I'm going to look
for my passport tomorrow
and then I'm leaving.
I can show you
how to turn it on,
but that's... that's as far
as I'm gonna go.
Where is it anyways?
I don't know, we don't have it.
You don't have it.
No.
Well, do you know where it is?
It could be over
at the professor's home.
He had a lab over there,
but the police
have all that shut down.
Well, there you go.
Yeah.
Simon, I'm glad you're here.
I'm glad someone is.
♪ (SOMBER MUSIC) ♪
(CLICKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
♪ (SOMBER MUSIC) ♪
♪ (CHILDREN SINGING) ♪
(SIGHS)
♪ (SINGING CONTINUES) ♪
God, get me out of here.
(DOOR CREAKS, CAN CLATTERS)
Huh!
So you are still here, huh?
Well, I'm praying that
your passport resolves quickly
so that you can leave.
The sooner the better.
(SIREN BLARING)
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
Oh! Enrique.
ENRIQUE:
Hola, niños.
Como estas?
Mira, mira, mira,
mira, mira, mira.
SIMON:
Looks like a popular guy.
JUAN:
Mayor De Angelo.
Let's me call him "Enrique,"
like a Mexican Superman.
Oh, yeah?
JUAN: He's the first mayor to stand up against drug cartels.
Even El Noche is afraid of him.
Enrique is running
for governor of Chihuahua.
Bet you 50 pesos he's gonna win.
Yeah, looks
like he wins all right.
Ready, guys?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Up, up!
Who the pleasure do I have?
Uh, pleasure of Simon Orwell.
Enrique De Angelo.
Sofia told me you have
some problems and...
Mm-hmm.
...I'm very sorry
about that.
That's not the way
to greet a visitor.
And he needs you
to contact the Embassy
so they can reissue
a passport immediately.
You lost your passport?
Mm-hmm.
That's not too smart, Simon.
But I'll tell you what,
for Sofia,
I will offer my services.
Because we don't want
to keep Mr. Orwell here
any longer than we have to.
Gracias, señorita.
You're welcome.
Hasta luego.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hey, welcome to my town.
If you need anything,
please don't hesitate.
I'll be more than
happy to help you.
More than happy to help me, huh?
ENRIQUE:
Yes.
All right.
I could use a ride
to Mr. Vasquez's house.
I need to get something.
It's about this big...
There's wires, there's...
it's shiny.
Mmm.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
The professor
was your friend, yes?
That's the reason
why I came here.
And this shiny thing,
the device,
do you know how it works?
I do, actually.
I helped him make it.
Oh.
Well, I'll tell you what, Simon,
um, we believe the professor
has been poisoned,
he's been murdered,
and I suspect by his doctor.
She's a very dangerous woman.
Because it's a police procedure,
I can't let you snoop around,
and I hope you understand that.
No big deal.
Just thought I'd ask.
I'll tell you what,
why don't we fill out
the paperwork
so I can get you a new passport.
Don't worry.
Everything is gonna be fine.
Hey, niños!
Vámonos!
Yeah, I think
I'll find my own passport.
(CLICKING)
PEDRO:
Hola, Mr. Simon.
How did you do it?
Pedro, are you busy?
Why?
♪ (UPBEAT MUSIC) ♪
So what's up with Harold
and all of his Jesus talk?
That man sounds like
a bumper sticker.
It's weird.
Who talks like that?
Dr. Harold does.
♪ ♪
SIMON:
Yeah, this looks right.
Stop.
That's the same guy.
He took something out of my car!
Uh, and he's coming this way.
What do we do?
Duck.
What?
He's gone.
He's gone, get up.
Now what?
Well, you know, we follow him.
He took something of mine.
We follow him.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(ENGINE REVS)
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC) ♪
No, no, Simon.
Simon, Simon, stop!
(DOOR SLAMS)
I can't believe that, man.
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC) ♪
Hurry up, man.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WHISPERING) Get out,
get out, get out, get out!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ ♪
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
Loco, get to the back.
(ENGINE ROARS)
(LAUGHING)
I can't believe it.
Ha-ha!
Hallelujah!
Gloria a Dios!
Man, you're about as subtle
as a Mexican jumping bean, man.
(LAUGHS)
Come on, man, let's go.
I need my passport.
No, no, no, no.
It's an old house.
Let's go.
(TRUCK DOOR CLOSES)
Simon, listen, man.
This is not a good idea.
You shouldn't be over here, man.
It's okay.
We're just gonna... we're gonna
look through the windows
for a second.
We're not gonna go inside.
Hey, tell me about your sister.
Sofia?
Yeah.
She always so welcoming?
Oh, she's headstrong, you know.
Always has been.
But... well, you know
we were both orphans, right?
I didn't know that...
I'm sorry.
No, don't be sorry.
Dr. Harold took us in.
He taught us
that we could be anything
regardless of where
we came from.
He said our potential
was ilimitado.
So now you're using
your unlimited potential
to be his janitor?
Hey, man, listen,
I'm gonna run an orphanage
of my own one day.
I'm just learning
the ropes here.
Yes, that's very noble of you.
In the meantime,
I'd keep an eye on your sister
because it looks like
she runs the joint.
Well, you know, she took
Dr. Harold's teachings to heart.
She went to business school
in the U.S.
Oh, yeah?
She has way too many dreams.
Anyway, I think
she's gonna settle down
now that she's engaged.
She's engaged?
Well, not too many people
know this,
but they've been dating
for, like, three months.
Harold and I met him
about two weeks ago.
I think he'll be
good for her, though.
He's a powerful man.
Oh, yeah.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
What are you doing?!
I told you
I'm getting my passport.
You're crazy, loco, man.
(DOOR CREAKS)
Careful.
(DOOR CLOSES & LOCK CLICKS)
This is a mess.
Oh, man, is that what I think?
Simon, we've got to get
out of here right now, man.
I don't want to be here anymore.
We've gotta go.
What are you looking at?
Professor Vasquez.
This must be his house.
Oh, you're loco.
No, we've got to get out
of here right now, man.
Loco!
Simon, you're not
listening to me.
That blood back there,
I think that belongs
to Professor Vasquez.
What are you doing?
I'm just looking at this e-mail.
(METAL CLANGS)
What are you do...
why are you touching that?
He used to have this
on his desk at MIT.
We've gotta go.
What are you doing?
(LOCK CLICKS)
Is that a key?
How'd you do that?
Where'd you get that key?
What is that?
It's a frequency chart.
What else is in there?
Just this Bible.
(DISTANT MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC) ♪
MAN:
Sí, sí, sí, sí.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ ♪
Yoo-hoo?
(MEN SCUFFLE)
Give me my passport.
Agh!
(GRUNTING)
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC) ♪
(TAPPING)
Yoo-hoo?
Yoo-hoo-ooo?
Yoo-hoooo?
♪ (UPBEAT MUSIC) ♪
Ah, agh!
(ENGINE STARTS)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
SIMON:
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
♪ (UPBEAT MUSIC) ♪
I can't...
(GASPS)
I can't keep doing
these adventures
with you anymore, Simon.
Hey, who's this woman?
Her name is Clara.
She's a doctor in town.
She's known as the bruja.
What's a bruja?
It's a...
how do you say?
A witch.
HAROLD: What were
you two thinking?
That's a crime scene.
Look, to be honest,
we didn't know
it was the professor's house
till after we broke in.
Broke in?
Pedro.
Pardon, Dr. Harold.
Look, there's something
we're not being told.
Uh, Enrique thinks
the professor was poisoned,
and you think that he died
of natural causes, right?
That's what was reported.
Yeah, well, we just
came back from his house,
and it was completely destroyed
and there was blood spatter
all over the kitchen,
not to mention
the device is missing.
Does that sound like
natural causes to you?
It's true.
And the guy who led us there,
yeah, it was the same guy
who tried to kill me
and took my passport.
Hmm.
Who's this Clara woman, huh?
I'd like to talk to her
because I'm pretty sure
she knows something.
Maybe she does,
but she's been missing
ever since Vasquez died.
Somebody wanted me dead.
Somebody wanted my advice.
Clara happens to be missing.
This is all connected.
When was the professor
pronounced dead?
Last week sometime.
I got an e-mail from him
three days ago,
asking me what time
I was gonna cross the border,
what kind of car I was driving,
and what my license plate numbers were.
Somebody hacked into
his e-mail account,
and that's how they knew
I was coming.
We need to talk to Enrique.
And you two need to stay put.
No problemo.
♪ (SOFT GUITAR) ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SIREN BLARES)
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
Hola.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Harold.
HAROLD:
Hey, Enrique.
Good to see you.
Good to see you, my friend.
How have you been?
I've been good, I've been good.
Well, I've got a present
in the back for you.
Oh.
Police evidence.
Really?
Simon, I take it
he's treating you well, huh?
He's put me to work.
Well, he's good at that.
Well, I've got
some good news for you
and I've got
some bad news for you.
Let's start with the bad news.
That's bad news,
it's really bad news.
Where did you get this?
Well, our reach
is long around here.
But I'll tell what you,
the good news,
with these we'll be able
to expedite your new passport.
Should receive it within a week.
Excuse me.
HAROLD:
Simon, Simon.
Enrique apparently found
this in police evidence.
Look at this.
Well, what do you think?
They treated her like
a piñata is what I think.
Can you rebuild it?
I'm not touching that thing.
Why?
What is it with you
and this device?
Bad memories.
Simon, there's a world out there waiting for this thing.
Now, this is not about you.
It's bigger than that.
Let me show you something.
Old Vasquez and I may have been
retired for a while,
but we never stopped dreaming.
Millions of people
die every year
for one simple reason:
lack of access to energy.
This device will allow us
to provide free energy
to the most remote villages.
You know what that means?
We can open orphanages anywhere.
Theoretically.
All right, my device
can generate 500 watts max.
All right, that's...
that's like a light bulb.
All right, this is...
this is a whole village.
Listen, you don't understand.
Your device is a prototype.
It's just designed
to show what's possible.
You don't need your device
to light up a village.
This is what's possible.
When I was at NASA,
I had this colleague.
He now runs
Sol Energy Enterprises.
He runs Sol?
Yeah, he does.
If we can demonstrate
a sustained flow of energy
even for a little while,
he wants to buy
the patent to this thing
with the agreement that
he'll fund it and develop it.
Sol Enterprises
is interested in...
Yeah, he wants
to buy this patent.
He's gonna be in town next week
for a demonstration.
And you didn't tell him it was dead in the water, did you?
Is it?
♪ (SOFT GUITAR) ♪
(WHISPERING)
What's up?
Oye!
You scared me!
I'm sorry.
How's he doing?
I don't trust him.
You don't trust anybody
from north of the border.
Huh!
That's not true, I trust you.
Enrique said that he found out
some things about him.
He may not be
who you think he is.
Just be careful
with your trust, Harold.
♪ (SOMBER MUSIC) ♪
(METAL DOOR CLANGS)
(BUZZER)
(PHONE RINGING)
DR. VASQUEZ:
This is Armando.
Simon, is that you?
Simon?
(METAL DOOR CLANGS)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
HAROLD: You don't have your hand raised, so I'm gonna ask you...
What about some others here?
What would you like to be?
CHILD: When I'm...
I'm big and grown up,
I'm going to be a doctor
of animals.
HAROLD:
Ah, okay.
Julio, what do you want to be
when you grow up, buddy?
An adult.
An adult?
(LAUGHTER)
Once you become an adult,
what would you like to be?
A pilot.
What about some others here?
Most people look at these kids
and all they see are
future drug dealers and thieves.
People like pets
around here a lot.
People like...
Dr. Harold, he sees doctors
and lawyers and businessmen.
Okay, you know who this is?
CHILDREN:
Juan.
No, this is not Juan.
This is a baby elephant.
(JUAN MIMICS ELEPHANT)
See?
(LAUGHTER)
Let's do something here.
Let me show you something.
I'm going to put this
on the baby elephant.
So, try to walk away.
(CHAIN CLINKING)
Ahhh, he can't.
He can't leave.
Why?
Because that's the way
they train elephants.
They put these heavy chains
on them,
year after year after year.
They want to walk,
but they're held back.
So after a while
they just get used to it.
The baby elephants...
My turn is coming up.
Baby elephants
become grownup elephants.
And we just happen to have
with us today
a grownup elephant.
Mr. Elephant,
come down.
(MIMICS ELEPHANT TRUMPETING)
Looka there.
Looka there, looka there.
He wants some peanuts
or something.
Looka there.
All right, here he comes.
All right,
Mr. Grownup Elephant.
Now, we're gonna
put something on him.
It's not a heavy chain.
I don't know
if he knows it or not,
but it's just a piece of twine.
Now look at this elephant.
This is a big, strong elephant.
Look at those muscles
in this elephant, yeah.
(LAUGHTER)
Clearly,
this big, strong elephant
could break this piece of twine if he wanted to,
but that twine
is holding him back now.
How can that be?
Because after all those years
of being held back
with that big ol' chain,
he apparently
got to feeling like,
you know, that's the way
it was supposed to be.
So this little piece of twine
can hold this
big, strong elephant.
Thank you, Mr. Elephant.
My little friends,
you may feel like
you're being held back.
(WHISPERS) You're
a really good elephant.
Some bad things
might happen to you,
might have already
happened to you.
Some thoughtless people
might put you down.
All these things,
they're not good,
but they are not chains
that can hold you.
Know that you can do
whatever you want to do,
go wherever you want to go.
Don't ever feel held back
because God has a wonderful plan for each of us,
but we must do our part.
♪ (GUITAR) ♪
When you guys cross the border
with the supplies,
how often do they
check the cargo?
Not much anymore.
They know us...
Why?
Could be cheaper than hiring
a coyote to get me home.
Don't talk like that, Simon.
You'll get your passport.
The good Lord will provide.
Hey.
The lanterns are ready.
Really?
Yeah, well, I don't sleep much.
How's the device?
Same as it always was.
Hmm.
Well, since you're gonna
have a little time...
sort of a compilation
of the seminars I used to give.
Oh, yeah?
You know, keys to unlocking
those impossible dreams?
Thank you.
(BALL THUMPS)
Wanna play some football?
You mean soccer?
Silly me.
Why call a game that uses
your feet "football"?
It's a good point,
but, you know,
I don't really feel like
playing games right now.
Ask this guy.
Yeah, I'll play.
Vámonos.
Go long.
I'll, uh...
I'll give it a read.
You're the man.
♪ ♪
(CHEWING)
(ZZZZZT!)
(DOOR CREAKS)
Juan?
What is this?
What's going on?
What's it look like?
Power's out.
I see that.
Where's Harold?
Out with Pedro getting supplies.
Want to learn a cool trick?
Sure.
Yeah?
Follow me.
Sometimes those carteles
force the power company
to shut off our power.
Yeah, well, I'm about
to turn it back on again.
You sure this is safe?
Used to do this all the time
when I was a kid.
Wires.
All you've got to do...
Careful.
...is hook these
like that.
Simple.
Ah.
Careful.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
Simon!
(CLATTERING)
Agh! Ouch!
Uno mas.
Uno mas!
Agh!
Ándale!
It's the loco!
Hey, you okay?
You okay?
HAROLD:
What's going on here?
SIMON: Your friendly
power supplier cut the power.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I was trying to hook it
back up for you.
By stealing it?
Harold, you're
running an orphanage.
You need power.
Not this way.
We have to set an example.
Little hard to do in the dark.
Well, it's impossible to do
without a moral compass.
Oh, please.
Can't we use
those solar lanterns?
No, they didn't finish
charging in the sun.
Look, what they did was wrong.
Let me just hook it
up for the night.
Two wrongs don't make a right.
I said no.
All right, fine.
Fine, I'm sorry.
I was just trying to help you.
Break out the candles.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Hey, man.
You still pouting?
Why would I be pouting
when I have a huge basketful
of candles?
Look, Simon, I know your
heart's in the right place.
You just need to under...
Shh, shh.
What's wrong?
She's afraid of the dark.
Yeah, well, I tried to do
something about that earlier.
Well, you know what?
You could turn the lights on
for a lot of little girls
if you'd just finish
the professor's work.
You wouldn't even have
to climb those poles.
Never quit, do you?
No, never do.
So you're afraid
of the dark, huh?
(SOFIA SPEAKING SPANISH)
I think I might be able to solve that problem for you.
You know, I used to be
afraid of the dark,
but then I discovered
a little trick.
See this guy, the light bulb,
hasn't changed much
since its conception,
but in order for it to work,
it needs a power source.
And we need wires.
These are very important.
See, these wires carry
energy from the battery
all the way up
to the light bulb,
which heats up the filament,
which excites electrons
to create...
light.
Huh?
She doesn't speak any English.
(LAUGHS)
Thank you
for not telling me that.
Ah.
Now she says she wants you
to make it work
without the battery.
Tell her she sounds like
an old professor of mine.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Thank you.
You're welcome.
What are you looking at?
I don't want anything
to do with you.
Fine.
♪ (SOFT PIANO) ♪
♪ (UPBEAT MUSIC) ♪
(DOOR CREAKS, THEN CLOSES)
♪ ♪
Ha-ha-ha!
I know that look well.
What look is that?
Madman reaching for the stars.
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Yeah, right.
Sorry, Mr. Soccer.
Let me guess,
too busy to play football.
Yep.
Oh.
But I'll school you
in some soccer.
Try me.
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
♪ (UPBEAT MUSIC) ♪
Ahem.
Harold said
you would be working late,
and he asked me
to bring you some food.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
I'm finding myself very envious
of all those
little Mexican orphans.
(SOFIA LAUGHS)
It's kind of ironic.
A privileged American jealous
of poor little Mexican orphans.
Yes, I think that is
pretty ironic, Simon.
You hate me, don't you?
You really do.
You know, that was
very kind of you what you did
with the light the other day
for the little girl.
I used to always
be afraid of the dark.
That's probably why I got
into electrical engineering.
So then that must
be your goal, right?
Mr. MIT bringing light
to us impoverished,
poor little Mexican people.
You're talking about
Harold's three goals?
Exactly.
Yes, Harold makes
everyone do it.
In fact, the first time that
I introduced him to Enrique,
he sat him down
and made him do it too.
Mm-hmm.
He didn't do it?
Yes.
I think Enrique had
his secretary do it.
Probably.
Yeah.
Well, then, what is
at the top of your goal list?
You don't know.
No idea.
Ha-ha.
Why does that not surprise me?
You are, then, the...
the goal-less wanderer
floating from town to town.
That's what it is.
Since you know me so well,
why don't you let me
get to know you?
(LAUGHS)
Enjoy your meal, Simon.
(PLAYFUL CHATTER)
Power's back.
I noticed.
Miracle?
Sort of.
Enrique made a call.
How's it going?
I got it working again.
All right!
How's it work?
It's pretty simple really.
Yeah, I bet.
All right, so this
captures radio waves
and then converts it
into energy.
It's like one of those
old crystal radios.
Yeah.
And then we use
good ol' Tesla's theory
and shoot the power
up through the air.
The only problem,
I don't know how to send
that much electricity without...
Rzzzz.
Rzzzz, yeah.
But I'm thinking
it has something to do
with this frequency chart
that I found at Vasquez's house.
I just don't know which one.
Yeah.
You'll figure it out.
Let me tell you,
when Vasquez died,
I thought all hope was lost.
But I must say, you have been
the answer to my prayers.
Oh, yeah?
Never heard that one before.
Not much of a prayer man, huh?
Not much of a faith guy.
Really?
Well, I think science
requires faith, Simon.
I mean, we know there's gravity.
Yeah.
We can even measure it.
Just don't know
the source of its strength.
You believe in electricity.
You can even manipulate it.
You just don't know where
the electron gets its energy.
You just know it's there.
That's faith.
I can buy the whole
higher power thing,
but the benevolent Father,
doesn't really hit home.
Well, I hope to prove
you wrong about that.
Well, I hope you can
prove me wrong about this,
figure out
this frequency riddle.
Back at NASA...
Glory days story?
Yeah.
I was wrestling with the problem
of how to control the heat load
on the Apollo spaceships.
People were telling me,
"You'll never send
a man to the moon.
"They'll either burn up
out there or freeze to death.
You'll never get there."
A real problem.
How did you solve it?
Um, eating barbecue.
What?
What do you mean barbecue?
(CHUCKLES)
I was watching
this juicy chicken
on this rotisserie one night,
and it occurred to me
if that rotisserie
could evenly distribute
the heat on that chicken,
why couldn't we do
the same thing
for our spacecraft?
So we took it
and made it rotate.
You came up with that?
Why do you think they call it
the barbecue roll?
Oh, I've heard
of the barbecue roll.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
Yeah, well,
these things come to you
in strange ways sometimes.
Some of them defy
human comprehension.
That's when you have to tune in
to a little bit
of a different frequency, Simon.
And by that,
I'm talking about prayer.
I'll tell you what,
I'm about ready to test this.
So why don't you
clasp your hands
and get God's attention
because I need a miracle.
I'll do it.
Take Pedro?
Trade you Pedro for Sofia.
(LAUGHS)
You better take
what you can get.
Pedro it is.
♪ (PIANO) ♪
(GRAVEL CRUNCHING)
(ENGINE HUMMING)
♪ ♪
You sure that thing works?
It looks like
a failed science experiment.
Looks aren't everything, okay?
It's about what's inside
that really matters.
Wow, muchas gracias,
Dr. Harold.
Thank you for
the fourth key of wisdom.
You're welcome.
Seriously, you better hurry up.
El Noche's men like to move
at this time of night.
Well, I didn't think
it was the best idea
setting this up
in the middle of the orphanage.
Better to play it safe,
you know, just in case.
In case of what?
In case it kills everything
in a mile radius.
Hold this.
Thanks.
So let me get this straight,
if El Noche doesn't kill us,
your experiment will.
Wonderful.
I never said
there wasn't a downside.
But on the upside,
you could make history.
Okay, well, Señor Loco,
if you don't mind,
I'm gonna watch history
from the van.
Suit yourself.
Let's light it up!
(CLICKS SWITCH)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(DEVICE HUMMING)
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on,
come on, come on.
(DEVICE HUMMING
& ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
You're seeing this, right?
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Yes!
You're seeing this, right?
Ha-ha!
I can't believe it!
Yes!
Simon, you did it, my friend!
Ha-ha!
Ha-ha-ha!
Oh, my goodness!
Let there be light!
Amazing!
(HUMMING INTENSIFIES)
Simon?
(EXPLOSION)
Oh!
Simon?
Simon, you've gotta see this.
(DEVICE HUMMING)
This is a historical blackout.
This is bad.
We have to do something.
Turn it off.
(CLICK)
Hurry, man.
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
It's not working.
Do something.
Turn it off, man!
This is really gonna suck.
What?
Ugh!
(EXPLOSION)
Simon?
Simon!
Simon, you okay, man?
(EXHALES FORCEFULLY)
Are the lights back on?
Sí, they're back on.
Merry Christmas.
♪ (GUITAR) ♪
Dr. Harold?
SIMON:
Agghhh!
Maybe Sofia
can take him next time?
Oh, it was awesome.
It was just like the video.
Yeah, blackouts and all.
Yeah, I was thinking
I can... I can find a way
to modulate the frequency.
That's why Vasquez had me
bring my tuner, you know?
Just got to find the right one.
Well, find the right frequency.
Yeah, but, I mean,
it's like looking for a needle in a haystack.
When does your... when does
your NASA guy get here?
Three days.
Okay, I've got
some fried components
that I need to fix,
but that's still not enough time
to test each frequency.
Well, maybe you won't have to.
I mean, did you...
did you look at this?
I mean, he's got
some circled here.
Yeah.
It's not a proper frequency.
It doesn't... doesn't work.
Well, it must mean something.
Yeah, I thought that too.
I was thinking,
Tesla had this code like...
It was like a...
it was a numeric cryptogram
that Vasquez and I used to do where a number equals a letter.
But unless you guys have
any idea what "Juan 812" means.
HAROLD:
Juan 812?
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
Yeah, he's here.
Okay, I'll tell him.
Principal's office.
Simon.
Please have a seat.
You hungry?
No, I'm okay, thanks.
Hmm?
This guy has the best cuts
from Texas,
and my favorite,
Kobe from Japan.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Do you know what makes
Kobe beef superior
from the rest of the world?
Sake.
The way they treat the cow.
They feed them high-quality beer
and they massage them every day.
It's a great philosophy.
Hmm?
Pamper the herd,
and it will spoil you back.
So if you need any pampering,
please don't hesitate to ask.
All the way
to the slaughter house, right?
You know, Simon,
last time we had
a blackout in the city,
you know who was
responsible for it?
It was your friend, it was
your friend the professor.
I'm sorry about that.
That's a pretty dangerous device, no?
It's not;
I can fix it.
It's not supposed to
turn the lights off.
It's supposed to turn them on.
Yes, yes, of course, of course, of course, of course.
You know, Simon, I maybe know
somebody interested to buy it.
Hmm?
It makes you a lot of money.
You can help the poor
people in Mexico.
It's a win-win.
It sounds nice, uh,
but it's not... it's not for sale.
It's Harold's.
Mm, I will talk to Harold.
We both want
the same thing, Simon.
But in the meantime,
I want it back.
Excuse me?
You're gonna finish
your work on the device
and just return it to town.
Why would I do that when it doesn't belong to the town?
Professor Vasquez's murder
is under investigation,
and that device is
the only evidence we have.
Where were you that night?
You sure you don't want to eat?
It's a good steak.
I think we're done here.
(QUIETLY)
We've just begun, muchacho.
♪ (MARIACHI MUSIC) ♪
If I can fix the component
and find the right frequency,
then I can get this working
by the time Enrique
tries to confiscate it.
Just try not to ruffle
Enrique's feathers too much,
will you?
Yeah, well, tell him
to stop ruffling mine.
(LAUGHS)
He's been ruffling your feathers
ever since you found out
he's with Sofia.
(LAUGHTER)
I'm gonna pick up some things from the market.
See you in a bit.
Hola.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Este es mi amigo Simon.
Got one of these?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He wants to know
what happened to it.
Why?
Listen, do you want his help?
My girlfriend fried it
with her hair dryer.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Tell him I'm kidding.
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC) ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He wants you to give him...
I know what he wants;
I don't have it.
Sorry.
(PEDRO SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He wants you to take him...
take him where the device is.
You want it, it's right here.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
It's right there.
There you go.
That's it.
(PART SHATTERS)
(CARLOS YELLING IN SPANISH)
PEDRO: Okay,
he really wants it.
(CARLOS SPEAKING SPANISH)
He wants you to take him
to where it is.
You want me to take you
where it is?
(CARLOS SPEAKING SPANISH)
Yes.
Take him.
All right, all right.
Follow me.
Here it is.
(THUD)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SCUFFLING)
HAROLD:
Agh!
(GUNSHOT)
(POTTERY SHATTERING)
CARLOS:
Agh!
Harold?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
CLARA:
Get in! Get in!
SIMON:
Who's that?
Ándale! Ándale!
(GUN RACKS)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Agggh!
♪ (FAST-PACED MUSIC) ♪
(PEDRO & CLARA
SPEAKING SPANISH)
Give him your shirt.
Harold?
(CLARA SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hello, Simon.
My name is Clara.
Why would you bring her here?
What choice did I have?
I was stuck between
a gun and a hard place.
What if she poisons Harold?
Why would she poison Harold?
Ah-ah-agh!
Shh, shh, shh.
It's okay, it's okay.
JUAN: I brought the
cayenne peppers you asked for.
Cayenne pepper?
CLARA:
How are you feeling?
Like I've been shot at and hit.
Simon, you need
to finish that device.
Don't worry about the device.
You just need to focus
on feeling better, okay?
CLARA: Good thing
the bullet isn't lodged.
Yeah, good thing.
This will sting a bit.
Agh! Agh!
So you are a witch doctor.
Juan.
I pray to the same God
as you, child.
And I study the same science
as doctors.
Cayenne pepper will clog
this wound within ten seconds.
He'll be fine.
He just needs to
drink plenty of water.
HAROLD: Oh, now... now
my head is throbbing.
What should I get him?
(CHUCKLES)
Tylenol.
Well, that's the last one.
Looks like I'm ready
for El Paso.
Listen, when I get back
to the U.S.,
I'll bring you back a new part for your fried component.
Gracias.
You got it, amigo.
And I'll try to figure out
what Juan 812 means.
You do that.
Adios.
Hasta luego.
♪ (GUITAR) ♪
(KNOCKING)
Hey.
Come in.
I need to give you something...
from your professor.
We were very close.
Engaged to be married.
You were engaged?
His key.
I miss him so much.
Yeah, me too.
He was hurt, but he
never stopped loving you.
Months ago he knew something bad
was about to happen,
that he might be killed,
so he reached out to you
one final time,
praying you would come.
Do you know what's going on?
Do you know who's behind this?
Do you know what
this Juan 812 is?
Oh, Armando was
always very secretive.
I must be going.
(WHISPERS)
Trust no one.
Goodbye, Simon.
Did she give you something?
Hmm-mm.
Simon, I don't trust her.
It's kind of a reoccurring theme with you, isn't it?
You don't trust her,
you don't trust me.
Since you have arrived,
a lot of bad things
have happened.
Well, that's hardly fair.
You arrive under
violent circumstances,
with no story and no past.
So you don't trust me?
No, I trust you.
(SIGHS)
And Harold trusts you.
And Pedro trusts you,
and my brother's
a very good judge of character.
He is.
Mm-hmm.
He really is.
Well, thank you.
I like you, too.
(SCOFFS)
I said trust, not like.
Yeah, but you
like me a little bit.
Mm.
You like me a little bit.
This little machine, then,
if it was so important,
why didn't you just mail it
to the professor?
Why did you come
all the way to Mexico?
Because I needed something.
What?
It doesn't matter.
Can't get it anymore.
Good night, Simon.
(SWITCH CLICKS)
(SIRENS BLARING)
>> Francisco.
Jose...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(DOOR SLAMS)
Pedro, what's going on?
How could you do this?
SIMON:
What?
Who assembled these lanterns?
You put this whole orphanage... don't touch me!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
What?
You put this
whole orphanage in...
Who assembled these lanterns?
What are you talking about?
I did...
Why?
Enrique, what is happening
We're so lucky we got tipped off
before Pedro crossed the border.
That's why you came
down here, Simon?
No, I didn't do that.
I did not... hey, I did not put... I did not put that in there.
SOFIA: Using us
to smuggle drugs?
Sofia, I did not
put that in there!
ENRIQUE: Just say
the truth once.
Why don't you tell everybody
why you came down here.
It's the same reason...
Harold.
It's the same reason
you went to prison.
SOFIA:
Prison?
Tell 'em that!
I didn't put that in there.
Harold, I've been meaning
to talk to you about this.
Do you know what we found
when we did his background check on his passport?
He's not even supposed to
leave the United States.
Harold, you have
to trust me, okay?
The same way
the professor trusted you,
and the poor professor,
what you did to him?
What you did to him, Simon?
Tell them.
Harold, do you know why
Professor Vasquez left MIT?
Simon?
ENRIQUE:
Go ahead, go ahead.
Tell 'em, tell 'em.
I didn't put that in there.
Tell them why
Professor Vasquez left MIT.
Are you gonna
answer his question?
What about the professor?
I set him up.
ENRIQUE:
Yes, he set him up.
Vámonos.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Vámonos, vámonos,
vámonos, vámonos.
♪ ♪
(SIREN BLARING)
(CELL DOOR CREAKS,
THEN CLOSES)
♪ (SOFT GUITAR) ♪
PROFESSOR VASQUEZ:
I use it for everything.
My house, my office.
I want you to have it.
Mi casa es su casa.
Don't worry,
I have the original.
Hey, Simon, I'm sorry
about your parents.
(KNOCKING)
Simon.
Harold, what are you doing?
You want to tell me
what happened.
I didn't do it.
Well, I believe you.
But it doesn't matter,
I'd be here anyway.
What went on
with you and Vasquez?
When I was 16, my parents died and Vasquez took me in.
I had been doing dual enrollment
at MIT since I was 14,
and I eventually became
his understudy, and that...
that's where the device
came from.
He trusted me.
Gave me the key to his life.
This was his.
I had a copy,
but I threw it away
when I got busted.
Busted for what?
Um, when I found out that I could control electronic signals
with the device, I...
(SIGHS)
used it to block out
the security system,
the cameras, and the alarms
at the chemistry department...
where they kept a large supply
of sodium hydroxide.
The methamphetamine?
Yeah.
I had this brilliant idea
to sell it to a student
that I knew was cooking it.
It was stupid.
I got busted...
and I got scared.
When the cops questioned me,
I lied and blamed it on Vasquez.
And then he got fired
and deported,
and I ruined his life.
How did you get
Vasquez's original key?
When I got out of jail,
there was a letter.
He asked me to come help him.
And inside...
was the key.
And that's how I ended up here.
I just wanted him to know
that I was sorry.
Harold, it's time.
Well, I have to go,
but I just wanted you to know that I was here for you,
I don't care what you've done.
And, uh, since it looks like you
might have a little free time
on your hands...
You really want me
to read that book, don't you?
And, um...
and this is the Book
it's based on.
We'll have you out
of here before long.
Gracias.
♪ (PLAINTIVE GUITAR) ♪
VASQUEZ: "Simon,
I sincerely hope
"that you never read
this letter.
"It means that
my paranoid delusions
"have come true
and the worst has occurred.
"Regardless, I need you
to know that I forgive you.
"There are some very bad people
who want to use this device
"for the wrong reasons.
"I disassembled it
so they can't use it,
"but you can figure it out.
"Use the key to open your world.
"I love you always...
Juan 8:12."
♪ ♪
"When Jesus spoke again
to the people,
He said,
'I am the light of the world.
Whoever follows Me
will never walk in darkness,
but will have
the light of life.'"
John 8:12.
(ENRIQUE SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Harold, how long
have you been out here?
Are you spying on me here?
I guess I would
have been, Enrique,
if I understood Spanish better,
but I just heard a voice.
Oh, what's going on?
You borrow something?
Hmm.
Simon didn't tell you?
No, Simon didn't tell me.
Well, after the blackout
in town,
I told him
that I wanted it back.
This thing is
clearly more dangerous
than what we thought, Harold.
We don't want it to fall
to the wrong hands, do we?
No, we sure do not.
It's too bad you can't make it to my fundraiser
tomorrow morning.
I'll pray for you,
that you're gonna
feel better, Harold.
We need you here.
(TRUNK SLAMS)
Well, you have a good night.
♪ (GUITAR) ♪
ENRIQUE:
Señoras y señores...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CHEERS & APPLAUSE)
My philosophy,
let's fill up schools
and university, not orphanages.
(CHEERS & APPLAUSE)
My good friend Harold said once,
give a child one opportunity
for education,
and he will give...
he...
he used to say...
Harold, what a surprise.
Harold Finch himself
came to our church,
so please welcome Harold Finch.
(APPLAUSE)
HAROLD:
Muchas gracias.
Perdón, voy a hablar Inglés.
I understand Spanish
much better than I speak it,
but I will be very brief
and direct to you today.
Corruption is a cancer that
slowly but surely destroys.
It can destroy a community's
standard of living.
It can destroy the job market.
And, friends, I must say to you
that corruption has
a death grip on our town.
(AUDIENCE AGREES)
But... there is a cure.
That cure is honesty
and integrity.
(CHEERS & APPLAUSE)
But it must start from the top.
We are here in front
of St. Mary's beautiful church.
Therefore,
I would like to... to close
with a few words of prayer.
If you will join me
in that prayer.
Dear God, we pray
that You give us leaders
who will live up
to Your standards.
And we also pray,
heavenly Father,
that those leaders who will not or cannot do so
be cut down
and stripped of their power.
We pray in Jesus' name, amen.
(APPLAUSE)
ENRIQUE:
Gracias!
Thank you.
Harold Finch!
(WHISPERING)
You know what that means, right?
I answer to God alone.
I can arrange that.
Harold Finch,
ladies and gentlemen.
Harold Finch.
(CHEERS & APPLAUSE)
Together we're gonna
clean our streets!
♪ (WOMAN SINGING SOFTLY) ♪
And remove ourselves
of corruption.
Anyone who stands in our way
will be treated
as the enemy of Mexico.
Viva México!
Viva la libertad!
Together we'll prevail
by the grace of God.
♪ ♪
Oh, Simon, I'm so sorry.
You don't belong here.
I know you had nothing
to do with the drugs.
I should have believed you.
I...
should have came clean
about my past earlier.
It doesn't matter now.
Some very bad things
have happened today.
What do you mean "bad"?
Enrique, he lied to us all.
He put Harold
under house arrest.
The children,
he's taken all of them.
What do you mean he's
taken all the children?
He's working with El Noche.
He's using them to get elected.
Harold overheard everything.
He's going to meet
with him tonight.
He wants to show
them the device.
It will be two hours without
any power along the border,
so they can take their drugs
in and out as they will.
You've got to stop them.
We have to stop them.
That's why I'm gonna
help you escape.
Shh.
Don't worry about Martinez.
The reason she likes
orphans so much
is because she used to be one.
Now, listen carefully, Loco.
At exactly 3:00 p.m.,
a guard will come by
and slide you your meal.
(METAL SLIDING)
Underneath the cup
you will find a pill.
What's the pill do?
It will help you escape.
(RETCHING)
I will create a distraction.
Buenos dias, señor!
(THUD)
(YELLING)
When you get
to the medical room...
(METAL CLATTERING)
you will find a gift.
Yo soy!
Pedro, man!
Ha-ha-ha!
(COMMOTION & YELLING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Muchas Gracias.
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC) ♪
CLARA: We need to stop
meeting like this.
(DOOR SLAMS)
A gift from Pedro.
Gracias.
Where to?
Vasquez's house.
Be quick.
I need to look for
something in the closet.
(LOCK CLICKS)
♪ ♪
ENRIQUE: Simon,
you're so simple.
You see, I knew
I'm gonna find you here.
Yeah, you're
pretty simple yourself.
Oh, yeah?
I think so.
Why don't you
enlighten me, punk?
You want me to enlighten you?
Yeah.
Well, for starters,
I know that you killed Vasquez.
That was easy.
Next?
Hacked into his e-mail.
That's how you
found out about me.
Sent this guy over here,
Huggy Bear,
who welcomed me at the border.
Luckily for you,
he sucks at his job.
(CARLOS SPEAKING SPANISH)
Shh.
You have the device,
but it doesn't work.
That's where I come in, right?
When Dr. Vasquez
disactivated the device,
I lost hope.
But then God brought you to me
as a miracle to fix the device.
And you did fix it.
You continued Vasquez's work.
The way that I figure it out,
it turns out to be that you brought some component.
(CLATTERING)
And I need you to fix it.
No.
So you're not afraid to die?
Wow.
Looks like Harold's
religion got to you.
But, if Carlos' 9-millimeter's
insufficient reason enough...
(GUN RACKS)
(SIGHS)
How about Harold?
Nah, Harold is too old.
He'll die fast.
Oh...
Sofia.
Mm, you wouldn't.
Vámonos!
We've got a border to shut down.
Let's go, wrap him up.
Vámonos aquí, ahora.
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC) ♪
(CAR DOORS CLOSE)
ENRIQUE: El Noche is gonna
be here in one hour.
That means he want to see
what that device is gonna do.
SIMON:
How about some light?
Sweetie, there's no power here.
All right?
So let's not get spoiled,
and go to work.
(CLAP-CLAP)
Ándale.
(GRAVEL CRUNCHING)
ENRIQUE:
Do you really need this tuner
to make this device work?
Do you want the lights on,
or do you want the lights off?
All right, buddy,
this is show time.
You better behave yourself.
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC) ♪
Bienvenidos, El Noche.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Who is the gringo?
El gringo, Señor El Noche,
se llama Simon Orwell.
Let's just call him
a helpful scientist.
This place is a graveyard
of those who have tried
to be helpful.
Not far from here
is the U.S. border.
If you can cut its power,
it will be helpful.
If not, you will
have wasted my time.
I consider that...
not very helpful.
Well, Governor,
should we get started?
♪ ♪
(WHISTLES LOUDLY)
Rico!
(DIAL CLICKING)
I don't need to tell you
what is at stake here, right?
I think he was pretty clear.
(SWITCH CLICKS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(DEVICE HUMMING
& ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Carlos...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC) ♪
Sí!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Bien, muy bien, muy bien.
(ENRIQUE SPEAKING SPANISH)
Muy bien, muy bien.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Oh!
(PEDRO LAUGHS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(AGENT MARTINEZ
SPEAKING SPANISH)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(EXCITED CHATTER)
(YELLING IN SPANISH) Federales!
(SIRENS BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
♪ (FAST-PACED MUSIC) ♪
Agh!
(GRUNTS & SCUFFLING)
Adios, Simon.
Aghh!
(THUD!)
(ENRIQUE GROANING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ ♪
REPORTER: The small border town of Tialingua
was rocked by scandal
two months ago
when it was revealed that
one of the biggest drug busts
in history's ringleader
was none other than their mayor, Enrique De Angelo.
But now they may be
known for something else.
Sol Energy Enterprises
has announced the acquisition
of a revolutionary new device
promising to provide
free unlimited energy.
And, remarkably,
the birthplace of this device:
an orphanage in Tialingua.
The prototype was created
by an MIT dropout
named Simon Orwell
and his professor,
the late Armando Vasquez.
Mr. Orwell says he plans
to donate all of his proceeds
to orphanages around the world.
And we'll have much more
on that coming up.
(APPLAUSE)
Ah, Loco.
Pretty amazing we got a signal
all the way from El Paso.
Can I borrow you for a moment?
(CHILDREN LAUGHING & TEASING)
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hola?
Oh, Dr. Harold.
Niños,
say hi to Dr. Harold.
(IN UNISON)
Hi, Dr. Harold!
So, how's the Philippines?
Yeah, things are great.
I think we found the spot
for our next orphanage.
That's so great to hear,
such good news.
It's great to see a man that
practices what he preaches.
It means that I'm gonna
have to be gone for a while,
so I guess now is
as good a time as any.
For what?
Well, for you
to take over the orphanage.
(DOG BARKING)
Pedro?
Oh, thank you so much,
Dr. Harold!
You've earned it, Pedro.
Submit your ways to the Lord,
and your plans will be achieved.
Oh, Dr. Harold,
this is so exciting!
How is Simon?
Simon's good.
Already working
on his third goal.
Oh, you must mean your sister.
I think unlimited power
is easier than Sofia.
I think you're right.
Ah, but, you know,
the more impossible,
the bigger the blessing.
Something came for you.
No way.
(SIGHS)
Well, that takes care of two... two of the three.
Two of the three?
Harold's three goals.
I was wondering if maybe
you could help me out
with this third one, though.
Yeah?
JUAN:
Wanna play?
Wanna lose?
♪ ♪
WOMAN:
♪ Ahh ahhh ahh ahhh ♪
♪ Ahh ahhh ahh ahhh. ♪♪
CAPTION TECHNOLOGIES, INC.
www.captiontech.com
♪ ♪
JACI VELASQUEZ:
♪ Things may change ♪
♪ You'll find a way. ♪
♪ There are no limits to
what His love can do. ♪
♪ What others say
can't take away ♪
♪ All He's given you. ♪
♪ No doubt His Word is true. ♪
♪ When thoughts grow cold,
it's not the end of the road. ♪
♪ No matter what you're told, He's always in control. ♪
♪ I know where you are;
yeah, I've been there too. ♪
♪ Let Him answer you. ♪
♪ How far can you dream
if you just believe ♪
♪ There is no end, no end... ♪
♪ How far can you go? ♪
♪ He'll let you know ♪
♪ Now I fear not ♪
♪ To end the strife,
that's a goal in life. ♪
♪ Now you're pushin' through
the dark ahead of you. ♪
♪ (SINGING IN SPANISH) ♪
♪ I know where you are;
yeah, I've been there too. ♪
♪ Let Him answer you. ♪
♪ How far can you dream
if you just believe ♪
♪ There is no end, no end... ♪
♪ How far can you go? ♪
♪ He'll let you know ♪
♪ Now I fear not ♪
♪ Now it's possible to breathe ♪
♪ When you're carried
by the breeze. ♪
♪ How far can you dream... ♪
♪ Oh...
there is no end, no end. ♪
♪ How far can you go? ♪
♪ Now I fear not ♪
♪ How far can you dream ♪
♪ If you just believe
there is no end, no end? ♪
♪ How far can you go? ♪
♪ He'll let you know ♪
♪ Now I fear not. ♪♪