--== McEphie ==--
[upbeat music playing]
[chanting softly]
[ticking]
[man in English] Good morning!
Rise and shine!
Beat you again!
[satisfied groan, yawning]
[shower water running]
Dad! Towel!
Bela, get your brother his towel.
Miss George, towel, please!
[loudly] Benedict, towel!
Oh, that's me. Sorry. Towel, coming!
[chuckles]
[upbeat music resumes]
[sizzling]
-Is this everything?
-[Miss George] Yes.
[Benedict] Bela, Dad, let's eat.
[grunting]
[screaming]
-[game playing]
-Hey, we have to go.
One moment. Wait!
[Dad] I can’t beat your sister yet.
Dad, you really can’t beat her.
Why?
You're using this.
But your score's high.
Come on. Let's go.
I miss you so much.
-[in English] Happy birthday.
-The restroom's so far.
Ah…
-Happy birth--
-Let's go. I'm running late.
[in English] Happy birthday, okay?
Happy birthday!
-[cheerful music playing]
-[whistling softly]
[engine revving]
[car horn honking]
Good evening to all my peeps out there
who are listening
to our live podcast tonight.
This is Papa Tak.
I'm here to solve your love problems.
The time is eight o'clock in the evening.
We will now start
our conversation with Papa Tak!
-Our first caller.
-[caller] Hello, Papa Tak. This is Helen.
[in English] I've had a boyfriend
for five years now.
We haven't had any problems so far.
Helen! So why did you call
when you don't have any problem?
[Hugot Tina]
That's her problem.
Good that she doesn't have any problems
while others have lots of it.
Here's what you need to do.
Call me once you have
a problem, okay? Next!
[caller 2] Hello, Papa Tak, this is Jun.
-I have a question.
-Yes, Jun?
I would like to know
when the girl I am courting
will finally say yes.
Jun, let me remind you.
I'm a DJ, not a fortune-teller.
Ask the girl you're courting, not me.
And Jun, if you really want to know,
go to Quiapo.
Ask the fortune-teller, and also,
ask when you two will break up. Next!
I prefer someone
not too beautiful but kind,
obedient, hardworking, thoughtful,
who knows how to cook,
and who can do chores.
Zaldy, you aren’t looking for a girlfriend
but a house help. Tell us if you want her
to stay in or stay out.
[laughing]
Before we continue with our program,
I want to introduce my co-host first,
who's been speaking her mind.
Here's Hugot Tina!
[voice echoes]
Good evening, Papa Tak.
To our listeners this evening,
I'm the girl who speaks my mind
out here, there, and everywhere!
My name is Hugot Tina.
[staff yelling]
Good evening to you too, Hugot Tina.
And now, let's continue
our conversation with Papa Tak.
Next caller, please.
[woman] Hi.
[Hugot Tina]
And for our next caller, here she is!
[caller 3] Hugot Tina,
Can you help me with my boyfriend?
[Hugot Tina]
Why? How old are you?
[caller] Twenty-one.
He’s my first boyfriend.
-[Hugot Tina] How old is he?
-[indistinct]
-[Hugot Tina] This is what you should do…
-[in English] Thank you!
[man in English] One coffee for Papa Tak.
No, thank you.
No, it's mine.
Babe, why are you late?
I already started with my podcast.
I thought you’d be off by 5 p.m.
[in English] Babe, sorry.
My boss talked to me.
That's right. My boss talked to her.
It took so long.
Is it about your promotion?
Babe. Please let me accept it.
You should be happy for me.
[sighs]
I am happy for you, babe.
Babe. It's just Singapore.
I can go home every weekend
or you can visit me there.
[sighs softly] Babe.
Singapore or any country,
you’d still be leaving.
We will still be apart.
That's what I'm asking you…
not to leave.
And speaking of leaving, I have to leave.
I need to go back to the podcast.
Just wait for me here
and I'll take you home.
No need. We'll go ahead.
Go ahead. I’m only taking her.
[in English] Thank you.
He's sweet, isn’t he?
-Right? Sweet.
-Let's go.
Let's go.
[Benedict]
We'll see us again tomorrow.
Same time, same place.
Only here, on our program with…
Hugot Tina.
And Papa Tak! Goodbye!
-[upbeat music playing]
-[ticking]
-Here, sir.
-Thank you.
[sneezing]
Mm-mm.
[gushing]
Mm-hmm.
[murmurs]
[inaudible]
And that's where we end our program,
but we'll see each other again tomorrow.
[in English] Same time, same place.
Only here, on our program with…
[Hugot Tina] Hugot Tina.
And Papa Tak!
[in English] Goodbye!
-[mix instruments playing]
-[staff sings][in English] Bye bye!
Tina, you're late again.
Sorry, there was heavy traffic.
[staff mocking]
But you're always late.
If you leave early,
then you'll get here on time.
-True!
-Know what? If you do that again,
I will replace you!
[staff] Right. Right.
Right? You'll get some hitting too.
You, Jon, Bon, Jovi.
Are you perfect?
We've been doing this for years.
Your timing is still off.
-Sorry, Papa Tak.
-Sorry.
-You always say sorry.
Get your act together!
Will you always apologize after each show?
We're always like this.
I'm getting sick of it.
Right, Papa Tak,
we’ll get it right next time.
-Okay, I’ll go ahead.
-Take care.
[sigh]
[atmospheric music playing]
Victoria.
You know what, when you're with me,
my world stops.
That's why I want to give you…
all my time.
Victoria.
Will you marry me?
Papa Tak?
Papa Tak!
[screaming] Papa Tak is here!
It's Papa Tak!
Mother, Papa Tak is here!
-You are my idol!
-Thank you.
-Papa Tak, you are my idol!
-[in English] Roses?
-Yes, roses.
Wait, I have many stories about that.
Miss, is this seat taken?
-No.
-Can you move here?
[in English] There. Thank you!
You know what, Papa Tak? About the roses.
I gave my girlfriend one of these,
but we still broke up! [sobbing]
-It was just bad luck.
-I’m not unlucky.
I’m not unlucky.
But let's take a selfie first.
-You want to hold it?
-You're crying?
No, I already moved on. That was long ago.
Aren't you listening to my stories?
-Sorry.
-Okay, you take the selfie.
[deep breath]
You're not even that techie, Papa Tak.
-Let's stand to get another angle.
-Stand?
Yes, so we can show the ambiance.
-[in English] Ambiance!
-Ambiance!
[man giggles]
Okay. Now, take a picture of me.
-Ambiance… Yes, for my profile picture.
-Are you sure?
-Yes. Sure.
-Okay.
[romantic music playing]
-Sorry, babe. Am I late again?
-No, babe. It's all right.
Ugh. Babe.
Babe, flowers for you.
[sighs heavily]
Let's order?
I already ordered for us.
[clears throat]
Babe.
It's not my birthday.
And it’s not our anniversary.
What’s the occasion?
Because babe…
-I have something to tell you--
-Wait. Let me talk first.
I also have something to tell you.
[chuckles] Wait, babe,
don't tell me you're breaking up with me.
That only happens in the movies.
Yes, Benedict,
that's what I really want to tell you.
I think it's time for us
to go our separate ways.
Why, babe?
[guitar playing]
[woman]Thank you, honey.
♪ Ask me, ask me ♪
♪ Who I love, who I love ♪
I’m getting tired of our relationship.
You always decide.
You never listen to me.
I feel like you want to control my life.
At first, it was okay because…
because I loved you.
But no.
I don't count in this relationship.
You don't even know
that I don't like it here.
But babe, all our occasions,
our events, we celebrate here.
I thought this was
your favorite restaurant.
Your favorite.
You just assume that I like it here.
I'm allergic to seafood.
[waiter] Excuse me, sir. Your order.
[clears throat]
[clears throat louder]
I'm sorry, Benedict.
Babe.
[in English] You have to let me go.
[melancholic music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
-[thunder rumbling continues]
-[crowd chattering]
♪ My aching heart is crying
My aching heart is crying ♪
♪ I don’t want anyone to witness it
I don’t want anyone to witness it ♪
♪ No matter how hurtful it is
No matter how hurtful it is ♪
[thunder rumbling]
♪ I don’t want her to see it
I don’t want her to see it ♪
Step aside!
[voice whispering] Turning Point.
[crowd chattering]
[rain drizzling]
[crowd shouting]
[suspenseful music playing]
Sir,
it looks like you're going through a lot.
How did you know that I have a problem?
You won't be able to see this bar
if you're not going through hard times.
Why? What kind of bar is this?
This is the Turning Point bar.
All of those who come here,
get the chance to change their fate.
[chuckles]
[smirking]
You know what?
I can't tell who between us is drunk.
Fate?
You know,
ever since my girlfriend dumped me,
my fate is gone.
Destroyed.
[sobbing]
This is the Wishkey.
When you drink this,
you will have the chance to correct
the wrong decisions in life.
Oh? Really?
Oh.
Try it.
I wish
what you’re saying is true.
But it's not.
Hey! [squeaking]
Don’t waste this!
Psst. Woo-hoo!
[bird chirping]
[sighs deeply]
Wake him up.
-Brother, wake up.
-[murmurs]
Wake up.
Son, wake up.
You will be late for your appointments.
So be it!
Brother, wake up!
[grunting]
Son.
We know that
what you’re going through is painful.
Let's talk about it.
That's right, Brother. We're here for you.
If you already know, why talk about it?
Your life shouldn't stop
just because of what happened.
I'll forget about Victoria in time.
-I just don't want to see her things.
-[Miss George] Sir?
Where do I put Victoria's slippers?
I just said it.
-[Bela] You sure?
-[Benedict] Bela?
I can't replace her,
-but I promise you that I will move on.
-Where should I put these?
Keep it. Wear it as a cape.
Is it possible?
We're always here for you.
Just don't mind me.
I can forget about Victoria.
This pillow? Where should I put this?
I will take it and throw it in your face.
Leave me!
I said I will forget about Victoria.
I just don't want to see her pictures.
End of story.
I'll just keep this, then.
[screams]
I said I don't want to see you anymore!
[sobbing]
[sobbing] I don't want this anymore!
[in English] I love you! [sobbing]
[car engine turns over]
[suspenseful music plays]
I’ll end the trip, sir.
Five stars, please.
Okay.
Thank you, Joel.
[delicate music plays]
-How are you Victoria?
-I’m not okay.
[man] Is it about the promotion?
[Victoria] I hope he understands.
[man] Are you okay?
-[Victoria] It’s hard not to think of him.
-Don’t think too much.
You were talking about Singapore,
when the truth is,
you dumped me for that guy.
Sir, did you say something?
You're awesome!
I can hear you talk with your mind.
Huh. What is he talking about?
You said that girl
replaced you for that guy.
She made you believe it's about Singapore.
Huh? How did he hear it?
What a jerk!
You're the jerk!
You're not the only one who can do that.
Is someone there? Stella?
-Yes?
-Check if there's someone outside.
[in English] Okay.
[mysterious music plays]
[voice whispering] Turning Point.
[Stella] There’s no one here!
[rapid breathing]
[Benedict] How did you appear here?
What am I doing here?
That's right. What are you doing here?
Perhaps it’s time for you to drink.
That's right!
I have to drink the one you offered me.
[hissing]
-Saro.
-Benedict.
Wait!
[phone chimes]
[shattering]
-Eh--
-I'm sorry.
Someone texted me.
Another one.
Wait! One moment.
Is it really effective?
It's guaranteed.
[gulping]
[slurping]
Nothing’s happeni--
[birds chirping]
[delicate piano music]
[man] And now, I’m going to create
a handsome man like me,
so I can rest in the meantime.
I’ll just sleep. BRB.
[gushing]
Why am I naked?
[birds chirping]
[indistinct growling]
[indistinct animal sound]
[Benedict] Victoria?
Victoria. So you're an open-minded person.
I am too.
I am not Victoria.
I am Eve.
Who are you?
If you are Eve…
Then I must be Adam.
You are not Adam.
Don't eat that!
Who are you?
I’m no longer open-minded.
I'm not Sinoka. I am Adam!
-I am Adam!
-You are Adam!
-Thank you!
It suits you better.
Hold on! Let me ask you something.
Why did you have to climb
to the top of the tree
when there's a lot here?
You’re right! It's very high.
-Why did I do that?
-[indistinct animal growling]
-[Victoria] Drop it.
-[Benedict] Huh!
I am Adam!
-I am Adam!
-[Benedict] No!
[Benedict breathing heavily]
It hurts!
[grunting]
[hissing]
[gasping]
Eh… Eh…
[cricket chirping]
[scratching]
[scratching continues]
-Bon? Jovi?
-Sh!
Don't be too loud.
If Humberto hears you, you are dead!
Crude.
-Is Humberto here?
-Sh!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
-What are you doing?
-I am making a fire.
We are cooking food.
Making a fire?
Sh!
-What is that?
-You eat raw meat?
I'm hungry! I eat raw meat!
[disgusted sound]
What? Why do you have blood in your mouth?
My wife has…
-Ew!
-has food.
-[Benedict sighs]
-[man] There's a lot of blood.
[in English] Okay.
-Wanna a bite of my bird?
-I don't want it. Too many feathers.
Can I make fire?
You can help.
I don't have that!
-[whispering]
-Sh!
Help. Help.
Okay. Okay!
-Victoria?
-[fire lights up]
[soft instrumental music]
Why are you staring at me?
Do you have a problem with me?
Me? I don't have a problem with you.
I am staring at you
because I am admiring your beauty.
Wait. Where are you going?
I will look for food.
No! Let me look for food.
Here he comes--
Shh.
[rumbling]
-Humberto is here!
-[indistinct growling]
Run!
[crowd mumbling]
-Who's Humberto?
-That stinks.
-[Victoria whispers]
[growling in the distance]
-Who's Humberto?
-[whispering]
-[Benedic sighs]
-Who's Humberto?
-Sh!
[whispering] Be quiet!
-Humberto will kill you.
-[Benedict] Okay.
I don’t believe that.
If we make a noise, Humberto will kill us.
Oh, come on.
-[man chuckles]
-[Benedict humming]
[growling]
Bokbok!
Pokpok is gone too!
[gasping]
I told you!
Humberto will kill you!
Now I believe.
If we make a noise, we are dead.
[cracking]
-I will kill Humberto!
You kill Humberto!
-You're the hero.
-You are strong!
-[Victoria whispers]
-[Benedict groaning]
[tense music playing]
-[screaming]
-[farting]
Sh!
[farting]
[low growling]
[growling]
You are Humberto? But I just farted!
[roaring]
No, Humberto! No! [gasping]
I look like a catfish.
Victoria? Victoria!
Where are you?
[man] They are here! They are here!
They are here! They are here!
[screaming]
[intense music playing]
[yelling]
[grunting, screaming]
Wait!
[clamoring]
Guys, we are friends! Let’s not fight!
[clamoring resumes]
[grunting, groaning]
[man] Wait.
[screaming, whimpering]
[grunting]
[in English] Sorry!
[woman in Spanish] ¡Despacito!
I know you!
Does it hurt?
[grunting]
Oh, it hurts? I’m sorry. I’m sorry.
[woman echoing] ¡Despacito!
[dire music playing]
[screaming]
Ouch!
Despacito.
[in Spanish] I love you.
I love you with all my heart.
[sobbing] I want to breathe in your neck.
[sobbing]
[in Spanish] I love you!
[heart beating heavily]
[in Spanish] I love you too.
-[sad music playing]
-[panting]
Does it hurt?
Just pick me instead.
[grunts]
[gasping]
Victoria! Victoria?
[rapid breathing]
[gasping] Sir Saro!
Sir Saro! Hi, idol!
Don't talk to him!
Why is he here?
He wants to go back to his past fight!
I see. Can I get an autograph?
Idol! Can I get an autograph?
That's what happened to me?
[stutters] But Sir Saro,
what you were saying is true.
I have been to different eras!
But how did I get back here?
You restarted.
Restart? How? Like a video game?
Exactly!
When you die,
you will go to a different era.
If you couldn't complete your mission,
you will come back to the bar.
What? Why did you just tell me now?
I was supposed to tell you,
but you already drank the Wishkey.
But why do I need to go
to different times?
Why can't I just go back to the time
when Victoria and I broke up?
Because now that you started this,
only the Wishkey knows
where it's power will take you.
What? So it means I have to go
to a lot of different eras?
Now you know!
Oh, come on!
[sighs]
-Sir Saro!
-Huh?
Why does Joey Marquez have a bottle?
-Where?
-There!
I already broke that one!
[grunts]
[gasping]
[classic guitar playing]
[spitting]
-Are you okay?
-Bela?
Why are you here? Where's Dad?
Who's Bela?
I am not Bela. I am Gregoria.
And you. Who are you?
I am… Hua Ze Lei.
-Hua Ze Lei?
-What-che-lei-lei. What-che-lei.
I can't understand you.
Fix it.
How are you?
Victoria!
-I am not Victoria.
-I am Maria.
Excuse me.
Maria.
You need to know something about me,
why I am here.
What do you want?
It's because I'm not from here.
I came from a different time,
and I have a mission.
Because of you, Victoria. I mean, Maria.
You're not from here?
-Are you a spy?
-No!
No, in fact, I love our country.
Um… um…
I am here because you need to love me.
If you're not a spy,
then you're probably crazy.
Yes. I am crazy about you.
Really, now.
If you're telling the truth
and you are not a spy,
prove it in our attack later.
[in English] Attack? Go! Carry.
Comrades!
Um…
Supremo is calling us.
[dark music playing]
Who is he?
-Don’t you know him?
-No.
He is the Supremo.
Supremo?
Why does Richard Gutierrez
look different in person.
Don’t you know the Supremo?
I said I don't.
Supremo is Andres Bonifacio.
Andres Bonifacio!
Sh!
He’s my idol.
Comrades!
Supremo has an important announcement.
[eventful music playing]
Comrades!
The revolution has begun!
Later, our attack is set
to ambush the civil guards
who will cross Balintawak.
We will meet there
the group of Berting, from Hagonoy.
Long live the revolution!
Long live!
Long live the Katipunan!
-Long live free WiFi!
-Long live…
Long live freedom of speech…
Wakanda forever!
Sorry about that, Supremo.
Let's take out our daggers!
Let’s show our loyalty to the Katipunan!
[screaming]
Brother!
We're done. We did that yesterday.
Comrades!
Take out your identification cards!
[up-tempo music playing]
Let us all tear our identification cards!
Long live the revolution!
Long live!
Long live the Katipunan!
Supremo!
Good news.
What is it, Poochy?
We are getting our firearms!
Good! What do we need?
Our identification cards.
[crickets chirping]
Pick up the identification cards. Hurry!
Double time!
I have one, and it's intact!
That's good. Give it to me.
[tense music playing]
Get ready, comrades.
They're getting closer.
[Benedict] Maria, are you sure
about what you are doing?
[Benedict] This is dangerous.
You are talking nonsense.
I am ready to fight for our freedom.
If that's what you want to do,
then let me be the one to do it for you.
Remember.
[in English] With great power,
comes great…
great…
taste love of all.
And I promise, if you jump, I jump!
They're here.
What?
-The Spaniards are here.
Positions, comrades.
Okay, I will follow. I'm almost done.
[suspenseful music playing]
[sword blade scraping]
[clanking]
-[sword blade scraping]
-Alert!
Charge! [screaming]
[intense music playing]
[screaming]
That's right!
[grunting, screaming]
Ouch! Ouch!
[soft instrumental music]
Ouch!
-[screams]
-[grunts]
Ouch!
-It's itchy! Itchy!
-[indistinct]
It's itchy! It's so itchy! Ouch!
Horrible.
Hey, can you at least look at it? Please?
[screaming]
Charge!
Brother, let's go.
Oh, is it that way?
[grunting]
[sword blade scraping]
Thank you very much, Berting.
-Anything for our country, Supremo.
-To your positions.
Go! Hurry!
[man] To your positions!
[breathing heavily]
-Let's go, brother.
-You are a Spaniard!
You took her from me!
This is what you deserve!
[grunting]
[man] What are you talking about?
-I'm not Kapatid, I'm Kapamilya!
-Traitor.
Comrades! There's a traitor here!
That's right. There's a traitor!
Why are you fighting Berting?
You're a traitor!
Oh, she's a Kapuso.
[groans]
[Benedict] Victoria!
[Benedict] Thank God, I’m alive.
I really thought you killed me.
[Benedict exhaling]
[Benedict] You’re coming.
At long last, I can finally taste you.
[Benedict] Really?
What are you saying?
You really missed me. [chuckles]
[stutters] It feels like…
You seem so strong, Victoria.
[chuckles]
[ominous music plays]
Is that a beard?
And do I have red hair?
-Goodbye, Dick!
-[screaming] Why can’t I move?
[clamoring]
Wait up, comrades!
The chicken ass is mine.
-[man] I'll take the butt part.
-Okay!
-[gasping]
-Good luck!
[breathing heavily]
Beny, you’re awake! [groaning]
Get ready!
We might get reprimanded again.
Beny?
Who are you?
Rodolfo, Beny, get ready.
You are next. Hurry up.
[chuckles] Let's go, sleepyhead.
We will be reprimanded again. You'll see.
-Are you ready?
-Huh?
Hurry up!
Let’s give a round of applause!
We had great performers tonight!
But here's what
we've all been waiting for.
The team-up of Rodolfo and…
What's his name again?
-[man] Beny!
-Huh? Jenny?
-Beny
-Oh, Beny.
The team-up of Rodolfo and Jenny!
Round of applause!
[claps]
[Rodulfo exhales]
[mumbling]
Hey!
[piano playing]
Hey. Dance!
-Huh?
-Dance.
Dance?
Dance. There are so many people.
Dance? What kind of dance?
Like this. Tap dance.
Tap dance? That's a dance?
It's like removing poop from your shoes.
This is what you call tap dance.
Come on.
-Okay.
-Game!
[man snoring]
-What kind of dance is that?
-Huh?
Tap dance.
Tap dance revolution.
-[man 1 sighs]
-[man 2 whistles]
[Rodulfo chuckles]
[girl screaming]
-[girl] When are you visiting us?
-[Rodulfo] It's up to you.
Later, if you want?
-Later? Okay!
-[moans softly]
[gasps] He looks like Rizal!
Bring him with you.
[chuckles]
[gasping]
Okay, go ahead and we will follow.
-Okay. Promise?
-Of course!
[smacks lips]
[girl] Bye, Dolphy!
Bye!
[chuckles]
Dolphy?
Yes.
Lodi! Lodi!
What's..
-What is lodi?
-Idol!
-Idol.
-Idol?
Idol!
Is he going crazy?
He's going crazy.
Dolphy.
Is that a bulb?
[chuckles]
Be quiet about this.
[clears throat]
I got it from the makeup room.
The one in my bathroom is busted.
Lodi!
[Rodulfo] What? [chuckles]
-So, let’s follow them?
-There? [laughing]
-Let's go.
-Okay.
I just got invited here before
and it was so much fun.
Really?
[Rodulfo] Don't be nervous.
Welcome to Casa Fantastica!
Where we will make
all your fantasies come true.
No, I don't want to.
-Thank you.
-[girl] I want to.
No! No! I’m fine.
Thank you, Macario.
Take care.
Come again!
Goodbye.
What happened to you?
Did you have an X-ray?
[sexy music playing]
Don’t play hard to get.
Who is that?
[girl] That's Victorina.
The most in-demand girl in here.
Just like her, long ago.
She's the one for you. She's yours!
-No! I'm okay.
-I can manage.
I'm willing to wait.
[woman] come with me
You. You're mine.
[man] Go there.
I want her.
But she’s already reserved.
Her client may come any minute.
So, you’re mine instead!
No, here!
I will pay any amount for her.
-Just give me money to get home.
-Victorina!
Take care of our guest.
[panting]
I thought you didn't want to.
But it seems you have chosen ahead of us?
I like her.
[girl sighs]
Let's go.
[in English] Hi!
We're closed.
[sexy music playing]
Hi, handsome.
Are you next?
I'm a little lonely.
You might want to have fun with me.
-You want to have fun?
-Mh-hm.
Here. Go to the town fair outside.
[in English] Enjoy.
Town fair. Town fair!
[girl giggling]
[playful music]
Take off your clothes.
Or you want me to do it for you?
[sexy music playing]
Eh… ah…
[stammering]
That's not what I want.
I just want us to talk.
You paid a big amount of money
just to talk to someone like me?
-Yes.
-Why?
Because I love you. I mean…
Yes, since I paid a high price,
it means we should do
whatever I want, right?
[breathing softly] Okay.
Your wish is my command.
What do you want us to talk about?
[delicate music playing]
If it's okay with you,
and please don’t get this wrong,
is it okay if I help you?
I never met someone
who had good intentions for me.
There’s Roberto.
He comes here often for me,
but I don't think
it will lead to anything.
So, if it's true that you have
good intentions for me, thank you.
My name is…
Beny.
How did you know?
Don't you
always perform?
-What?
-In the vaudeville!
[chuckles]
And you are very good at…
What else?
…dancing.
Do you really want me to make you happy?
Hm?
[crowd cheering and applause]
♪ Ask me
Ask me ♪
♪ Who I love
Who I love ♪
♪ Ask me
Ask me ♪
♪ I won’t answer long
I won’t answer long ♪
♪ You’re the only one I love
You’re the only one I love ♪
♪ Your love is what I need
Your love is what I need ♪
♪ A long lasting love
A long lasting love ♪
♪ That’s what I truly feels
That’s what I truly feels ♪
♪ I have only one feeling
I have only one feeling ♪
♪ You’re the one I love
You’re the one I love ♪
♪ I hope you believe me
I hope you believe me ♪
♪ To me, there’s no one else
To me, there’s no one else ♪
♪ You’re the only one I love
You’re the only one I love ♪
♪ Your love is what I need
Your love is what I need ♪
♪ A long lasting love
A long lasting love ♪
♪ That’s what I truly feels
That’s what I truly feels ♪
♪ I hope you know
I hope you know ♪
♪ From north or south or west
From north or south or west ♪
♪ No matter where
No matter where ♪
♪ I will always shout  ♪
♪ You’re the one I love
You’re the one I love ♪
♪ I hope you know
I hope you know ♪
♪ From north or south or west
From north or south or west ♪
♪ No matter where
No matter where ♪
♪ I will always shout
I will always shout ♪
♪ You’re the one I love
You’re the one I love ♪
♪ You’re the one I love ♪
-Give him a round of applause!
-[crowd clapping]
And this ends our program!
[Benedict] But before you leave tonight,
let me tell you that today
is a special day for me.
Because I want to say something to my bae.
What’s bae?
To my love.
[audience murmurs]
Where are the flowers?
[girl softly shaking]
[indistinct]
[moaning]
[delicate music playing]
[crowd gushing]
Will you marry me?
Yes.
-Yes.
-[crowd applauds]
[crowd cheering and clapping]
[Benedict] Victorina,
where do you want to get married?
A beach wedding or a garden wedding?
Of course, a church wedding.
That's right!
A church wedding. I also like that.
These kids are so cute.
And of course, when we're married,
we will make babies.
How many do you want?
Right away?
Uh-- Victorina.
I want to tell you something,
but I don't know how to explain it to you.
[birds chirping]
Always remember this.
You are the most important woman
in my life.
I am willing to give up everything
so I don't lose you.
[giggling] You're silly.
Let's DOTA?
Let's go that way.
So this is why I don't see you
anymore at the Casa, Victorina.
You're flirting with another guy.
This can't be.
Victorina is mine.
Your wish is my command.
Really, promise?
-[crowd shouting]
-Promise. Cross my heart.
Even if someone points a gun in my head.
-[gun cocking]
-Or maybe tomorrow?
[crowd clamoring]
I’m not doing anything wrong!
[in Japanese] You are connected
with American forces!
-What did he say?
-He said you are a spy.
[in Japanese] We have evidence
you are one of their allies.
What did he say?
He said you took someone's dear love.
Japanese men hate that.
[blade scraping]
[in Japanese] Where are you from?
He asks where you're from.
I'm from Bohol.
[in Japanese] Where are you from?
Where are you from?
I'm from Sampaloc.
[in Japanese] Where are you from?
Eh… [panting]
I'm from QC.
[humming]
[in Japanese] Idiot!
[grunts]
[screams]
Ouch!
[gasping]
-[soldier 1] Open the cage!
-[soldier 2] Yes, sir!
[Benedict gasping]
-[soldier 1] Get him out!
-[soldier 2] Yes, sir!
[Benedict gasping]
Let me go! [grunting]
Shut up!
Where are you taking me?
[soldier] Shut up! Just go with us.
[soldier speaks in Japanese]
[Benedict grunting]
Victorina?
What are you doing here?
You might get in trouble!
Don’t worry.
I'm asking them to let you go.
[man laughing loudly]
Oh!
[in Japanese] I see. I see.
So you are the one.
[Japanese music playing]
Mm-mm.
[in Japanese] One of their men
is saying that you are a spy.
[in Japanese] Bring them here!
[techno music playing]
[in Japanese] You! Guess who you think
accused you as a spy.
The General said,
choose who you think accused you as a spy.
-I have to choose?
-How about this man?
[in Japanese] This man!
[crowd chattering]
[all] That man!
[clamoring continues]
This man!
One, two…
three.
[indistinct]
[man in English] Are you sure?
[mumbling]
[in Japanese] This man?
[buzzing]
[laughing]
[laughing continues]
Roberto?
What are you up to again this time?
What foolishness
are you planning to do
to save this man, Victorina?
I will do everything for him.
That's why, release him
and take me instead.
Roberto, you really are
the pain in my ass!
It’s me that you want. Deal with me.
The General made his decision,
and his decision is…
death!
-[breathes deeply]
-[gunshot]
[Benedict whimpers]
[dramatic music plays]
Victorina?
Victorina!
[heart beating]
[gasping]
Sir Saro! I need to go back.
Please give me a Wishkey.
I need to save my love.
What happened will never be changed.
You won’t be able to change her fate.
You don't understand!
I need to save Victoria!
Wait, okay?
I said wait.
-[breathing heavily]
-Here.
♪ Ask me
Ask me ♪
♪ Who I love ♪
-Miss, one more beer, please.
-[song continues in background]
Okay.
[gasps]
Hey, best friend.
You bastard! You betrayed me!
Hey! Best friend, calm down.
Best friend. You’re drunk.
You slept in the middle of my stories.
There’s still so much beer.
-[glass clinking]
-What did you say?
We are best friends?
Yes, we are best friends.
You forgot because you drank too much.
Wait, I'll order more.
Excuse me.
[sighs]
Sorry about that, bestie.
Maybe I was just drunk.
-Cheers!
-[man] Cheers!
You're so amazing!
What is that?
-I mean, the singer, amazing.
-[clapping]
You're right.
Hey!
-Hypebeast.
-Hypebeast?
What do you mean?
What I mean is,
hype, peace, man!
[laughing]
I knew I would find you there.
I know you so well.
What is bothering you?
Me?
That’s all right.
I’m on your side.
Because, if not for you,
I wouldn't get a girlfriend.
You have a girlfriend?
[coughing]
Dude, what have you been drinking?
Yes, I have.
Come on. Let's go inside.
Why did you bring him here?
[in English] Sorry.
He got so drunk. That's why I brought him.
You should have let him
crawl home by himself.
I can't do that to him, sweetheart.
[retching]
You’re sweethearts?
Dude, go inside and have some coffee
so you can sober up.
But…
Careful, you drank too much.
[sighs]
[light music playing]
Do you want some water?
-Yes.
-Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Uh… Victoria, can we talk?
Who’s Victoria?
Vicky! Water!
Victoria, the girl from the bar.
She looks just like you.
Vicky.
What have I done to you?
You don't know, Ben?
If I knew, I wouldn't be asking you now.
You know what? If you don't know,
then don't bother asking.
Know what?
The thing you said that you don't know!
[sigh]
[Benedict] Why don't you just tell me
what you know,
so that I will know it also?
Right?
I don't care if you don’t know
what I know.
But Vicky…
I put salt, didn’t I?
Yes, I like my coffee salty.
Tastes like the sea!
[man] Dude, I have a favor
to ask from you.
[man] You're my best friend, right?
What is it?
-[man] Help me take Vicky away.
-[clacking]
What? You're eloping with Vicky?
Yes!
Dude, you know that her parents
disapprove of me.
[sighs] And we planned this
a long time ago.
But I cannot do it alone.
That's why I need your help.
[sighs] But…
Dude, not that way.
Eloping is a different matter.
Dude.
Are you going to bail on me now?
You even agreed on the previous favor
I asked of you.
What previous favor?
To date Vicky.
[man] When you broke up with her.
-I said that?
-Yes.
You told me you don't like her anymore.
And remember, you owe me a lot as well.
[ball clacking]
I'm very sorry, friends.
-[tense music playing]
-Did you who shoot this?
[man] We've been trying to do that
for three hours,
and you just shoot it that easily?
And from the other table?
But Pacquito, he is good.
Stop it, Rez!
Do you want me to crush this
in front of you? Huh?
Bomber. Do it.
[grunting]
Let me do it.
[squeaking]
It's Bata! It's Bata!
Bata?
-[crowd cheering]
-[Benedict] Right. It's really Bata.
Who’s Bata?
Ben, I'll go ahead. I need to see Vicky.
-All right!
-[man] Bata!
[Benedict] He has a mustache?
Bata?
[panting]
Vicky! Vicky!
-[girl]What is that!
-Oh my!
Grandma, is Vicky around?
Kristina!
Why are you wearing my clothes again?
I just tried it on. What’s wrong?
It looks good on me anyway.
You don't want to lend me your clothes.
I will just wash them or buy you new ones!
Vicky, can we talk?
What for? We are done!
-Bert is here. Get out!
-You need to hear me out.
-[Benedict] Please hear me out.
-Go out!
Get out of here!
Ouch! I want to explain everything to you.
Please forget about
whatever I did wrong before.
Which one?
Neglecting me as your girlfriend?
[rattling]
[grunts]
I can never do that to you.
I mean, Vicky!
See, you're still thinking
about the girl in the bar.
You did it when we were still together.
You don't have time for me
or for our relationship.
You only care about yourself.
So please get out of here.
[rattling]
[grunting]
But Vicky,
please forgive me.
Let me explain.
Everything is clear to me.
Because of what you did, I met Bert.
He showed me how to love and be loved.
[banging]
[sad music playing]
[tense music playing]
-[gasping]
-[woman] Hey! What are you doing there?
[screaming]
Ouch!
Are you okay?
[gasping]
-Mom?
-[gasps]
I'm not your mom.
I don't have a husband and kids.
[grunting]
You're overreacting.
You won’t die jumping from there.
That’s too low!
You should be thankful
that I have not put away my laundry.
-[flicking lighter]
-[Benedict grunting]
Hey! Don't jump.
I'm not jumping. I'm just stretching.
My body aches because of my fall.
You know what?
You really have a big problem.
Bigger than you think.
It's because the person I love
went with someone else.
But why?
I don't know. I've done everything
I could, but it still happened.
Are you sure?
You know how she feels?
We women,
what we expect from the person we love
is that they know how we feel
even without talking.
That they understand us.
Wait up.
I'm the one who has a problem.
Why are you upset?
You remind me of my love. Dominador.
Why? What happened between you and Dad?
I mean with the person you love.
My parents don't want him for me.
They want me to work abroad.
How will I be born?
When you love someone,
shouldn't you fight for him?
You still have time.
Do everything you can.
It’s a beautiful thing you said.
Wait. What are you doing?
It’s your fault. I remembered
my Dominador,
and what you said was so beautiful.
You know what? You're right.
I still have time. I'll tell Mama and Papa
that I love Dominador very much.
And I will do everything
for us not to separate.
What you said was nice.
That's what I'm going to do with Vicky.
I still have time.
You're amazing, Mom!
I'm not your mom!
Virginia is my name.
Virginia, I am Benedict.
Benedict.
Thank you.
Bye.
Where is Bert?
Vicky, forget about Bert.
Vicky, I still love you.
Come with me and I’ll give you everything.
-I'll do everything you want.
-I thought you already understood me?
Vicky,
give me a second chance.
Like what John Lloyd once said,
"Give me one more chance
to show you how much I love you."
Vicky, I can't live without you,
no matter when.
Who is John Lloyd?
John Lloyd, the poet.
Ben! I don't love you anymore.
Do you understand?
I don't love you anymore!
-I don't love you!
-[slaps]
[banging]
[gate opening]
[heart beating heavily]
Want to take me instead?
[gasps]
No. I'll just get the bag.
[gasping]
Do you still want more?
No, thanks.
I have no reason to go back.
I don't need your Wishkey!
[glasses shattering]
[gasps]
[melancholic music playing]
[clock ringing]
[knocking]
Brother?
[Bela] Are you okay?
-[knocking]
-Brother?
I'm okay.
-[Bela] You're not okay.
-I'm okay.
Mm?
Yeah. Yeah.
There. Do you want to eat now?
I said I don't want to eat!
So arrogant!
Then don't! I'm hungry!
I’ll eat if you don’t.
Son! Son! Come on! Try it!
-I can't beat your sister.
-Come on!
Dad, I'm not in the mood.
[sobbing]
Dad.
If only I knew that
I would see Mom
for the last time at the airport,
I wish I didn't let her go.
Son.
That's your mother's destiny.
It happened.
We cannot do anything about it anymore.
Even if I blame myself
for not stopping her.
That's it.
Why, Dad?
Son, if only I can turn back time--
[Bela] Dad, the car is here.
Are you sure you're not coming?
You go ahead.
Yes, take care.
You might see ghosts here.
[sigh] You take care.
[Bela] Dad, why did you have to scare him?
Mom.
What do I still need to correct?
I already did everything.
-Sir, aren’t you going home?
-[gasps]
I thought you were a ghost.
I am.
[ominous music]
Aren’t you too early?
Aren’t you from the night shift?
[breathing heavily]
[voice whispering] Turning Point.
[suspenseful music]
Sir Saro.
Yes?
What?
I thought you're done.
That's what I thought.
Do you want to go back to the past?
Yes!
Are you sure?
But now, I will make sure
I will do it right.
-Are you really sure?
-I'm really sure!
Cheers?
[sighs deeply]
Why did you eat all the chocolates?
Look at you! You're a mess!
You know that your salary is not enough.
Benedict is going to grade 4.
Bela will soon go to school.
Hilda! Clean her up.
I'll get an extra job. Just don't leave.
I will not waste the opportunity.
It is only a six-month contract.
It’ll be quick.
What about our children?
I know that you'll take care of them.
This is for our family's sake.
Benedict, why are you still here?
You need to take a bath.
This TV is still on?
[gasps]
I went back to my childhood.
Ah! Still uncut!
Yes.
Help! Help! I'm stuck in the escalator!
I need to go.
Always obey your dad. Be good.
-Come on!
-Let's go now.
By the way, don't forget Bela's milk.
Let her sleep in the afternoon.
Her vitamins. I already put--
Mom!
[emotional music playing]
Son.
Son, don't be sad.
I'll be quick, and you won’t notice it.
[announcement, in English] Last call!
-[airport announcer speaking]
-Okay! Okay!
Ouch!
It hurts!
Wait!
Wait! I need to check my son.
I don't know.
Mom! It hurts!
What happened?
I need to go.
Come on!
It hurts!
Why are you having a stomachache?
An airplane crashed 300 kilometers
after it took off.
-According to our sources,
-Sir, can you turn up the volume?
-it was supposed to fly to Hong Kong.
-[Benedict] It hurts.
According to reports,
-there were no survivors.
-Oh my. That was my flight earlier.
Yay!
Eh? Why?
My stomach doesn't hurt anymore.
[mother sighs]
You're eating too much.
Are you sure your stomach is good now?
Yes, I'm now okay.
You eat too much.
-My mom will not leave anymore.
-My bag!
-My family is complete.
-[brakes squeal]
[crash]
[dramatic music playing]
[father] Virginia!
Virginia!
Son.
Son!
Son! Stay there. Don’t go closer.
Mom!
Stay there. Don’t go closer.
Virginia! Virginia!
My love.
Mom…
[heart beating heavily]
Mom?
[crying]
Why wasn't I able to stop my Mom's death?
Benedict.
In this journey,
it's a different story
when it comes to…
life and death.
The only thing permanent is…
the birth and death of a person.
What's the use of that Wishkey
if it can't change my fate?
[sighs]
The purpose of the Wishkey
is not to change what happened in the past
but rather for you to realize and change
what you should do in the present.
But how do you know about this?
Who are you?
Like you, I also made a mistake.
I also wanted to go back.
I abused it
because of my selfish intentions.
This is my punishment.
Listen to those who failed,
those who have been hurt many times,
so I can teach
the right things from my experience.
Last shot?
-Cheers?
-Table.
[freeze]
[sighs]
[Victoria] Babe, it is not my birthday.
It is also not our anniversary.
What's this for?
I know there's something
you want to tell me.
But,
is it okay if I go first?
You know what I want to tell you?
You want
to break up with me, right?
[sighs deeply]
Wait, babe, they’ll sing.
[guitar playing]
Our relationship is getting toxic.
You want me to obey you always.
-This restaurant--
-Because
you're allergic to seafood.
You know what, babe?
You're right.
No matter what your decision is,
I will understand.
Because I'm not the old Benedict
that will control your life.
I will give you freedom.
Freedom to decide for yourself
and for your family.
No matter
how many years will pass by…
my love for you will never change.
I'm sorry, Benedict.
[sighs]
[in English] It's okay. I understand.
[delicate music playing]
[heart beating heavily]
[dramatic music playing]
[man] Hey, stop it, bro…
[man] Listen to me.
[man] Our friends left us already.
Hey, bro…
-[thunder rumbling]
-[suspenseful music playing]
[voice whispering] Turning Point.
[man] We can go home now.
[thunder rumbling]
[man] Ouch!
[delicate music playing]
[caller] Papa Tak, I'm Jane.
Hello, Jane.
[caller] I just wanna ask
what I should do with my ex
because I've realized
that I still love him.
[Benedict] Jane, it is very simple.
If you realized that you still love him,
you need to talk to him.
Tell him that
you still love him.
You should be true to yourself.
[caller] What if
he doesn't love me anymore?
[Benedict]
Jane, how can we know the answer
if you don't talk to him?
You know what, Jane?
Communication is very important
in a relationship
to know that you still love each other.
Jane, try to talk to him.
Tell him that you
can't afford to lose him.
[voice cracking]
Tell him that you still love him.
Do you understand me, Jane?
[caller] Yes, Papa Tak. Thank you.
[delicate music playing]
We haven't been paid yet.
Perhaps someone can pay in the meantime.
[gentle piano music playing]
[Hugot Tina] Look, it's her.
They finally meet.
You're late.
Sorry, we came from work, then--
Wait.
Did we have plans for tonight?
Ah, it's just that…
I always think of you.
And I always listen to your podcasts.
The reason why I'm here…
How do I say this?
Ben, I want to tell you that…
Uh…
[in Victoria's voice] I'm giving you
a second chance for us to be okay.
How did you do that?
Is that what you want?
Well, it's up to you.
But if you don't want to,
then I'll just leave.
There's no problem if you want us to talk
and fix things.
See? It's meant to be.
Look, it’s Valentine’s Day.
Valentine’s Day?
Babe, it's not yet Valentine's Day.
From what I know,
it's National Heart Attack
Awareness Day today.
[mascot] Let us take care of our hearts.
Let’s avoid eating fatty foods.
Oh, sorry.
I don't have a sense of time anymore.
[in English] Sorry.
Before we settle our problems,
what is Humberto to you?
Well, it's…
Humberto is here!
[tense music playing]
Victoria!
This guy! He is Humberto!
The villain in my life!
Dude, relax!
Wait. Wait.
Is that him?
Wait.
Humberto is my boss.
-Your boss?
-Humberto.
I’ve been through a lot,
and you always get in my way.
I'm Benedict.
[girl] Love, let's go!
Hey, love.
Wait. I'm confused.
-He's your boss.
-Yes.
But he wanted you
to go to Singapore, right?
He was tearing us apart.
What?
Stella is Humberto's girlfriend.
Not me.
[Humberto] Dude, you're lucky
to have her as girlfriend.
She loves you so much.
-She even refused the offer for Singapore.
-That's why I got promoted.
I'll fly to Singapore next week.
-Is it true, babe? You're not leaving?
-Yes…
Yes. That's what I was talking about.
-We will be together.
-Yes!
Hey, I miss you.
[Benedict] What happened to the lights?
Direk! Direk?
What about our kiss?
Direk!
[techno music playing]
[man] Excuse me.
I heard you're the only one
who can help me.
Why are you here?
I'm so sick of being handsome.
I wanna go back to my old self.
[lively music playing]