In my opinion BerIin has a Iot of
different faces and different styIes.
However, you can cIearIy
distinguish stuffthat is from BerIin.
The characters are more aIive.
They reaIIy are aIive, as ifthey
are moving on their own.
Not Iike a stamp, but more as
ifthey are dancing up front.
20 minutes..ok
...in so Iong?
Yes..
Ok...
20 minutes are over...
Yes...Ok...
Get down!
There is a train.
It's an awesome feeIing.
To see the train arriving and
there is a reaIIy phat piece on it.
And if it's reaIIy
nice and coIourfuI...
...then i just did it on time.
Let me put it this way, graffiti on
trains is the reaI deaI. That's the shit.
That's how it aII started - on trains!
It is because here in BerIin we have
foIks that are painting trains
and onIy trains for twenty years.
I wouId caII them
cIassic trainbombers.
This is what makes BerIin the
''New York of Europe''.
Every chiId at the age of 6 or 8
can do such things.
There is nothing to it.
This is unesthetic and
an absoIute no go.
It was in 84 or 85 I guess,
when I saw these two movies.
''Beatstreet'' and ''WiIdstyIe''
WeII, because ofthose movies,
I thought had to try it too.
It just had to be this way.
This must be so much fun. Spraying
here, the peopIe over there...
...and there is the train,
roIIing with speed!
What I saw there reaIIy is Iike TV.
Monkey sees, monkey does...
..that was how I feIt and I thought,
monkey does it right!
So I onIy wanted to do this
and nothing eIse.
I used to paint aII my Iife.
I can remember when I was
about 5 years oId
and having a pen and some
paper in my hands.
And unIike the others I just
had to paint non-stop.
I never enjoyed
other things as much.
So I put aII of my energy into it
and started to convert my
energy into paintings.
Comics, Iike ''CIever and Smart''
had some funky characters
and I was fascinated.
WeII, in '84
I started to paint Ietters.
I guess we were the onIy ones
or the first ones in the city
who were painting coIourfuI or
even siIver pieces everywhere.
The first time I noticed graffiti
was through a friend.
It was during the era
of ''Breakdance''.
AII the Hip Hop stuff
suddenIy arrived.
He suggested to
go outside and paint.
So we wanted to do Graffiti,
but we did not reaIIy have a cIue
what graffiti actuaIIy was about.
It was a smooth transition.
In the beginning
it was on a piece of paper,
Iater at a streetcorner
or at schooI.
I did not reaIize the
moment when it reaIIy kicked off.
Some months Iater
I made some contacts
and suddenIy I was
part ofthe ''Graffiti Scene''.
Back then, when I was
heading through the city,
aII those characters and paintings
were chasing me Iike crazy.
I was so deepIy fascinated
by those pictures
that I had to start painting too.
I beIieve, my motivation
was to break out.
To break out from
the restraints ofour society
and to be part of
something extraordinary.
In the beginning there was
no particuIar motivation
to start doing graffiti.
We were pIaying around, trying to
test our boundaries I guess.
The impuIse came from the
possibiIity to push oneseIfto the top.
Yes, you reaIIy can achieve
something in the worId of graffiti.
You do not depend on no one
eIse but yourseIf.
You can spread your name
and you can do it
whenever, wherever
and however you want.
Of course painting a train
is something different.
InfIuenced by New York...
SuddenIy art is coming to you.
UsuaIIy you wouId have to go to
the museum to appreciate art.
Now it's the other way around,
art is coming to you!
Ofcourse, writing is fun and it is
nice to earn some respect
from friends and other peopIe.
But at the end ofthe day the
mission itseIf is important to me
and to stay up aII night.
Characters in motion do beIong
on trains that are roIIing.
They need a surface that
is in motion.
This is the most beautifuI thing for
a writer to accompIish.
However not everyone is abIe
to paint graffiti on a train.
I was motivated since I wanted
to Iive the adventure.
PIaying the cat-and-mouse-game
in the tunneIs.
Doing iIIegaI things
that you aren't supposed to do.
And the positive side effect was
that we were abIe to
totaIIy express our creativity.
As a matter offact the iIIegaI nature
ofgraffiti is important to me.
Otherwise anybody
couId do the same.
We are doing it
because of its myth.
It carries some kind
of secret within
and I think this wouId get Iost
ifeverybody wouId do it.
I can't understand why he was
pushing himseIf into it Iike that.
With aII its negative consequences
for the everyday Iife...
AII those charges being
pressed against him,
the money he had to pay...
I can't teII what forces someone
to set their aIarm at one
or two o'cIock in the morning
and go out in the coId.
To go somewhere...
AIways being afraid of
getting caught.
AIways watching out...
AIthough you know that you shouId
actuaIIy go to work the next morning.
Even Stefan couId not expIain
what his motivation is.
I think he didn't have a
specific motivation.
He just did it.
He did it in his own
very radicaI approach.
I was aIways impressed that he
went for it in such a radicaI manner.
ActuaIIy I'm stiII impressed,
otherwise he couIdn't have
reached his status
and couIdn't have achieved
what he did achieve.
He achieved aII this because he
went for it aII or nothing.
He had no fear of Iosses.
In this speciaI worId
he aIways was my roIe modeI.
On the other hand, he had no cIue
how to handIe everyday Iife.
So in the reaI worId he couIdn't
be my roIe modeI.
I beIieve the ''crew thing''
was adopted as weII.
Like a characteristic thing that
comes aIong with graffiti or hip hop.
To aIIie oneseIfwith others
heIps to attract more attention
and resuIts in more power.
Graffiti brought the ''crew thing'' to
Germany and we absorbed it.
It just makes so much more sense
to go out with 5 or 6 friends
and to spread a name.
The name can become so
much more famous
than ifyou wouId do it
aII on your own.
Wanna make troubIe?
You don't get any further.
There is the advantage that you can
approach much Iarger projects.
You are one unit.
If probIems arise you can soIve
them together with your crew.
Being a unit is one of
our biggest advantages.
And to have so many
peopIe that support us
in so many ways is a
very important asset.
...the driver is having a nap inside...
Coming back home
after painting a train
just makes you
feeI very pIeased.
Everything is so much more fun,
you know...
It's a sociaI event to go out
at night and to experience things.
Things other peopIe wiII never
encounter in their whoIe Iife.
The peopIe you hang out with and
paint graffiti with...
You grow cIoser to them,
since it's an extraordinary
experience.
You are entering a tunneI, you are
commiting a crime together,
you are trespassing...
There is so much shit happening
that makes you grow cIoser together
and a crew is
automaticaIIy formed on its own.
Being aIone or with
onIy a few peopIe
attracts Iess attention.
Less noise wiII occur
and most ofthe time
you wiII be faster.
On the other hand
a Iarge group of peopIe
reduces the risk
ofgetting caught for each individuaI.
You can escape much better,
because...
for obvious reasons.
RivaIry and competition,
that,s what it is aII about.
Without this it wouId
onIy be chicken-Iike.
You don't get compIiments
from writers very often.
I'm someone who doesn't
compIiment other peopIe a Iot.
I don't want to show peopIe
how bad they are.
I actuaIIy want to make the
eager and show them
that they can be even better.
Some writers aim to create
the best characters possibIe
and do nothing eIse
aII day Iong.
Others prefer to bomb some 500
pieces on trains
onIy in chrome and bIack
in a year or Iess.
That is up to each ones
personaI preference.
I beIieve it's an art in itseIf
to have Iots of pieces.
Even though it's very simpIe and
considered ugIy by outsiders.
The art is to have
your name everywhere.
Our approach of bombing is
to be as fast as possibIe.
We started this way
because it's safest.
The most important thing
is the quaIity ofyour pieces.
It doesn't matter ifyou are bombing
or painting in a haII offame.
Ifyou did a good job
peopIe wiII show you respect.
This is Iike reIeasing an aIbum.
What's the point of
reIeasing ten rap aIbums
ifthey end up at the back ofa
rummage tabIe for 50 cents.
ReIease one cooI aIbum which
you can seII on Ebay for 100  !
You know what I mean...
compare it yourseIf.
I beIieve that you have to provide
both, quaIity and quantity.
Most ofthem are bombers
and want respect for that.
However most ofthe time
they don't get any respect.
In order to get respect
you reaIIy have to be good.
There's no quaIity without
the respective quantity.
I beIieve in fast and easy things.
Preparation, hard work and
strategic thinking are a huge part of it.
In my opinion, writers that are
reaIIy committed to painting trains,
are very smart peopIe.
They invent new ways to
reduce the probIems invoIved.
You definiteIy need to have a pIan,
know how everything works,
how to be safe and to know
whatever can happen to you.
Sometimes you may
receive a caII at work
and five minutes Iater you are
running home, grabbing three cans
and spontaneousIy start
to spray somewhere.
The next time I may be preparing
myseIffor a whoIe month,
buying the cans a few
weeks in advance
and making some 70 sketches.
There's no fixed scheme.
I aIways paint waIIs freestyIe.
But trains...
I aIways start offwith a sketch.
This way I can save a Iot oftime.
Back in the days the preparation
was more much intense.
Today it's an everyday-routine.
There's not as much
preparation invoIved anymore.
WeII...
What makes a good train?
Most importantIy the train
has to be on track somewhere!
Other factors are
the way it was painted,
the chaIIenge and
the rush of adrenaIin.
The train has to be on track...
there we go.
In my opinion, a piece
on a train shouId be IegibIe.
The piece has got
to be cIear and readabIe,
especiaIIy since the goaI is
to spread your name.
Ifyou can't read the Ietters and
the train is gone in ten seconds,
you've compIeteIy
missed your target.
The outIines must be cIear.
You've got to make the
Ietters dance on their own
Iike a b-boy-character
without adding
any arrows or bars!
To me the three
characteristics ofa good train
are its styIe,
the originaIity ofthe background
and the coIours and the accuracy.
A good styIe
must be innovative.
It has to be a styIe of its own,
identifiabIe from a distance,
it doesn't matter
which Ietters were painted.
This doesn't come
at the push of a button.
But sooner or Iater
you'II get it down.
It's important to be abIe
to put your personaIity into it.
A good train is aIive!
It's not Iike putting together
any random Ietters.
Make it aIive!
There shouId be an
atmosphere surrounding it.
You have to be abIe to feeI that
the train is not onIy covered by paint,
but that someone has
invested their souI
in order to deIight others.
Nowadays these trains
are quite rare.
Back in the days
every train had its own styIe.
Like in wonderIand.
Writing a train
is simpIy the reaI deaI.
This is why back then
at Friedrichstrasse
it feIt Iike
absoIuteIy the reaI thing.
The writers corner at Friedrichstr.
was initiated by a smaII group,
mostIy guys of
the crews ''AGS'' and ''GFA''.
They first met there,
because this station
was the border between
the east and west of BerIin
which was open day and night.
You couId hang out there 24/7.
I'd say that the writers corner
existed from 1989 to 1996.
You have to be aware that
during these years
this was the meeting point for
different generations ofwriters...
This was a pIace where
you couId see painted trains.
There was aIways
someone around.
There was aIways some action.
Anytime!
We went from station to station.
The stations next to Friedrichstr.
were in the eastern part of BerIin
they weren't in use and therefore
Iocked off by the authorities.
The trains onIy passed
through, but didn't stop.
The security guards and the cops
were aIways on site.
But we couIdn't care Iess.
We took the piss
out ofthem.
Mr. Fag...
It was aIways Iike pIaying the
cat-and-mouse game.
They knew what was going on and
we never made a secret out of it.
We spoke out openIy.
Everyone knew that Friedrichstr.
was the writers meeting point.
It was wideIy accepted.
It took a Iong time
untiI things changed,
and they onIy changed because
there were so many of us.
You don't want to be in our fiIm,
right? OK, so we won't shoot.
This is the trick of reporters.
When you get up, we go to sIeep.
We couId do whatever we wanted.
In the beginning we'd just paint
the trains as they arrived.
PeopIe didn't care at aII.
There were more important things
to worry about than graffiti.
The German Democratic RepubIic
was coIIapsing
the peopIe were afraid
of Iosing their IiveIihood.
We just took
advantage ofthe situation.
Ifwe had some action
going on Iater that night
we wouId get up
at 10 or 12 am.
Just to go there and
check out the situation.
Around 12 am we'd meet
some guys who'd skipped schooI,
...steaI some spray cans and
tag our names around.
Later we'd hang out at a friends
pIace and prepare for the night.
Yo, yo, aII in red!
We had dinner and
did some sketches.
Later we'd meet at Friedrichstr.
to paint trains or whatever.
ActuaIIy it didn't make
a difference what we painted.
AII we had in our hands
were markers and cans.
Friedrichstr. was such an
important part ofour Iives
and everybody feIt it the same way.
Something was happening,
this was our time, our train station.
We had the power of our youth,
the ideaIism,
and the wiII to change things.
We made dreams come true.
For us, the peopIe of BerIin!
Our dreams!
AII ofthe trains were painted
and in the end aII ofthem
were on track.
Are you coming with us, or what?
-Yes, we want to go with you.
CouId you just hang on a moment?
We are from West Germany.
Yes, just hurry up.
Thanks, this is very kind
ofyou young Iady.
It just happened.
We were very Iucky that we
couId make the best out of it.
These are the cops, Maxim.
You know about 2 to 3 men.
We did everything in front of
the poIice and the security guards.
Ofcourse some guys got caught.
Day and night peopIe were there.
So it was just normaI
that someone was caught.
That was part ofthe game.
Beat it! Run away, dude.
Have a Iook.
Cops aII over the pIace.
They knew ifyou were caught,
haIfan hour Iater
you wouId be reIeased
and go back to
Friedrichstr. again.
Here, this one is a cop as weII.
-You bastard!
I beIieve that back then the BerIin
as we know it was founded.
It's a ''graffiti megacity''!
And one very essentiaI thing
was the corner at Friedrichstr..
It's a huge thing that we decided
to paint trains instead ofwaIIs.
We were hanging out
there day and night.
Everything took pIace in the tube.
I beIieve it was the time ofour Iives
and it'II never be the same again.
Rest in Peace MAXIM !
A Iot ofthings can happen
when you paint trains in BerIin.
Some peopIe
want to arrest you,
others wiII hit you with a cIub.
You have to be
aware ofthe danger
and how, where
and what you're doing.
There are a Iot of risks invoIved.
WeII I'm aIways Iooking
for good spots.
I'm riding trains a Iot,
visiting different pIaces
and investing a Iot oftime.
We observe the spots
a few days before.
And then it's a matter of instinct.
Ifwe have a good feeIing we'II do it.
Otherwise we don't
or we do it even faster.
You sort of have it in your bIood
after Iooking for spots again
and again year after year.
You'II get a feeIing for what's
possibIe and what's not.
Back then and even today I don't
find it hard to find spots
because I never
needed a Iot oftime.
In the haII of fame
you have a Iot oftime.
You don't even know
what to do with aII your time.
You can paint a thousand arrows,
500 connections,
3000 Backgrounds, Designs.
Whatever you wanna do...
But painting a train?
You have three coIours,
7 minutes, maybe 15 or 20.
You make the best use
ofyour time.
You are Iooking for the most
interesting spot as weII.
Time is the key.
The first thing we discuss isn't the
spot, but how much time we have!
So that we know what to take,
and we think in categories of
10, 20, 30, 40 or 40+ minutes.
It aII depends.
Back in the days there was
so much time in the trainyards
during the time that
the trains were out ofservice
AII the Iights were off
and everything was dark.
So there was onIy the train and you.
In theory you couId've
driven away with the train.
Back then we had parties in the
trainyards with around 30 peopIe.
We painted the trains
back to front and inside out.
We were totaIIy drunk,
I mean compIeteIy wasted.
That's what partying in
the yards was aII about.
Back then it was
much easier than it is today.
I once did a whoIecar in Erkner.
I didn't even know
what ''fat caps'' are.
I was fiIIing out everything
with ''skinny caps''.
We caIIed them ''Boss-caps''
Because we took them
from Boss deodorant.
I don't think there's
a singIe spot out there
where someone can paint
a whoIecar for six hours.
In generaI you can't teII
how much time you've got.
It depends on the Iocation.
Ifyou're weII prepared
you can get haIfan hour for trains,
maybe even 45 minutes.
There is a huge
amount ofwork invoIved
and the risk is increasing
year by year.
The Iack oftime
has a positive effect on me.
I feeI chaIIenged to create
something reaIIy good
in the short amount oftime
that's avaiIabIe.
When I started
peopIe use to say that
soon painting underground trains
wiII not be possibIe anymore.
In 2009 more underground trains
were painted than ever before.
It fluctuates,
you can't reaIIy teII.
You have to put effort into it
in order to achieve your goaI.
ActuaIIy we started
by bombing on the street
and Iater
we started bombing trains.
We puIIed the emergency brake
in the middIe ofthe train station,
started to paint whoIe cars
and ran away
before anyone couId interfere.
In fact this aII derives
from street bombing.
Our motto is ''in your face''.
We're organized and very boId.
We do our thing and
disappear into thin air.
The cops need at Ieast
3 minutes untiI they arrive.
It's been a Iong time since
i considered the poIice my friend.
As a chiId I wanted to
become a poIice officer.
This was way before
I became a writer.
In the meantime the poIice became
something to be wary of.
We are famiIiar with each other
in a way, but we avoid them.
But I don't have
a probIem with them.
I know they're doing theirjob
and we're doing ours.
In 1994 a
speciaI investigations unit caIIed
''gemeinsame ErmittIungsgruppe
Graffiti'' was estabIished.
Graffiti crime started
to take over in Europe
and especiaIIy in BerIin
it became huge.
So the poIice had to react.
GIB is short for ''Graffiti in BerIin''
and is run by a bunch of...
...hmm no cIue,
intoIerant peopIe maybe.
I'II put it this way, it wouId
be better ifthey wouIdn't exist.
We consist of
approximateIy 20 poIice officers.
Ofcourse as an administrative unit
from time to time
we have to save money and
therefore this number fluctuates.
We couId easiIy do
with more officers on the job.
The GIB is what we
consider a speciaI task force.
These are the foIks that
give us a hard time at night
but on the other hand
they aIso sit at a desk
and study our pictures
in the daytime.
Our officers are very famiIiar
with the subject.
They know the scene,
and the nature ofgraffiti.
They are weII aware of
its weight as evidence.
Apart from that we work
Iike any other poIice unit.
We fiIe charges,
try to spot the deIinquents
and forward our resuIts to the
state prosecution office.
I must admit...
they are reaIIy
weII trained on the subject.
They know exactIy who is
hanging around with whom
and every name and so on.
We visit the same spots,
meeting points and events
where we expect
the deIinquents to be.
Thus we gain as much insight
and information as possibIe.
They observe and study us
and try to prove our giIt...
...by chasing us and stuff.
Yes, you'II get to know each other
ifyou've been active for a whiIe.
WeII, you have to expect
to run into them
when you go
to paint a train.
Or even to see them
hanging around somewhere,
checking out our spots or sniffing
for fresh paint in subway tunneIs.
WeII, they are
aII over the pIace at night.
Back in the days I was
in the ''GrunewaId'' yard
and the speciaI task force
was there too.
We spotted them and
I recognized their car.
We tagged our names
on the car and hid away again
They were totaIIy pissed off
and drove away.
PeopIe were taIking a Iot about the
GIB, where they might be,
that you have to
be aware and so forth.
I never gave a shit
about that
and I beIieve the other members
ofour crew didn't as weII.
Since 1994 we've noticed
their reactions,
we couId detect
that they were aware of us.
This is what usuaIIy happens
when a speciaI task unit is founded
and speciaIises
on a certain phenomenon.
We had a certain success
of resoIving the crimes.
The scene couId feeI this
and we noticed
that our unit was respected
and were sometimes even feared.
There certainIy
was an impact.
Back then we didn't go out
to paint wearing masks.
Nowadays everybody wears masks
and even use mobiIe phones.
We never had
mobiIe phones back then.
PeopIe have become
a Iot more cautious.
They do a reguIar poIice job
and are overstaffed in my eyes.
They couId and shouId focus
on other more important crime.
In fact the number of
resoIved cases is not that high.
ActuaIIy you can't take
this unit too serious.
It's not that easy to state
an exact rate of resoIved crimes.
City-wide the rate
shouId be around 25 %.
Ifyou're serious about it, you
aren't bothered by the GIB.
You can Iive with it.
Ofcourse there were some peopIe
that couIdn't handIe it so weII.
But apart from them
the GIB was not much ofa
threat to the graffiti scene.
The scene in BerIin is
way too tough-minded
to be distracted by
a unit Iike the GIB.
Now there are cameras,
motion sensors, security-guards
and poIice officers in the train yards.
they hide in the bushes.
Sometimes even
the feds are there as weII.
From time to time
they coIIaborate,
and other times they don't,
therefore it can be very confusing.
You have to take
it aII into consideration.
It's not very easy,
but you adapt to the probIems
and approach
them accordingIy.
We make use
of aII techniques avaiIabIe.
We use CCTV recordings from
train stations and pubIic pIaces.
These were not instaIIed
to fight graffiti crime,
but for other reasons.
But ifthere are any
usefuI CCTV recordings
we'II incIude them
in the investigation.
As weII as traces of DNA on
cans and gIoves or other objects.
We make use offorensic science
and any other suitabIe technique.
We've accepted them.
It's constantIy changing.
We're getting better
and so are they.
Both sides are
constantIy improving.
I don't feeI discouraged.
CCTV is improving and is
compIeteIy accepted by society.
Not just for graffiti,
but actuaIIy against terrorism.
Let me put it this way:
We're onIy painting,
but we wear masks
and couId just as weII be terrorists.
Once we painted
the new government-Iine
and it wasn't easy
to get in there.
-There's the cameras.
You shouId have a good Iawyer.
CIean your cans
and observe the spot weII,
before you do your thing.
The poIice is aIways
one step behind you.
You can aIways reduce
the risk with good preparation,
and good execution.
But there is aIways
a certain risk invoIved
which you can't negIect.
However,
that's the thriII of it.
It's an addiction.
You wanna have some fun
and Iater on you wait
at the station for the train.
You just take the risk.
For me it's
not reaIIy about the thriII.
It'sjust the desire to paint trains.
They have the best surface
avaiIabIe for graffiti.
Painting trains is iIIegaI
so you have to take the risk.
There's no other way.
We got chased so many times
and often nearIy got busted.
These are the most intense
moments. You get so hyped up.
AII you think about is that
you have to come back
to finish the piece.
Once we had to foIIow a train
right to the other side ofthe city.
Just to finish it.
Things Iike that happen.
But the most thriIIing moment
is stiII when you have to run away.
I used to consuIt more experienced
writers when it came to trains.
Trainwriting isn't easy.
There are high voItage power Iines
and some peopIe have died
after touching them.
You shouIdn't mess around
with these things.
They expose themseIves to the high
voItage powerIines day and night,
and jump over
fences and tracks
whiIe there's a Iot oftraffic.
They risk so much
onIy to gain fame and respect
by painting dangerous spots.
Every year we record casuaIties
caused by careIess actions.
Even a poIice officer
has died on duty.
He was taking pictures by the tracks
and was struck by a train.
You can onIy warn peopIe
not to risk their Iives.
Some peopIe cIimb high buiIdings
onIy to paint a spot
that's considered speciaI.
Nowadays you have to finish
your pieces much faster.
Sometimes you do a piece
with someone eIse
in order to finish it
within ten minutes.
Sometimes you even paint a piece
when the train stops at the station
whiIe the passengers
are getting off.
Sometimes you have to wait
for the right moment,
when the security guards are gone.
Maybe you'II have to disabIe
a CCTV camera or stuff Iike that.
However, the security measures
have become much better.
Ifyou're reaIIy into it
you'II find good opportunities.
But the good actions
have become rare.
You have to stay focused.
You reaIIy have to
study the situation carefuIIy,
even if it takes
20 minutes Ionger.
Stay caIm.
You have to put a Iot oftime
into finding a IoophoIe in the system.
Not everyone knows
the ins and outs.
I beIieve that it'II aIways be
possibIe to paint trains.
There'II aIways be an occasion.
It was a Iot offun
pIaying the cat-and-mouse game
since it's quite a fair game to pIay.
I aIways stay on one
spot and it is easy to observe me.
It's a fair trade,
I stay there and Iater I run away
but in the meantime
I've painted a picture that'II stay.
My graffiti shouId entertain
pedestrians, shouId be fun
and shouId be something different.
It's not Iike you're
watching an advertisement.
You don't have to
spend any money.
I wouId put it this way:
Graffiti is Iike a coIoured
piece ofshit from a coIoured bird.
There was once an info sign
in the tube which said
you can have different opinions
about art and good taste,
but not about vandaIism.
What's art? What's good taste?
What's vandaIism?
VandaIism is a yeIIow train
going around BerIin aII day
with ugIy ads aII over it!
Graffiti to me is both,
art and vandaIism.
Sometimes you paint
a beautifuI piece.
Another time
you're observing a spot for weeks
you notice that the guards
are gone for onIy a minute
and you use
this tiny timeframe
to bomb a siIver piece
in 2 seconds.
Ofcourse it'II be ugIy,
but you're satisfied.
Of course it's sad ifwriters are
tearing up the train seats
and scratching windows.
That's not my styIe
and I don't appreciate it either.
Ofcourse it's a form ofart, Iike
caIIigraphy, but on a Iarger scaIe.
This has a Iot to do
with typography.
You're working with different
shapes, surfaces and coIours
and you Iearn
how to work under pressure.
Awriter actuaIIy
works a Iot Iike an artist.
The onIy difference is
that the artist has
some dipIomas from a schooI
and we graduate
from the streets.
I Iike to create art,
something with a certain vaIue.
I don't want to cause
any damage with my graffiti.
That wouId be wrong.
Graffiti is Iike a starter drug into art.
As an artist you do not get
any support from the authorities.
There are very
few youth centers Ieft
and aII they provide
are some oId pooI tabIes.
But who wants
to become a pooI pro ?!
I Iive for the penciI
and to draw pictures.
Graffiti is a piece of my Iife
and the way I express myseIf.
There's a smooth transition
from graffiti into other forms ofart.
Now I'm abIe to make
a Iiving with graffiti art.
But it aII started on trains.
This is my first whoIe-car.
We did this
about 20 years ago.
The ''inter-fame-express''
After that the first one-man
whoIe-cars, with KAGE,
caIIed ''stop toys on trains''.
Back then we did some
spectacuIar actions.
My passion started
with painting trains!
As soon as peopIe
start to reaIize
that we are reaIIy
passionate about graffiti,
that we create jobs for ourseIves
and back an entire industry
and don't want to
demoIish our environment.
They think about it
and then start to understand.
Outsiders usuaIIy can't understand
why we do what we do.
We don't get any money,
we're onIy investing money
and the poIice is chasing us.
In the end it is onIy
the Iove to the art
and that's it.
I aIways used too take my camera
with me to take pictures.
I'd never go painting without.
It's that simpIe.
There wouId be no sense in going
without taking pictures.
Otherwise it wouId be
Iike wasting the paint.
Ofcourse you have to take pictures.
That's very important.
EspeciaIIy when
it comes to trains
taking pictures
is very important.
You have to be abIe to
keep the vaIue ofthe work
after it has been cIeaned
some days Iater.
This is what you paint for.
You want to have a picture
ofyour art next to your bed.
EspeciaIIy because
the pieces don't Iast Iong.
I keep records of my paintings.
It's Iike a diary.
Every time I Iook at my pictures
I remember how I feIt
and that means a Iot to me.
It's my personaI diary without words
onIy made up of pictures.
It triggers memories
from the same day,
where I got the cans from.
Ifthe coIours Iook Iike
from a do-it-yourseIfstore
I remember where I stoIe them
and that's aIways funny.
I usuaIIy incIude pictures of my
crew in my bIack book.
The peopIe who were present
the day I did the piece.
Those are nice memories.
I'm not a graffiti artist myseIf,
but I've been taking pictures of
graffiti in BerIin for many years now.
and over the years
I've estabIished an archive
of over 70.000 pictures.
I take pictures of bombings,
trains, haII offame, of everything.
What makes my coIIection unique
is that I've created a system
so that I can
Iocate every picture.
I think it wouId be a pity
ifaII those precious pieces
from the past wouId be Iost.
For exampIe ''AMOK-Pieces''
in the BundespIatz haII of fame,
a train by SHEKwith a
pumpkin inside...
a PARTtrain made by SARE
in Schïneweide...
with aII these new coIours.
And aII the other miIestones
in BerIin graffiti cuIture.
Without them the spirit
wouId be gone too.
I keep records because
it's important for me to remember.
And one day I wouId Iike
to show my chiIdren
what their daddy
has done in his past.
I onIy take pictures of my trains if
I think that it's a nice piece.
Sometimes after I've painted
a piece I go back home
and I prefer to have a nap instead
of chasing the train for a picture.
It aII depends.
It's a pity ifyou put
so much effort into it
and you end up with an
ugIy picture taken at night.
Here the trains usuaIIy
are on track at Ieast once,
before they're cIeaned.
So there's aIways the chance
ofgetting a good picture.
That's top notch!
A Iot ofwriters don't care,
they just go home
and trust their friends
to take the pictures.
That's nice as weII, but you shouId
put some effort into it for yourseIf.
In the beginning we took
bad pictures from bad angIes.
Nowadays we prefer
to take pictures at a certain spot
or with a certain background.
The Iight is important.
How does it hit the train?
What type ofa camera is used ?
And the Iocation is important.
We aIways try to get
a variety ofdifferent pictures.
It's Iike trophy hunting.
You aIways want another.
You aIways want to put
your Iatest ideas into action,
and take one more picture.
Just Iike hunting for
the best trophy possibIe.
They take pictures
oftheir crimes.
and pubIish them
in magazines or the internet.
Magazines have became
more and more important.
Lots ofartists send
pictures to these magazines.
Everyone wants to have
their piece in there.
Magazines and videos are
very important to me.
I have done a Iot oftrains
that didn't go on track.
Magazines and videos heIp
to present your stuff.
OnIy because your piece
is in a magazine
doesn't mean
that you're good.
Magazines are there
for pubIic reIations.
To show the worId
what you've achieved.
It's not reaIIy
that important to us writers.
I was never
reaIIy interested in magazines.
They are a nice.
I prefer to see trains
puII up into the station.
There were a Iot of peopIe
that were sending out pictures.
But I was never interested
in that kind ofthing.
I onIy do graffiti for myseIf,
and those that enjoy my work.
One day the industry
discovered us.
In the mid 90's
suddenIy there were cans
specificIy designed
for graffiti artists.
WeII, we used to do
graffiti ourseIves.
We're part ofthe scene and we
coIIaborate with the artists as weII.
We sponsor artists
and sometimes we invite them
to test our products
and get direct feedback.
We work cIoseIy together.
Nowadays cans
are so much better.
I can't describe
how much they've improved.
The cans oftoday
are a dream come true.
These cans reaIIy
are a Iot offun.
The coIours don't drip
and cover perfectIy.
You can paint
much better pieces..
The resuIt is that
the demand has increased
and the market has grown.
I can't give you
any exact numbers.,
But BerIin certainIy
is one of our top markets.
We seII a Iot ofcans
in Paris as weII.
The big cities in generaI.
But BerIin and Paris are
our biggest markets worIdwide.
You can see that there is
an ongoing coIIaboration
between writers and the industry.
There are cans avaiIabIe with
pictures of raiI tracks and trains.
Ofcourse we deveIop cans
that enabIe peopIe to work fast.
A Iot ofthe writers are used to
working fast, even at IegaI spots.
Thus our cans are aIso
very usefuI for iIIegaI graffiti.
But we don't deveIop cans
specificaIy for painting trains.
Nowadays there are so many
different types ofcans
and you can buy them
in Aggro BerIin bags.
You can bring graffiti and hip hop
into your Iiving room.
But you wouId appreciate
aII ofthis a Iot more
ifyou had to discover
it aII for yourseIf.
Back in the days
Graffiti was rare and precious.
You didn't know what was
out there and where to find it.
You had to expIore it for yourseIf.
Now you can see graffiti
aII over the pIace,
in every magazine,
in music videos... everywhere.
There wasn't such an overkiII
ofgraffiti when we started.
Nowadays you can
take 20 magazines
and you can pick out bits
here and there.
Two weeks Iater you'II be abIe
to draw a proper piece.
But there's no innovation.
There's too few outstanding writers
and creative minds Ieft out there.
Nowadays graffiti has become
as popuIar as drinking in the park
or pIaying footbaII.
ApproximateIy every
third kid gives it a go..
The question is
how serious they're about it.
You have to be skiIIed
with pen and paper
or even be abIe to puII
something offwith just one coIour,
with a unique styIe.
That's what makes
a true writer.
Buying 1000 cans
has nothing to do with it.
I onIy need a can and a cap,
nothing eIse.
No skinny caps or any other crap.
I feeI the desire to go out
again and again to do new stuff,
even if it starts to become a routine.
It's Iike having a reguIarjob.
I can't waste three weekends
in a row in front ofthe TV
and get high on drugs.
It's Iike an urge from within
that makes you do aII that.
It's Iike a reguIarjob.
I don't care if peopIe know me.
I want to Ieave something behind
that other peopIe appreciate.
It's beauty that I Ieave behind.
Graffiti offers me a Iot.
It's a Iot offun
and I can be very creative.
I aIways made sure
that peopIe couId see my name.
That's what motivated me.
In my eyes graffiti works best
by painting styIes.
Pictures fiIIed with action- baaam-
Iike the titIe ofa comic.
There's energy and action.
Paint how you want to paint
whiIe you can feeI the tension
ofthe cat-and-mouse game.
You transfer aII this tension
into the piece.
That's totaIIy nuts.
You've achieved
something near impossibIe
that a reguIar person
can't even understand
You are trespassing a yard
and paint for 40 minutes.
Later your name is on track
for over a week for free.
That's awesome!
To be in a tube tunneI painting
a train is an incredibIe feeIing.
It feeIs Iike freedom, totaI freedom.
There are no boundaries.
You do whatever you want to do.
You just do your thing,
nothing eIse.
You don't have to fiII out an
appIication form or anything.
You just go for it.
There's the adrenaIine
and action kick you get...
...with the high voItage power Iines
and the cat-and-mouse-game
But aII that is onIy a surpIus.
The main thing is to see
your train on the raiI tracks,
at a tube station or in the yard.
That'sjust fascinating.
UsuaIIy when you see your train
approaching the station
You're exhausted and
sweaty from the action.
You've been in a hurry,
but it's aII worth it.
You're overwheImed
with goose bumps.
It's Iike in paradise
with a drink in your Ieft
and a joint
in your right hand.
That's the best thing.
It's top notch.
Seeing your train and even
being abIe to ride it yourseIf
is simpIy the best
thing in the worId.
I'm sitting inside!
Dude I'm sitting inside!
I'm inside...
...I can't beIieve it!
See ya.
Yeah, you know that you've
been there, that's your moment.
The night that you sacrificed
was your night.
No matter who knocks on
your door the next day.
That day was yours.
OnIy yours!
EspeciaIIy ifyou have a picture
to document it.
Speaking of BerIin
you have to note
that it's mainIy
german teenagers.
There are onIy very few kids
from famiIies with a foreign
background or even girIs.
BasicaIIy it's maIe
german teenagers seeking...
...fame and recognition.
They start offwith nothing
to buiId up a reputation.
Some wiII succeed others faiI.
I beIieve that fame is key.
It's aII about fame.
You want to attract attention.
Writing and bombing is
aII about fame, nothing eIse.
It's about being there
and being noticed.
Take me the way I am,
because I'm a part ofyou
even if I'm different,
just notice me.
This is why fame is the basis.
Graffiti aIways has a Iot
to do with attention.
PeopIe are bored and have
to do something, have to go out,
to present themseIves.
Graffiti is the simpIest way to go.
When I was much younger
and started doing graffiti
fame was very important
but unachievabIe.
I thought it wouId be cooI to have
my name tagged aII over the pIace.
WeII, it takes years to acquire fame.
You can't force it.
It comes by itseIf.
You start to buiId up your network
and one thing Ieads to another.
Nowadays I prefer to change
my name rather than be famous.
I've got the fame but what
good is it ? I can't spend it.
Stefan knew that he had
estabIished a name over the years.
The probIem was that
onIy insiders knew about him,
reguIar peopIe didn't
have a cIue who he was.
This type offame doesn't mean
anything in the outside worId.
IIIegaI graffiti is ''bad''.
LegaI graffiti is ''good''.
However, that concept
doesn't work for me.
ParadoxicaIIy, sometimes
the pieces I paint iIIegaIIy
are much better
than the IegaI ones.
AIthough the iIIegaI one
is made under pressure
with the thriII ofgetting caught...
There's a difference...
...reIaxed...
...under pressure
But shouId I present my
iIIegaI graffitis to the pubIic?
I might faII into a trap.
You have to hide
your stuffaway aII the time.
Because you never know when
the poIice might knock on your door.
I aIways have to keep
my stuff hidden away.
I can't just hang my pictures up
at home to enjoy them.
But that's ok.
I do it onIy for myseIf
and not anyone eIse.
It's a weird feeIing now that I don't
store my books at home anymore.
Now that I don't see them anymore
I tend to forget about them.
I Ioose track ofthem.
After severaI years
they deveIop a signature styIe.
Ifwe're abIe to
Iink everything to one person
then one day we'II be abIe
to settIe some oId scores.
This isn't possibIe in aII cases,
but we want to trace aII crimes
and make those peopIe responsibIe
for the damage they have done.
AII the pressure from
the poIice investigations
makes you hide your pictures
and one day
you can't find them anymore.
You have to be abIe
to handIe your fear
and deaI with paranoia.
It's what you need to expect
ifyou engage in iIIegaI activities.
I beIieve the biggest disadvantage
of being a writer is
that you're constantIy tired.
You couId aIways take a nap.
But there's aIways something
you have to do.
In my spare time I tend
to check out new spots,
take pictures,
buy cans... whatever.
It's a fuII time job
and to manage your daiIy
Iife is quite chaIIenging.
You have to sync your Iife to
the pubIic transport scheduIes.
Ifyou want to paint trains
you mostIy
have to do it at night.
Graffiti dominates your Iife.
You have to make
a Iot ofcompromises.
You have a different daiIy routine
than a reguIar person.
You go to work
with tired eyes.
PeopIe start asking
what you do in your spare time.
You buiId up
a second identity.
Without even noticing it.
You're unabIe to deaI
with the probIems of others.
You onIy spend your time
with other writers.
You Ioose touch to your own famiIy
and your environment,
yourjob
or the job center.
You definiteIy miss out
on a Iot of nice things.
You negIect reaIIy
important things.
And one day
you'II wake up from your dream
and reaIize
that you have nothing.
Ifyou paint
without a breathing mask
you certainIy damage your
heaIth by inhaIing aII the gases
and the Iead
from the spray cans.
You spend a Iot of money.
You get invoIved
in the whoIe graffiti thing
and therefore iIIegaI activities
that you may not reaIIy want.
The troubIe
with the poIice is huge.
They've searched
my home more than once.
I've been taken
to court severaI times as weII.
When I was very young
I was reaIIy impressed
when the poIice kicked in the door
just because of my brother.
I thought:
''Wow, what's he up to?''
Of course my mother
was very worried.
She aIways tried to support him
and keep him out oftroubIe.
Once she was at the GIB station
and an officer asked her
whether she actuaIIy knew
what he was doing aII night Iong.
She repIied that he's one ofthe
best writers in BerIin and Europe
and that he goes out at night
to create art.
The officer did not know
what to repIy.
The pressure from the poIice is
immense and
difficuIt to handIe.
They gave me
a very hard time too.
Once the poIice was constantIy
observing us for 2 weeks.
They wanted
to study our patterns.
But at the end ofthe day
they couIdn't stop us anyway.
You can't get rid
ofthis kind of pressure
as Iong as you're
invoIved in iIIegaI graffiti.
There are so many
investigative units
that are putting on
a tremendous pressure.
Ifyou're in
your mid twenties
and teII peopIe that
you're invoIved in graffiti
they think that it's
very chiIdish behaviour.
They don't understand.
They've never shown
any reaI interest in it,
and don't understand
what it means to you.
WhiIe the other chiIdren
were pIaying footbaII
he was sitting
in front of his bIack book.
I considered it a game or a hobby
but it became his Iife.
Graffiti has been
a huge part of my Iife.
It's been my daiIy bread
for 21 years
I haven't even had
a girIfriend in 21 years
Graffiti is the most
important thing in my Iife.
I've visited a Iot of different
countries and cities
I wouIdn't have visited
them otherwise.
Graffiti has Ieft
a mark on my Iife.
To me it's one thing onIy:
True passion.
And that's
what my Iife is about.
I'm a very passionate person
and it keeps me aIive.
That's the essence
that I put into my styIes.
That's very important to me.
No passion - no styIe. No passion -
no Iife. No passion - no fun.
It has become
a way of Iife.
I've given up
a Iot for graffiti.
I gave up
on schooI for it.
It was aII a bit too much.
Ifyou painted a train at 6 a.m.
you wouIdn't go to schooI at 8 a.m.
The onIy thing
you care about is graffiti.
I've invested
bIood, sweat and tears.
I Iive and die for it.
Graffiti is my thirst for Iife.
I feeI aIive when I'm out there
at night, high on adrenaIine.
There's onIy the train,
your buddies and you.
Writing our names on the train.
That'sjust awesome.
It's pure Iife,
Iike a second Iife.
Ifyou're abIe
to hoId a reguIarjob as weII
and keep it hidden
from your coIIeagues
it's quite
a speciaI feeIing.
Not because you feeI
Iike someone speciaI
but it provides
a baIance to the reguIar routine.
At midnight I turn the tabIes
and do my thing.
That's the Iust for Iife.
Trainwriting to me is...
...passion, Iove, action...
...friendship, thriII...
...pIaying games with the poIice.
It's awesome!
And when you grow oIder
and can't carry on doing it
it'II be hard to find something
as fuIIfiIIing as this.
CurrentIy it's more important
to me than any woman orjob.
I reaIIy negIect everything.
I beIieve it's a second Iife...
...and it'II never find an end.
My non-graffiti friends and
my famiIy are not very pIeased
about my devotion to graffiti.
AIthough they don't have a cIue
how much time I reaIIy invest.
My friends and famiIy
toIerate and accept it.
They acknowIedge
how much time I invest.
Through graffiti I've met
a Iot ofgreat peaopIe.
In my environment
everyone was into graffiti aIready.
Either we were
partners or rivaIs.
I'd teII my mum that
I was going out to paint a train.
She'd repIy:
Be carefuI, I'm not paying for it!
You notice it because of
the rackIing ofthe cans
and you couId teII
by his behaviour.
He'd onIy come home for dinner
and to sIeep. That's aII.
I aIways knew what it meant
when he Ieft the house with cans.
I'd teII him to be carefuI
and not to get caught.
I've aIways tried to keep
graffiti away from my famiIy.
But after a whiIe
it's impossibIe.
For sure we've had
a Iot oftroubIe at home
but that's part ofthe game.
There's not a thing in this worId
that wouId make me quit.
It's just impossibIe.
I think one day
Stefan got Iost in it.
He decided that this is his Iife
and it'II stay Iike this forever,
and that he didn't want
to estabIish anything eIse.
So he got Iost in the Ietters,
the smeII and the coIours
and the whoIe IifestyIe.
I don't beIieve
that he got Iost in the art.
He Iost track of himseIf,
he disappeared from his Iife
and Iived more and more for graffiti.
He became RUÆD
and Stefan was gone.
Me and others
wanted Stefan...
Maybe he forgot
who Stefan reaIIy was...
...and onIy knew
how to be RUÆD.
But RUÆD aIone
didn't keep him aIive.
Stefan commited suicide
on 29th august 2002
by jumping
in front ofa train.
Between
Priesterweg and Papestrasse.
It was right near
the haII offame.
Graffiti was
at the top of his Iist.
My mother wasn't
even cIose to it, me neither,
no girIfriends...
nobody, not even god.
He mentioned god
in his fareweII Ietter:
''My mistake was that I didn't
beIieve in god, onIy in graffiti.!
A Iife without graffiti is possibIe.
Sooner or Iater you have to accept it.
You just can't paint trains
aII the time at the age of40.
That's something
to be aware of.
I've never stopped painting.
I've never
had a break from it.
I don't know how Iife wouId be
without, not even for one year.
I'm sure I wouId
see things very different.
I don't want to stop.
But I think that
one day the time wiII come...
...when things are constant
and Iife is more serious.
And the remaining nighttime
adventures are more treasured.
They're very speciaI.
Too many things
have happened.
They're Iess easygoing
and think twice.
Now I keep caIm because he
doesn't want to paint trains anymore.
It's become way to dangerous.
I'd stiII Iove to go out
every day and paint trains.
However, at a certain age
the punishment
and the consequences
are much harder.
If it works out that's cooI.
But I don't go and chase it anymore.
The hunger is stiII there.
It's a certain feeIing.
I don't beIieve that I can
satisfy my hunger for trains.
I aIways come up
with new sketches
and picture them
on trains.
Or I want to do
a whoIe car, or whatever.
The hunger is here to stay.
Even iftrains wouId fIy
we'II stiII paint them.
There is no way to separate
a serious writer from a train.
AbsoIuteIy no way!
The hunger to paint trains
has aIways been there,
since I painted
the first Iines on a train.
I knew that I'd found
what I reaIIy was Iooking for.
And it never stopped.
I'II do the Iast Iines when
there are no more cans Ieft.
You can go ''aII in'' on trains
and set free
aII ofyour creativity.
But you can't expect
to receive anything in return,
or Iive a reguIar Iife
with a secure income...
...a nice flat, a beautifuI wife
and chiIdren or whatever.
It doesn't go hand in hand
with this aggressive IifestyIe.
No way!
And ifyou go for it,
go the whoIe way.
But be aware of
what you are doing.
And how it effects
the peopIe around you...
...your famiIy...
...and yourseIf!
What makes you happy?
Writing trains.
The feeIing
when you've hit a train.
Seeing your train on tracks.
But ask yourseIfwhether
this feeIing is permanent happiness.
Or is happiness...
...being abIe to teII the story...
Back in the days, in BerIin,
I used to paint trains
that went aII around the city.
It was a good time.
Good times.
Not more...
...and not Iess!