Do you know when you dream
you're drowning?
You can't breathe
and you want to get out of it?
It's even worse in real life.
They say you see your life go by
when you're going to die.
But I could only think
of one thing.
No, hold on! Stop it.
Let's start at the beginning.
It started the day
my mom went on a trip.
Honey, the money's
in the drawer, ok?
If you need anything,
call your father.
And call me every day
like you promised, ok?
Actually, don't call your dad.
He is really complicated.
The paper's there,
on the fridge.
Better call your aunt first.
Are you listening to me sweetie?
20 days alone.
The entire house to myself.
I couldn't believe it.
And things you'll need, medicine,
grocery, all that stuff, ok?
I was scared to death
that she'd cancel the trip.
My mom's crazy.
I'm about to cancel.
Are you sure you'll really be ok?
I'll be fine, mom, I will.
I trust you honey, ok?
I hate it when she says that.
There's always a guy
who's "the"guy.
Rafa. Do I need to say
anything else?
Of course he has something
to do with this story.
He looks at all the girls' asses
on the beach.
Do you think that's cool?
If he looked at mine...
Looks like everything's
in place.
If he'd only notice
that I exist!
What a drama!
You could try to use that.
Do you like it?
It's great for Carnival.
This is Caco. My best friend.
My only friend.
Look at this.
What is it?
Some of my mom's stuff,
I think.
You could sell it all
in a thrift shop.
You think she'll remember this?
No.
It's a relic.
What's this?
That's my dad's!
Read it for us!
"Clara, I must confess that I wasn't
that into Simple Minds..."
That concert was eons ago.
"...it was just to win you
at that concert."
How cute!
"Now, I listen to it
without stopping...
This tape's for you
to remember me with a soundtrack.
Kisses, Gabriel."
- Check it out, man.
- She sings like hell.
She is clueless.
Nice voice.
But you missed your stop,
we passed your school.
Later!
Rafa?
Rafa!
Driver!
- The great Tize!
- You're ridiculous, you know?
But you are... marvelous.
Did you take it?
I'm crazy man,
I want whoever wants me!
There's just one thing:
No one wants you.
And you're a big success,
right?
My business is in Alfenas.
I already told you.
Coutinho. What's up?
- Look at the time, Priscila.
- I know.
You're late! Slept more
than your bed?
Take a picture of her panties.
I took it, I did.
Look, red panties,
the color of passion...
Good morning, teacher Roberto.
Good morning to all.
Good morning!
Please take those
headphones off.
I'm sorry, teacher.
And you too, Tize,
turn off the cell phone.
I have a cool deal for you.
You're going to do
a quantitative research.
For this, you'll use
statistical calculus tools.
To make it more enjoyable,
cooler,
you'll choose themes you like,
current ones,
that are part
of your daily life.
Like, define the percentage
of fabric used in Tize's skirt?
How about calculating
the percentage of idiots
in our class, Boca?
Lovely exchange of compliments.
Nice to see you love each other.
But I have good and bad news
for this project.
The good one is that it will
be a group project.
The bad one is that
I'll select the groups.
What about democracy, teacher?
Democracy requires
centralized power...
and, here,
I'm the central power.
Think about the brighter side.
You'll build new social circles,
make new friends...
And who knows, even find
the love of your life...
The first group is...
Priscila, Carlos,
Tize...
She's Rafa's sister.
And João Pedro.
Who's João Pedro?
"What are you wearing?"
A top and really tiny shorts?
Jurema, get out of here,
please...
Boca!
"Little Doll"?
That's a man.
Boca, dude, get real.
If you're tall and got muscles,
she could be anything!
Jurema, you're messing
with me... Leave!
- I'm so scared!
- Stop it. Leave, please.
Ask her what nail polish
she uses.
Why would I ask
what nail polish she uses?
Because you'd find out
if it's a man or a woman.
Nice... Ask.
Calm down, Jurema.
"What nail polish do you use?"
She's taking too long.
No. She'll reply.
Yeah... he must be
googling the answer!
Come on, we're going
to miss the movie.
Now, don't leave stuff
on the keyboard!
Get out, Jurema, please.
Mom! I'm just kidding, idiot.
Sometimes I feel like
I'm at the movies.
I'm watching Rafa's life...
and he doesn't even know
I'm here.
Thank you.
I don't know how you
convinced me to follow this guy.
You love me.
- Look, our little princess.
- And my future sister-in-law.
- Keep dreaming!
- It's true.
That guy's looking
at you or me?
You know, I'm sick of this.
- Finally. Let's go?
- No. No way.
Captain's log,
Stardate 3 thousand and a ton.
Louse 1 tries to land
in the Venusian wasteland,
the driest place
in the universe...
But we are ambushed
by the terrible bald monster.
Losers, got nothing better
to do?
The terrible monster is angry!
Danger! Danger!
Get a girlfriend.
Get a fuck, you idiots!
The Venusian vulture
is really pissed off.
Next victim.
Attention, Mr. Suba,
we're being attracted
by that big black hole!
I repeat, an immense black hole.
What should we do?
Use the gluteus ray!
Repeating, use gluteus ray.
What's this?
I'll get you, punks!
You brat,
I know your mother!
The attack
of the furious laser beam.
8.
"The Payback".
Where're you heading?
Nowhere, I'm staying right here.
Let's leave.
No, no, honey.
It's now.
Or never.
"Rafa is pissing."
Just keep walking.
You ok?
Yeah.
Let's go in.
- Hey.
- Hey, man.
We're going. Gonna stay?
I'm done with this place.
I can't believe it.
You and my brother.
Hi, Tize.
She's in my class.
- This year's looking good, Rafa!
- Sure does.
What's your name again?
Relax, Priscila.
What? "Relax Priscila"?
Nice name!
It sounds like
a massage parlor.
Ignore them. It only gets worse.
- How about a nightcap?
- I'm in!
No, I'm out!
I'm in, I'm out, I'm in,
I'm out, I'm in...
Stop!
Now I get it.
You're the 80's girl
from the bus.
You don't want to go in?
You won't have a swim?
The water's great.
No. I'm afraid of the sea
at night.
Really? But that's why
it's good.
And during the day too.
I'll tell you something,
I stayed a lot on the shore.
A lot.
When the waves were big,
you know,
picturing myself in the wave,
catching a tube,
at the breaking of the waves...
Then, suddenly... it's real.
You're in it.
Real...
Hi. How's it going? You there?
Is everything ok?
No. I'm picturing myself
on that wave out there.
Or wherever you wish.
Pri. Where are you?
Hi, it's Clara.
I don't know if you remember me.
It all started
when I got pregnant with you...
Wrong number...
I have to tell you something.
Let's talk later.
I think it has
to happen sometime.
I think it's cool
that you're going to be the first.
You're a virgin?
Look, babe,
it's not gonna happen.
No, Rafa, you don't get it...
I get it. It's just
that I'm drunk, tired, stoned...
- It won't be cool for you.
- Yes, it will!
- Plus, it's late.
- So?
Let's talk another time, ok?
I'm gone.
What other time?
You're going to call me?
Rafa!
According to my Biology teacher,
70% of our body is water.
Would it be enough
to drown in?
Dude, you're really mixed up.
Why'd you say you're a virgin?
Let him find out.
I never thought he'd leave.
He must've thought
you'd be clingy.
Fall in love.
Then he's done for.
- Me?
- No, me. Obviously you.
And he was right, see?
Now it's impossible anything
will happen between you two.
Great, I don't have the courage
to look at him.
Caco, I want to die.
Caco!
Rafa, Letícia. Letícia, Rafa.
- How are you?
- Nice to meet you.
So, going to kill yourself?
Why's my brother
even talking to her?
Nothing in common.
My bad yesterday, I overdid it.
No, I shouldn't have said
what I did.
Rafa, you want
a ride or not?
I'm coming.
So... we'll talk.
See you.
Let's go.
How many girls are virgins
in our school?
That doesn't exist, girl.
Of course it exists.
I personally...
I knew it!
I know a ton.
Like the majority of girls
in our class.
But that's not a problem,
I can help solve it.
You think you're so hot, right?
Why, is there a problem?
I don't want to flunk again, ok?
No one will answer that type
of question.
Sure they will,
if we ask properly.
Good idea, we can interview
at my house.
And if there're any left,
I'd serve them.
- Weird.
- I'm going to have nightmares.
Don't you think it's cool?
Aren't you curious?
Ok, "Relax Priscila",
count me in.
- Keep working, I'm off.
- Already?
Me too, we can think
about the questions.
How should we start?
Like name, age...
You look naive, but you
picked up my brother.
Thanks.
Don't cling to him, ok?
Like, I love Rafa,
but he's a real player.
Friendly advice, ok.
She called me a friend?
Hey, you dig Winning Eleven?
I prefer Sims.
Sims? The game where you
build houses, furry animals...
Yup.
Cool, cool.
Ok, so... Bye, dude.
I'll give it back, dude!
What? The journal?
No, I'll do it.
It's Priscila's, my friend.
Keep it cool,
I'll return it to her.
Boca!
Shit!
Boca, open the door, Boca.
Open up,
I want to take a shower.
Boca!
Mom! Mom!
Boca's reading dirty magazines
in the bathroom again!
Boca, open up now!
One, two...
"Virginity is not having
done something.
What've I really done?
I'm a getting wasted virgin,
all-nighter virgin,
travel by myself virgin."
"Hang-gliding virgin..."
Me too.
"Where should I start?
Rushing, fear, laziness...
I don't know.
Everything's so grey."
"But I think I saw a blue spot
in the sky."
"Maybe I'm just another girl.
But I don't want to be
just another girl."
Come on,
make up your mind!
Boca, open up now, Boca!
"The new Priscila's 3 wishes:
I want to feel special.
Like the people everyone
looks at in the street?
I want to stop being afraid
of the sea.
Stop dreaming about
a far-off wave,
I want to be in it.
I want someone to dedicate
a song to me.
Like my dad did for my mom.
Someone who likes me.
Is it possible?"
Go talk on the phone
and leave me alone, Ema!
Boca!
Jurema?
No, it's Priscila.
- Do you have my journal?
- Priscila?
Just a minute, wait.
It's ok now.
No, not yet, wait.
Now, it's ok.
You ok?
No, do you have my journal?
I was going to return it
tomorrow.
Ok, you can return it now.
Is it here?
What do you think I'd do with
your journal in the bathroom?
Of course not.
I can't believe it!
Can you lovebirds court
somewhere else?
No, she's not my girl...
My sister.
Your journal's in my room.
In my room.
Sorry.
Just a minute.
It's here somewhere,
let me look, one minute.
Did you read it?
Did I? I started,
but I thought it real boring
and dozed off.
I found it, here it is!
I found it in my bedroom.
Ok. Thank you. Bye.
See you tomorrow, Priscila.
What's up with that?
Hi, Jurema.
Boca.
Now it's your boyfriend.
Next time you open.
Come in.
Come in, son.
Loser.
Did you fucking do her
or didn't you?
When I tell you I did,
you don't believe me.
When I say I didn't, you don't
believe me,
I dunno what to say.
Boca, I'm your friend,
you can tell me the truth.
Dude, I told you,
I didn't do her.
But I don't hide anything
from you.
I told you what happened
with my aunt in Alfenas.
Dude, don't start with that story
about your cousin again.
It's my aunt once removed.
I don't care if it's your aunt,
cousin, niece.
- Make up a better lie.
- Lie?
Dude, you don't believe me,
it sucks.
I'm not a virgin like you,
cherry.
You really wanna know?
I did it with Priscila.
I boinked her right where
you're sitting.
Now, say that again.
Dude, Priscila's a total slut,
does everything, see?
We've set a date to do it again,
but at her house.
- You wanna know the best part?
- Do it.
The best part is that
you're not invited.
Get lost, please.
Shit, Boca,
you're a real asshole.
Dude, let me ask you,
do you have a home?
I come to the beach
for one reason.
Reason with name, address
and phone.
I mean, the sand itches,
I get sun burnt,
I look horrible in a bikini
and I said I'm scared
to death of the sea.
Wanna come in?
Why? Have you ever seen
me in it?
I should get a bucket so you
can get wet like the kids.
How funny!
I want to see you laugh.
Caco, stop!
And what if we did it?
What?
You know what!
You're joking, right?
Of course I am.
No, I'm not.
Caco, it's weird.
We're friends.
So, then you'd no longer
be a virgin.
No, I'm not
completely desperate.
Me neither.
But my mom's out of town...
Forget about it.
Caco, it was a good idea.
Was.
At least in theory.
Practice is the problem.
Listen, I'm going
to get it going, ok?
How's it going, excuse me?
Can I ask you
a simple question, please?
Which one of you is still
a virgin?
What?
I wanna know
if you are still pure.
Are you sick? You're crazy,
get out of here, kid!
I want to know which of you
pushed through, see?
Go ask your mother, shit.
What's up with this?
My mom already did,
that's true.
Idiot, get lost.
Moron. Are you nuts?
It's only a question.
Just a minute.
Are you nuts?
Nobody'll answer it that way.
Weren't we supposed to ask
if they were virgins?
Dude, you're as subtle...
as two elephants fucking
in a china shop.
- Go ahead, ask yourself, go!
- You want me to ask them?
Go. Go then, go.
- I'm going.
- Go!
Hi, how's it going?
Excuse me.
I'm Priscila from 1102...
And we're doing a Math project
with teacher Mauro.
Would you mind answering
some questions?
Ok, what do you want to know?
Name, age, year.
Adriana, 16, I'm a junior.
Are you a virgin?
That's what you want to know?
Our project is to find out
how many virgins are
in high school.
I understand.
Yeah, I'm a Virgo.
And Scorpion's
my ascendant.
Good, really good Priscila.
Well done! Great interview!
You have a future.
No, for real.
What do we do now?
I don't know.
Now, let me do it, right?
Who are you going to interview?
No one. You're going
to interview me.
You wanna bet that after I do it,
everyone will?
Way to go! I'll do it too.
I'm not doing it in front
of you, ok?
Why not? I'm just as much part
of the group as anyone else.
I'll feel far more comfortable
with a girl.
Boca, it's true.
Yeah, Caco's gotta go too.
Neither of you, come on!
Couldn't you keep
your mouth shut?
Tize, 17, sophomore.
Obviously
I'm no longer a virgin.
- Ok, how old were you?
- 13.
What's up?
It's just that, at 13,
I still hadn't kissed.
Poor little thing.
And him?
It was my brother's friend,
as usual.
We were together forever.
Like 3 months, you know?
Place?
Full-sized bed.
At a friend's house...
No, at his house.
Is it over?
I don't know. Is it over?
No.
So, we went to his house,
like I said...
And it was after a party...
Boca's group is really pumped!
Of course, their project's cool.
Not this shit you thought up.
Calculate how many guys
leave the toilet...
wiping their hands
on their pants?
But it's cool!
Dude, couldn't find
anything grosser?
Quit complaining
and do the damn project.
- What's theirs?
- Virgin girls.
I bet it was Boca's idea,
that jerk off.
No, it was Priscila's.
The virgin herself? Spare me.
Ex-virgin.
What? You did it?
I know nothing. Ask Boca.
That tool boinked her
and didn't tell us.
It's a lie, can't be true.
There's more: People say she's
a slut and does everything.
- Everything?
- Come on. Get real.
- Slut...
- Dude!
Everything was right.
I'd already went to the doctor,
was on the pill.
And I gave up right there.
And a week later,
we'd broken up.
I'm still a virgin.
I wasn't thinking clearly.
And if I had been thinking,
it wouldn't have happened.
All my single friends
are also virgins.
It's normal.
Can I say how I think
it will be?
Almost...
If something happens by the end
of the month, I'll let you know.
It hurt!
I've been dating
for a year,
of course we already spoke
about it, but...
one day it'll happen.
It hurt like hell.
We were messing around
and suddenly...
I was no longer a virgin.
We spent a lot of time deciding,
it stressed me out.
And one day I pushed
and there it went.
Well, technically speaking,
I'm still a virgin.
It was funny.
We were there almost falling,
the intercom buzzing away,
and my head banging
on the table.
It was beautiful.
First time with a boy or a girl?
I went to Paraty with my parents
and boyfriend.
And there we had a room
to ourselves.
So...
I don't know, see? Like...
It's not time yet.
The truth is that I took
my own virginity.
Because,
if he had to do it...
My parents thought that we'd
been doing it for a long time.
But it was there,
with them sleeping next door.
In the bathroom at a party.
It was my first time,
and the only thing I saw
was a sign saying:
"Don't throw paper in the toilet!"
Ok, you can start by saying
your name, age, year.
Leticia, 18, junior.
My first, second and third time
were at the same time.
You can see I liked it.
And you?
- Me?
- No, the wall.
You, of course.
Hey, and that chubby one,
is he all that?
- Who?
- Quit being naive.
Everyone's seen your video
with Boca.
What video?
No, it's a lie.
Yeah? And I'm a virgin.
You are?
No, Leticia! I'm serious.
I'd never screw that nasty Boca.
Leticia!
Hey, last shot!
Ok, it's over.
Team, let's play.
Hey, you're playing like shit.
I'm world champion, respect me!
You weren't even born
when your team won that cup.
I don't talk with crybabies
about soccer.
Why are you complaining?
You do nothing.
Fuck, I made a goal.
You know what?
Priscila's making him like this.
That pale one?
That's her.
The insatiable pale girl.
You're talking shit! You don't know
what you're saying.
He's in love. How cute!
You don't you have
anything better to do?
Not really, dude.
Hey Boca!
You can tell us,
we're your brothers.
Tell us, wait!
Dude, Priscila is a total slut.
She does everything...
We've set a date to fuck again,
but at her house.
You wanna know the best part?
The best part is
that you're not invited.
At least the editing is good.
Play it again, play it again.
You.
What the hell, Priscila?
This is the men's room.
So what are you doing here?
Calm down,
don't be rude.
Rude? Are you crazy?
You put it on the internet
that we screwed.
Ok, we didn't, right.
Ew! Obviously not.
Obviously?
What attitude is that?
I'd sure screw you,
if you want to know.
Cause I'm a super-slut
who does everything.
Aren't you going
to wash your hands?
Sorry Priscila,
Amaral put it online...
- Amaral?
- But he's going to take it off.
Can't you do it somewhere else?
Great, that's all I needed.
Wait, you're not listening,
let me explain.
Priscila! You're not listening to me.
Stop and listen please.
- Priscila.
- Hi, Tize.
You were together in there?
No, I was trying to tell Priscila
what happened...
The site... You saw the video?
- Boca, forget it.
- What?
Forget it, everyone knows now.
- So, I'm trying to explain...
- Wait, is it true?
No, it's not true.
Yes, it is, Boca. We did it.
Did it? What?
Does your brother know?
You're joking?
Everyone knows.
You've got no idea.
How brave!
What? Did I hear right?
Brave?
Why "brave"?
So, I was thinking of camping
this weekend...
with Rafa and Ale,
wanna come?
- With Rafa?
- Camping? Cool, good idea.
No, we're not together.
I know, but we can camp.
- Dude, quit stalking me.
- I'm not stalking you.
Dude, we did it once.
Never again.
- What are you talking about?
- Can I talk to my friend?
- Sure, but I'm just saying...
- Dude, get lost, go.
Goodbye.
What?
Asshole.
What happened?
Tell me!
I dunno, I didn't think.
If I did,
I wouldn't have done it, see?
Can I ask you a question?
Did you use a condom?
Yeah, we did. Got to always.
Why?
Nothing. When I grow up,
I want to be just like you, bye.
Bye.
Hi Dad, it's me.
How are you?
Yeah, I know you exist,
that's why I'm calling.
So, do you have a tent?
For me.
Dad, everyone's going.
Everyone who Priscila?
Can I go too?
Dad, it's quick, just a weekend,
I'll be right back.
So, you gonna take it?
I don't know,
how many people fit?
Hi Pri.
- What people Priscila?
- At least 3, right?
Three who?
Did you already ask your mother?
Did she let you go?
Dad, don't worry about my mom.
I'm not worried about her,
but about you.
Will your cell work?
Or you trust me
or I'll have to lie to you.
Good.
Whose side are you on?
It's the first time you go camping?
There's 2 sleeping bags,
a hotplate...
You don't have
to bring anything back.
- Wanna take a backgammon?
- The backgammon stays.
Not the backgammon!
What's up?
Good morning.
- What you got?
- Tangerines and apples.
That's exactly what I wanted.
- Can I take some?
- Yes.
Know what I can do?
Wow!
Clever girl, 'eh?
- Hi.
- Hi, honey.
- Let's go to the beach?
- Can I take it?
- Of course.
- Thanks.
You think you're going
to do her again?
- What?
- Shit, Boca!
Isn't that why we came
to this summer camp, dude?
No, you came here
to redeem yourself.
And she's got a name.
Look around, look around.
Only cool tents
and look at ours... a clothesline.
Shut up!
We're the homeless
of this beach, right?
It's the best I could do,
if you don't like it, hit me.
Ok, cool.
Hey beautiful!
You ok?
Are you sure?
Scoot over a bit, thanks.
Beautiful sunset...
Hi, can you lend me
that flashlight?
No.
Quickly, Caco and I, we're...
No!
Fuck Boca!
Priscila, Priscila!
- Here's the flashlight.
- Thank you.
If you need anything else,
Amaral and I are here to help.
Just ask.
Seriously, Boca.
You came here for me, right?
Who, me? Of course not.
Forget about it.
Priscila, you never forget
your first time.
Was it good for you?
It was so fast,
I don't remember.
Ok, cool.
So, if you want to eat,
come over, Caco's grub is ready.
- Thanks for the invite.
- No problem.
No way I'm eating Caco, man...
I left the flashlight
with your nice friend, ok?
It was about time!
You know when you dream
you're drowning?
Can't breathe, want out
of the dream any way you can?
It's even worse in real life.
They say you see your life go by
when you're going to die.
But I could only think
of one thing:
I can't die a virgin!
You lose, dude.
What does he have that I don't?
It's true,
he doesn't have a gut.
At least I think she showed
some breast, dude.
Oh, dude, show me later.
This'll be a smash-hit
on Youtube.
Or not.
It is for each one, isn't it?
- What is this?
- Take it easy.
What? No, calm down, thanks.
"I never"...
The game is "I never", right?
- I'll begin, ok?
- No stuttering!
I never faked...
an orgasm!
Whoever did
has to drink.
You faked well, 'eh...
Who's next?
It's me, here I go...
I never...
I never had sex
without a condom.
I'm sick of this stupid game!
What happened?
Great Tize.
Go talk to her, Ale.
Who's next?
It's me, me.
- It's my turn now.
- Just go, then.
I never...
kissed anyone
of the same sex.
She said kiss, you have to kiss.
What? I didn't see anything.
I missed!
I didn't see it!
Who saw, saw.
Who didn't, tough luck.
It's my turn.
Now it's my turn.
I never went limp.
That's true.
- Can I lie too?
- Did you?
Hey, she just said it's true.
- You acted like an ass!
- How could I have known?
You should've noticed!
You drop this bomb on me now.
It's not easy for me either!
I have to think.
I'm going for a walk.
Coward!
He acted like
it was all my fault!
Do you know what
you're going to do?
Of course not.
It might be good to see a doctor.
Now you're, like,
super-experienced?
Your Mom's cool?
I don't know.
It'll be the 1st time
I tell her I'm pregnant.
Mine'd kill me.
Maybe torture me first...
You're not helping much.
Sorry.
Pri, come back.
I don't want to sit here alone,
please.
Will it be a boy or a girl?
No, it's not anything yet.
You're tripping.
And if it were you?
Me?
I'd cry.
A lot.
I did that already.
How's my sister?
She's sleeping.
So, Ale went back to Rio.
Moron.
The guy fucked up,
fucked up real bad,
- but...
- But?
Give the guy some time, ok?
He came here to relax
and got a shock...
And you?
I use condoms, remember?
No, what did you
come here for?
To save girls in danger.
I was foolish.
Foolish? Not at all.
You learn making mistakes.
There's no other way?
Want to teach me?
Almost.
It's not time yet.
It hurt.
It hurt like hell.
Of course we already spoke
about it, but...
I wasn't thinking...
Suddenly...
It was perfect...
It'll happen.
I was no longer a virgin.
You were a virgin.
I was.
You were.
What about Boca?
Nothing happened with him.
This was my first time.
You're really nuts.
No, I'm not.
Well, I was a little with you.
A little?
You bring me here,
you trick me, you seduce me,
to use my body
and toss me out?
I know the type.
Yup, I'm a real heartbreaker.
What's wrong?
I don't know.
Isn't this what you wanted?
Difficult question.
- Is it multiple choice?
- No, it should be an essay.
Well, they're going
to wake up soon.
Let's go back?
No, stay a little longer,
let's watch the sun rise.
I've got to go.
I'm all messed up.
I'm the one
who's messed up.
You knew.
I knew.
Go ahead. I'm going to stay
a little longer.
You are?
Ok, so I'm... heading off.
Are you really ok?
Yeah.
Amaral, wake up!
Let's go dude.
Let's go, pack your bed.
I'm outta here.
You wanna know?
Took you a while.
This clean air was starting
to make me sick.
Cool.
Take the bed.
Give it to me.
Outta here. Let's go!
Hey Boca, do you really think
we missed the fucking bus?
Hey Boca! Hey fatso!
Dude, you're far away.
You're spaced out.
Amaral.
I need to tell you something.
You're going to be
a daddy, right?
Going to be a dad,
I knew it.
Shit, congratulations.
My bad. Spill it.
I didn't sleep with Priscila.
I knew. Fuck, Boca,
I knew it, I was sure.
You lied to me.
Boca, you're a son
of a bitch, man.
How could've I lied
if you just said you knew?
VB - Virgin Boca
Just like AVT.
What's that, a disease?
No. Amaral's a Virgin Too.
Joker. Why virgin?
I already told you
about my aunt in Alfenas.
Don't start again.
Alfenas, Alfalfa, Alfie...
- I don't care.
- Ok.
I don't wanna know.
Does it have to be with Priscila?
For God's sake,
be rational, dude.
Sophomore girls
only want older guys.
What do you want?
Sex.
Now you're talking, dude.
Forget that weirdo.
Pale, unloved...
Not worth it.
Hello?
Hi, Mom.
No, I was waiting for a call.
From nobody.
I'm sorry. I know.
I was going to call you.
Ok, ok, ok. And you?
And work?
How's everything?
Are you eating your greens
and brushing your teeth?
I'm concerned.
How much
you think they charge, Amaral?
Let daddy fix it.
Wait, what if
they're transvestites?
You can't recognize a woman?
There's a lot of people
who mix'em up.
C'mon, dude.
- Four hundred.
- Fuck! That much?
Looky here, ain't it worth it?
It is, of course.
But, we don't really have
any money.
We'll do it fast.
I bet!
Half-price for students?
Don't pay attention,
he's a virgin.
No, Bruna, I'm done.
I can't do charity.
I'd even do both of you!
But you know how it is, right?
We're working and can't.
Come on Bruna!
Maybe later?
Who knows?
Come on, Bruna.
Ah, dude.
You said you'd call.
I know, but there was
no signal, sorry.
Finally, the kids are asleep.
I spent the entire weekend
without news.
Sorry.
Your mom calling me,
cursing me...
He even wanted
to go check, Pri.
Sorry, but nothing happened.
Funny isn't it?
How can someone
travel for 3 days
and say nothing happened?
- Well, it happened, so what?
- What? Tell me!
Dad, there are things
I won't tell you.
What?
I'm your father, Priscila.
Why won't you tell me?
- Honey, don't raise your voice.
- I'm not.
Priscila, you know
you can tell me anything.
Yes.
So, what do you have to tell me
that you don't want to?
It's your turn.
No, your turn.
Dad, I'm not in the mood.
- Priscila,
- Dad, no...
Priscila, stop stalling me.
Spit it out.
Dad, it's not the right time.
That I'm no longer a virgin
for example?
And do you love him?
Who's winning this game?
She is, of course.
I think it's good now,
let's go!
You saw how many guys
they've been with?
Bro, don't say that,
I'll go limp.
Let's go.
Oh, fuck...
Fuck.
Another guy. Shit, let's go.
No, wait.
Stop, calm down.
- Calm down.
- Get the fuck in!
Let me go!
Let's go, dude!
Are you crazy Boca?
Motherfucker!
Brad, get the kid.
Let's talk!
I'll pay for it.
The cops,
let's get outta here.
Brad!
Come, leave that punk.
Bruna, I wanna go to bed!
You said it was a quickie.
Only 15 minutes more.
We have 15 minutes.
Let's do it.
Ah, no pressure,
it'll get worse.
What's wrong?
Are you still hurting? Bruised?
Dude, I can't believe it.
Ah, it's ok. No problem.
No problem for you.
You have no idea
how much I wanted it.
My bad.
Look, what you did for me
out there...
was better than the best sex
in the world.
- You think?
- I do.
Well I don't.
Don't be silly.
You don't understand women.
So learn.
A man can't win a girl
just in bed, understand?
No, can you explain?
Ok.
Look, a woman likes
surprises, romance...
Ah. There's a girl
in my study group...
At college?
No, in high school.
Ok, and what do you do
to win her?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Well, now that is a problem.
Hello, it's Clara again.
The person who pays
your cell phone bill.
Your phone will be cut off
if you don't contact me.
I repeat:
Your phone will be cut off.
Honey, I'm worried
and angry too, ok?
Kiss, bye.
SO THAT YOU
DON'T FORGET ABOUT ME
Hi... Like the tape?
I loved meeting you,
you crazy little thing.
It was the 1st time
a woman stripped for me.
Let's do it all again?
I promise I'll drink less
and make it more enjoyable.
What does he mean?
No pressure, but did you break up
with that loser yet?
Hurry up.
Mrs. Clara...
Wow!
Jurema, is there someone
at the door?
Just me, Mom.
I came to get the paper.
Your brother up yet?
Boca, well, Boc...
The remote's yours.
Not enough.
The remote and the computer.
Mom...
For 3 months.
Forever, Jurema, forever!
Let me go please?
Boca's in the bathroom, Mom.
Taking forever as usual.
I spoke with my mom.
Tell me!
It was weird.
She followed me
around the house asking,
"Where did I go wrong?"
And me: "I was the wrong one".
Crazy.
Conclusion: She cried, I cried,
we both sat there crying.
And Ale?
I don't know him anymore.
Asshole.
Know who really supported me?
- No...
- Was super cool with me?
Rafa.
My brother
never treated me so well.
Yeah? What else?
And you guys?
I don't know, we had sex.
That's all.
That's all?
Leticia is breathing fire at school.
Well, but she has a reason.
She's no saint, I know.
- And?
- I don't know. Why?
Nothing.
No, it's not
that important to me.
Of course you're in love.
He could've called.
- You see him?
- No.
Caco, what do I do?
Why don't you get
professional help?
You don't listen
to anything I tell you.
- Hey, what's with you?
- Nothing.
A ton of things.
Forget it.
No.
Can you understand
without me speaking?
Can you?
Did you know
I thought you liked me?
But I like you.
Like a friend. Hot or cold?
Hot, but I thought
it was something else.
Ah, me too.
Stop!
And now, suddenly, you're starting
to look at guys in a different way.
Cold.
Come on, you don't want
to play the game?
Lukewarm.
Nothing happened and...
You think?
Sometimes.
Look, we're close, right?
Of course.
Is it to make someone jealous?
Look who's coming.
What do I do?
Call him.
Yeah?
Thank you.
What is it? Who is it?
It's a woman?
A girl, another pussy,
eh dude?
Hi, Julia.
Let's go?
- Check it out.
- What?
What's wrong, dude?
I just ran faster than you.
Good morning,
ladies & gentlemen,
I could be robbing,
stealing, killing,
but I'm selling candy,
3 for R$1. Sir?
Hey Boca,
you have no idea who's coming.
No need to knock, you're family.
What's up?
Why the long face?
Priscila,
this is for you.
You're traffic-stopping pretty.
Really, it's for you.
"It's the first time
that I write to you."
Thank you.
"Now I'm hiding,
but I can see you from here."
Priscila! Priscila!
This here's for you.
"I only wanted
to make your wish come true."
- She's digging it.
- Cool, you're lucky!
Who's there?
What do I say?
Rafa?
Rafa, is that you?
- "Rafa"!
- Man, I can't believe it, bro!
I WANT TO SEE YOU!
I did all this for Prince Charming
to get that pale girl!
Gimme a break, dude.
You want me to attack that bitch
with my laser?
100% confirmed?
Aye, Captain.
Fire the fuck away!
Hi Mom, OK.
I'm not going to cheat
on a boyfriend that I don't have...
stripping for some drunk
I just met at a rock concert.
Mom?
Ok, I love you too.
Big kiss.
I like.
I was on that wave
and remembered you.
What wave?
That tube far off.
Crazy talk!
Hey, you want a sip?
No, I'm not so good now.
Crazy woman,
wanna dance?
No, later.
Leave later for later.
Hey girl, you need a life jacket?
Bye, angel...
Enjoy class.
It was true!
Did you see that?
Priscila!
- I found a place.
- You did?
Yeah, but I'm not sure
I have the courage.
- Bye.
Tize, Tize!
Hold on there.
- Tize...
- Ale, get lost!
- Calm down.
- I don't want to talk to you.
Stop. Get lost!
Tize is free
but the defence is closing in.
Goes to the right,
but the defender tackles her.
She tries to go left,
but is blocked by the other team.
The game's very difficult,
very hard.
Yeah, the game's really tough.
Looks like Ale's
going to counter-attack.
Back to you, Boca.
Tize makes a foul,
but the ref doesn't see it!
Ale defends, holds her back.
The game goes on.
He's close to the goal.
Is it a goal? It is...
Goooaaaaallll!
Tize-ze-ze Zero.
Ale-le-le one.
Ale-le-le one, you're right.
Bye.
Please, stop that, please.
Ok, you can start.
So, almost half the girls
in High School are still virgins.
We interviewed up to last week.
And we also worked
with a margin of error,
'cause folks lie.
Like, a lot!
And some data might have changed,
life goes on.
So, of the 120 interviewed,
about 70 lost their virginity...
Will I still remember him
in 20 years?
Of course I will.
But will it be
so important?
I don't know
if the time was right.
I don't know if there's
a right or wrong time.
That's losing your virginity,
it happens.
The best comes later.
Great, great, everyone.
Very cool.
I'll only give the grade...
after all the projects
are presented, ok?
Where is our comrade
João Pedro?
Where's Boca?
Golden eagle
to pink lil' elephant.
The target's in the vehicle
as planned.
Good luck, soldier!
Driver!
Ladies and gentlemen,
sorry to interrupt
the quiet of your trip.
I could be stealing, killing,
but I'm playing the guitar.
I've brought a song here...
that I dedicate
to someone special.
Priscila, this is for you.
Where does it start?
Which way does the rush go?
When all was grey,
I started to see
a blue spot in the sky
When it was all grey,
I started to see
I want to stop
being afraid of the sea
stop dreaming
about the far-off wave
One day,
I want someone to dedicate
a song to me
Is it possible
- I think he's kinda cute.
- So cute!
That someone
likes me so much?
Is it possible
that you now like me?
that someone like you
likes me?
Is it possible
like that, someone likes me?
Give me a chance
Thank you!
Can I sit there?
Hey, kiss him!
Don't worry, he's 12 years old.
I love it when you laugh.
I love it when you make me laugh.
Kiss, kiss, kiss, kiss!
There, it's in the right place.
And you, Boca,
what is your biggest wish?
A pen.
A pen?
Fine, I'll go get a pen for you.
Honey, honey, I'm home.
Priscila!
"Mom, before you kill me,
remember you were 16 once.
Kisses, your beloved daughter."
Stop! Stop! Stop, dude!
Don't turn the lights on yet.
Relax.
Leave it off for people
to read the credits.
Let's enjoy
the romance in the air.
And let everyone kiss.
Exchange some spit.
Hug and cuddle, right?
"Cuddle"? Seriously?
Jim Kerr?
From Simple Minds?
Hi.
Hi. I only exists
because of you?
My mommy and may father met
on a concert of you in Rio in 1988?
Did you remember?
We never forget that we've
been in Brazil.
Because it was magic for us.
It was the first time
we1ve been in the country.
Na the boys of Glasgow,
you grow up listening...
that Brazil is a magical,
place to go for.
- What is your mommy's name?
- Her name is Clara.
I would like to dedicate...
"Don't You Forget About Me"
to Clara.
Everybody!
What is that?
Burt.
What?
Now you're exaggerating.
Nothing like first time.
Wow, I've drooled!
Done by (c) dCd / july 2011