You there up on the tree.
This is your last chance
to get down,
or we'll be forced
to take measures!
Come on!
Nitzan, you listening?
I'm asking you for the last time...
Get down, before it's too late.
Nitzan, please, give up!
Get down off the tree now!
Gal Toren
Sarah Adler
and Maya Kenig, who also edited
Cinematography
Sharon Meir
Produced by David Mandil,
Moshe Edri Leon Edri
Written and Directed by
Gur Bentwich
UP THE WRONG TREE
Hey buddy! Come here.
Come here for a sec.
You wanna sign, man?
Say, you happen to see a cute girl
walking a big black dog?
No.
-Can I have one?
Don't you wanna know what you
wouldn't sign?
What wouldn't I sign?
-Nice of you to ask.
A petition to turn this lot
into a park.
What's wrong
with the way it is now?
Nothing,
but if we don't move fast,
this whole place
becomes a parking lot.
You don't say?
Motherfuckers, huh?
-They sure are.
An outrage!
Ever heard of Tzemakh?
-Not really.
He was in city council,
and for the green party...
Man, I don't care about no politics.
This ain't politics,
don't be a cynic.
Just sign here
and get it over with.
With all the shit in the world,
this is what bothers you?
Seriously? This lot?
You know what,
don't sign, okay?
Thank you.
You upset now?
-I ain't upset.
Hey, buddy, you wanna sign?
I already signed, thanks.
-No, thank you.
I don't want to butt in, but I think
someone else is walking your dog.
Zorba?
Big, black, ears like this, right?
Do us a favor,
can I leave this suitcase
with you for a bit?
You've got some nerve, huh?
Municipal Inspection,
license please.
Hey, Nitz.
I missed your lousy humor.
-What's up?
Want do you want in your pita?
-Sabikh.
With hummus?
You know what, make it
shakshuka instead.
On second thought,
shove them both in there.
Nitz, trust me, you don't want
that kind of mess.
I can't make up my mind
you know how I've missed them both.
You're the boss.
-Thanks.
So tell me, how was Australia?
It sucked.
Really?
Na. Just not much to tell.
You guys do alright here without me?
Thank God.
What's with the...?
Getting closer to God.
How is it?
Man, this "Mess"
is fucking delicious.
You've gotta taste it.
-I trust you.
You still saving
leftovers for Zorba?
Sure am.
-l'll take them over now.
They're glad you're back,
Zorba and...?
Kessem. -Yeah, Kessem.
Were they happy to see you?
They don't know I'm here.
-How's that?
A surprise.
Hello.
-Hi
Hold on!
One second.
Hey, come in.
Sorry for the mess.
You can set that down here.
You know what, put it here.
No, put it there, that's perfect.
How much should I give?
Don't know, never had a dog.
No, I meant the tip.
-It's on me.
Why? No way.
Wait, l'll find my purse.
What's his name?
I found him this morning,
haven't even named him yet.
Come here,
you've got to hear this.
You're assuming
that I'm afraid of you...
It must be love, huh?
I can see it now...
- You have an issue with money.
Reminds me of my parents.
They've been like that forever.
You'd hang me if you could.
You always end up with the same...
Pooch, what is it? What?
Cutie...
Cutie, what is it?
Alright, Zorba,
I left something for you.
You tell Kessem I was here.
You know what,
don't say a word.
That's it, had enough?
Gimme a light.
-I quit smoking.
How come?
We're not kids anymore.
Maybe you're not.
What are you reading there?
You got a light?
Tell me
-Yeah?
You still hanging out
with that stewardess?
That's so last year.
Any new chick lately?
Nothing specific.
And Kessem?
-What about her?
She got somebody?
Let it go, man.
Come on, let's play!
I heard there's some asshole
walking Zorba every morning.
What do you care anyways?
Letting some stranger walk my dog
seems right to you?
I walk him, you retard.
I know.
I saw your name on that
park petition thing.
Is this an interrogation now?
I'm just curious, why does it
have to be you walking Zorba?
'Cause he's too old and
heavy for Kessem to carry,
so I take him down on my way
to my "stupid job". Let's play!
What now?
Why didn't you tell me before?
-We agreed not to talk about her.
I've got to see Zorba.
-No you don't.
What have you got
against me, huh?
Cut it out.
What's your problem?
Remember what you said
before you left?
That she's out of your system, right?
So I said so.
-Great.
I haven't seen you for a year
and instead of playing some ball
you're talking my ear off.
Then let's go grab a beer.
-Forget it.
Gimme the key.
-What key?
You take Zorba out,
you've got the key, right?
I want to see my dog.
That's not cool, bro.
Why?! Are you judging me?
You're supposed to be my friend.
She doesn't need to know about it.
Do me a favor. I just want to see
the dog, honest, I miss him.
Why don't you do us
a favor and go fetch?
Why are you looking
at me like that?
I'm sorry, alright?
I'll never leave you again.
You know, sometimes...
parents don't get along.
It doesn't mean
I'm not crazy about you.
You know how much I missed you?
Hello, mind if I ask you
a few questions?
We're not interested, thanks.
Are you were aware of the struggle
regarding this lot
and what's your take?
Fuck your struggle, alright?
Okay. Is it because you think it's
hopeless, or you think it's dumb?
So you're like
a video-activist, huh?
Sort of. And who are you?
You don't live here,
so what are you
doing here anyways?
Not much.
Interesting, and your name is?
-Nitz.
Nitz, do you mind
taking over for me here?
Excuse me?
I just gotta upload this to my blog,
and you're here anyways.
You think I'm going to waste my time
watching over your stupid struggle?
Why not? It's a worthy cause,
and it might just be worth
your while. -Really...
Give me a break, you don't need
to do anything but sit here...
Hold this for a second... You don't
even have to get anybody to sign.
You can put the shirt on
if you want to.
And if you see something suspicious,
our phone number's over there.
I don't have a cellphone.
Oh... What's the worst
that could happen, right?
Yeah, this whole thing's
kind of useless, isn't it?
Ok, bye Nitz.
I'll get the blog up
and I'm back. Thanks!
You're the best!
There's snacks in the action tent.
The city promised we'd have a
park here by the end of the year.
Meanwhile, looks like we've got
tough times ahead.
But Lahav, what's with the tent?
You see the booth that scumbag
Tzemakh put up last night?
It's a sneaky attempt
to overtake the lot.
That's why we've gotta keep
this place occupied 24/7.
That's why my daughter and I
made this tent.
But who's going to occupy the tent?
Folks from the action committee,
people like me, like you.
People who care.
Fuck your struggle, alright?
Nevertheless,
our park shall arise.
She said, why don 't you take a break?
Why do you involve her in our
sex life? - What% the problem?
If I wanted to involve her
in our sexual life I would...
I can't talk any sense into you.
Good dog. Shhhh...
I'd like to go back to my house.
You hear me,
do you mind getting out?
Where are you, on the roof?
If you come up here,
I 'm calling the cops.
Have you lost it? What am I,
a rapist or something?
I don 't want to see you, alright?
Who told you I was here? Eran?
No, Zorba.
Very funny.
Get the hell out of my house.
Kessem.
Don't 'Kessem' me.
I 'rn supposed to fall into your arms
just 'cause you're back?
You're not wanted here.
Get lost.
It's my right to see Zorba,
he's my dog too, remember?
That didn't keep you
from going away.
But I came back.
Well, good for you.
What do you want here anyways?
I want to see my dog,
what's your problem?
Like it% going to help now.
What's wrong with him?
He can barely walk.
ltk his lower spine.
The doctor says he hasn't got
much time left.
And it% only going to get worse.
Then let me see him
while he's still around.
As long as you're not here
when I 'm home.
Fine.
- Finek not good enough.
I leave evely morning at nine,
and get back at six thirty.
What's with this new job?
You a yuppie now?
Hilarious.
Remember, it% his back leg
on the left that hurts the most...
And that% it.
I'll deal with his food.
How about "hi",
"welcome back",
anything like that?
Justpromise me, starting tomorrow
I won 't find you here
otherwise I'll change the locks
and you'll never see him again.
You promise?
I swear on my mother, alright?
Bye.
Fuck.
Mommy doesn't want me
to stay here tonight.
So I'll see you tomorrow. OK?
Bye, Zorbie.
Good evening.
You can go if you wanna,
I'm sticking around either way.
If those parking lot shitheads
try anything I'll let you know.
What's so funny?
I'm with the parking lot shitheads.
-Whadya mean?
Guarding.
Guarding the booth?
Making sure it doesn't run off?
No. Guarding against vandals.
Who's going to vandalize?
People like you,
so-called park activists.
You want any coffee?
Be honest with me,
isn't it a waste? Huh?
Turning this into a parking lot?
Isn't a park way better?
Better for who? Me?
-For example.
And if there's a park here,
I'd be drinking coffee,
or sleeping here at night?
Why not?
'Cause they'll have special
park rangers against that.
And if there's a parking lot here,
they'll let you spend the night?
That's what they promised me,
a job during the day, and the
booth to lay my head at night.
That's one heck of a deal, huh?
I wouldn't trust those assholes.
Tzemakh is my brother-in-law.
So you're in tight, aren't you?
Then you tell your
brother-in-law, okay?
That Nitz said, there ain't gonna
be no parking lot here, okay?
Whatever you say.
Here, you want some?
What is that?
-Ritalin, it'll keep you awake.
Don't worry man, you can go to sleep.
I got no plans for tonight.
Me neither.
Good night.
-Good night.
So who are these people who've
decided to invest their time
in this esoteric ideological
struggle? And why?
Today's blog is dedicated
to this question.
I don 't like the...
Turn off the porn,
you've got a client waiting.
What can I get you? Sabikh?
-A "Mess".
And cigarettes, a lighter,
and a beer.
Put it on the park committee's tab.
What, you too?
-Why are you surprised?
You just don't seem the type.
You don't seem
the religious type either.
I'll have another beer.
Pack it all up, and don't
forget the leftovers for Zorba.
So what's your connection
to this place?
Irony is I live right here.
Oh, do you wanna
sign our petition?
We signed it, thanks!
This struggle made me realize
how connected I am to this place.
Can you explain it to us too?
Thank you, Yomtov. It was good.
-Welcome. Bye.
Go ahead.
I've lived here before.
In your childhood?
- Long before that,
it was our family's orchard.
See, we came from Bavaria.
We were Templers,
and we grew oranges.
Are you saying you lived
right here in a former life?
That doesn't seem
statistically probable.
On the contrary, we're drawn
to places we've lived in before,
to make amends with people
we might have wronged in past lives.
It's not just me, it's true
about everybody here and now.
Hey buddy, come here!
Boris, I'll be with you in a second.
Come here, sign this.
What is this?
A petition to turn this
lot into a park.
What's the problem?
A parking lot, that's what
the tycoons are up to.
On second thought, you know, a few
more parking spots around here
wouldn't be such a bad idea.
'Cause of talk like that and
people like you, no offense,
this whole city's full of parking
lots, and not a single park.
You really think a tent and some
signatures can make a difference?
I'd like to believe so, yeah.
Sounds like a waste of time to me.
Time will tell, buddy.
Good luck with the cause.
If you see Zohar,
tell him I left him this radio!
And say 'hi' for me,
Tzemakh!
Good morning,
A short update concerning
our struggle.
Sony I was offline.
I've been busy.
First oft we've got a new energetic
and hot activist in our ranks.
Even if ideology
isn't his biggest concern,
he makes up for it
with his consistency.
Already a month here, chilling
with his loyal companion, Zorba...
abandoning post only
when necessaly.
The "Mess"!
In other words: a model activist.
More news: we had
a festive day of planting.
I believe we need to "plant
some facts on the ground".
When they take root,
our message will go through,
that the park is already here.
Goodbye... bye...
Thanks for coming...
After eveiyonek gone,
our hero stands guard alone...
...or maybe not alone.
That% all for today, friends.
Stay tuned...
Love you in evely way possible.
Bye.
H3)'-
Long time no see.
Am I early? You want me to come
back after you've left for work?
No... I'm not going.
You alright?
Zorba's been crying all night...
I don't know what to do.
Can I come in and see him?
You can.
Pooch, what's hurting you?
-His back.
He can't stand up.
Come here, wanna go out?
-I've never seen him like this.
I 'm leaving and I won 't be back!
I 'm moving to a fucking hotel...
Why don't you get a divorce
already, you losers!?
I told you the whole building
is listening.
I don 't give a damn!
Have you lost your mind?
Great, ciy all you want.
Hey.
-Hi.
Thanks for coming.
-What's going on?
Zorba's not doing so well,
we're going to the vet.
Poor thing.
You want me to get my dad's car
and we'll drive together?
It's more important that
someone stays here.
But how will you get to the vet...?
Oh, right.
So you finally met her?
How was it?
You're not telling, huh?
Nice to meet you, I'm Teddy.
Hey. You coming?
So...
Be strong. Bye, handsome.
We had our good times,
didn't we, Zorba?
Just like a real family, huh?
That time you were a puppy
and ate all our hash...
and then stared at us looking
so confused, you remember that?
Maybe it's wrong to put him to sleep?
I know that doctor said
it was terminal,
but even a week is something...
-What good is it?
I can't take this, Nitz.
You were with me on this
15 minutes ago, so what... why?
Because I miss him already.
Let's go into the other room.
You got a blanket to put him in?
What can I say, Zorba?
Life sucks, huh?
If you ever come back then...
Drop by, say hello.
Or at least send me a sign.
Sweetie.
It's OK.
Good dog...
Can you turn that shit off?
I can't deal with this
melodrama right now.
Take over, will you,
I can't drive.
You mind?
It's so great coming home
to your womb.
-Shut up already.
If it wasn't for your struggle,
we'd have found a place to park.
Lucky for us, it would have
ruined the moment, no?
Would you say I come too fast?
The circumstances weren't ideal,
but it was fun.
Wasn't it?
Totally.
I'm just asking, you know...
In general, now that you've got
some perspective.
Who says I've gotten perspective?
Right, like you've been
waiting for me?
Is that what your activist girlfriends
told you? That you come too fast?
"Girlfriends"
is taking it a bit far.
Right, "the whole concept
of monogamy is capitalistic".
Did I say that?
Not particularly.
-What?
You, coming too fast.
Who're you comparing me to?
-Stop bugging me.
You really
didn't have anybody else?
You never wanted
to be with someone more...
dunno... different than me?
Does it stress you out?
No.
What?
Kessem, what's your problem?
Give me the keys.
-Aren't we going to bury him?
No way, I'm not coming with you.
-Kessem.
What's with you?
To the life and untimely
death of Zorba.
Poor thing, he was a good dog.
He wasn't a dog, he was a man.
He felt that way too.
"Here Lies Zorba RIP"
You know, on our walks,
dogs would come sniff him,
check him out,
he'd look at me like,
"Do they actually think I'm a dog?"
He loved beer
he hated fights.
He'd cry when we fought.
Also when we fucked.
We done here?
I've got to go.
Can you stay a bit longer?
I've got to pop by Yomtov's.
I've been here
half a day for you.
Five minutes,
a phone call and I'm back.
Use mine.
Yeah, but I've got to...
get supplies for the night.
Okay, then go.
You need anything?
-No.
Go on, then.
What?
Alright...
bye.
Hi, you've reached Kessem,
if you 've got something smart
to say, say it.
You shall love God
with all your heart and soul
These words that I command you
shall be in your heart
And shall be taught to your children
and spoken of when you sit at home...
And you shall bind them as a sign...
Can I have another Shekel, brother?
Write them on the doorposts
of your house and on your gates...
Leave her alone, Nitz.
Put one more on the tab.
-Nitz, Nitzan.
Come pray with me.
It'll do you good.
L'll pray on the way.
To the struggle,
the park and the parking lot.
You see that there?
That's where I used to live.
With Zorba, and Kessem.
We lived there happily ever after,
till one day I disappeared on her,
and now that I'm back,
she's not into me.
She's got a point.
Theoretically, sure,
but today, in the car,
we made love.
After we put Zorba to sleep.
You heard about Zorba?
Let me have that.
Kessem, if you want to call me,
you can get me at this number.
I'm here all night,
so call me, okay?
All of a sudden she flipped out,
ran off without saying why,
won't answer my calls.
What am I supposed to think?
She's playing with you.
-Think so?
If I knew anything about this shit,
I wouldn't be alone out here.
Kessem's not like that.
When we're near each other,
we can't hold back, you know?
Kessem, pick up already,
you trying to drive me nuts?
What's your deal, huh?
-Just let her sleep, man.
Answer the phone, if you don't want
to talk to me, you don't have to!
Just answer it, you whore!
Let her sleep!
You think she's got a guy there?
-How the hell should I know.
Wait here, if anybody calls,
give us a shout.
Kessem!
Goddammit...
I'm going up there.
-What good is that?
If she's got someone up there...
-Listen to me, man.
I'll kill her, kill him,
kill the both of them.
You don't wanna go up there
like this, wait till tomorrow.
Kessem, open the door.
Kessem, I'm coming in.
Open the door!
Who's in there with you?
Open this fucking door,
or I'll break it down!
Everything alright up there?
-Yeah, yeah.
Excuse me...
What's going on?
She's probably locked herself in.
Whadya mean, locked herself?
-She won't open up.
Maybe she doesn't want to see you.
You don't get it...
I'm worried she's
harmed herself, okay?
Does she have a history?
Has she ever tried to...
Talia, get me the phone.
-Okay, sure.
Come down please.
Call an ambulance.
-Not the police?
Gimme the phone.
I need an ambulance to...
Kessem.
Why won't you answer me?
Kessem?
You changed the locks?
-Don't come here anymore.
You know how worried I was?
-Sorry.
I'm not moving till you let me in and
explain why you been ignoring me.
And where were you all night?
Where?!
Get the fuck away!
Kessem,
Open Up, will you?
I'm going to score some stuff.
Keep an eye on the booth, will you?
Kessem!
Can't you hear me calling you?!
Buddy.
Good morning.
Come out, please.
Come on out.
Mr. Tzemakh here is saying
you burned his booth down.
Why'd he put it here?
Why do you sleep here?
This your daddy's lot?
This is public property, darling.
Does that mean you did the burning?
-And if I did, would I tell you?
Look, gasoline.
You've got proof.
This yours?
Yeah, we toss some fish
on the grill every night,
you're welcome to join us,
or is that against the law too?
He is now impeding
an officer of the law.
This is public property.
-No it isn't, you're an anarchist...
Yes it is, our lawyer Nahumi
looked into it.
You can say Nahumi all you want...
It's public, I can do whatever I want.
-Not at all! Not at all!
Nobody will tell me...
Goddammit, the two of you,
Why waste your time fighting?
-Excuse me?
Take your girl to a movie,
go surfing, keep me out of it.
We'll see who has the last laugh.
Excuse me, officer!
Yes, Nitz,
you got something to say?
You wanna drop in
for a quickie in the tent?
I'm not friends with people
who aren't nice to me.
Who said anything about friends,
just a quickie to boost morale.
Get your reward blowjob
from your girlfriend, okay?
Yes, things are definitely heating up.
What's so funny, ha?
It's money I worked hard for.
And a lot more money
rotting away on permits
while shitheads like you
live on your daddy's Visa Gold.
While Tzemakh works the authorities,
we're getting ready for battle.
What? Gas masks?
They're good for tear gas too.
Isn't that going too far?
Who knows how this'll end.
Could you tie the rope to the masks?
What's up?
Tzemakh's people destroyed
our eco-garden
while someone was
ditching his post...
I've been sleeping out here
for a month
so you could play at being
Che Guevera, okay?
No, we've been funding your beer
and cigarettes for a month,
while you were partying...
You burnt down the booth against
our will and escalated the struggle...
Anger levels are rising to
new heights in our camp as well,
or are these first signs
of an ideological crisis?
Just because you're
a tree-hugging pacifist, and I'm...
You're what now?
-I believe we need to act differently!
Nevertheless,
our park shall arise.
So be yourselves,
and stay tuned...
Teddy.
You see that?
-I did.
Over three thousand hits
since this morning.
It's not about ratings,
it's about the message.
So, what's wrong with our message?
It kinda makes us look like psychos.
Good, let them think
we're psychos.
Make me a Mess.
And add the beers to the tab too.
-Nitz, forget about the beers.
They told me you were off the tab.
Who said that, Lahav?
Beers don't look good on camera?
Or am I being punished?
It's not a punishment, it's a budget
thing. These weeks add up.
Why don't you just let it go?
Here, take your Mess,
and let it go, ok?
With your permission, I'd like
to trade the Mess for beers.
Nitz,
one beer on me and that's it.
OK?
Want some gum, sweetheart?
I can't really explain where my
knowledge comes from. It just does.
Like when I saw you with Zorro.
-Zorba. -Yeah, Zorba.
I usually don't tell people
about their past lives,
but I thought you'd like to know,
I saw you two together,
back when he was human.
-Obviously.
You were still you, but younger,
a sweet little boy, and he...
He was very important
in your life. Impressive, close...
maybe a father.
Is your dad alive?
This is what you're telling me?
That Zorba's my dad?
Let's do the math. Was Zorba
born after your father died?
My dad came back as a dog to
sit around my apartment all day?
What about his friends, his wife,
his colleagues or whatnot?
He wasted a whole lifetime on me?
Why say 'wasted'?
You two have unfinished business.
Too bad you didn't tell me sooner.
'Cause now Zorba's dead too.
He's just dead, yeah?
Didn't finish any business. Dead!
Oh, that must have been
so hard for you...
You know, he'll probably be back
sometime, but I'm just so sorry.
I'm sorry.
Why did you tell me
all that anyways, huh?
I felt you were going through a
rough time, I thought it could help.
You and your husband scream at each
other like crazy. What's that about?
Huh? Isn't that rough?
True. We do fight a lot.
We've got unfinished business
for quite a few life-cycles...
But we're working on it.
What if he's just a shitty person?
Maybe if you dumped him,
you could have a peaceful life.
Ever think of that?
-Yes, I have.
So how come you're so
sure you shouldn't?
Because the thought
of life without him...
I just don't want it.
Bye...
Kessem, it's me, Eran,
you can open up.
I'm not here to nag,
you left your phone at my place,
SO...
Talk to me.
She ignores me too.
Hey, what's up?
Probably went to her
parents or something.
Why didn't you tell me?
Don't play the victim,
you're the one who ditched her.
So now you're an expert
on who ditched who?
That's what you told me.
So you waited for me
to get on the plane
before you made your move?
No way, man.
So?
Up until yesterday
there was nothing going on.
I swear.
So suddenly, after all these years,
she realizes she's into you?
Exactly two hours after I fucked her?
Does that make sense to you?
Yesterday of all days?
Doesn't it seem strange?
Cut it out.
She's only looking for someone
to fertilize her egg.
Fuck off. -She fucked you just
to drive me nuts, don't you get it?
Friend!
Kessem, slow down.
I'm doing eighty.
Yeah, but it's night, it's dark,
it's winding.
Don't you trust me?
It's not that, it's just that your
driving is stressing me out.
I ever had an accident?
Why can't you cool down and drive,
instead of being edgy all the time?
Don't change the subject. All of
a sudden my driving's so important?
It stresses me out, okay?
What? My driving or the pregnancy?
You gonna quit smoking now too?
It's not for life, you know.
Why are you stressing out?
A family can be a cool thing too.
Don't get all psychological on me,
just 'cause you had a model family.
You're one fucked-up paranoid,
you know that?
Like I did it on purpose.
You stopped taking your pills.
-It's fattening, I told you!
Then that's why we'll have
a baby, 'cause it's fattening?
Kessem, pull over,
you're going to kill us!
You're driving like a madwoman.
Kessem!
Oh, Zorba, no, don't cry...
We're not fighting,
Mommy was just singing, and dad
joined in for a duet, right?
You're a good dog,
give me a kiss.
Look at you with Zorba...
you're so good
and loving and caring.
Just because your dad blew it
doesn't mean you will too.
"Mom Calling"
Yeah, mom, we're...
What?
We're on our way.
Yeah.
Alright.
Want me to drive?
Maybe I just need more time
to get used to the idea.
How much time?
Who wanted to get off at Rosh Pina?
Kessem on the Sea of Galilee
A moon sings in the blue sky...
Kessem.
I came here to tell you
not a day goes by
I don't regret what happened.
I want you to know I've changed,
that I finally understand
what you knew all along.
That you and I are meant to be.
"Changed" my ass,
you returned exactly the same.
Waiting for you under your house
for a month proves I've changed.
Oh, poor thing,
waiting for a month.
I sat around for a year
wondering where you were!
So this is revenge now?
If it's revenge say so,
then I'll get it.
No, you won't get it,
you don't get anything!
You don't really care, you just hang
on to me to feel like you exist.
You impotent piece of shit, you can't
even tell when you're being loved!
Why are you saying
these things, huh?
You trying to ruin everything?
Is that what you want?
Kessem.
Why you gotta do this shit?
Go whine
to your activist girlfriend.
Look who's talking.
You fucked my friend
just to drive me crazy!
Then fuck off already,
just fuck off.
No, I will not fuck off.
And you know why?
'Cause I love you.
And you are the woman of my life.
Stop bullshittingl
What do you know about love?
What is love for you?
You want romance, is that it?
Here you go, I got your
fucking romance right here.
If you don't fuck off right now,
I'm getting my parents,
they're at the neighbors!
You're getting your parents?
-Go!
Then l'm going-
If your parents are so
protective and loving,
how come their daughter's
so screwed up, huh?
Besides, if your parents are here,
why isn't their car outside?
Daddy!
How about you and I
part as friends?
You did your job, I promise to get
lost, you'll never see me again.
Sorry, brother,
I already called it in.
Letting you leave now would
make me look real bad.
I see.
Hey, whoa!
Where you going?!
I hadn't even brushed my teeth
when I got a call from a neighbor.
He noticed suspicious activity.
So here I am, straight out of bed,
bringing to you, live, Tzemakhk
attempt to take over our lot.
Whoa, driver, cut your engine,
stop this tractor right now.
Tzemakh, get him out of here,
don't you hear me?
You burned my booth.
You wanted war - you got one!
It wasn't us, OK?
Even if it was, that doesn't
give you the right to invade.
Lahav... move back.
-Watch out Tzemakh...
You looking to go to jail?
It's done, I sent it.
-You there at home, come here now...
I've got to get to the lot.
You wanna come?
I'm not so sure it's a good idea,
you know I'm kind of a wanted man.
Have it your way, but I've
gotta close up, huh?
Photosynthesis will prevail, Teddy...
Today, even the last of the cynics,
regardless of creed, race or gender,
are climbing out of their shells
to block this shocking injustice.
We won 't let the forces of evil
build their parking lot here.
But who's there sitting idly by,
if not the legend himselli
the dangerous rebel on the loose.
Nitzan, what are you doing here?
People, let's gather for a
discussion circle under the tree.
You think I'd miss out on
this embarrassing happening?
Next thing you know,
they'll be holding hands.
You got a better suggestion?
Why don't you and I
get the hell out of here?
Teddy, you too, we're waiting for
you with the camera under the tree.
Alright, a brief explanation:
Brown areas on the map are
meant for public buildings...
The court has ruled that a parking
lot is not a public building.
That's how I got the
injunction against it.
Yeah, but now they're
fucking us over, how come?
This lot belongs to
The Land Administration of Israel.
So everything set by the
municipality doesn't count.
And you just noticed that now?
- Look who's here!
They recently rezoned the lot,
there's nothing we can do.
We can stand our ground.
What are they going to do?
Tzemakh graciously suggested
that we clear out within the hour,
Otherwise he'll personally sue each
and every one of us for damages.
Before people start running off,
I suggest we form a plan together.
We've got Judge Gardinger, who's on
our side, supporting the cause.
I'll need an hour to look
into that, so bye for now.
Hold on, Nahumi, what if you're not
back in an hour? Then what?
I'll be back, but if not then
I suggest we vacate the premises.
Sorry.
-Vacate? No way.
We can't give up now.
-Our park will arise!
We met, as always, by chance,
I discovered I wasn't even mad anymore,
We sat on a bench in the square,
then moved on to her place,
She showed me her paintings and
told me she'd been alone for a while
I suggested we sleep together,
she said it was a bad idea
So we talked some more,
and I walked out to the hot street
While struggling with the bicycle
lock, I told myself "I get it now"
She was worth her weight in gold
Alone for a long, long while...
Block that end off too!
Tzemakh, how does it feel to be
the bad guy in this story, huh?
You proud of yourself?
-Yeah.
Friends, I'm really sorry,
I tried my best,
Gardinger said we haven't got a case.
Not so fast, Nahumi.
If we don't leave now,
we're risking a law suit...
I'm very sorry, it's time to go home...
Tzemakh, this is your chance to say,
let's call off the parking lot.
You live in a disney film or what?
Run off, better to scream
at each other all day, isn't it?
If you don't leave now,
you'll lose our legal guarantee.
Take your legal guarantee
and make a career off it.
Don't you have any unfinished
business with Tzemakh too?!
Don't mind him.
Is this all bullshit?
-Bye.
Is this about playing activists?
The rabbi said we need
a parking lot here, right?
Shut up already, Nitz.
What are we going to believe in now?
What's going to be as cool?
Something photogenic
and trendy and shit.
Goddammit, Nitz.
-What is it, Che?
It's depressing enough as it is.
What about all the signatures,
the work, the speeches?
What do you want me to do now?
You got a light?
-I quit smoking.
Then fuck off.
Go, your little girl's
waiting for you.
Get away from the tree!
Move it.
-Bye.
As the leader here, I'd appreciate
it if you got that clown to give up.
He's no clown, he's right, and ifl
wasn't a pussy I'd be there with him.
Come on!
Come, if you're man enough!
I suggest you get down from there.
-Come and catch me!
If I come up there, it'll end badly.
-I can imagine.
You coming, there's a great angle
from up here.
You don't want to come down?
-Now? The fun's only starting.
The girl with the camera,
get away from the tree.
You there up on the tree.
This is your last chance to get down,
or we'll be forced to take measures!
I'll come down in a sec.
Nitzan, let's go!
Get down, it's dangerous!
I'm ready! Do your thing!
I'm waiting!
Please come down!
Go ahead, take me down.
Take any measures you want.
Let's have it! Gas me!
Who do you think you are?!
What's your problem?
We love you, Nitz!
Stop!
Nitz, wait!
Stop it, Yusuf,
stop, stop!
Cut the engine.
Nitzan, you listening?
Mr. Tzemakh here is willing
to drop the charges.
I'm not coming down until Tzemakh
and his tractors are gone,
and I get a signed document from
the mayor cancelling this parking lot.
Hey, Nitz. Hey, sweetie.
I wanted to say,
I feel I shouldn't have told you
about your past lives.
Why not?
I'm worried it confused you,
and now you're taking it too far.
You think I'm up here to settle
my unfinished business?
You're not?
-No.
Then why?
You got a light?
No, I don't smoke.
You can see ten lifetimes back, but
not that a man's dying for a smoke?
Bye, sweetie.
You think I'll clear out just
'cause some idiot's waving a rope?
Can you take responsibility
over something like that?
You listen here. If this lot isn't
flattened by the end of the day,
including that fucking tree,
then my name isn't Tzemakh.
I've got two tractors, a court
order, it's my money, my time.
Not yours, and not his.
-Hey Talia, what's up with him?
It's just not his time to get off
the tree yet. I'm leaving now. Bye.
Who's there?
It's Zohar, Nitz's friend,
you don't know me.
What do you want?
I'm not sure you know,
but he's stuck up on the tree.
Yeah, I saw it, and I've
agreed to drop the charges.
Yeah, but it didn't help.
I thought maybe if you talked to him,
he'd be willing to come down.
He's got some nerve, after all he put
me through, to ask me for anything.
It ain't him asking, it's me.
Oh yeah, and why would I do
something like that?
He loves you.
That's bull. Take a look,
look at how he loves me.
He's stuck on his tree,
right in front of my face,
peeking into my house.
Obsessed with something
that's been over for a long time.
How do you think that
makes me feel? Look at him.
Maybe it's inconvenient for you,
but he's stuck...
He's stuck up the wrong tree.
Why does he always
get away with it?
Why does everyone forgive him?
Like he's a little boy or something?
Enough, enough, I'm sick of it.
This business with the
rope could end badly.
Don't worry, he won't do it.
What makes you so sure?
'Cause he loves himself too much.
Too bad, it ain't healthy,
leaving things open. For you too.
You see that there?
There, under the sign?
That's Zorba's grave!
You like it?
They want to put a parking lot here
of all places, that seem right?
What do you want, Nitz? What?
I want a park
where people can meet up,
where kids can play and moms
can come with their strollers,
and you and me too.
We can look out
the window at them.
And we'll procreate like bunnies,
and live happily ever after.
What do you say?
Maybe, but not in this lifetime.
You coming? It's starting
to get boring here.
Where is there to go?
You wanted to disappear
somewhere together, didn't you?
So this is your way
of getting me out of this rope?
Don't be heavy. Come on.
You won't come just 'cause
I invited you, right?
Run, go ahead, run!
Come here, good dog.
So you're finally back.
Not even a phone call?
Didn't you say you'd quit smoking
till your pregnancy was over?
The pregnancy is over.
How can do that without telling me?
It's my baby too.
Then no.
-What?
I haven't done anything yet.
Kessem, that's not funny.
Did you or didn't you?
What do you prefer?
You decide.
Zorba?
I'm so glad you came.
Zorba...
I wanted to tell you I was sorry,
for abandoning you like that...
On the other hand, you weren't
the greatest dad either.
Daddy.
What's with this problematic
personality you passed on to me?
Couldn't you leave me
an operating manual?
It's fine, I ain't bitter.
It's too late for that, I know.
How about getting me a light?
I'm just joking with you two.
Alright then...
Bye.
When did all this happen?
This morning. You tripping or what?
Say, you wanna work with me here?
We'll split our shifts?
Thanks, man, but I think
I've had enough of this place.
Take care.
-You too.
Peace, bro.
-Bye.
Nitz - Gal Toren
His loyal dog - Pasha Toren
Kessem - Sarah Adler
Booth guard - Zohar Dinnar
Mess - Sasha Agronov
Teddy, blogs and editing - Maya Kenig
Director and head activist-
Gur Bentwich
Reincarnations - Talia Fishman
Her husband - Natan Brand
Beach buddy - Yuval Sheferman
Tzemakh - Doron Tzabari
Merciful policeman - Ze'ev Tene
English: Yaron Kaver
Subtitles: Cinematyp Studios Ltd.