-[light music playing]
-[film projector clicking]
[wind blowing softly]
[distant indistinct chatter]
[footsteps]
[cabinet opens]
[water splashes]
[brushing]
[water runs]
[traffic passing]
Come here, come here.
Here you go, here you go.
Which one is it, huh?
Which one?
Hm.
[whispers] There you go.
You could lose,
but you never do.
[man] I don't know
what the fuck--
[woman] Hit me, slam it.
[man] Hit me-- hip to slammin'.
[both laugh]
[cooing]
-[man] Ezekiel's gonna come out.
-[woman] What?
-[laughter]
-[indistinct chatter]
Loses the effect.
You know, that's strange.
[train rumbling]
[no audible dialogue]
[woman chuckles]
[chuckles]
[telephone rings]
[man] Bart's Pizza.
How's it going?
[distant rustling]
[traffic passing]
[door creaks]
[soft rock music playing
in distance]
[soft indistinct chatter]
[woman laughs]
[item clinks]
[drawer slides]
[traffic passing outside]
[car honks]
[door opens]
[doorbell rings]
[door opening]
[creaks, shuts]
-[woman] Hey.
-[man] Hey.
Give me one sec.
[door creaks, shuts]
[birds chirping softly]
[door shuts]
[traffic passing]
-Thank you.
-There you go.
[woman] Oh, my.
How are you?
-[man] Hey, how are you doing?
-I haven't seen you in a while.
-What time you come home?
-Hey, Dia.
-How are you?
-I'm good. How are you?
Nice to see you.
Come in, come in.
Oh, I have to get on the road,
actually.
Come in.
Talk to me a little bit.
Okay.
[liquid pouring]
[sets item down]
[Dia] Okay, honey,
have a little coffee.
[woman] Thank you.
[Dia] Robert!
Robert!
Esta muchacho no escucha.
El no escucha.
[birds chirping]
You want a hair dryer?
No, I don't need a hair dryer.
[Dia] No?
You don't need that?
-I don't really use it.
-[Dia] Oh, okay.
[plastic bags rustling]
Lipsticks.
El color no es bueno para mi.
¿Lo quieres?
Okay.
[Dia speaks indistinctly]
You need cranberries?
For the road?
Okay.
And some cookies, too.
They're gonna be good.
[carton clatters]
[Robert] Fuck me.
-Don't fuck up my car.
-Mm-hmm.
-[Robert] I don't need that.
-[chuckles]
You gonna go see
your boyfriend?
He was never my boyfriend.
Look at you.
-What? What?
-You look so ugly.
-What do you mean?
-What happened with you?
¿Que te pasa, chico?
[Robert] Nothing's wrong,
ma'am.
Why do you start with me
every morning?
Every morning, it's something.
Oh, my God.
[Dia] Want a breakfast?
-[Robert] I want--yeah, yeah.
-[Dia] Okay.
[children shouting]
-[engine turns over]
-[car chiming]
[child shouts indistinctly]
[whimsical music]
[birds chirping]
[music continues]
[music fading]
[crickets chirping]
[car door closes]
[man] Hey.
Hey.
[man] How are you?
How was your drive?
Good.
You?
-Nice ride. [laughs]
-[woman] Yeah.
They let you drive her
in the shop?
[both laugh]
I made good time, though.
-[laughs]
-[chuckles]
[keys jangling softly]
[man] Hey, sweetie!
[zipper whirs]
Look who I found.
[singsong voice] It's Liz!
-[woman] Hi!
-Hi.
It's so great
to finally meet you!
Thank you for
taking the trip up.
-No, thank you.
-Yay, she made it! Whoo-hoo!
-Oh, this is for you.
-Oh, no, no.
-What?
-No, it's nothing.
Come on.
[all chuckle]
[indistinct]
-Cute.
-[man] Geez.
Whoa.
-It's so fancy.
-Yeah, it's fancy.
[chuckles]
[paper rustling]
Oh, wow.
Wow, that's really beautiful.
Thank you.
-It's cute.
-Oh, it's so sweet.
-Oh, and...
-She loves it.
I love it.
-That's for you.
-Whoa. Whoa!
An appropriate offering.
I'm pleased.
Wow, you must be starving
after your trip.
-You hungry?
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
Good, good, 'cause we're
gonna have a great meal.
-So, uh, here.
-Awesome.
I'll take this, and she
probably wants to freshen up.
-You need to freshen up?
-Wow.
-Freshen up?
-[both laugh]
[water running]
[humming melody]
-[Liz] Really?
-[man] Yeah.
[Liz] What kind of band is this?
[man] It's, uh--
it's like Stomp.
[Liz] What?
[laughs]
Aww.
-[man] Yeah.
-[Liz] Sounds pretty good.
[man] Yeah, well, the kids--
the local...
[dishes clanking]
[both laughing]
[man] This is fun.
[sighs contentedly]
[crickets chirping]
-Does she need help?
-Oh, no, she's fine.
[Liz] I feel bad.
I feel like we should help.
No, no, it's good.
Don't worry.
-Yeah, maybe I should help.
-[Liz] Maybe you should help.
Yeah...
I'll help.
[door closes softly]
[indistinct chatter]
[dishes clank]
[door opens]
[door slams]
Hello!
There you go.
[woman] Wow.
[laughs]
[man] Oui, oui.
-Madame.
-[woman] Thank you.
[Liz] Thanks.
-It's so quiet.
-I know.
At first, I was totally
freaked out by it,
but after a while,
you get used to it.
[Liz] You guys really live
up here year-round?
[woman] Mm, it's been
two years now.
-[Liz] Living the dream.
-Yeah.
[Liz] So, how did you guys
meet anyway?
-[woman] Oh.
-[chuckles]
[laughs]
Uh, we, uh...
we met in the desert.
Wow.
Really?
We met at Burning Man.
-Burning Man?
-[couple laughs]
Burning Man.
You went to Burning Man.
Yeah.
I went with Don.
Don, right.
[man] It's amazing, really.
It's-- it's-- it--
it's just so beautiful.
You're-- you're out in this--
in this incredible heat.
And, um, it's like this
alien landscape
where this makeshift city
has erupted.
It's-- there's really
something about it.
-Okay.
-[woman] Stevie got lost.
He walked right into my camp.
So...
Steve says you guys make dolls.
[woman] We don't actually
make them.
We have them made
in South America.
They're these traditional
folk figurines.
They're just...
[mumbles]
Yeah, I know it sounds
ridiculous, but, um...
they're-- people love them.
And, um, they're-- they're--
they're cool, really.
They're-- they're really
surreal-looking.
And we sell them mostly
on the Internet
and some stores and boutiques.
[Steve] They love them
in the fancy boutiques.
They do,
in those fancy boutiques.
And, you know, we--
we import other stuff, too.
And, you know, we really
get to work with the locals
and feel like you're making
a difference in a small--
Well, plus the twice
yearly trips to South America.
That's not bad either.
Yeah, but I mean,
it's nothing like what you do.
[woman] Oh, my God, your work,
it sounds--
Fuck!
How are you?
How's the center?
Actually taking a little bit
of a break, a little breather.
[Steve] Totally.
-What have you been up to?
-Mm.
Nothing much, really.
[Steve] Who have you heard from?
I never hear much
of anything up here.
-Hmm.
-So, uh, what's up with Ariel?
You know, I haven't really
seen her recently.
[Steve] And Mitch?
Mm.
[Steve] Going through
a misanthropic phase?
How's your mother?
She, um...
she died last year.
[woman] Oh, my-- oh.
I'm so sorry.
You're too young
to lose a parent.
Thanks.
I don't know what I'm eating,
but this is delicious.
[woman laughs]
Thank you.
It's fried quinoa
and some parsley
and dried cherries.
The parsley is from my garden.
[Liz] Garden.
Wow.
[crickets chirping]
[door creaks]
I'm gonna go check on the soup.
Do you need anything?
-No, I'm good.
-[woman] Okay.
I'll be right back.
[door creaks, shuts]
She seems...different.
She seems strange.
She seem strange to you?
She seems fine.
You seem strange.
You're the one
that's on the floor.
[Steve] Fuck.
She doesn't call me
when her mother dies?
You've just grown apart.
Give it some time.
You'll reconnect.
It'll be fine.
Okay, Mom.
Oh!
Jesus.
People change, you know.
Maybe you changed.
Yeah, maybe.
She's probably just...
mm, going through a funk.
-A funk?
-[woman] Yeah, a funk.
-[laughs]
-[woman] What?
Sorry I can't be more
articulate.
[both laugh]
Aah!
Oh!
[woman giggling in distance]
[Abba's "Chiquitita" playing
in distance]
[dishes clinking]
Let me help you.
Oh, no, no, I've got it.
You two talk.
-Are you sure?
-[woman] Yeah.
[door creaks]
The house is beautiful.
This is the living room.
Obviously, I decorated
everything myself.
[chuckles] Really?
[Steve] Mm-hmm.
Can't you tell?
-Mm...
-[Steve] It's all me.
Somehow, I doubt that.
[chuckles]
What's this?
Oh, look, it opens.
Oh, don't go in there.
You won't come back.
Hmm.
What is this, one of those
priest scarf things?
[Steve] Yeah, that's
a priest scarf thing.
I do a little priesting in town.
[Liz] Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
I've married a few people.
I can marry you one day.
So...this is a guest room.
Yeah, my bag's here.
Yeah, magic.
Thanks.
So, um, you can hang out here
if you need a minute,
or you can follow me.
No, I'm good.
Okay.
I'm the doll king.
They do my bidding now,
you know?
Can I touch 'em?
Wow.
You've seen
the bathroom already.
[Liz] Yep, got the bathroom.
It's a little-- little tight.
[chuckles]
Oh, our bedroom--
Sylvia and mine-- is up here.
-You know, I don't need to--
-[Steve] What?
I don't need to go up there.
It's okay. I don't...
[Steve] Sure.
[Liz] Looks like you're
gonna have
a little trouble
with the stairs.
[Steve] Yeah.
[water splashing]
[dishes clinking]
[Steve] And...that completes
our tour.
These weren't here yesterday.
Hm.
Mm.
You got to try this.
[chuckles]
-Seriously.
-Mm.
-No?
-Mm-mm.
Okay.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
Sylvia made this pillow
herself.
-[Sylvia] Oh.
-[Steve] Oh.
So what do you think
you want to do tomorrow?
Because we hadn't planned out
tomorrow, every single second.
Well, okay, maybe she has
her own ideas.
Well, what do you say, Liz?
Do you have your own ideas?
Uh, no.
I mean, whatever you guys
have planned is great.
I'm easy.
[Steve] Yeah, she's easy.
You're also far away.
[Sylvia] Um...
So, we were thinking that--
Whoa, we-- we were thinking?
What were we thinking?
We were thinking
that maybe she--
We're Borg, you know?
Hive mind.
That's what happens
when you get married.
Yeah.
[laughs] Okay.
I was thinking--
I was thinking that, possibly--
that you might want to go
to the Shaker Museum.
Maybe check it out.
Really cool.
Yeah, no, that sounds great.
-Yeah.
-Oh, my God. Liz.
You've got to hear this song.
Oh, no.
Oh, babe, not tonight.
[Steve] Just-- hey, now,
Liz is gonna love this song.
-It's late.
-[Steve] It's a great album.
-Babe.
-[Steve] Just one song.
[rock music plays loudly]
It's great, right?
[music stops]
[grunts]
[birds chirping]
[birds continue chirping]
What?
-[rustling]
-[clanking]
[thuds]
[birds chirping]
-Good morning!
-Good morning.
-Want some coffee?
-Yeah.
[Sylvia] How'd you sleep?
Great, thanks.
[liquid pouring]
[dish clanks]
Hi.
Good morning.
[birds chirping]
[woman] Are you free
as you are?
Are you in, any degree,
bound by your appetites,
your passions, your self-will?
Are you at all in bondage to
the opinion of your neighbors,
to the customs
and notions of society,
however harmful or absurd?
These do not trammel
the true Shaker.
[women singing]
[woman 2]
I think that mother believed
that despite the sort of body
and the sort of physical
and mental makeup
with which we might be born,
everyone was called
to be mother,
father, brother, sister
to everyone else.
Those who were men would
have to show compassion
and tenderness of women.
Those who were women,
physically speaking,
would often have to take upon
themselves roles of dominance,
of power, of strength.
One had to be,
within the Shaker family,
all things to all men.
[women] ♪ I will bow and bend
To get it ♪
♪ I'll be reeling,
Turning, twisting ♪
♪ Shake out all the starch
And stiffening ♪
♪ Oh, oh, I will have it
♪ I will bow and bend
To get it ♪
♪ I'll be reeling,
Turning, twisting ♪
-You all right?
-[laughs]
[music ends]
[birds chirping]
[animal howls]
[ducks quacking]
Where are you going?
♪ "Little children,"
Says Holy Mother ♪
♪ "Soothe and comfort
One another" ♪
♪ Lo, lodle, lodle, lodle
♪ Lodle, lodle, lodle,
Lodle, lodle, lo ♪
♪ "Little children,"
Says Holy Mother ♪
♪ "Soothe and comfort
One another" ♪
♪ Lo, lodle, lodle, lodle
♪ Lodle, lodle, lodle,
Lodle, lodle, lo ♪
[talking indistinctly]
♪ Draw the cords
Of union stronger ♪
♪ Wind and bind them
Around each other ♪
♪ Make them feel your love
And blessing ♪
♪ Draw the cords
Of union stronger ♪
♪ Wind and bind them
Around each other ♪
♪ Make them feel your love
And blessing ♪
♪ "Little children,"
Says Holy Mother ♪
♪ "Soothe and comfort
One another" ♪
♪ Lo, lodle, lodle, lodle
♪ Lodle, lodle, lodle,
Lodle, lodle, lo ♪
♪ "Little children,"
Says Holy Mother ♪
♪ "Soothe and comfort
One another" ♪
♪ Lo, lodle, lodle, lodle
♪ Lodle, lodle, lodle,
Lodle, lodle, lo ♪
♪ Draw the cords
Of union stronger ♪
♪ Wind and bind them
Around each other ♪
♪ Make them feel your love
And blessing ♪
♪ Draw the cords
Of union stronger ♪
♪ Wind and bind them
Around each other ♪
♪ Make them feel your love
And blessing ♪
[chuckles]
[spinning wheel creaking]
-[Steve] You can decrease
your speed...
-[Sylvia] I am!
[Steve] Even if they don't hit
the brake lights,
if you're getting closer
to another car.
[Sylvia] Look, see,
we're being passed.
Just to--just to...
[Sylvia] Look.
See?
[bell rings]
[up-tempo folk music plays]
This place is great.
[music continues]
[no audible dialogue]
[music ends]
[birds chirping]
[Steve] Hey.
[Liz] Where --
where's the title again?
[Steve] Inside.
Okay.
-Oh, like Africa.
-Is that what that is?
[Liz] Yeah, that's what
it looks like.
-No, look, he's going inside.
-Oh, nice.
[Steve laughs]
I want a giraffe
coming into my window.
[Steve] Dude, that would
wake me up so fast.
-It's like, "Hello!"
-[indistinct]
-Bah!
-[laughs]
[Liz] This one's North Carolina.
[music resumes]
[no audible dialogue]
[music continues]
[indistinct chatter]
He really misses you.
You know.
I don't want you to think
that just because...
he's married now
that you can't come up.
-Whenever.
-Yeah.
Come up, again.
Visit.
Thanks.
Or he's also --
he's in the city a lot, too.
[indistinct chatter continues
in distance]
Wow, look at you guys.
Oh!
[laughs]
-[laughing] Gross.
-[Sylvia] Aww, hey!
-[Steve] Hey.
-[Sylvia] Hey, babe.
-[bell ringing]
-[laughs]
[Sylvia whispers indistinctly]
-Here!
-[Steve laughs] Look at 'em.
-They're so cute!
-Oh!
-They're hungry.
-Aww!
They're so hungry.
I love them.
Can we get one?
Please?
[man] Hey, you know, he's just
trying to look down your shirt.
I know.
He lured you with those
soulful bedroom eyes.
[Liz laughs]
Don't believe a word
that Sam tells you, all right?
He's a dog.
-Oh, yeah?
-[man] Yeah.
-You two are friends?
-Yeah, Sam and I go way back.
-[Liz] Really?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, just me and him.
-[Liz laughs]
I'm just kidding.
His name's not Sam.
It's Phil.
And I'm --I'm Paul,
by the way.
-Hey.
-[Paul] Hey.
I'm Liz.
He's gonna sing
Beatles songs or something.
Oh, look, look,
I think he's singing.
You hear that?
Yeah.
So...you're telling me Sam --
I mean, Phil's-- taken?
[Paul] I'm afraid so.
Can I buy you a root-beer float
as a consolation prize?
I don't need your charity.
[Paul] Aw, it wouldn't be
like that.
Hey!
Hey.
Oh, this is, uh, Paul.
Hi.
Uh, P-- Paul raises,
uh, alpacas.
Oh, wow.
[Steve] I think we're gonna go.
Uh, ready?
[Liz] Yeah, yeah, totally.
Let's go.
Okay.
Bye.
Nice to meet you.
-And Phil.
-[Paul] Yeah.
Definitely.
Way to blow it, Phil.
[boy] Why--
why do you have to jump
onto the-- your--
your brother?
Why?
Okay?
That is not good.
He is-- he doesn't
do anything to you,
when you jump on him
for no reason, for enjoyment.
And you just want
to get over the fence to--
to go to your friend
or go to talk to them.
But why?
Why?
This is my favorite little boy.
[indistinct chatter]
[brushing]
-[bell ringing]
-[laughter]
[man] Hey, hey, hey!
Come here.
-Alfredo!
-[woman] Oops!
Ready?
Let's go.
-[bell rings]
-Go, go, go, go, go.
[chatter, squealing]
[woman] Is he coming?
[whimsical music playing
from ride]
[laughing]
-[whines]
-No, seriously, it's fine.
Oh, my God.
Look, it's so beautiful,
you got to--
-you have to open your eyes.
-[Liz whines]
[Steve] Come on, what is it?
You're afraid?
We're getting off, right?
We're getting off?
No, no, no, no.
We're gonna go around again.
-Are we down? No!
-Again.
Again.
-God!
-Oh, wow, geez.
-This is unbelievable.
-[Liz] No!
-[Steve] Open them.
-No, no, no.
Open them. All right.
I'm pulling them off.
-Stop, Steve, stop!
-Open your eyes! Huh?
[laughing] Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
All right, stop.
I can't see it, I can't see it.
[both laughing]
Stop! I can't believe
you got me on here!
-This is awesome.
-[clicking]
Aah!
What just happened?
-What just happened?
-No, no, it's perfectly natural.
I think sometimes they stop them
because, you know,
they've got to work on them
a little bit.
-Let's see.
-Um...
Yeah, he's working on it.
He's just--
he's just screwing
and tightening some things.
-Shut up!
-[both laugh]
No, no, this thing was probably
built around 1970, so...
Oh, God.
Steve, I hate your guts.
And they take it apart
and they, like...
-Shut up!
-...back it up and put it...
-So, you know, like,
they pretty much always
get it right, though,
as far as I know.
Oh, man, I'm gonna
get you for this one.
Oh, you know, we're good.
Assuming we live through this,
that's fine.
Shut up already!
[Liz gasps]
[Steve] See?
[laughs]
[engine starts]
-[coughs]
-Oh, no!
-Here.
-[Liz retches]
I'm okay.
-[retches]
-Holy whales' tails.
[Steve laughs]
Aw, it's okay.
[Liz whimpers]
[clatter]
Hey, do you want some tea
or anything,
just to give your stomach
a little...?
-[Liz] No.
-Ginger?
[Liz] I think I'm just gonna
hit the sack.
-Yeah?
-[Liz] Yeah.
Okay, well, you have
a good night.
[Liz] Yeah, thanks.
If you need anything,
just let me know.
[Steve] Night.
Hey, babe, we got to get some
rest tomorrow for the big hike.
[crickets chirping]
[birds chirping]
[mechanical whirring]
[wings fluttering]
It's, like, soulless.
[Liz gasps]
It's scared.
It looks like a-- they're like
dinosaurs, you know?
-[wings fluttering]
-[thud]
Aah!
This way-- aah!
-[Liz] No, no, no, no.
-[Sylvia] Take a towel...
[Steve] What?
Take it and do what?
[Liz] Just...
[Steve] I'm not gonna --
I'm not gonna touch it.
[Liz] Hug it!
Hello.
[Steve] Sure, sure.
We'd be happy to.
Of course.
I totally dig.
They'll go out first thing
Monday morning.
Okay, cool. I'll, uh--
I'll shoot you a message then.
All right.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
All right, I'll, uh--
I'll talk to you then.
Bye.
-Emergency doll situation?
-Yeah.
The doll business
stops for no man.
[chuckles]
[Steve] Sleep okay?
Yes.
[Steve] Feel like a hike?
Yeah, let's do this.
[door creaks]
Liz, I have an extra pair
of boots if you need them.
-No, I'm good.
-Okay.
Thanks, though.
[traffic passing]
[no audible dialogue]
[birds chirping]
[Liz] Do you think we'll see
some deer or something?
[Steve] I don't know.
Dearly hope so.
[Liz] Have you seen them?
-[Steve] No.
-[Liz] No?
Bears?
Do you see bears?
[wind blowing softly]
[water running]
[Liz] Wow.
[Steve] You can say that again.
Wow.
[Steve chuckles softly]
I always liked that about you.
Liked what?
[Steve] That you always
said it again.
It's one of my more
winning qualities.
I've missed you.
[Liz] Me, too.
Yeah?
Of course.
[footsteps]
[leaves crackling]
[Steve] I've missed you.
[Liz] Me, too.
-[Steve] Yeah?
-[Liz] Of course.
It hasn't felt that way.
I mean, this weekend's
been great.
I don't mean that, just...
in general.
Where the fuck have you been?
I kind of dropped out.
I-- I get that,
and I understand.
Really, and I feel like
such an asshole.
Your mother died.
I totally get that.
I mean, I don't get that.
I can't understand what--
what you must be going through
or...what you're feeling.
Why didn't you call me?
I would have been there for you.
I want to be there for you.
[leaves crackling]
I was embarrassed, 'cause
I didn't go to the wedding.
I didn't even--
didn't even RSVP to the wedding.
[Steve] It's me.
[Liz] I know.
[Liz] How do you
reconcile death
when you don't believe
in God?
You don't believe in anything.
Someone just
turns out the light.
That's it.
[water pattering]
[water running]
Sylvia!
[leaves rustling]
There you are.
[breathing heavily]
I was getting worried.
We should...
We should head in.
It's getting dark.
Liz is waiting by the car.
Oh, well, you don't want to
keep her waiting, now, do you?
[Steve] Here.
Let me help you up.
Hey...
Come on.
I'm sorry.
I know.
We were just...
catching up.
And I'm sorry I've...
I've been a little distant
this weekend.
Liz and I have this thing.
Yeah, you have this thing.
No, listen.
I don't need to listen.
I see. You think I haven't,
since day one?
-See?
-You think I don't see--
See what?
It's late. I'm not gonna
get into this right now.
We better go.
See what?
I don't love her.
I'm not in love with her.
-Not really, n-- not like that.
-Jesus Christ.
Fuck! This isn't
coming out right.
Okay, look, you've--
you've never imagined--
-What?
-You...
-I'm the only--
-What are you saying?
You are my husband,
I love you, we're married.
I love you, too.
And I don't want
anything to change.
Well, then you better stop
talking right about now.
No, no.
[insects chirping]
-[knock on door]
-[Sylvia] Hey, it's me.
Um...
Hi. I'm just changing.
[Sylvia] Can I come in?
Sure.
Just gonna put my shirt on.
-I should check you for ticks.
-What?
Deer ticks.
We have a lot of them.
You can catch Lyme disease.
It's really serious.
I should check you.
-Uh, I can check myself.
-No, it's better if I do it.
It'll only take a second.
Oh.
Mm.
[pats]
Take your pants off.
[chuckles softly]
[sniffles]
I, uh...
I wanted to have that feeling,
you know?
Like you're in a room with
someone and you're not
talking or saying anything,
but...
you just know.
[sniffles]
Not that they love you, but
they really know who you are.
[sniffles]
I think I just got confused.
[water splashing]
[spout clicks, water stops]
[Liz chuckles]
We had sex once.
Why don't you guys have kids?
We tried.
I had a few miscarriages.
That's what happens
when you get old.
You got to have
your first kid by 35.
They don't tell you that.
Who knows, maybe we'll adopt.
Gonna go Asian
or Eastern European?
What's wrong
with South American?
[Liz chuckles]
Not a damn thing.
We'll see.
Plus, you have experience
importing from that region.
Oh!
Nice one.
[laughs]
-You should freeze your eggs.
-[Liz] What?!
Seriously, think about it.
You should.
I don't know.
I don't think I'd be
a very good parent.
Man, I need a bathtub.
Shit dreams are made of.
[both laugh]
It was just once?
Yeah.
It was a long time ago.
I like being old.
Besides the miscarriages.
-You're not old, Sylvia.
-Relatively.
When you're old...
you start liking yourself.
I wanna like myself.
[Sylvia] You will.
Hungry?
Sorry to pull you out.
[insects chirping]
[Liz] Who eats their pizza
with a fork?
You do.
[both laugh]
[Steve] You better take it fast
'cause it...
-[Sylvia] Okay.
-[Steve] All right.
[bottle clanks]
-[Steve] You need to drink.
-[Sylvia] Oh, yeah?
-I am, I am!
-The power of Christ compel...
[Steve and Liz laughing]
I'm eating a carrot
and smoking a joint.
-That's kind of gross.
-You guys, I didn't--
I wanted to tell you
about the other nun.
[Liz] What?
The one that I gave
a nervous breakdown to.
That's what she gets for being
so right about everything.
-"Nun" too soon.
-[Sylvia] Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
No, well, seriously,
she taught typing,
and we would, like, stick
pencils in the doorknobs
and break them off,
break them off, break them off.
[Steve and Sylvia laugh]
[both laughing]
[Liz] We just got it.
We should go for a walk.
I think that's
a really bad idea.
-Yeah, that's a horrible idea.
-[Steve] No, no.
We've got to-- we've got
to get the blood moving.
[Sylvia laughs]
I'm pretty sure my blood
is moving all the time.
It's kind of upsetting
if you think about it.
What if we tried
to be very still?
-[howling]
-Oh, God!
What was that?
[overlapping chatter]
[all laughing]
-Oh...
-[Steve] You all right?
It's probably just
the Ionics' dog.
Oh, yeah,
it makes this weird sound
because they put
this collar on it
that shocks it
every time it barks
'cause it makes these
horrible growling noises.
Anyone want an omelette?
I want to make an omelette.
How can you possibly be hungry?
What are you gonna put in the
omelette, babe? With some peas.
-Peas in an omelette?
-[Sylvia] Yeah! Why not?
Experimental omelette!
Yeah!
[Steve] Um, peas and hot sauce.
Is Apple peanut butter weird
to put in an omelette?
[Steve] No, I don't think so.
This is our omelette, babe.
We're making this
how we want it.
-[Sylvia] Here.
-[Steve] Thank you.
-What you chopping there?
-[dog howling]
[Sylvia] Shallots.
Muy good.
[Steve] Okay.
Oh-ho-ho, yeah.
Listen to that sizzle.
-[chuckles]
-[chopping]
[Sylvia] Is that a good thing?
I think we should turn
the heat down.
Oh!
I like the way you think.
Okay. This is looking
well-ordered here.
-Peas.
-Get that in there.
And let's, um-- let's get
focused here, though,
'cause I think this is--
this is really
in a good place right now.
Okay.
I think it's good.
-All right.
-[Sylvia] Yeah?
[Steve] And here we go.
I know.
This is a terrible omelette.
It's okay.
We will rebuild.
We have to help that dog.
What dog?
The Ionics' dog?
-[Steve] Oh, no.
-Oh, yeah.
Look, I assure you,
the next time we're in town,
I will give them
a very stern look.
We won't send them
a holiday card.
No holiday card.
We send out holiday cards?
We have to destroy that collar.
It's an abomination.
Well, you know what this is,
is a shock.
It's really not that bad.
No, I-- I can't get that sound
out of my head.
[Steve] Keep low, keep quiet.
Let's go.
[Steve speaks indistinctly]
[Liz] Wait. Where are we going?
Wait.
-[Sylvia] This way.
-[Liz] Wait.
Where are you going?
Hey!
-[giggling]
-Shh!
[dog whining]
[laughs]
-Hi! See? [Laughing]
-What's that?
-Oh, my God.
-Shh.
[Sylvia laughing]
-[dog whines]
-[Liz speaks indistinctly]
[Liz] Oh, my God.
Go!
Go, go, go, go.
[dog barking]
[both giggling]
Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
Go!
Go, go.
Go.
[dish clanks]
[giggling continues]
-Oh!
-Why are we sitting in the dark?
-[Steve] Shh!
-[Sylvia laughs]
[Steve] I'm gonna put
this collar on you.
[Liz] Give me that thing.
[dog barking in distance]
Woof!
[Sylvia laughing]
-[imitates dog barking]
-[Steve] God.
[Liz] That doesn't work.
Here, you try it.
[Sylvia inhales deeply]
[barks loudly]
[Liz laughs]
[overlapping chatter]
[Liz] Let me try.
Try this one.
Yip, yip, yip, yip!
[Steve] God, that fucking noise.
-[Liz] What noise?
-[Steve] You don't hear that?
High-pitched screeching noise?
[Sylvia] Oh, my God.
I know what this is.
This doesn't shock you.
If you bark, it makes
a high-pitched screeching noise
that only dogs can hear.
-[Liz] Steve heard it.
-[Sylvia] I know!
[Liz laughs]
[Steve] What are you
laughing about?
[both laughing]
[dog barking in distance]
[Liz] Oh, my God,
that dog barks a lot.
[Sylvia] We have to go and put
this collar back on him.
-No. No.
-[Liz] No, I totally agree.
-[Steve] No.
-[Liz] Yeah.
You. You were the one
just crying about the poor dog.
[Liz] Well, I'm a poor drunk.
What can I say?
Well, you guys have fun.
I'm staying here.
[Sylvia] We're out of omelette.
What are we gonna do?
[Liz] I don't know.
Let me see that.
[Sylvia] Veggie dogs.
[Liz] Veggie dogs?
Will it go for that?
[Sylvia] Well, it ate
that fucking omelette.
[Steve] Don't insult
my omelette.
[Sylvia] I don't...
Um, Cap'n Crunch!
[Liz] Oh, no, that'll
scratch up its mouth.
[Sylvia] Oh.
-[laughs]
-[Liz] What?
-What are you laughing at?
-[Sylvia] Jackpot.
[Liz] What is that?
[Sylvia] I think it actually
came from the Ionics!
[both laughing]
Okay.
Let's go, let's go.
Do you have the collar?
[laughs] The collar?
-Give me the collar!
-Let's go.
[Liz] Go, go, go.
Here, you take this.
[both laughing]
[birds chirping]
[sighs]
Oh, God.
[groans]
[silverware clinking]
Sorry.
Did I wake you?
No, booze wore off.
Ditto.
You want help?
-Dry?
-Mm.
[birds chirping]
[speaks indistinctly]
-[glass shatters]
-Fuck!
Fuck.
Sylvia will love that.
Remember when
you lived with Iris?
[chuckles]
Yeah.
Yeah, and whenever she would
break something...
-Just leave a note...
-...she wouldn't pick it up.
-...that said "Broken glass."
-'Cause she was amazing.
Picking it up would have been
so much more difficult.
I know.
God, and whenever she would buy
toilet paper, she would, like...
Invoice you for, like, 33 cents.
Unbelievable.
[both sigh]
-[laughs]
-She was a magical woman.
Sometimes I wonder if she ever
really existed at all.
Are you suggesting
that Iris was
a figment of our imaginations?
Maybe she existed
on the astral plane.
You were tapping into some
pretty heavy shit back then.
[both chuckle]
I don't know, she had a right
to be mad at us.
You were always there.
Yeah, yeah.
She probably hated us.
Me.
Oh, well.
I do love Sylvia.
She's pretty awesome.
[chuckles softly]
Burning Man, huh?
-Ah!
-[laughs]
I wasn't gonna get off easy
on that one.
[laughs] No, seriously,
I want to know, like,
were you dancing around
a bonfire, like, hula-hooping
while juggling glow sticks
or...?
Ha, ha.
I'm curious!
What was Mad Max like in person?
You've been
seriously misinformed.
But there isa Thunderdome.
There is!
I read it on the Internet, man.
[loud rumbling]
[birds chirping]
[distant chatter, laughter]
[water splashing]
[indistinct chatter continues]
-They go into the water.
-Okay.
-You can take off any stems.
Because the stems
will puncture the skin,
and once the skin is punctured,
you can't sell it as a first
and you may not be able to
sell it as a second for sauce.
What is the difference,
first and second?
-Well, this,
because it's so small...
-Uh-huh.
...But also because it has
a bad spot, it's a second.
[Liz] Now, what about this here?
-[woman] That's a second.
-[Liz] Okay.
[woman] That's where it laid
against the ground,
and that's where it's gonna
start to rot first.
If the weather continues
to stay as cold as it is,
we won't have
many more tomatoes.
[Liz] Mm-hmm.
Oh, really?
[woman] They have to have sun
to ripen.
And they don't like
the cool nights.
And remember, the animals
like their fair share.
Mm.
[woman] So you have every
creature under the sun...
trying to eat their fill, also.
But yeah. And that's it.
That's what it's all about.
Cool.
And on a nice day like today,
when it's hot,
playing in the water is fun.
It is.
Thank you.