Welcome to
your worst nightmare.
You are about to make
the ultimate sacrifice;
The supreme test
of immortality;
A rope--
Now--
Now !
Look out !  Look out !
Uh-Oh.
Uh, the supreme sacrifice...
Cut !
Will take place--
Stop.  Time out.
I'd rather hang than listen
to this again, you know ? Come on.
I mean, this isn't a frat house.
It's a halfway house for morons.
The spooky costumes
and the phony hangings--
- Guys, gimme a break.
- Silence, pledge.
The emma dipsa phi
initiation has just begun.
Oh, i get it.You're trying to
bore us to dea--
- They're trying to bore usto death.
It's working. - Oh, yeah.
I asked you guys to be careful with my
clothes. Now, who wrinkled my shirt ?
-It wasn't me !
We've misjudged you two.You're obviously
not dipsa phi material.
No.  You know, i think it's keith
and i who seem to be mistaken here.
Am i right ?Oh, yeah.
Fooled completely.
We were under the impression
that this wasthehouse on campus !
But if you're the kind
of organization...
That'll take any dickhead who will jump
off a stool with a noose around his neck--
Guys !  Obviously,you don't see the
advantages of your position.
What advantages ?
You have something we want.
Plus, your accommodations, cable
television, accommodations.Cable !
Continental cuisine--
Food.
Instead of making us go through
these stupid, immature-
- What's the word i'm looking for ?
Asinine. Asinine tests-- Which
we find incredibly boring--
Wouldn't it be much more
to your advantage...
To take this situation...
And get something
for yourselves ?
Y-Yes !  You got a big party
tonight, right ?
And for this party,you're definitely
gonna need party--
Stuff.Booze.Tunes. Stuff.You're gonna
need booze, tunes, entertainment.
Booze is easy.
We provide it.
Anything at all. Anything you need,
and we're in.
- Anything ?
- Excuse us. One second. Come here.
Listen, a.J. I'm really excited about the
way this is going.
I'm a little concerned
with this "anything" part.
Couldn't you have said,
"a thing," or "something" ?
Keith, keith, keith !
Relax, will ya ? These guys are operating
on empty.
I'll take care of this.
Trust me.
A stripper.
And by tonight.
This is great. I can't wait to see you get
us out of this one.
After all these years,
you don't trust me ?
The truth ?
No, lie to me.
Yeah. I trust ya.
Yeah.  Yeah,
just one number.
That's it. I know you're a dancer,
professionally-Trained,
And i wa--
I was just thinking...
How interesting it would be
to do it with your clothes off.
You're doing well,
you know that ?
- Bear with me here.
-
Hey, sandy.
How are ya doin' ?
Yeah, this is a.J.
Oh, so you heard ?
It'll only take
five minutes.
Come on.
I'd do it for you.
Field trip.
- We'll hire ourselves a pro. - Great !
Call me when you get back.
How much money have you got ? A.J., they're
not worth it.
They ? I could care less about those wimps.
It's their frat house. What a place to
operate from !
Aw, come on. You're givin' me a headache.
We're 200 miles from civilization. We got
no money...
And no way to get there-- Tell me the dipsa
phi house is worth this aggravation.
I got 82 bucks.
Right.
Together, we total 168.
That and a little charm...
Should get us a stripper
and one deadly number.
Now all we need
are some wheels.
Duncan.
Duncan spriggs unleashes a monstrous drive,
right down the center of the fairway.
It's a beauty.  Once again,
an amazing performance...
-By-- - Hi there. You have a car, right ?
Uh, i have-- Listen, i'll pay for the
damages.
I shouldn't have parked there
anyway, i know that.
What car was it anyway ? No, no, you see ?
Weneed a car.
Yeah, we're taking a little trip, and we'd
like to work out a deal...
For some transportation.
Oh !
Hey, guys !  Guys, hey,
where are you goin' ?
Hey, i ordered some pizza !
I'm a vegetarian.
Hey, wait just a-- I'm buying ! Your
russian lit essay.
Oh, great.  Uh,
listen, uh--
Anytime you want to catch a movie, you just
give me a buzz, all right ?
Just give me a buzz !
Buzz this, huh ?
It'll be a pleasure
helping you guys out.
Can i call you "guys" ?
Great.
Aw, come on. Sit down.  Relax. Kick back,
dudes.
You know, i mostly get your basic dorks
hanging around here.
They seem to gravitate towards me. I don't
know why !
Yeah.  Yeah.
I'm surprised. I haven't seen you two up
here...
At dunc's place before.
This place is
usually swinging.
You ought to
pop up sometime.
Come on, fellas.  Eat.
Mangia', mangia'. Eat.
So.
Takin' a trip, huh ?
Need a rod, huh ?
You're in luck.
One left.
Now, normally i charge the average shmo--
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Charge ? Yeah, we were thinking something
more along the lines...
Of a favor,
to be returned.
Of course.
That's new.
I like that !
One hand washes the other, right ? Right !
Yeah !
Now, if there's anything-- If there
wassomething that we could do for you.
I already know.
Be my friends.
Take me with you.
Oh--
All right.  For a week. Take me with you
and be my friends for a week.
-
- All right !
Take me with you and just pretend to be my
friends for a week.
This is fantastic ! Hey, guys, i'm psyched.
Let's party.
Hey, where are we going ?
Ah, doesn't matter.
What counts is that
you're my buddies.
For a week.
????
?? You think i'm cute ??
?? A little bit shy ??
Uh-- ?? Doctor, doctor give me the news ??
?? I got a bad case
of lovin' you ??
?? No pills ??
?? Shake my fills ??
?? "Tallywhackers."  "G-Spot." Hey, guys !
"Boob-O-Rama !"
Hey, "strip search."
?? I got it bad ??
"Meat rack."  "Lido lounge !"
Let me have this.
Hey ! This is the one, right here. I can
feel it.
"The after dark club.
Hottest acts anywhere."
Guys, it sounds classy. Think we should
have called for reservations ?
I'm ready.
Weareready.
Twelve for a dollar-Fifty. Socks, six for a
dollar. Twelve for a dollar-Fifty.
Socks !
A.J.  Watch--
Whoa !
Guys !
Uh, you get the feeling
we're not in kansas anymore ?
Well, the guy says
it's just down the street.
But the ad says that the club won't open
until after dark.
Don't know what the hell
that means.
Well, it's dark. Yeah, but is it "after
dark" ?
No, but i definitely
think it's dark.
But it might have
just turned dark.
How are you supposed to know the exact
moment it's dark ? If we knew that,
We'd wait a few seconds, and it would be
"after dark," right ? So when's that ?
I don't know. But you know what i'm saying.
"After dark"
could mean morning.
Am i making sense ?
No.
Um, hurry it up.
It's closing time.
Okay.  Yo, dunc !
Hey, let's go !
I'm going
as fast as i can.
I just closed.
You just opened.
Again.
Coffees.
Six cups.
To go.
- Don't do that.
- Shh.
I'm not kidding.
Branch.  Snow !
A.J., help me.
Nope.
You see something funny ?
I think
this is serious.
A.J., i live,
you die.
I think i'm gonna let maven there cut one
of your balls off.
Uh, whoo-Ee.
Looks like it'll be...
Another hour or so
on these toilets.
These pipes are tough. So, if you 'scuse
me, i'll get back to work.
Yeah, i definitely think
it's after dark now.
Snow.
I'm a.J.
Come on.  All this over
three lousy teeth ?
Who spoke to you ?
Uh-Oh.
No-O !
-
-  Stop !
Drop the knife, snowflake, or you'll be
picking these up off the floor.
?? Volare ??
?? Oh-Oh, oh-Oh ??
Hey, duncan.
If you've finished with those toilet
seats-- ?? Cantare ??
?? Whoa-Ho, ho-Ho ??
?? Oh-Oh, oh-Oh, oh-Oh ??
Lucky they didn't try
the bathrooms.
I was ready. What i would have done to
them--
-
?? We can sing in the glow
of a star that i know of ??
?? Where lovers enjoy
peace of mind ??
?? Let us leave the confusion
and all disillusion behind ??
?? Yeah, yeah, yeah
all behind ????
Hey, messin' with my buddies, huh ?  Wham.
Right in thetzhatzhkehs.
Hey, one guy takes on
the three of us.
Hey !  Maybe we ought to wait and see if
you want to go another round !
How about that, bernie,
huh ?  What's--
Dunc, they ordered
six coffees.
Okay, so it's not
caesar's palace.
Let's get this
over with quick.
?? I'm in the mood
for love ??
?? Simply because
they're naked ??
Guys, i'm on a roll tonight.
And when that happens,
I attract women
like flies.
Even.
Shit.
?? Only because they're naked ?? I'll see
you in a few.
Uh-Huh. ?? I'm in the mood for love ??
Hey--  Wait a minute.
Wait a-- Wh-- Where--
I thought-- We gotta be gettin' back soon.
A.J.'S gonna take care
of everything, okay ?
Wait a minute.
This isn't fair !
We come out here, and i don't even get a
chance to watch ?
I should have a say
in the selection.
You can interview her
in the car.
Uh-Uh.  No way. One for all, and all
inside, i say.
Ta-Ta !
Duncan, don't do that.
Six coffees.
?? I'm in the mood
for love ??
?? Simply because they're naked ???? ????
????
How are ya doin',
boys ?
Could i see
your i.D. ?
Good.
Good enough !
Perfect.
Go ahead.
?? See him talkin' to a lady ??
Bar or table ?
Ringside.
????
Thank you. Sir.
?? You remember when he said ??
?? You're the only girl
i need ??
?? And now the words they sting
and the harm they bring ??
????
?? This just is like a knife
right in the back ??
Oi, vai.
?? Now that you were caught ??
?? In a jealous trap ??
?? These words are ringin'
right through the dark ??
?? Of your suspicious mind
and jealous heart ??
?? Lipstick on his collar ??
-?? Perfume in his hand ??
-   Hey, blondie.
?? And when he came home
last night ??
?? He was sneakin'
up the stairs ??
?? 'Cause he's the only boy ??
?? Your body wants to know ??
Hit 'em.
?? And is it worth the pain
to hide the shame ??
?? Or better to let her go ??
?? This just is like
a knife right in the back ??
?? Now that you are caught
in a jealous trap ??
Over here. ?? These words are ringin' right
through the dark ??
?? Of your suspicious mind
and jealous heart ??
?? These words are ringin'
right through the dark ??
?? Of your suspicious mind
and jealous heart ??
?? Whoa ??
????
You don't remember me,
do you ?
It has been a long time,
but i remember you.
I'm "amaretto"--
Not really--
And i will be your waitress for this
evening, guys.
So, what can
i get for ya, huh ?
I would like
a slow, comfortable screw.
A beer.
And one for my buddy...
For a week.
I know i gotta get it fixed.
It drives me crazy.
Drivesyoucrazy ?
You don't remember that ? I'm gonna
remember that for the rest of my life.
?? Ooh, ooh-Ooh ??
????
Good !
Builder of major erections,
our construction engineer,
Hard-Hatted hannah !
Come on.
Let's hear it.
You have any friends
that wanna rememberme?
Nah, i didn't think so.
Gentlemen.
I give you...
katrina.
????
?? Hey ??
?? Hey, hey ??
????
Wait till those wimps
at dipsa phi see this.
????
I loved it !
Yeah !
What was it ?
- Whatever it was, i love it ! - She--
She's ju--
Yes !
He scores !
I love the show, girls.
It's brilliant.
Very tastefully done.
Come on !
All right, gentlemen.
You're in for a treat.
She melts in your mouth,
she melts in your hands:
Sweet, sweet candi.
Hello ?
Katrina.
You scared me.
Uh, nice hair !
Yeah.  I, uh--
I caught your act out there.  Ooh ! Some
show.
Very... new.
Very...  now.
Uh--
Anyway, i was wonderin'
maybe later tonight,
If you're interested in doing a little
encore performance--
For a much more
appreciative audience.
I could definitely
make it worth your while.
Yes, i could.
And i'd be willing
to pay you top dollar.
'Cause i can see that
you're a professional.
And i like working
with professionals.
And i likeyou.
I can see
you like me too.
Whoa.
Wow.
Ooh.
Allow me.
Oh !
Oh.
Like to play rough, huh ?
-
I'll be back.
Anybody want to
claim this lush ?
I'm trying to run a respectable joint here,
gentlemen.
Going once.  Twice.
Keep him.
He's alone.
Clean this mess up.
Hey, it's show time.
What's happenin' here ?
I wanna see
a girl up there !
And now:
she's not much upstairs,
But what a staircase !
Gentlemen, the fabulous
dominique !
Come here.
Class.
Shit !
That's it.
We're out of here.
Oh, excuse me.
Could you go backstage...
And tell my friend that
his buddy is waiting ?
It's time to go now.
I see no friends.
Uh, yeah, yeah.
You took him backstage.
Uh, he's tall, dark-Haired. Gray jacket on.
I take no one back.
I--
Excuse me.
Aren't we fickle ?
Did you ever have
one of those nights ?
There's a problem.
He was not alone.
He has a friend. He's downstairs talking
with the new girl.
I think there's
another one of them.
That's it.  One number
to get into a frat.
Except now i don't care. All i wanna do is
find a.J. And get back--
A.J. ?  Not mr. Dynamite !
You guys still hangin' out ?
I knew it, yep. Come on.  I'll bet you
he'll remember me.
Hey, you see a guy
come back here ?
Welcome to bow-Wow city.
Hey, you guys see a guy come back here ?
Tall, good-Looking--
You see a guy come back here ?
No guy came back here.
No guy came back ? No, he came back.  One
of the girls brought him.
Her. You !  I remember now. So sorry.
Your friend wanted to see katrina.  I tell
him no one see katrina.
He didn't have much of a chance with her.
Katrina owns this dive, sweetheart.
After that-- Are you saying that you didn't
see what happened ?
Wait !
Where's candi ?
She's half-Shift tonight.
Mm-Hmm. I'm afraid a.J. Has decided to hold
auditions.
No, he wouldn't
just leave.
Not even with a girl who will melt in your
mouth and in your hands ?
Yeah, he'd leave. I'm gonna kick his-- But
wait !
W-What a coincidence.
It's time for my break,
And i have to go over by the hotel and pick
up a change of tops.
Some of the girls stay there. I bet if we
hurry, we can catch a.J.
I'll meet you at the side entrance in two
minutes, okay ?
Excuse you !
You wanna find a.J., right ? Right.
Well, then go !
She'll use you,
she'll abuse you.
She'll whip you guys
into shape.
Cimmarron !
?? And the meaning of love ??
?? And the meaning of love
and the meaning of love ??
????
-
Don't !
Aren't we jumpy tonight ?
This is really weird. It's like a reunion
or something.
Yeah, i wish
i knew with who.
When the time is right,
i promise i'll tell you.
He's on his way.
Don't screw up.
You got it ?
All right.
Okay, you're dying
to ask me.
What ?
Why i strip.
No, i wasn't. I wasn't going to ask you.
Yes, you are.
Why not ? It's none of my business.
It's nothing to be ashamed of, really. It's
natural curiosity.
The club's not a permanent stop, if that's
what you think.
I mean, it's easy to get, it's loose, i can
express myself--
And that is really important, because i'm
still trying to find my purpose in life.
Know what i mean ?
God knows i've looked.
Tried the acting thing for a while-- What a
trip.
I was onthe love connection.
I got picked !
Oh, god.
That's so sad.
Little girl,
where's your mommy ?
Parents like that
should be shot.
You screwed up.
You're sushi, baby.
He was so beautiful.
I was sure you would like him.
You knew the rules.
She knows the rules !
Only the transients,
the loners, the strays.
The ones that
can't be traced !
He said he was alone, that he was just
passing through.
He fit the profile.
Ha !
He was a gift.
Nice gift.
I'm gonna have to kill 'em both.  Don't
worry. I'll take care of it.
You're not gonna
punish her ?
If it were me--
Look, if i had some power--
All right !
All right.
If we had just moved the whole operation to
vegas, like i suggested--
Thank you. I am loyal to you forever.
- I will be more care--
-
Well, i...
Guess vegas is out.
Ex-Cuse me.
Twenty dollars
a half hour.
I'm from the club, remember ?
I checked in this afternoon ?
I'd like the key
to 1311, please.
Thank you !
Oh, could you please ring candi ?  You
know, the redhead ?
Ah.
It's busy.
But you can go up
if you like.
Room 1309.
????
Thirteen, please.
]
???? [ Continues humming
- Wait !
-
You're not the same woman.  You're sleepin'
all day, you're up all night.
I can do what i want !
????
Jeez.  Uhh !
Jesus christ.
Ah.  Fuck.  Jeez.
We should heard
something by now.
I don't like it.
If something goes wrong, that queen bitch
is gonna chewmyass out.
Vlad, give it up.
There's nothin' goin' on
between you and her anymore.
All you are to her
is a quick fix.
Hey, but
what do i know ?
-Hey ! - There you are. What happened ?
They told me you left. A.J. Did you find
him ?
No.  God, you look awful.
What happened to you ?
The girl.
What did she say ?
Well, it's weird. I went to her apartment.
It was like no one lived there.
Empty. Just some garment bags. What are you
so testy about ?
"Testy" ? You want to know why i'm testy ?
I'll tell you why i'm testy.
Today, i was nearly hung.
I got into a fight
with a psychotic albino.
I met a human pincushion
in the bathroom.
I ate a cockroach,
my best friend disappears,
And then i'm nearly assassinated by a
runaway elevator.
I've had a bad day.
All i want to do is find a.J. And get back
to school.
- Is that too much to ask ? - Well, no.
But i don't see what the big hurry is.
- He'll probably show up. - Listen.  Where
else would a girl like...
Candi take a.J. ?
Uh-Huh.  You mean a girl like me, don't you
?
Just go ahead and say it. I was only trying
to be helpful.
I thought it would be kind of nice if you
and me spent some time--
Oh, screw it.
If you knew me
a little better--
I don't know you at all ! And that's
another thing. How comeiremember you...
So well, and you--
Obviously our moment together wasn't as
important to you as it was to me.
What moment ?
Look--
Oh, look yourself !
????
I love you !
No, i loveyou !
Say, babe, what time
do you get off ?
2:30.
Can i watch ?
????
All right ! Anybody want to claim this lush
?
Going once.
Going twice.
We've been
lookin' for ya !
Hey, snowball.
How they hangin' ?
- Shit.
- Come on !
-Hey, what's that ?
- Nothing.
Hello, baby !
Gotcha now.
-
Come on, boy.  Don't you
want to join the party ?
Come on, boy !
Come on ! You better get used to it,
scumbag.
All this for
a fucking fraternity.
Psst !  Psst !
Psst.  Psst.
Well, now, where's
your mama, little girl ?
Fuck !
Jeez.
Uh, hey !
I found my friend.
Snow !
There he is !
Shit !
Hey !  Over here !
A.J. !
Hey !  Stop !
Help !
Wait !
Stop !
Wait a minute !
Come on. Emergency operator. May i help you
?
I'll take care of the cops.
I-I'll tell 'em a story,
like i always do.
They won't follow up.
They don't care...
What happens down here.
Have you given any more thought to my idea ?
A club.
In vegas.
New blood ?
"New blood" ?
See, they're all...
tourists.
I-I hear that clubs are very hot right now
in vegas.
We'll do very nicely.
All right, all right. I'll do something.
Vlad !
Bring the trash
back in here.
This is
a nasty habit.
Nasty.
???? Hey, bud. Where ya been ?
I've been making some progress. The police.
Did they get here yet ?
Jesus christ.
A.J.'S dead.
Stay here.
?? Baby, now, roll on
past my window ??
-
- It's occupied.
There's somebody in--
Wh-Wha--
Relax, will you ?
It was just a joke.
I thought you--
You asshole !
You scared the shit out of me, you know
that, huh ?
Relax, will you ?
Relax ?
You were dead.
You were in a dumpster.
I thought that snowflake
had killed you.
Hey, i was rolled.
Anyone could have
an off night.
Off night ?
We're out of here.
You.
There's some... uniformed gentlemen in the
back to see you.
Look, i-I found
my friend.
Yeah ?
But he--
Well, helookeddead
anyway.
He looks real dead to me. It was in the
garbage--
Your friend here apparently likes to flash
his money around.
In this neighborhood,
that makes him a meal ticket.
Hey, tell me about it. Iama meal ticket. I
should know.
Look, i just--
No, you look.
Now my stomach's all upset, thanks to you
and your dead friend here.
This is not a nice area, and i don't like
coming to it,
So before i lock you up, i want all three
of you out of here.
Go home. I've been trying to do that for
the past--
Now.
Officer, why don't i escort you out
personally ?
I know you like to catch
the last act, am i right ?
Hey, guys, if you don't mind,
i'm going to catch the last act.
Okay.  We'll see you out there in a few
minutes, buddy.
And i promise you'll never see us in this
neighborhood again, officer.
I'm pissed at you.
Mmm.  They treat you
real good here.
Looks like we can
forget about the fraternity.
Why don't we just
go back home, okay ?
What's the rush ? A.J., gimme a break, will
ya ?
Would you calm my friend down here, please ?
I've been telling him
for years to relax.
I'm fine, i'm fine. Let's just get out of
here. Please.
That's not fair.
Come on.
- Wait !
-
I didn't think
you had it in you.
Yeah.  Looks like you discovered the only
way out of here, pal.
What the hell you
talkin' about ?
The club, everyone here, man, they're
vampires.
Can't let you leave.
We got a problem here.
Yeah ?
Why don't we go home ?
We'll call a doctor
or something.
You don't get it, do you ?
Home is a million miles
away from me now.
Home's another planet.
I'm a fuckin' zombie now !
I mean, look at me.
Watch out, man !
You wanna know
how bad things are ?
I love you, keith,
But all i can see
right now is food,
And i'm starving.
You're carrying my next meal around with
you in your veins.
They got me.
They got me real good.
Okay, why don't you take
what you need for now ?
You know, to get you through.
That's too much.
And you're so nice.
Do i look like
a mosquito ?  No.
I can't be trusted,
buddy.
Will you look at my clothes ? They're
ruined.
Do i look real bad ? You know, it's just
like the movies.
You can't see yourself.
There's no reflection.
It's weird.
?? No pill's gonna
cure my ills ????
Jesus.  You're really
gonna do it, aren't you ?
You're gonna kill me.
A.J., do me a favor, huh ?
For old time's sake ?
Sure, buddy.  Anything.
Anything at all.
No.  Not anything.
Just one thing.
Make sure i don't
come back like you, okay ?
Hey, you think i like this ?
Or them ?
They're boring creeps.
They don't call 'em "walking dead" for
nothing !
Try talking to one of them
sometime.
I am.
Come on, man.
Just take me out.
Just kill me.
I can't go on like this.
A.J., i--
Come on !
Shit !
You can't, can you ?
Even though you know
it works, you can't !
It does work, you know. The fire, the
wooden stakes, the sunlight.
Got a list right here
somewhere.
You're ready to die
for me, aren't you ?
You would 'cause you can't believe that i'm
not me anymore,
That maybe there's
something left, huh ?
Jesus christ.
Maybe there is.
Nah.
Sorry, pal.
Now get lost fast.
Go on !
And remember, you can burn 'em or keep 'em
from their coffins past sunrise.
I think you know the other one.
???? Last call, gentlemen. Last call.
Hope you enjoyed
the show.
Don't forget our
single man's special:
All you can drink
for a dollar.
Come alone, you drink yourselves into
another world.
?? I know a lot about
the world outside ??
?? It's not too safe
so i usually hide ??
Hey !
We're leaving.
That's not fair. I only had to promise her
$50.
Now.  I'll explain later.
Guys !
Excuse me, there seems to be a little
problem with your bill.
When the place clears out, why don't you
and me go in the back...
And handle it personally ?
Hey, call the police ! These people,
they're all vampires !
Eat shit and bark at the moon. That doesn't
make 'em bad people.
Listen, a.J.'S dead. Again ?
Vampires !  Vampires.
You don't think you're gonna get away with
this, do you ?
Of course.  You know how many people
Disappear off the face of
the earth every year ?
Not thousands. Tens of thousands. You're a
statistic, kid.
Why us ? Why'd you pick on us ? It was a
mistake.
Okay ?  There was
a little error there.
A little communication
error.  I'm sorry.
We'll be missed. They're gonna come looking
for us. Who ?
Who'd you tell that
you were comin' here ?
Nobody tells anybody when they come to a
joint like this.
Quite a racket, huh ?
You see, i'm runnin'
a central service here.
Waste disposal.
Oh, yeah.
Look around.
Look who comes here:
The sickies, the degenerates, the forlorn,
the lost,
The lowlifes, the fuckin' dregs of humanity
wind up here,
And we take care of 'em.
It costs you nothing.
Yeah, just my best friend.
Hey, nobody's perfect,
okay ?
I do the best i can
with what i got.
Your self-Pity
makes me sick.
You know that ?
Listen, kid,
i used to own this club.
You know who worked here ?
Louis prima.  Buddy greco.
Phil harris.  Class.
Wait a second.
Where are you going ?
What are you trying to do,
get outta here ?
Why ?  There's
more of us out there.
Oh, yeah.
So where you goin' ?
Here, there.
We're everywhere.
Can i ask you somethin' ?
You ever been to vegas ?
Hey, how about you buying me and my friends
a last round ?
Kind of a last request,
like they do in vegas.
They do that in vegas ?
Whoa.  That's classy.
Now, that's classy.
Sure.
Uh, excuse me.
Would you give this gentleman whatever he
wants ?
Give me a brandy.
Make it three.
Make 'em doubles.
Triples.
Hell, leave the whole bottle
when you're done.
I'm not drivin' anywhere.
Spill these
all over the place.
Oops !  Oh, i'm sorry.
Excuse me.
Duncan, have a drink.
To vegas.  Oh !
-
Whoa !
Let me out of here !
Come on !
The trap door.
Okay, you win.
I'm gone.
What the hell
you doin' ?
The bitch owed me money.
This way.
?? Old black magic
has me in its spell ??
I would loved
to have seen vegas.
Once.
Just once.
????
Ah...
My first drink...
in 75 years.
Vlad,
To the good ol' days.
?? Aflame burnin' desire ?? ?? That only
your kiss ??
?? Put out the fire ????
-
- Shit.
Guys ?
How you doin'
back there, dunc ?
I'm hungry.
He's okay.
No.  I mean i'm starvin'.
Yeah, well, we'll order some pizza when we
get back to school,
If that's okay with y--
Guys !
W-W-Wait, wait.
Move.
Looks like we're not the first ones to be
midnight shopping.
It was already bent.
Find some bullets.
Will this help ?
You got ammo with that ? You mean bullets ?
No.
Hey, where'd you get that ?
Get back.
I'm good with this,
believe me.
Look.  No fangs.
Come on.
- Who are you ?
- I-I-I, um--
Your name.
Tell me your real name.
Um, i, uh-- This isn't exactly the time i
had in mind.
I thought maybe--
Did you actually think i could've been one
of those ? I-- I--
No.
This way.
Yeah !  We're saved ! Thank god for mass
transit. Come on.
Last stop.
I don't believe this shit !
Talk about timing.
Come on !
What gang is this ?
Wait.
Come on.  Help me.
Keith ?  It's time.
What ?
My name.
I'm allison. I'm allison hicks. Remember ?
Seaside heights, summer vacation, fifth
grade.
We were in
sue leonard's basement.
We were playing spin the bottle, and i spun
and it landed on moose,
And you kinda pushed the bottle and i
didn't have to kiss him.
I ended up kissing you.
Remember now ?
Yeah.  You have incredible timing. Thanks.
You sure it's safe
down here ?
Trust me.
This is an abandoned system.
Been here before.
What was that ?
Probably just a wino
or something.
In high heels ?
Come on.
Here.
I have matches here somewhere. Don't.
I smell something.
I think we should leave. This is not a very
good idea.
Allison, the matches.
You called me allison !
The matches !
Allison !
Keith !
Go !  Shoot her !
Shoot her, please.
Now.
Keith.
Let's go.
- Come on ! - There's something i gotta do
first.
Oh !  You're bleeding !
Oh, it's nothing.
Mmm.  Mm-Mm.
This could get infected. We'll have to have
this checked out.
Thanks.
Uh, hon ? Come up here a second. I wanna
show you something.
What ?
God !  That supposed
to be funny ?
No.
You kill my katrina.
You both must die !
Ugh !
Well, don't everybody
thank me all at once.
Wai-- Y-You--
Formica.
Go figure.
Hi, allison.
Relax.  I'll take care
of this somehow.
This... has been
one wacky night.
You're tellin' me ?
I'm gonna need
some new clothes here.
Wait.  Where you goin' ?
After all these years,
you don't trust me ?
I can handle this,
you know.
Look, there's always
night school.
Hi there.
Hi.
And jobs ?  I'll--
I'll take a graveyard shift.
Yeah.  That's what i'll do.
Keith ? Relax.  I'll take care of
everything.
Follow us.
I'm right below you, pal.
Hey, you guys
live in a barn or what ?