I play men. You see I have a moustache.
I play men but I also play women.
Taxi driver: Then you put a wig on?
Bridge: Yeah.
TD: How do you like it when you play men?
I like it a lot. It’s fun.
Driver: It is, right?
It’s fun because I’m not a man.
So it’s fun to put on that other gender.
Driver:   Did you ever think to be a man?
No, it’s more fun to be, to play than...
I don’t want to be a man. No.
Interviewer: When you play man
you play like husband role?
Like husband role?
I: Husband or boyfriend.
No. Actually, I don’t play
husbands really.
Sometimes maybe
when I play with a drag queen.
Some years ago
I set out on this journey
in search of women
who live in between
who also live the man within
whatever that means
be it for a night, be it for a lifetime.
The young King movement
in New York City
had just got on its feet.
Here I met Mo B. Dick and his friends.
Mo was co-initiator and moderator
of Club Casanova,
the first king meeting place.
Mo B. Dick: It was a variety,
a total mixture of people that went.
You didn’t know who’s who,
what sexuality anybody was.
Nobody cared.
Brothers and sisters,
I’m Reverend Jimmy Johnson
and I came here as a special messenger,
I came here as a special messenger
to tell you
to the people of New York city,
that the drag kingdom has come.
Hallelujah! Hallelujah!
Amen.
And on the 8th day the gods
realised there must be a third sex.
[With the participation of]
Oh drag kingdom come,
drag will be done.
Brothers and sisters,
I have many many people ask me:
"Reverend Jimmy Johnson,
what is a drag king? I wanna know."
I’m here to tell you,
brothers and sisters:
A drag king is a person
who wants gender euphoria.
A drag king is a person who has accepted
their female masculinity.
Amen.
Bridge: I mean I just come from Berlin,
and in Berlin,
actually the last few weeks
the weather has been
like almost Hawaii,
maybe St. Tropez
or something like that.
So I really have to cover up
so I don’t get a cold or something.
I already feel it coming.
[Written and directed by]
(German) I always had my eye
on pinstriped suits.
I had my first one at 17...
because I had seen David Bowie
wearing them.
And then I also wanted
to wear one.
I always wore
androgynous and crossgender
make-up.
And I have been collecting
pinstriped suits for several years.
Hey Garland, this is Bridge.
I told you about this drag king night
that we’re doing on Tuesday the 23rd.
You know, there’s going to be
so many great drag kings in one show.
I hope you come.
Talk to you soon. Bye.
Society is more aware of drag queens
than they are of drag kings.
No one even really knew
what a drag king was.
And so we really wanted to introduce
that to the New York scene
and we wanted people to see that
gender is really undefined.
It’s what you make of it.
It really helped us to sort of
get full circle come from drag queens
all the way around to drag kings.
(German) Biologically, I am a woman.
I don't want to change that,
but the point is...
that there are different
forms of femininity.
And mine is definitely very androgynous.
I can be feeling bad.
I can be feeling like a nothing.
(German) I can be feeling bad.
But then...
when I put on these trousers.
(German) When I put on these trousers.
Particularly from a pinstriped suit.
(German) Particularly from
a pinstriped suit.
And I put on a nice dress shirt.
(German) And I put on a nice dress shirt.
And I button it up slowly
up to the collar.
(German) And I button it up
slowly up to the collar
And I tie the tie.
(German) And I tie the tie
and I put on my jacket
Every time I put on the suit jacket,
I feel a little bit more powerful.
(German) I button my fly
Every time I button my fly
I touch myself a little bit
to kinda stay hard.
And I put on a moustache.
(German) And I draw a moustache.
And I think...
(German) and I think...
I am fucking hot.
(German) I am fucking hot.
(German) Alter ego is that part of me
that wants to scream out:
"Here I am,
the whole world belongs to me."
And I can conquer any man
or any woman I want to.
I also enjoy playing assholes,
because then one can
release these asshole qualities
which every one of us has.
Hey, dig me! I can punch you
in the nose and
you can't do a damn thing about it.
[music]
(German) Karl, for me,
is a very positive figure.
He's a cuddly old man.
He couldn't hurt anyone.
He's very sweet and also helpless.
I created him after.
my father and my oncle.
They were both bald-headed,
had a tonsure
and were fat, ageing men.
But Karl is good natured
compared to them. And nicer.
He would never harm anybody.
He's a truly kind man.
The kindest man I play.
[opera music]
(German) Ever since I've been bald,
I've noticed that female sexuality,
for many men, surely not
all of them, but many,
is strongly linked with hair,
and as soon as you shave
your hair off, they think
you deny your sexuality.
I feel it as a liberation.
[water running]
For women...
it's more natural for them
that I am bald.
But I prefer men.
I fancy women, but men turn me on more.
[music]
(German) I am a chameleon.
I am really Bridge.
(laughs)
You could say I am at home
on the bridge.
I live on the bridge.
Interestingly enough,
the bridge is moving.
So I also go to wherever it's going...
and then I'm back on the bridge.
Again, going wherever
the bridge takes me.
But even if you say drag king
some people don't know that.
They don’t know
what a drag king is.
When I say I teach
drag king workshops.
They ask: "What are
dry-cleaning workshops?"
Dry cleaning is so fabulous.
They don’t know any better.
I think the Gap and
Calvin Klein and television,
and everything that‘s around us
in advertising and sitcoms and movies
teaches us so much about
wanting to be like everybody else,
wanting to conform and to be
the popular girl or the cool guy in school.
I think what they don’t show is that
it's all the geeks and nerds,
the people that were rejected and
that felt like shit in school
who really try 200% more
to make something of themselves.
The final step.
Well, I’d like to stay, hang out with
the drag kings all night long,
but I’m off to LA to see Hugh Hefner
to be the first drag queen ever
pictured in Playboy magazine.
But I wanna tell all those
hot sexy studs tonight:
Good luck, drag kings,
you rock New York.
The hottest, the cutest, the finest boys
in this room tonight.
The Backdoor Boys.
Please give a round of applause
to Shelly Mars.
I’ve been doing drag
for a long time, 20 years.
It’s very erotic for me to be a guy.
My name is Damien Corson.
I’m an independent digital filmmaker.
He’s a young guy,
he’s into film and poetry
and it’s like very now,
the dotcom film digital guys.
Film.
I’m making a film.
I’m making an independent film.
I’m a filmmaker.
I’m writing a film.
I’m writing an independent film.
Read my script you idiots.
I think I started out
in a political way
but not consciously
"I’m being political".
Any artist that breaks boundaries
it’s a political thing.
It’s saying like why not?
Why can’t I do this?
This is actually one of the first times
I ever did him as Martin in this act.
People either were screaming,:
"Oh my god, this is fabulous, I love him",
or were like
"Get off the stage, booh",
basically throwing tomatoes at me.
I think some women
really have the biology
to be like totally female
and some don’t.
And it’s the ones that don’t
that are made to be like
"I’m supposed to be a girl"
that have the problems.
Same with guys.
Everyone is a little different
with what’s comfortable for them.
What we or our society
just doesn’t allow more than...
either you’re a blond nice girl
or you‘re a guy like that.
I mean there are
many degrees in between,
and that’s what we don’t allow
and that’s the problem.
Yeah you look good.
You look good babe.
Her name is Bridge Markland.
All the way from Berlin, darling.
There she is!
Oh, my god!
Ladies and gentlemen:
Bridge Markland.
(German) It makes me happy
to be on stage,
where everything just flows,
where I am at home,
within myself
and I can draw creatively
from my own energy.
[music]
Basically, when I deconstruct
this sex bomb, Angela,
she's called Angela,
and approach the audience,
androgynous, sexy,
self-confident, half-naked...
I choose my own sexual objects.
Sometimes, I have the urge
to shake people up,
to get very close to them and say:
"Here I am, and you can't avoid me.
And I stick my tongue out at you,
as if you were my father.
You can't escape.
Maybe you’re being filmed or watched.
You can't get away, you're here
and you have to look at me.
I really enjoyed her performance
because it was Weimar Germany,
kind of Bertold Brecht, kind of
feeling to it.
And I’m glad I got to do
the little tongue dance with her.
That was really fun.
(Knocking on the door)
Philly: Hello?
Hey it’s me.
Hi babe.
Come on in.
Are you coming down?
I identify with Brandon a lot,
because Brandon was stuck
in that small town insane mentality
and that’s really really scary.
Brandon Teena,
born as Teena Brandon
was killed in Nebraska, 1993,
for living as a man.
Well I went back down
to South Jersey where I lived
and when I was like 16
I went to my brother’s wedding
and I got beat up by 7 guys
on the board walk in New Jersey.
They started beating up
my friend calling him a faggot
and I jumped in and
I was pulling people off him
and they started like punching me,
I got punched in the face.
The cops weren’t doing anything either,
and this Italian woman
from behind the sausage stand
jumped out and just ran over
and grabbed me
and ran me off the board walk.
but it was like an angry mob mentality.
It was really scary.
I’ve always been gay and I’ve always been
butch or transgender even,
you know what I mean.
Growing up I identified as a little boy.
I liked girls but
I was really happy that...
I didn’t want a dick,
you know what I mean.
And I remember my brother
teasing me saying:
"Oh, we’re gonna send you to Denmark".
when I was little because
I was such a boy.
They don’t want women looking like men.
That’s the crossover.
Because I think it makes them feel
that they might be queer
if they like a butch version.
I would say that my male
is all drag queen
and my female is all amazon.
You know it’s an everyday thing for me.
When I take this off
I don’t assume a different role.
It’s very hard to find anyone here
who will identify with the term butch.
Whereas in London, a lot of people
would say that one of the reasons
they are interested in dressing up
in drag is because they are butch,
and they love... this is just part
of what they love to do.
What is then butch exactly for you?
- What is it?
- Yeah, for you.
Butch is masculinity
as an identity in women.
I’m not butch or femme.
I’m just whatever I’m feeling.
I can be one way one day
and another way the other.
I can’t put myself in a category.
So you would sleep with a woman
in drag and you do drag.
I would sleep in drag with a woman.
Well you’re just very versatile.
But for me it's not whatever I’m feeling.
For you it’s different.
I would never wear a dress.
I only go out with feminine women.
I consider myself butch,
I can’t change it.
I admire that you can do that, Dréd.
But for me I can’t.
I can’t switch today and tomorrow
I’ll be something different.
You gotta be yourself.
And it’s this very strict thing.
[rap music]
I was inspired by seeing
a bunch of drag kings.
I thought it was very empowering.
And it made me wanna do the drag.
I was like, I wanna give this a try.
The transformation
was definitely amazing.
And surprising.
I was like wow,
I look like a man.
A good looking one too.
I feel so natural that one time
I said that in my past life...
I definitely felt like
I’ve lived as a man before.
I’ve lived it in previous life times.
I believe in all that stuff.
I definitely feel like
I was a ladies man, definitely.
I’m not sure exactly how it was.
But, you know, sometimes
having all the women
and all that stuff
in line waiting, but it’s...
I’m not really like that.
Not in this lifetime anyway,
I’m not like that.
When I was growing up
I was very, very feminine.
I had big hair and red red lipstick
and all that stuff.
A lot of people think that
Dréd have all the women
every night a woman and all that,
but it’s not even like that.
I’m very shy and Dréd is shy too.
But Dréd is very respectful I feel,
like I perform and
the ladies are all screaming,
sometimes they throw
heir bras at me and stuff.
But that’s as far as it goes
pretty much at the shows.
This one is real.
Time to get dressed.
I love shoes.
Like the drag queens oh my god,
you see the shoes that Luscious wears?
Oh they are so sexy
and I like the pretty toes and
the nail polish and the long heels...
It turns me on.
It’s very exciting and sexual for me.
Ladies and gentlemen, it’s a pleasure
to bring out an old time friend.
Ladies and gentlemen: Dréd and Luscious!
[music]
I feel everybody has a male,
a masculine and feminine side.
But not everybody chooses
to explore the other side.
Stay just like that.
We met on Christopher Street,
which is in the west village in NY
where a lot of gay people
are up in the area, specially men.
I was walking and in front of me
there was this beautiful ass
Beautiful butt hanging out of
these really tight white shorts.
So she’s like "Excuse me".
I was like "Yes?". I had my moustache
so I didn’t want her to see my face.
So she’s like: "Excuse me",
I say: "Yes?"
She said: "Oh, how you doing?"
You know, cause she sees that I’m a man.
Looking still good.
Still... she played herself.
No I didn't play myself,
I still liked how he looked.
You know how the queens are,
you know what I'm saying.
She still spoke to me but then again...
... still I wanted the digits.
She still didn't want me to know
that she knows I am man.
Real honey, real.
Jiggle baby jiggle.
Well, she’s so nasty.
But doesn’t it look real?
Yes, I like it.
Gay mean happy.
As long as you don't bother nobody.
Do what you want.
You wanna go to town now....
Well, got the pussy boots on.
The kings are coming along.
Dréd she’s the powerful one.
She keeps me on my feet, you know.
Oh we’re good good friends,
really good friends.
She thought she could be my girlfriend,
unfortunately I was a man,
I definitely wanna be a household name.
Dréd or Mildred.
But it’d be nice to be more well known.
But it’s a step by step process
and I'm working on it.
So it doesn’t happen over night.
When I was going to the gym before work,
I would get up at 5:30 or 6,
go to the gym, tak a shower, go to work,
go to class after long very long days,
and this drag thing, in the beginning,
I was always performing like
3, 4 times a week,
just to get my name out there.
I have a full-time job
working on computers,
doing data processing and
creating computerized questionnaires
for a research institute in Manhattan.
My dream one day is to just
make a living of my creativity.
She’s always been the same person.
I think that’s what’s so great about her.
It’s like Dréd and Mildred
are two different people
because when  you’re watching her perform
she’s like uninhibited,
she entertains you, she’s great.
But when you’re just with Mildred
she's a very shy person, very sweet,
soft spoken and everything.
So it’s like she’s two different people.
I don’t think she’s changed at all.
It’s definitely helped me
to be more expressive.
Dréd has helped me to open
another sides of myself
that I didn’t know I had.
It has also helped me to feel that
it’s okay to try new things,
to be different.
It’s so different from
when I was growing up.
I was very shy, I was teased a lot
and I was very sad.
I believed people said
you're ugly and all that stuff,
little kids could be so cruel.
And I believed them,
I didn't know how to deal with it.
I didn’t tell anybody.
I kept very quiet,
I didn’t really have any friends.
And so now it’s kind of totally opposite
I feel I've bloomed and
I can look at myself and say
yes you’re beautiful,
you’re strong
and you gotta do your thing.
And it’s hard sometimes,
it takes time to heal
from those wounds.
I feel I have my angels,
my guarding angels,
I am not really alone.
This is like my family portion
of this whole wall.
Because I have my family I’m born with
and I have my drag family,
so I mixed the pictures together.
And that’s me.
I’m so short compared
to all the queens.
They’re like towering over me.
I have a lot of friends,
my family is very lovable...
and supportive.
That’s me as a little girl.
I think I was in junior high school then.
That’s me and my mummy again.
I love my mummy.
I would like to have a relationship
and a serious one.
I hope one day to have one,
but that takes time.
[door bell]
[knocking]
Hi there!
How are you doing?
- Good, and you?
- I'm good. Come on.
- Did you bring that book?
- Yes, I did.
All right, come on.
I was walking down a block
and you said good evening
and first I wasn’t sure.
I didn’t say good evening, I said:
"Good evening".
Well, I’m sorry I didn’t get
your fabulous voice and all.
It’s different.
Good evening.
[laughter]
I turned back and saw you
and said "Is that a man or a woman?"
Because if I thought it was a man,
I would be like "please".
[laughter]
No offense to men and all that.
We dated for a little bit,
but we’re definitely better as friends.
Sisters.
We’re family.
You meet your family and
sometimes you’re confused at first,
you think it's your lover,
but it’s your cousin
or in Mildred's case,
she's my granny.
And you’re my grandson.
Now that we know who each other is
we get on much better.
When we were trying to date
we fought a lot.
Oh god, I don’t even know
how stupid was.
You was trying to be the man.
Oh no, you know that’s not true.
You'd better take that back.
So you have [incomprehensible]
[chatting]
Let's see.
And you got here.
On the side it looks kind of cute.
I have a large head
and a lot of hair.
You're just wrong.
Need any assistance?
Let me see here.
Let me go back.
I’m right here, granny.
right here for you.
I’ll fix that tag.
Come here, come here.
Let me come out.
I feel in some way it’s different...
for black or white kings,
because  a lot I know don’t like
to show their womanhood.
They stay in male drag
during the whole show
and I like to mix it up.
I like to do a little stripping
and I show cleavage and stuff.
You know Dréd’s not here.
Dréd would be feeling it more,
because I got the make up on
and all that stuff.
Bring out your inner Dréd.
[music]
Storme: This is one of
my favourite songs in the world.
In some ways most of us
we all kind of make fun of
the characters we’re doing
but also I‘m paying tribute
to the music, our music.
It’s music I always loved
growing up and listening to.
A lot of this seventies stuff,
Isaac Hayes, and...
the Commodores or...
I’ve even done Little Richard before.
Isaac Hayes, he’s the man,
he’s the legend.
A friend of a friend of mine
gave me a poster
cause he said we look alike
And when I met him
I had some of my breasts showing
and he didn’t know
what was going on.
The first time Dréd was,
I was trying to catch a cab,
it was night time...
and just waiting for a cab,
it took like a good hour
before I caught the cab.
They would slow down
and then run off.
This white woman
comes in front of me
and is trying to catch a cab,
I’m like "You don't see
I’m trying to catch a cab".
She’s like "Oh I’m sorry man".
And then she walked away.
But it’s just very frustrating.
So that felt really bad when I realised...
the stereotypes they have
in their heads of black men.
Like they won’t pay, they’ll rob them
or something alike
which is really stupid.
Sometimes it’s really hard
for me, for Dréd
to catch a cab
and even as a woman
I experience that too at times.
You do have to be ready
to carry something
when you decide to define yourself.
When you decide to be different than
what the mainstream society
says is normal.
You may have to fight.
I think we’re very much
in the tradition too
because in African societies
and in Native American societies
there were always crossdressers,
and there were always people
who played both roles,
both gender roles.
A lot of times...
they were the spiritual people,
the medicine people, the healers.
And somehow I think by demonstrating
this comfortableness within ourselves
with both aspects of our gender identity,
that’s something healing
for people in general to see.
(singing poem)
I’m a stranger here, Lord,
I‘m a stranger everywhere.
I think I just realised
this year that I’m transgender.
[background singing]
Without intending to
I find that I live my life
as a passing woman
and that I’m very often perceived
as a man.
Very often.
And it’s interesting.
I’m not flat chested.
This is only natural.
When I was in my twenties,
there was maybe one.
I’m 40 now.
And it’s just growing, I don’t know.
I think it’s interesting
because it’s different.
That's why I like it.
Because you don’t think
a woman should have it.
Before they didn’t think
we should have trousers,
before they didn't think
we should drive cars.
They didn't think so.
I think that the world is changing.
That’s me and my mum.
This believe it or not is my father.
There’s my father
after he joined the navy.
(poem) A slash of brilliant
tropical color
I was very fortunate to grow up
in a queer environment.
My mother is a lesbian,
my father was bisexual.
So I remember when I was a child
and I saw a man and woman
kissing in a movie
it seemed so strange
and unnatural for me.
Because what I knew was lesbians
and gay men, relating with each other.
I think that it was challenging,
but I do think that it was a blessing.
Because I came into the earth
on so many margins,
because already my mother’s family
is Alaskan Indian and European,
my father’s family
is African and Choctaw.
So there was already such difference
within my mother’s family,
I’m the only black child.
My mother’s a lesbian,
we were quite poor.
I’ve always been on the margins...
of race, of gender,
of sex, of class,
I think it gave me a lot of strength.
Because I had to become aware
of how to move in each world.
While at the same time realising
I didn’t really belong into any of them.
My father died of...
carbon monoxide poisoning
He was in a car and he was cold,
he turned on the engine to be warm
and he fell asleep.
And he never woke.
He was 45.
(poem) I understand some things.
Like how life hurts sometimes
every moment
and how wearisome it gets always
trying to numb ragged feelings.
I don’t know any of his dreams.
I know that he ached inside sometimes
and sometimes he sent
that anguish outward
just like a real man.
I know everybody wanted him
that green eyed sexy smile somebody.
I know that filled a lot of hours
but in the end made nothing better.
(singing) If you ever...
change your mind...
about leaving me behind...
bring it to me
bring your sweet loving...
bring it all home to me.
Hey, sailor.
There he is once again,
ladies and gentleman:
Storme Webber!
[singing]
... like a chain, like a chain...
I’m always intrigued in any form of art
with the concept of negative space,
the concept of what is around a thing
which defines that thing.
So with masculinity it’s the same.
It’s what’s around it.
It’s always the dichotomy.
Moving forward and holding back,
being strong and being vulnerable.
And this is what is interesting,
What makes any performance good is...
passion.
(singing) ...like a train...
Masculine, I don’t know
what masculine means.
That’s the thing.
Yes, what does masculine mean?
What is femenine?
One of my dolls she's matching me today,
we're wearing green today.
This beautiful feminine doll.
A spiritual thing of my people,
gave her a little bell.
It’s hard. I can’t really define what’s
a man and what’s a woman,
who's a man and who’s a woman.
And I don’t wanna define it.
I think it’s great to just express it
and be what you wanna be
and be seen how you wanna be seen.
God have mercy
if I ran into my mum right now.
I share you with nobody.
First of all, what do you think
makes a good man?
When somebody is just there for you.
One is gonna hold you
through the thick and the thin.
Someone who is on your side.
It doesn’t matter for sake.
Somebody is gonna be there for you.
Accept you for who you are,
no matter what.
Would you think I was a man or a woman
if you saw me walking down the street?
I definitely think you’re a man.
Definitely, definitely.
That’s what I look like.
[incomprehensible]
First she has to become a lady.
And present herself right
to other people.
A lot of things make a good woman.
What does make a good man?
- Treating a woman right.
- All right.
If he treats a woman right
he’s a good man.
And if he believes in God, too.
We were just talking about that.
God comes first is the only judge.
What makes a good woman
and a good man?
The thing for me is not what’s defining that
but what’s defining
the shifts of mind involved in that.
So whether you‘re defining yourself
sexually as female or not,
it’s what happens with expectations
in people’s minds.
Once I knew you're a woman...
[music]
[song] Are you a boy or a girl?
The moto that I always have said is:
Instead of being an angry woman
I became a funny man.
A drag king is camp.
There’s a whole camp aesthetic.
So there’s parody.
Mo B. Dick as John Sex
and his beautiful sidekick Bob.
[music]
Camp is hard to define.
But generally, it has
a kind of kitschy element to it,
and also a certain amount
of foolishness.
Camp is a way to subvert sorrow also.
Diane Torr begat...
Buster Hyman...
Pretty much, yeah.
...and Johnny Science.
I first heard of the drag king workshop
when I was in Boston.
And I did the workshop
and it changed my life.
I got so high off it.
On the trail with Diane Torr
from Zurich
to Hamburg
to New York, 1997.
I enjoy the experience of being a man.
People would step aside
when I walk down the street.
It felt different.
Very different.
I could at last get my share of the seat
on the subway.
Even learned to pee in a urinal.
I have these three separate identities:
wife, mother and man.
But my husband and children
couldn’t embrace my fantasies,
and so I had to leave.
I was interested in exploring
what it would be like to live as a man.
And find another territory for myself.
There are times when I go out
as Danny King or Jack Sprat
or Charles Beresford,
who’s my gay man,
and I really get a vacation
from Diane.
You have a lot more
credibility as a man...
in the world.
It’s just the way it is.
You walk into the room as a man
and people immediately
pay you attention.
You walk into a room as a woman
and they check you out if you’re sexy.
That’s the first thing.
Men and women,
and if you’re a certain age,
once you’re over 40 or 35, forget it.
Unless you’re particularly
elegant looking woman
and then people could be curious.
Mum.
What? What?
[music]
That could work.
Oh my god, I used to
gogo dance to this song.
[city noises]
I came to this Aikido Dojo in 1977.
I have a third degree black belt.
Aikido has been a way for me to think
about an ungendered situation.
It’s really about energy,
redirecting that negative energy
into a place where
it’s not causing you any  harm.
Thank you.
A lot of Aikido is about
being able to extend,
not to withdraw.
Once you withdraw it’s over.
You have no more power.
So when I walk,
I have a sense of ownership,
a sense of belonging.
So that with each foot that I take,
you have a sense that
I could own that piece of floor,
for the minute that
my foot rests there.
I have this 360 degree boundary
around myself.
Something that I learned in Aikido
that you need to stand
very solidly on the ground,
on the earth.
Tony, Eric and Larry,
let’s see you occupy the space
let’s see how you can own...
the floor.
You’re a bit of a loss aren’t you?
- As a human being.
- Yeah.
I'm just very like...
It’s all right Larry,
you can hide behind that hair.
You have to remember that
boys grew up in playgrounds
where they always had
to defend themselves.
So you need to develop more armour
actually in your physicality.
How would this guy protect himself?
Every 3 minutes a woman
is being abused in America,
something like that.
If you think about that,
that’s astronomic.
As a woman I’m really communicating
and my gaze is on the edge,
is on the surface of my eyeball.
I’m like looking out into the world
with a lot of curiosity
and a desire to communicate.
As a man, as this man,
I’m a lot more reserved.
I expect the world to come to me.
So I’m much more withdrawn.
- You've got some hair.
- Mhm.
So do you have an idea of
who this man could be?
Do you think an Argentinean man
for instance?
Cause you’re Argentinean.
Do you think they’re very different
from American men?
The way that they behave,
their gestures?
Yeah, it will make a difference.
Men in Argentina I think
they have a lot of style.
They pay attention to
the way they look a lot.
[tango music]
(Spanish) Se cabreó el varoncito.
[tango music continues]
There are many ways to construct a penis.
When you fill it up with cotton wool,
then you have your penis.
That’s one way you can do it.
You can imagine the rest.
This is another method
that you can use.
I don’t work with dildos necessarily.
We just use this sausage,
that’s kinda like the fake penis
and it’s really just for packing,
for you to have
this kind of lump in your pants.
This is something that you can use
and when you use it you say
"I’m packing".
- It’s cold I know.
- It's clammy.
It’s clammy but it’s got
a nice sticky quality to it.
It looks good. Do that again.
It’s stuck to my pants.
It wants you...
The penis wants you.
It stretches.
The arousing reconstructions.
That was the first time I was in drag.
We also developed
this androgynous movement vocabulary.
It was 1981,
and nobody was really investigating
these ideas in performance.
This is me as
the Jean Paul Belmondo character.
Now she only almost exclusively
does male characters.
She got a bit more fanatic and hooked into it.
It fits her change in the physique
that she had over the years.
She used to be a little boy
and now she looks like...
a stubby man.
I lived in Amsterdam for a couple of years
and that’s where I met
the father of Martina, my daughter.
This is during the birth,
where I screamed at Marcel:
"You did this! I hate you!
You did this!"
I was so angry.
You have all this extra emotion.
I asked her.
I thought she could never get pregnant.
When she told me three weeks later,
she was surprised
and I was surprised she was.
It was a bit confusing because
I didn’t know her at all.
So it wasn’t really very planned.
Sorry Tinkiu.
Martina was totally demanding.
It was very easy to be involved with her.
It creates beautiful children,
if you’re involved throughout.
He’s been very, very supportive.
He’s a very special, wonderful man
and I know that
I will know him all my life.
We’re parents to Martina.
But in terms of our relationship...
we’ve reached an impasse.
I went to Manchester in 1996
and I taught a workshop there
and that’s where I met Jane.
And Jane became my lover.
I was having this relationship
with her in Europe
and having this other kind of
relationship here,
which is as a mother to Martina,
and living along side Marcel.
Eventually, these things
are very hard to sustain
and Jane decided that
she couldn’t deal with this anymore.
And I feel heart broken.
Each of the characters
I create are composites.
They’re not just one person.
Like Danny King is a composite of...
a number of ghastly men
I’ve seen and known from a young age.
I grew up in Aberdeen in Scotland
and I had these uncles
who were towering above you
and you’re so impressed by them.
They jingle change in their pockets.
And you think:
"Oh my god they’re rich".
But of course it’s just coins.
But you’re 5 or 6 years old
and you’re so impressed
by all this malebehaviour.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Welcome to the American society of men.
I am here tonight to train you
how to gain and retain respect...
as a man.
I’m much more controlled.
My shoulders become more rounded
and so the breathing is deeper.
Rule number 2:
Stop smiling!
It’s very nice when women smile,
it’s very appealing,
very unthreatening.
Makes them very friendly.
But when a man smiles
that could be conceived
as a conceding ground.
Allowing you a possibility to be exploited.
Rule number 3:
Stop apologizing!
Cause as a man in a man’s world
you are right.
And even if you’re not.
Who goes around saying
"I’m sorry!" all the time?
As women it’s like we’re open
for access 24 hours a day.
People have to like us.
That’s like the ruling thing in our psyches.
What does it mean to be a woman?
What kind of a woman am I?
I want you...
to like me.
to hold me.
I want you...
to fulfil my dreams.
[sound of kisses]
I want...
to be part...
of you.
I created this character
who starts off being someone
who pleases everybody
but then have her transform.
I don’t particularly like Danny King.
It’s more dealing with a reality
of how most men are.
It is a kind of a parody
but people have told me
that he’s real.
And I know he is, unfortunately.
What I’m saying is
that if I can do this,
from this female who’s like
the woman who lives next door,
and I can become this man
who’s Mr Macho,
then anybody can do it.
And if that’s the case then
so much for masculinity
being sacred.
We can have a penis
any time we want,
any size and any shape or form.
I actually think that it’s men
who have penis envy of other men.
A particular favourite
of the housewives,
the women who stay at home
and all they have for company
is their dishwasher,
their vacuum cleaner
and I call this one vacuum gigantum.
You can think of them as props,
not necessarily as phalluses.
I don’t think there’s anything wrong
with something looking like
a phallus anyway.
Because who is the person
who’s handling it.
You don’t need to have
a man attached to it.
It’s just there, it’s available,
why not use it.
And you wanna maintain
the impregnability at all costs.
Keep your movements...
minimal,
guarded,
repetitive.
I would always use my father
as an image of like
my male in my life.
And he is so gentle and kind
and he’s really sweet.
He’s so different from Danny King.
I’d always say to her:
"Mum, you’re totally stereotyping.
I don’t want the whole world to think
that you think
this is the only type of guy
or this is the real kind of guy".
A pleasure,
My name is Jack Sprat.
It’s really great
to see you all here tonight
to come see me perform.
I know it’s a lot of other people
but it’s really nice
you can see me perform.
[music and singing]
I know I’m somebody
who has been doing this a long time.
So obviously I have
a certain amount of authority.
I know they think of me
as a daddy drag king.
[harmonica playing]
It’s much easier to be a powerful woman
behind the mask of a man.
And it's much more socially acceptable
to express anger
when you’re a man,
and the aggressive behaviour
as a man.
As a woman people go:
"Ah bitch!
What’s the matter with you?"
That’s exactly true because
I was always punished in a female form
because I was too aggressive.
Now I have permission.
People just see me.
I don’t perceive myself as a man,
nor as a woman for that matter
but people perceive me as a man.
I can be invisible as a man,
whereas for some reason
as a female I never was.
No, it really is
a subliminal absence of hostility.
Men relate to me as a man
and they are not guarding themselves.
Men look after men,
I’m telling you.
See how that works.
You want me to look
right into the lens?
Yeah. Let's rehearse that.
Give me that look.
Yeah that’s it.
There was so much
great discussion last night.
I felt like I wanted to talk more.
Should I try the other side?
What happened was,
I was doing drag so much
like 4 and 5 times a night.
And people always were:
oh Mo. B. Dick, Mo. B. Dick.
And then Mo Fisher’s getting lost.
I felt my inner man
overtook my inner woman.
As a result I lost sight of my female self.
(singing) Are you a boy or a girl?
What I did was, it’s difficult to explain,
but so it’s like I said:
that is my male side,
now what’s my female side?
I became confused and I said:
"Wait a minute.
I am a very aggressive woman
and I will remain an aggressive woman."
What is interesting is that they say,
spiritually your left side
is your female side
and your right side
is your male side.
And I’m reversed in the outfit.
[jiggling]
That's it. I have to change film.
That’s interesting because...
it was my left side
that overdeveloped
as female in the chest
and my right breast
didn’t develop at all.
These are photographs of Mo
that I took in New York.
When Mo was wearing the fabulous
half man, half woman costume.
[water dripping]
I think gender is performance
and I think gender is
more than performance.
I think that people
subconsciously perform
whatever gender role
they’ve been assigned,
but people might subvert that.
Generally people conform,
generally men don’t go around
wearing make up and dresses
and generally women
don’t go around...
scratching their balls.
We don’t as individuals
reinvent the meaning of gender.
Each person individually,
one person at a time.
We come into genders
that have already been
constructed for us.
within political, economic,
social, cultural contexts.
So what we do when we’re in a gender
is perform an already socially
constructed script.
A medically accepted clitoris
is between 0 and 1 cm,
and a medically acceptable penis
has to be between 2,5 and 4,5 cm.
If you fall in between
the 1 and the 2,5,
they usually cut it off
because they deem
it would be very very bad for a man
to have a penis that was too small
or for a woman to have
a clitoris that was too large.
So generally they just whack it off
and give no thought
to the sexual pleasure of the child
when they become an adult.
They still do that?
Yeah, they still do that.
In my everyday life
I’m probably perceived as a man.
It's fine for people
to perceive me as a man.
Photo exhibition for
The Drag King book premiere
by Del LaGrace Volcano
That doesn’t mean
that’s how I perceive myself.
I perceive myself
in the same way that I always have,
which is something that is
a combination of both.
Sometimes maybe
more female than male,
sometimes maybe
more male than female.
I know five men personally
that also have vaginas,
I know lots of men
that also have breasts.
And I know lots of women
who have beards.
Accompanying
Del LaGrace
to a Drag King performance
in Cologne, 1997.
Being a drag king for me
was a way to begin this journey.
But it isn’t necessarily.
It’s not like you go:
I’m gonna be a cross-dresser,
then I become a drag king
then I become a transsexual.
No. No. No.
That’s what people are afraid of
and for maybe some of us, yes.
Meine Damen-Herren,
Herren-Damen.
Ich bin Herr Doctor Delman.
Now most of you here are
what I call monogendered,
some are bigendered,
and some are omnigendered.
Myself I’m transgendered.
This is me with my family.
Can you show
a little bit of your stomach?
When I was born I was assigned
to the female gender.
My first conscious realisation
that I didn’t quite fit as a girl
came when I was about 5 years old.
I never behaved appropriate
for a female.
But I really didn’t see myself
as anything other than
a girl until puberty.
I always thought I was ugly.
This was...
This one here
was me right before
I had my hair cut.
I guess I was about 22 there.
I have a silicon implant
that I never wanted.
I too always wanted a flat chest.
Being female is what I construct.
Naturally if you have a default,
my default is masculine.
Being a drag king, once
I was  performing as a man
that did not feel as a performance,
that just felt pretty natural.
It wasn't as much fun
and it still isn't.
I still far prefer to be
a drag queen than a drag king.
Right now I'm in the process of trying
to get my gender amended
on my American passport
to ‘O’ designation.
They have male, female and
since the beginning of this year
in the software
you can be ‘O’ for other
or it could change
to ‘I’ for intersex.
Right now on my passport it says female.
I had to pluck my beard out
every morning
from late teenagehood.
And it was so cute,
the natural one was just
these two little horns
coming out of the side of the chin.
And some moustache as well.
Basically she told me:
"If you don't stop plucking
your eyebrows,
I don't think I'm gonna be able
to go out with you.
I couldn't stand it.
It was like such a relief.
I didn't have to pluck my eyebrows,
I didn't have to wear
make up or skirts.
I didn't have to perform
as a female anymore.
I came to get my prescription.
I do testosterone injections.
It's a deep muscle injection.
-... for the other two.
- Tomorrow.
Give it to me, give it to me.
Your voice lowers,
your period stops,
fat redistribution,
clitoral enlargement.
They say those are irreversible.
We don't know what
the long-term consequences are
of a female born person
taking male hormones
over a long period of time.
You have to bear in mind that
there could be health risks
that you're not aware of
or that haven't been recognized yet.
Finding Simo for me was
so amazing
because she was the first woman
I had been with
who had a really positive,
healthy attitude towards men.
She wasn't anti men at all
and we were both attracted to
the masculinity of each other.
We've been together and not together
for about 6 years.
I said: "Would you like to
come home with me tonight
or would you like to wait
for a proper date?"
And I was very impressed by that.
I've never been asked that way before.
It has always been:
"Would you like to come home
with me tonight?"
or something like that.
Never giving me a choice like that.
I was so impressed that...
You said: "Can I think about it?".
I did say:
"I have to think about it first".
I think our relationship
is really a lot in some ways
like some successful
gay male relationship.
They're together,
they're devoted.
Yet they know that after a while
the sex with only one person
gets boring.
And I'm not threatened by Simo
going and having sex
with other people.
I totally understand that.
I would like to have still
a more masculine body.
I'm waiting for a chest operation
and I think that once I have that
I'll feel much better in my body.
I feel that I'm less aggressive now
than I was before
I started using testosterone,
because I no longer have
to be as aggressive
to get what I want.
Because people perceive me as a man,
they're more likely to give me
what I want without a fight.
It was only when people
started seeing me as a guy
that I realized how much
of a man's world it really is.
Because, I am treated
with more respect.
It's amazing how friends of mine,
who I'm sure are not aware of it,
but that have known me before
and know me now,
just because it's like
women are trained
and totally socialised
to look after men.
And I'm telling you
it's so amazing how they do it.
And men talk to each other different
than they talk to women.
We all know these things,
but actually experiencing it
can be really sad.
It can be really really sad to see
how great the sex war is
between men and women.
How much fear and anger
and hostility there really is.
The one thing that I have lost is...
I can't indiscriminately flirt
with anybody.
I used to flirt with people,
mainly to get a discount.
And I would flirt even as an obvious dyke,
I would flirt with straight guys
and I would usually get a discount,
just by being funny or flirtatious.
If a man looks too long at a man,
he's probably gay
or trying to pick that guy up.
So that's what happened
to me in Austria.
I was just looking at this guy
thinking how beautiful he was...
for too long.
And he came up with his fist saying:
"What the fuck are you
looking at me for, faggot?"
I said: "Excuse me,
I thought you were gay."
And then I really got in trouble,
but never mind.
I've always been since I was 16
open to all sexual possibilities.
I wouldn't say I'm a Casanova,
but I have had a lot of
sexual adventures.
The film is called Pansexual Public Porn,
also known as
The adventures of Hans and Del
Pansexual is how
I describe my sexuality
and how Hans describes his sexuality,
in that we don't discriminate
on the basis of gender.
We don't choose
our sexual relationships
depending on if they're male,
female or other.
Usually this is called bisexuality,
but to me to say bisexual
reinforces the binary idea
that there is only male and female.
We had planned to do something
like that together for ages.
I was just being a model
which was great.
It was just getting stoned and...
having sex with these people in the woods.
It's very difficult
for each one of us
to understand that other people
have such a different life.
That seeing a film like
Pansexual Public Porn
is very strange for them.
But to me this is actually
my everyday life.
To experiment,
to have different projects.
That summer the project was to see
if we could have gay men
having sex with us.
And it was very very exciting.
Because we didn't know
if we would be accepted or rejected,
and mostly we were accepted,
which was really cool.
[background music]
You can't look at this
with your perfectionist eye for now.
Ok.
I'm really changing everyday so much
that the moment you tell someone
"this is how it is,
this is how it was before",
the next day that's not true...
so you fictionalise all the time.
I've lived as a so-called woman
for 40 years
so if I'm lucky and I live until 80,
I can live the rest of my life
as a man.
It’s a balancing act.
In these times I don't go out
a lot to have sex,
because I'm painting now.
I'm so into the painting.
I'm more interested in general
about transformation.
How can we learn to have
a non-discriminatory mind,
or how can we learn to use
our discriminatory mind
for practical things,
but not to judge people
or to judge ourselves.
Whatever I am, I am.
I try to be as much myself as I can,
negotiate with life and
with other people
so that's possible, to live
as lively as possible.
[laughing]
With all the flaws that one has...
and the cruelties and...
difficulties.
I wouldn't describe it
as a dream coming true.
In a way it's living the reality.
It's living a reality
of more completeness.
[bar noises]
[peeing sound]
If I always had to use the cubical,
I'd often have to wait a long time
and hang out in the main men's toilet
while everyone else
is using the urinal
and that can be a bit weird.
But because I have my prosthesis
then I just get on with it.
They're not as clean as
the female toilets,
generally speaking.
It's a prosthesis
and it's actually a device
for people with female genitals
to piss standing up.
So it's a sort of a funnel
and it's called a pisser-packer
because it's nice and soft silicon
so you can actually put it
in your underpants
and keep it there
for when you need to go.
Just start the game.
I think it's Orlan who says
"My body is my software".
I would say that mine
is actually my hardware.
It is like a complete reprogramming.
I'm a sculptor
so I'm used to transforming matter
but of course my own human body
is another matter, entirely.
I have a cyborg identity.
I will consider myself a cyborg
but as I am a human being...
I mean there are so many
plurals of identity.
A cyborg is somebody who's...
using that sort of the consciousness
of machines and prosthetics,
using machines
as a prosthetic as well.
Just their identity isn't confined
to their own human body.
It's something to do with
a broader consciousness of the self.
Am I just a cyborg when I'm  online?
If I'm gardening, am I a cyborg?
Would you do a phalloplastic?
If you would have
a functioning cock.
What would you do with your cunt?
Oh, I'd leave the cunt. Definitely.
I don't know what
I'd do with my breasts though.
No, I know.
I would change them a little bit.
I would become a hermaphrodite.
You can actually grow
from a cell of your body,
you can grow a dick.
Maybe not nowadays,
but soon, very soon.
Yeah. I mean I don't know.
I always wanted the genitals
I have now, so I'm quite happy.
You're quite happy.
I think it would be wrong to assume
that it's like a group of people
all shooting up testosterone together.
That's a kind of...
tabloid fear mongering way
of putting it,
because we all did come to
our individual decisions.
And we all were going through
the experience alone.
[chattering]
Somehow we are a bit
of family in that sense,
an alternative family.
People who are around
if you really have a problem,
you know you can call them.
[chattering]
Happy birthday to me
and everybody else.
[eastern music]
I had a dream about me in a sari.
In a sari it’s good
to have a bit of flesh.
Right, that's considered sexy.
I've always wanted a sari
and I like to do female drag
so I thought I'd work on
a few different outfits.
If you don't mind,
if you're patient with me,
I'm gonna try and see
if I can remember
what you told me
and you're helping me.
Just put it on heavy.
Pour it on,
be a bit exaggerated.
You're being a bit too subtle,
give it to me.
I'm relying on your skill.
[laughing]
I'm putting more eyeliner on.
I'll do the mascara, ok?
It'll be quicker.
Hey, you look cute.
So do you.
I thought you didn't like me
as a girl.
Well, I do.
Ok.
For a change.
Turn.
Put your arms up.
Brixton, doesn't that hurt?
Yes, it hurts,
that's why I didn't wanna do it...
today.
It does hurt.
Ok now.
Do you need any help?
That looks good.
It looks good.
Yeah. Check out these muscles.
(shouting) It's coming.
We're never gonna get it.
Yes, we will. Come on.
[underground noise]
Look. No fingernail polish.
Happy Birthday!
What are you doing?
Just checking.
Don't mess up my make up.
I'll keep my eyes closed.
- Keep your eyes closed. Ok?
- Yes, ok.
Keep your eyes closed.
What's going oooooooon?
Make a wish, make a wish!
[clapping]
(someone) Yeah!!
Everybody did it.
[music]
Yeeha!
[breaking waves]
The reason I became a photographer
is I never ever saw my world,
my reality reflected
in an accurate and beautiful way.
This picture is a wider shot.
This was the centre piece
of the grid of nine
and it's called Hermaphrodite torso.
When I take a picture of someone
it's almost as
if they become part of me.
I don't consider that
I have a clitoris anymore.
I call it a 'dick clit'.
A cross between a dick and a clit.
So it is a 'dick clit',
because it is small.
But that is exactly what I wanted.
Women were raised to feel
ashamed of their bodies.
Particularly, their genitals.
Women don't have
a lot of pride in their genitals.
Probably because of the way in which
they have been portrayed
in pornography,
in very invasive, intrusive,
ugly ways.
So I wanted to make my genitals
and other people's genitals look good.
This is another one...
I think some people might think
that it's quite shocking.
I find them really stunningly beautiful.
But I'm the first to admit
I'm out of touch with what
the person on the street
might think or feel.
I'm not so worried about
what people think of me
and because I'm surrounded by people
that I respect and admire
who I hope respect and admire me,
I'm really... that birthday thing.
I'm gonna start crying again,
cause the birthday thing was just...
Having felt so unpopular
in junior high school.
And feeling like
people really didn't like me
and then to have
all my friends get me
that beautiful bicycle.
It just made me feel so good
and so loved.
I'm really, really lucky to have that.
Anyway.
Mo B. Dick: Tonight is a legendary night.
Not all these drag kings have been
on the same stage all at once,
This fellow came all the way from London.
All right. Yeah, ok.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please give a warm round of applause
for Del LaGrace Volcano.
[music]
I like myself
and having come from
really hating myself
and having a really bad self-image,
it's important to me now
to have a good self-image
and I guess in a way to show people
that you can make that transition.
[music]
Be what you gotta be,
be who you wanna be,
you can't let what people
are gonna say,
what people are gonna
think about you,
get in the way,
you just gotta live it.
[music]
[cheering]
Ladies and gentlemen:
Dréd and Luscious.
Luscious get out here.
Hooooooly shit.
Oh my god, Luscious and Dréd.
Oh shit!
[music]
[Song]
["This is a Man's Man's Man's World"]
[big cheering]
[lyrics: This is a man's world...]
[...but it would be nothing...]
[...without a woman.]
[clapping]
Drag kingdom has come.
Can I hear an amen?
Reverend Jimmy Johnson,
I'm a heterosexual
and I wanna be a part
of your drag kingdom,
and what do you think I say?
I say amen to heterosexuals,
I say amen to homosexuals,
I say amen to bisexuals,
I say amen to transsexuals.
I say amen to anybody's sexual.
[cheering and clapping]
[English subtitles thanks to
Amaranta Heredia Jaén]
[Contact: amarantaheredia@gmail.com]