When you fly?
Tomorrow morning.
But not without a farewell party, right?
You are very good.
I'm looking for someone who
can organize a birthday party for the girlfriend of a celebrity.
None. I get pimples with celebrities.
A football star. A really great guy.
Great guys there are everywhere.
Great, we're there!
Welcome ... - ... Ibiza!
Boyd, look. He is also there.
We are famous.
Das ist Armin van Buuren.
Hello mate, we are also DJs!
Come on, Lars, we give him a CD from us.
Hey, let's do that I will not end up in jail again.
This is our big chance. We need but only ...
Caution!
What do you have now bought again?
What? - Jasper is eight.
Shit.
Hey, there's our luggage.
Pim. The los, Nun mach schon.
Jasper.
Guys, hey guys come down from there, go, go, go, down. Hey.
Honey, do not be angry, but your collection is currently in Dubai.
Dubai? - Yes. Unfortunately I can not change.
Since when new trends develop in Dubai?
I have to call back later, and ... - New trends are developing on Ibiza.
Yeah, well, listen, honey, I ... - Toll.
I take care of it, I get the ready to go back.
Do not worry, enjoy the time and do a few days of vacation.
I did not come here to vacation, Pim.
I'm here to promote my bikinis. Sorry!
Do you smell that, Irma?
Yes, it smells very strongly of kerosene.
Ich nur Riecho Testosteron, the Parfum von Ibiza.
How about us, honey? I pay in kind.
You could be his babysitter.
And if I were his grandmother, does not bother me.
We're here to have sex. - Oh yeah?
On my last sex I can barely remember, this was Scrabble.
Double word value. I have ten books here.
While you ausschläfst your noise,
I enjoy the beautiful beach weather with Dr. Zhivago.
Where we play our games Doctor, I do not care.
Na dann...
Real Madrid has paid all here?
Yes, that's really the nicest house we had until now.
Well, just this room here. Which is really terrible.
Why, what is it?
Here indeed fit not even clean my shoes.
Which must be true at least three times.
And Kevin agrees?
Dearest May, a single smile from me is enough.
Hello my sweet. - It's really not too big.
If you say so. Only the best for my best is good enough.
Only the walk-in closet is really too small.
Can we not make something bigger?
Klar, Süße. Hopa.
And what's in front of my strong Kevin on my birthday?
Oh, until now still nothing. - Nothing?
But I pay for it but this Mimique.
Na warte!
Lizzy, you can give me even a can of pineapple?
Fast Lizzy.
LOVING IBIZA - THE BIGGEST PARTY OF MY LIFE
Bibi, Schatz... - Hey.
You look really sexy. And so grown up.
I'm also grown. I'm 21
21?
And.
My birthday was two months ago? - Really?
You're not going to be like Dad, I hope, right?
Welcome to Grandpa, the party animals. - So, here we are.
Wow, I bet you, here there is also a swimming pool. Come on, this way.
Dad, can I jump in like this, or do I have to wear a swimsuit?
Since no water is indeed there.
Und jetzt, Papa?
Hello dear. - Hello.
Hey.
Hi. Oh...
You look stunning.
Oh, thank you. I have something for you. One for you and one for Liz.
One of your designs?
Of course. From the new collection.
Oh, cool. I find great.
Yes, fits well on it. The rest is now somewhere in the Sahara.
Zara! Sweety!
Hey! Guys, come to grandpa.
Bieb, you bring the glasses? - Yes.
Take your daddy's arms!
Slowly, Dad, I have a headache. My entire collection is now in. ..
Then we do it very carefully. Hello, sweetheart.
Hi Paps.
Can I help you?
If you want. How are you then, Pim?
Well, getting to my ears. Two small children, an ambitious woman ...
You need a change of times, I think.
Ja, ja, das kann man sagen, ja.
Very well, then you're landing to the right place.
In Ibiza, anything is possible. I have here my innocence lost with 14.
Prost! Cheers!
Lecker, Opa.
Ah, that's the right spirit, huh?
What shall we give him for his birthday?
I bet you know what?
I've since seen on eBay a plate of Perry Como, from the year
in which he is born. That would be a nice gift.
I do not think Dad would like to be reminded of his birth year.
Yeah, so I'll have to agree with you already.
Okay. Yes. Do you have a better idea? Then out with it.
When it comes to it, we just do a few days of fun
and enjoy ourselves in Lizzy's club, very simple.
Liz, tell me, do you still have the store?
And.
Dear, you can be much more than that, how old are you now? Almost 30!
26, Zara!
Do you have a friend,
or are you hiding still with your colleagues in the broom closet?
Lizzy's colleagues are so hot, I would do the same.
And soon we'll get back a new charge.
Oh, stop it with these guys rancid. Is indeed disgusting.
And? How did you get to your fun? Pim does not look so
as it would be very often dragged into the broom closet.
Enough is enough.
Pim and I have a balanced sex life.
Oh, yeah? I can hardly imagine, if you always are wearing the pants.
Maybe you should not so often take off your pants, Liz.
Girls, I think it's wonderful.
We forget my birthday and romp with the waves.
Jasper! Pim, watch it sometimes on. Must I do everything myself?
What is it, Liz?
Zara's right, I'm getting too old.
Too old? What for?
For this constant running around in the bar for anything, really.
You take football to the most beautiful places and the best restaurants.
You always reservierst a VIP table and never ask what it costs. Easy.
But be careful. The girlfriends of footballers are annoying,
and they are always jealous.
Look at the camera.
In the camera.
Oh, my God.
Take off your shirt. Come on, get down with it. Pull out.
Pretty, is not it?
Terrible.
Can you make it wet?
Yes, this looks great. Great.
Gebt mir the Ball. The Ball.
But not with this stupid ball
Forget it, the ball remains. Comm
Oh Mann, gut so. Sexy, sexy.
Kevvie...
Oh yeah, that's good. Wow!
I'll put you in front of him afterwards.
Hi. - Hi. - Kevin.
Lizzy... - Hoogland.
And.
Do you have experience?
Yes, yes, I ... I have been working together forever with musicians.
Well, they are somewhat difficult.
Just say what you want, and I'll organize it for you.
Tell me what you can offer.
The Gio is fully booked for months, but I can get you a VIP table.
Yes, Gio last week we were erst
Maybe a boat to Formentera? With DJ on board, loose feet in the sand ...
Beach is what wannabes.
So I do not know Kevvie can not organize someone your age that?
Sorry, aber...
Ah, her friend would really great find,
if they should do this for your friend.
N i ch t?
Yes. Yes, it is a really gigantic fan
Your girlfriend?
Yes. Yes, my girlfriend and I have been together a long time.
We are totally in love with each other.
And she is a fan of Kevin?
No, of you. She has voted dozens of times for you at X-Factor.
Do you hear that, Kevvie? - I hear that, honey.
Even lesbians are already fans of mine.
May I still call it that, right?
Of course. Out of me. Lesbian, Dyke, as you will.
My girlfriends and I have already made a list. I would ...
Yes, sweetie, but let all of the Mimique and ...
Minique ... - Lizzy.
Lizzy ... organize. They understand what it.
But I do have penguins on my birthday.
I can really laugh like that about them.
Well, if you want penguins, then you get even penguins, of course.
As you see it. Penguins, you can laugh about.
Sorry.
Omi. Hi.
What? Already?
That was Grandma. It is almost in the harbor.
I have to go and pick them up.
That can not but now. The designers of our tattoos coming.
Fuck! This shit.
I can not pick up your grandma.
Yes. - Really? - Yes.
Your full serious? - Yes, of course.
That's sweet of you. - Oh, no problem.
I hang namely very attached to her.
And what's her name?
Karla Hoogland.
Hey, thank you.
Hey, you're welcome.
"My heart goes boom". I'll see probably not right?
Please take your time. Do not you recognize me?
Jacky ...
Oh. Tag Lex.
How are you? - Prima. Just arrived. And you?
Still not grown up, I see.
Opa ...
How time flies. Even for a pop singer. Day, Lex
Jacky.
Have fun.
You bet, Lex
Previously worked somehow better.
Oh how nice, a scarf.
Das ist ein and cycles.
If you keep it running around like an old maid,
I can abschminken evening the same success today.
But surely you do not believe that I ...
Wear!
So I prefer not to. Whether you like it or not.
In addition, because I do not fit inside. - What did you do?
The schau doch mal.
So I wear this dress again and that's that.
Hello. Now I look like a pregnant van Almsick.
But unfortunately without medal.
No, not even. - No.
It looks great. Come, now, we go hunting.
So I do not know. - Do not argue.
If you do not like tonight,
you can flirt on the beach again tomorrow with Dr. Zhivago.
Yes, but now imagine it out before that ..
Was?
Imagine someone of the opposite sex suddenly has interest in you.
Well. Yes. Then you gotta run in your life.
Also...
Zara?
Hey, honey, I've been thinking what.
When we returned the bikinis and the photo shoot is over, then
we could go camping for a few days.
Comfortable for four. Under the stars fall asleep and wake up on the beach.
Maybe we can even sleep together again.
A long time ago. After that we no longer know how to do it.
Pim ... - And?
I have the most important photo-reportage of my career ahead of me,
and all the bikinis are simply gone!
I try now anyway with all this stress to cope.
So if you do not mind ...
Yes, but if the bikinis now are not there,
The magazine takes you next month too.
Then they already make their Autumn Special.
Then just next year.
A designer of 29 may still be hot and interesting.
But a 34 is something out of!
Honey, you're 31 You can always ...
Zara.
Then do whatever you want.
Ich bin Karla.
Welcome to Ibiza, Karla.
You've gained a lot. On television, you were much slimmer.
Oh no, no, no, I'm not Elza. I'm Lizzy, the party planner.
I organize Elza's birthday party.
That because they can not organize themselves?
Ah, for me ...
Oh, I'll take the here.
Ah, the bikinis, I'll tell you, eventually they'll kill me.
Such a fuss because a small piece of cloth.
And you ..
Still not old enough for a boyfriend?
No. The guys at my age're all still so very childish.
Do you understand that?
Yes, I can understand that very well. When I was as old as you,
I was even too cowardly to a girl we talk to you.
But that was a long time ago, Pim.
And.
I have the feeling that you really understand me.
Na and ...
I always feel so alone.
Hey. This is us all sometimes, right?
Wow!
What is it?
Grandpa has a real drum.
Oh my goodness, here it looks so chic it than for "Bold and the Beautiful".
Omi! Glad you're here.
Elza!
So this is Elza. You know her from X Factor, but this is real here.
Schwiegeroma. Omi. What should I call you?
Karla wäre gut.
Omi. I'm glad you're here.
How do you like it?
Really nice, is not it? I am.
And when it's done, can Kevvie it tattooed on the back.
But it did not fit after all.
Smaller, of course.
In the kitchen there are more pictures of me. Want to see them?
Because they eat enough?
Lasst reden Mich., okay? - Okay.
Hey We are looking for the manager of this shop here.
I'm the manager.
Okay,
I'm Lars and the two DJs, and Dylan Boyd,
and we have something here, I'll tell you something you've never heard of.
Music?
Yes. - And you want to hang up?
Wow. Do you hear that it is capable of.
We are powered. Good luck yet.
Hey, warte.
Vergiss Club... - Progessive... Electro... - Deep House...
Clubhouse... - Acid house... - Eurohouse... - Techno...
Drum and Base. This is different.
Listen, we've Ibiza House, we do not need your music too.
So this is Ibiza House?
What a smooth, prehistoric shit, hey, cemetery crash.
Get the snorer about all that?
Yes. But we will change that. Come friends, keep the spirit.
Do you know that I used to not even like fish?
And now I love fish. Especially tuna I find delicious.
By the way, nice here. Quiet.
What is it?
Nothing. Too little drunk.
Next time we go to Paris, right?
And how is it with bikinis?
Oh, Dad, that are truly gone by the earth.
But nice that you ask for it. - You know that "bikini" is an island?
And maybe they are back there. Yes, exactly. Back to the roots!
Pop. So I do not believe now, right? Did you about ... Hey!
Have you already taken about that stuff?
No, I have only taken a small pill cocktail.
I feel more than okay.
Okay.
Congratulations.
Ah, that's the day after tomorrow, but still ever thank you, my boy.
My wild tigress.
Oh guys, I love you all.
You are a true free spirit, I like that about you, you know? Base age.
Hi there.
Can I have a little champagne?
No chance, darling, no way.
We take two Coca Cola for the children.
You know that they are nervous about it.
But not as nervous as you, honey.
Cheers!
And.
The two flirt. - What?
Not too young, not too old, just right.
He looks at her?
No. Jumped.
He looks anyway.
Now he looks back.
If he finds me sexy?
Put it fixed. You surely have enough experience. Anyway more than I do.
Is kommt. Is kommt here, kommt here.
Hi ladies. How's it going?
Hi.
Prima. And you?
You two holidays here, yes?
Yes, that too. We are from Holland. And you?
I grew up here. But my parents come from Brussels.
My name is Steve.
Steve? I got my first kiss from a Steve. I Love Belgium.
Since the south begins, I always say.
Oh. The South begins to something deeper with you.
Your first day here? - Yes.
Then I beat before, we show you the clubs.
Das War and customs.
We take a taxi and a VIP table.
It looks delicious.
Good appetite.
Thank you.
How beautiful.
My daughters.
Pim ...
And the rockers, Jesper and Sam.
Jasper and Sem
Yes, I say yes. Jasper and Sem
I've missed you.
Little noticed. I thought you like it great on the island.
But it's true, Zara.
Now, just as before.
As I've wasted my time trying to make music ...
And rumzuvögeln.
To tour ... ...
With ... more women than there were condoms ...
Yes, and for what?
What do you want, you were even second in the charts of ...
Von Japan. - Japan and.
Yes, yes, you're laughing times. You're right. As a father, I have failed miserably.
And also as a husband.
We prefer not to talk about our mothers.
Yes, we can leave it out please?
I see them still. Your three mothers.
They stare at me. And suddenly she directed a gun at me.
Hey, hey, Lex...
And I say, "Shoot it!" Because they are right.
I'm a selfish, fucking ass Losch.
Guys ...
Grandpa is drunk.
Come on, guys, let's go. Ow! - You all stay here.
What is to become of it?
Come!
Out of me. - All three.
Dad, I'm working here on the island, remember.
I love you.
Dad, I can see your cleavage.
My fault.
Forgive me, please. - All is forgiven, Lex
Bieb? - When the Pap.
Und Zara, the auch?
Yes, all right. Now get up again and please behave yourself normal. Yes ...
I love you all. My sirens.
Starting today, I'll be a good father and grandfather.
This guy gets a makeover!
Raise your glasses.
Let us celebrate life!
Paps!
El, look how expensive this ring.
That does not matter. Once loving smile will suffice.
1.400.
He is determined to never say yes.
Aber er sagt doch immer: "Don't settle for anything less."
Does not something like: "The bigger, the better"?
He wants you to get the best ...
Omi, alles gut?
And.
You are not cleans surely?
Why not you?
Oh, Omi. You have here, but do not clean.
That her is well determined.
It has a name. It is Elza.
How do you find them?
Elza you mean? That is your decision.
I'll stop on her birthday for her hand.
What would have thought your father of Elza, what do you think?
Do you doubt?
To you two? No. But has Elza, except this X Factor,
still learned a real job?
I'm still not.
I've also just asked.
Tasse Tee?
Hello, here I am again. Sorry.
Hi. I just wanted to ask,
whether the reservation for tonight's okay.
Thank you.
Sorry. Do you like Ibiza?
Until now, very good.
Kevin! Kevin, can I ask you something?
No, please not now. - Yes, but ...
You married?
Baby, come on. - Kevin, can I have your autograph?
Get out.
Baby.
Hello, I am a big fan .. - Would you like an autograph?
Yeah, sure. - Turn around.
Regelst you? - Of course.
Comes.
Lizzy. I'm sorry, that we trouble you again,
but we have to go in there. - We do not deal drugs.
We do not smoke. - We do not drink.
What do you want there? So good. It's okay.
Du bist classes!
I've also started times.
These drinks are included, right?
Besides the Campagner, 1,000 euros a bottle.
Lars, that's ... this is ...
The sky!
The drinks for 43
This is us.
Champagne.
Welcome to Ibiza. - Thanks.
Hi. - Come on. - You're welcome.
Hey, man, get out, get out.
This is new music, I have to give it to him.
We come again tomorrow before the club opens.
Lars, now we are here ...
But that is never what.
Good. If you can do better ...
And.
Good. Then it does make it yourself good luck.
Okay.
Guys, come, man
What, 17 euros, so much? My goodness.
For that I can buy a whole iceberg at the North Pole, yes, if I want.
Since you get the free. - Please?
That is so expensive because the guys take pills. Then they deserve something.
But they are well informed. Thank God I'm too old.
Hey...
40 is the new 30 I guess you are not older than 37
Yes, thank you. That's nice, but you're so easy to see through.
Who is it?
Well, your generation.
And that bothers you, right?
No. No, no you're right. That's kind of great.
I'd not trust it. Sorry.
Oh, I am the way, Lars.
Irma.
And in case you think I'm only 26, I'm 27
Oh. Gott sei Dank.
Hey Leute, Belly Shot.
Say, we do not prefer to go to the lounge? Since it is much quieter.
Do not worry, nothing can happen in there, because depends a condom machine.
Ah, na dann...
And you're alone? Lars von already legendary 27
No, I'm here with two friends, Dylan and Boyd.
You are looking for a club where they can hang up.
So wie Tiesto, David Guetta, Armin van Buuren ...
You have no idea what I'm talking about at all.
No. No, "hang up" since the word I did not come already with.
What drives you here?
Oh, I guess that would be too boring for you.
I'm a suitcase full of books here.
No, leave that!
Oh, sorry.
I just wanted to order something stronger.
I thought you wanted to do something in my glass.
Wait, wait. Here.
What's this?
Sorry.
But absorbs well.
My God.
Oh thank you. - Please.
She loves to be the center.
Yes, but she also loves you.
Where do you want to know as precisely?
You never know for sure.
Even if you're not famous, you can not be sure.
Tja, da hast du recht.
You know, I would never want to be famous.
I would like to know the X Factor,
but then only on Saturday night 11 to 1
And then everything will be normal again.
With you it's never normal, right? But maybe you do not want that,
otherwise you would not do on Ibiza holiday.
Then you would be flown safely to a desert island.
That did not Elza. You have something already like.
I was hoping that I still meet you here.
A Pillchen?
Drinking.
That was a mistake, right? - No, that's good.
Oh dear.
Show me your request. Well come on, the application.
Okay. So I'll go first to his knees in front of her ...
And.
Armin makes appropriate music ... ... - Yes?
And then ... I see her in the eye and give her a hand. And then I say ...
Come on, you Elza richest hand, so I?
Okay, okay, pass auf.
Imagine that you marry your girlfriend.
It's now allowed, but you are allowed to marry.
Kevin! Hey...
Hey, hey, I'm not a lesbian.
Hi. - What is?
And I have no girlfriend, you know?
I had to say just before Minique.
Oh crap, now I've told it, and can not say it.
Sorry, was?
I'm not a lesbian!
I'll see it does not look like a lesbian.
You did not really think, I'd be a lesbian, right?
Hey, yet! So you've really kept me for a lesbian, right?
So then I really seh as if I were a lesbian?
Voila! - So!
Cheers!
Sun's what I call a real club duo!
I hope it is not a hobby of yours,
The nose to hit men on the first date bloody.
No, really, no, no, you were the first.
Beautiful language, is not it? - Yes, beautiful.
My shoulder is canceled. - No. - Yes.
This is not serious. Come on.
If I ... I mean just imagine, I think sometime really my dream man,
I would my marriage proposal
would like to get to a beautiful, secluded spot.
And there is here?
Auf Ibiza? Ja.
Comm
I can not.
Wait, wait times.
I need to rest for a while now myself. - Yeah, not so easy, huh?
What are you doing?
What's this? 50 cents.
Das ist if Irre.
For this, we buy an ice cream.
Ja, Gute Idee.
Shit. Sorry.
Now I have to go quite quickly once where.
Yes, I already understood. As is the bathroom.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Hey Bieb.
Bibi! What are you doing here? Why ...
I've been here the whole time.
How? But I do not understand. Who is it now with the children?
Lex Lex she took as part of his new grandpa Makeovers.
Lex?
That's handy. What is there already happen?
What? What's supposed to happen?
Fuck. Shit, damn.
Zara. Shit.
Hey, guys, are you still awake?
Hey?
Fuck!
Wow.
Beautiful, is not it?
Yes, beautiful.
Probably it would be something too quiet for Elza.
Yes, for sure Elza, yes.
Nostradamus has said that in a doomsday
Ibiza is the last refuge on earth.
Since he has chosen well, this Nostratus.
When the world comes, I want to be here at this place.
No, you can not. Now it is my place.
No, because I have shown you the place.
No, you have only taken me here, so it belongs to me now.
You just try to take away my place?
Do we share?
Good.
"Thank you, ma'am"
Your bill.
1,800 euros? Damn, shit-Belgians.
Plus tip.
Tip? Here you have your tip.
And now pulling leash.
Pim, stop.
Pim, what is this?
Pim, stop it!
His car is not there.
Lass the Pim.
Jasper?
Jasper? Which?
Pim! They're gone!
The beach is back there!
Are you okay?
What do you think?
Jacky.
Yes. Jacky again.
Do you have a flat tire?
No, I enjoy watching the sunrise here.
I'd enjoy it with you,
but my grandchildren have made with the quad out of the dust.
Search for your grandchildren, you quietly.
And order your much too young woman greetings.
I'm not a young woman.
Oh, Lex, stop it. I've seen you but yesterday.
That was my daughter.
Fuck!
Dad, wo sind the Children?
The guys are just ... currently go with the quad.
On the quad, Lex? How can you allow that?
Take just a little bit, just a bit, no problem.
As they pass on. Hey guys! Yes, they have a lot of fun.
Dear, I must stop. I have the boys. Yes? Bye bye.
Lex, I want you to come back here right now.
Yeah, okay, okay, honey, I'll see you later at home.
And they are at it?
He's lying.
Fuck! Fuck!
What's going on? - What?
Be glad that you have never married me.
As a husband I had not even made the second place in Japan.
I have to look for the boys. Where you have to go?
Hey! These are my nephews.
Hold on.
Hey!
Sem! Jasper!
Hold it! Hold on!
No, we want the beach!
Los, gib Gas! - Okay!
Shit.
Guys! Hey guys, if you remain standing, we play a game of football.
Das ist Kevin Highlands. - Yes.
But then you have to stop, okay?
Okay. Word of honor?
Yes, I promise, I promise!
So okay, we stop.
Attack.
And!
Wow.
You do not need any more.
Get in the car.
And!
Goal!
Dad, we played football on the beach with Kevin Hoogland.
Hey, dear ones.
That's really true. - Was Lionel Messi, too?
No, but we played on the beach and he stayed much longer,
than I thought. - Thank you, Lizzy.
Is that really true? - Yes.
Since you have had really good luck. - Yes.
So, guys, but now we go to bed.
Do you also have penalties practiced with him?
They are the favorite children of the world.
And.
Oh. I must have fallen asleep, what?
I've noticed, Snow White.
I wanted to kiss you awake already, because,
maybe tomorrow you're already a surfboard.
Yes. - Here.
I'm worried for you.
Do you know what I find so great about you?
No.
I expected what else, when I saw you.
And what you did not expect, in particular?
Romance.
I mean, a man who worried a dress for you,
in a hotel full of cockroaches and a dirty bathtub ...
A woman can be seen ... Yes, enormous longing, you know?
Say, we do not want but rather go to my apartment?
Yes, a good idea.
And? What do you think?
Cheesy.
You are right. I am a single cliché.
But I was already second time in Japan.
Ah yes, "My heart goes boom." That was a pretty lousy number.
Abolut.
The Japanese are deaf.
And you?
Married, no children, and when he is blown,
I've asked myself what I've actually done all the time?
You still look as good as then, Jacky.
Good God, what we used to but fucked horny. As the hamster.
Hey!
But we had fantastic sex, right?
Lex Be honest. Did you at that time what that means? I?
So honestly, no.
At that time I was busy with my little friend.
And I really had a lot to do.
Anyway, you're honest.
Only later I realized that you were something special.
But it was too late.
Hi.
Hi!
How was it?
Super! I've just lost the other.
I then took a taxi. At your expense.
Yes, that's my youngest, Bibi.
How old is Bibi?
21, And, 21
I want to go home.
Was?
Thank you.
We see each other again?
It's my birthday tomorrow. I celebrate today purely night,
in "Buffaage." I would be delighted if you would come.
We'll see.
Come here! I'll throw you in the pool.
No, you're not real. Caution, my champagne! Put me down!
Hi.
Hi. I am.
And.
I found this place very beautiful.
Yes. Beautifully.
I think you're great.
Oh...
Okay...
So now you'd have to actually say that you also found me great find.
Yes. - Or not?
Yes, actually, already, I think. Oh, sorry, I ...
When it comes to VIPs, I am somehow not as good.
But that was also on past that. If my father's birthday,
were many famous people there, and then I was taken out of my bed
and had to sing a song, though I can not sing.
That was really embarrassing, you know?
You're doing it again.
Was?
Well, you always give full throttle.
Sorry.
No, do not stop.
Look at me just once as Kevin.
Good. You know, actually I know all about not really you.
It does not really matter whether you're famous.
I mean ... I mean, you've got a friend who you will marry.
And so I'm not a girl, you know?
It was still great, Kevin. Bye.
No. Lizzy, wait, I ...
Who was that so early?
I'm going to fall in love. Add a footballer.
Well, that definitely fits to Ibiza.
Yes Yes
Black?
But all ...
Penguins.
Oh Zara.
Oh Bibi, du bist das.
Holy shit. This is no longer true.
Hey, hallo!
Bibi ... Bibi ... Bi .. Sorry. This is no longer true.
Since tonight I am again totally at Zara.
Bastard!
Pim? Oh ... - And?
Can you please take the children afterwards? When they are awake?
Is good.
Allow you, monsieur?
Hello. I am a green Seehulk.
I try to catch my mermaid.
But that probably will not interest you. You want to sleep better now.
I pull at me quickly and then I'm gone.
Ha ha, I have another one! Here, this is the vengeance of Neptune.
Dr. Zhivago probably had no office, right?
You're pretty hypocritical, I think. How old is that?
Much older than you might think. And also much more mature.
This does not work anyway.
Oh. Why is that? You must have only dim the light.
You're a real bitch.
The lesbian took just a boat to organize,
but even this she is too stupid. Where is she anyway?
Sleep? Sweet, it's just gone wrong ...
Kevvie, I want a speed boat.
And on the speed boat to be made then of course photos.
And these photos then I will tweet. After all, there are thousands of people,
really want to know what I do all day long, so everything.
Yes, but hardly what you are doing.
Actually, you're doing nothing at all.
Kev...
Women, women ...
You suck it all day long only to these stems.
A stem at a time.
Hello, it's me, Lizzy.
Good morning.
Hi. - Hi.
You could have a try to do something other than constantly just to tweet pictures.
You could for example go to the beach and read a book.
Read a book? The real but no one believes me.
No, you're right.
I only read somewhere when something is written about me.
That's the great thing about my life. I do not need to lie on Twitter.
For me, everything is just real. And everyone is jealous of me.
You understand that?
Yes, Elza. I understand more than you think.
We get a new boat. - And how big?
This is an ice sculpture of Kevin and Elza.
Oh, what a frosty affair. But very apt.
Senoritas! The black pigs.
The penguins.
The Penguins ...
Fuck.
Piglets. How sweet.
I want my penguins!
You should now prefer to make no more mistakes. Lesbian!
Well done to el. You're so unprofessional.
Sorry, I ...
May I join you today?
But you can spend on a two-million-speed boat the day.
"Armin van Buurens Sommerhaus fertig"
Hey! Let das. buy yourself one.
He is at home.
Hey Armin, we have a ... Oh, wait, Armin, ... Here, we have a CD for you.
We want to present you with. - Yes, we are DJs.
And we got here ... - Dylan Boyd.
Because ... we wanted to ask you ...
Come into the water, because we are only sure.
Swimming!
What's this? - A smartphone.
Ah! - I am.
Can you ever check if the prepaid is otherwise too expensive.
And.
80,000? This must surely be pesetas then, right?
No, those are euros.
Here it is. The ring I have designed specifically for your wedding.
Okay.
Wow.
Put it on time.
I would like to see what that looks like.
Really beautiful.
It is not for me ...
I have to call, penguins and such.
Kevin, Kevin, you look at the ring. There is so much personality in it.
It is specially designed for you.
How are you?
Before.
Would you rather to the beach? - No.
Or would you rather go home? - No.
What do you want then?
I would love to beat you mercilessly now.
Zara, Zara, Bitte, ich ...
I'm happy that you're back with me.
And you amuse yourself with my sister!
Half-sister.
Zara. I beg you.
Dad, it's boring here.
Here, you buy an ice cream, right?
That is 50 euros. Yes!
Not very clever to begin in the middle of the market with it.
But you're clever, yes?
Hey, when we arrived here, has been running our marriage sucks.
So you thought to yourself: "You know what, I'll do once a makeover."
Yes. No, I ... - Yes!
No, I, I ... It was wrong of course, but I feel so much better now.
But only because I now know again how much I still love you.
Hey...
Hey, worth doch mal.
Pim, I have to find my collection.
And when I'm back at Lex, you're gone, right?
Was?
And you take Jasper and also with Sem.
Dad, where are we going?
I do not know, guys. We just need to look for something new short times.
Maybe a campground or something.
No, but I will not! I find camping stupid.
Now keep it out finally your mouth, you hear!
Your whole life I have provided for you,
such as if you are in the ICU. Now you accepted me,
what I say, without nagging again, is that clear?
Was? Here?
Ah, very good. Bit boring. I read a lot on the beach.
Hey, how's your exam go?
Oh, very good, fine.
Okay, darling, yes, good. Bye.
It was still raining in the Netherlands.
Is this something serious with you and Lars? - No, of course not.
Why not you? - Well, Classify ..
Because you're scared, right?
Jacky, stop it. You know how old I am.
So far I can not count.
I just think people should behave well according to their age.
But is very trendy, MILF be. - What?
MILF. A mother I'd like to fuck.
Hey!
What will you do?
With just some things you need to accomplish. For example, therewith to be young.
Can I have it then?
For the most beautiful woman on the island.
Lars, stop, do not be an idiot. I could be your mother.
I found it very nice last night, really. Maybe too good.
You know .. I'm just not used to it.
And if I'm getting used to it again and it stops again,
I miss it.
And then I must himself around me again.
I do not know if I can do it. And wants.
Do you understand?
Of course not. You are ...
I'm old enough.
In any case, I was not born yesterday.
So here they take. I'm not vain picked.
I'm crazy. Oh ...
Lovingly crazy.
Not an eggnog. At home, you get to every street corner.
An eggnog for the lady? Is done immediately.
Are you doing to yourself? - Yes.
Ah, that's sweet of you.
It languishes then, since it is here.
But it is my job to meet you your dreams.
No, better not. - Once tapas!
Okay, I will. - No.
My father used to have a snack bar.
Has he sold?
Yes. And that he regretted the rest of his life. He died when I was 14.
He has never seen you play?
Yet. Until I was twelve. He was my biggest fan Then he got sick.
And you?
He lives here in Ibiza. Together with my half sister
and twelve very old, gold records.
Please, Lizzy, a kiss.
One only.
There have been ordered 1,000 bottles of champagne,
and in the end even someone sees us here. It really is not, Kevin.
Since the delivery of Amsterdam.
The? No, Seniors! A rather large box. Senior!
Your plate. Here.
Senior Verbeek? Senior Verbeek? Aus Dubai.
We apologize for the mistake.
Thank you.
Dad, what is it?
It's nothing.
Seid ihr und Dylan Boyd?
Das ist Armin van Buuren.
And you heard this CD here.
I want to hear how they sound in a large room times.
Cheers!
My Twitter!
Hey Jacky.
Wow, Armin. Das war so...
How did you like it?
Herr van Buuren?
Hey.
I guess this will be a pretty awesome show,
with you as support.
Here?
Tonight.
I do not believe it. - Real madness.
All ... doors open. I always thought it was totally great on this island.
So you still mix with?
You know, this island is, it is chilling rough.
Age is completely irrelevant.
Yes, but I see in the photos too often girls
who are even younger than your oldest daughter.
Na and ...
Then take them home with you.
And there they have to admire your collection of gold records?
Who make so well to the wall.
And? Are they impressed?
God, what a small child.
Jacky?
Jacky!
Hi. - Hi.
Excuse me, I am looking for Jacky.
Hey, I know you yet.
"My heart goes boom, boom", ja.
Great kindness, Jacky's right, you look like a wax figure at Madame Tussaud's.
Jacky is at the small beach there.
Hey.
Beware that you do not melt.
Hi. Have you already that before?
No. I have no plans.
Are you coming? I have to stand up in front me there.
I think I'll lie down. The eggnog is me probably gone to his head.
I think I would have been better but will not make a full liter.
Well, will you not eat something?
Here you go.
Yes you have to be half starved.
I'm looking really thrilled that I met you again.
So that I would really never expected. It's been so long.
That's what happens when you do not call back.
Ah, the time passed in a flash and then I was a comet.
Yes, we know that.
You were the Sun King, and I was one of your groupies interchangeable.
No, that's not true.
I see already, you do not believe me, but it really is not true.
Otherwise I would not have picked you up.
What do you think? Is there a chance
that we both have to start over again after 21 years?
Would you want that?
Why not you?
Perhaps we can also still set a child.
Why not?
Great God, Lex You're still a child herself. Of almost 60 years.
Sag mal ...
, 1992, 9 March for three clock at night, the whole background choir in your bed.
Since I was pregnant with you.
Do not worry, I do not want any alimony from you.
I got rid of it leave.
Otherwise, it might now with your youngest Binge drinking.
Fuck.
Hey, I can now make up for it.
Bastard!
Hi.
How was it?
It is really a great woman.
And do you carry it in your bed tonight?
No. Is not quite so simple with her.
I'm the big bad wolf.
Oh, I see.
What do you have big ears?
I can hear you better!
And what do you have for a very big mouth.
Then I can kiss you better!
And what do you have for a loud bell?
I hear too often.
Would you please open times? I have absolutely no desire to fact.
Who can that be?
I have no idea. I do not care.
Jacky?
Has a key.
Okay. I'll get it.
Oh, you is very good.
Hello?
Mama? Mama?
You have to get out of here. - Way? Why?
Yes, because I say so, go!
But how? I can not fly yet.
Maybe over the balcony.
Good idea.
Tell me, are you crazy? I'm not an acrobat.
Then pretend you were one!
Mama? Mama!
And, and.
Ah. Hey.
Hey, surprise. Were you still in bed?
Yes, I'm taking a nap.
But what are you doing here?
Oh, the weather was so awful at home.
What? Really?
Ein tolles Apartment, echt.
Yeah, pretty, is not it? And such a beautiful view.
I put my things sometimes just in the bedroom, that's okay?
No, the Deputy things only to the bathroom,
I can now quickly clean up the bedroom.
Are you still not gone? Get out on the spot. Get out!
I have a surprise for you. Should I give it to you right?
This is much too high.
Just because someone fell from the balcony?
But never. How do you say that?
How disgusting.
What's this?
This is a boy.
No, this is from a man
Oh. Is he a good guy?
No, a man Young man
Also our Callboy.
Oh, where do you think they going, child? He's just a nice young man
It was a one-night stand. So that is it?
You want a drink?
Yes. Mom, are you drinking again but not too much sherry, right?
Are you crazy? Do you know what it costs here?
A simple glass of water already costs 17 euros.
Oh, hallo!
Hey Maartje! - Hallo Jacky.
Hallo, ich bin Irma. - Hola.
What did he say?
I do not care. I did not intend to chat with him.
Well, welcome to Ibiza.
What was that for a fucking boat? I am kotzübel. Was totally stupid.
Terrible.
I think about you all the time.
I also.
Vom ersten Moment an.
As long as you're thinking of me?
Kevvie! Kevvie, das Tor ist kaputt.
Kevvie!
Kevvie, where have you been so long? Why do you make me wait?
I just had a meeting. For your birthday.
And you can still make use of this, the lesbian?
My birthday is tomorrow and you see nothing.
You will never forget this day.
Kevvie. You hot striker, du
Elza, look.
You're on the front page. - "Stand before wedding?"
Oh, I look great. - What? Fuck.
Who told the press that? May!
You are in my fucking house and abusing my trust!
Hey, I like to alternate as best man available.
For when the wedding is planned for, and where you want to celebrate?
I did not do anything yet.
But the wedding must organize not miss this lesbian.
And I want to go to Las Vegas! Honey, look at this,
what is this pretty picture of me.
I have very clear ideas of our wedding.
The wedding dress must of course be quite exclusive.
Musst du ... ...
Can not you call your mothers? The always clarify everything.
No, this time you need to clarify that, Pop.
Okay. - So to see ...
Okay.
Is something wrong?
There is obviously stress between us you Zara.
Shit, who hath not even stress?
Pop. - Everyone has stress it out, right?
I was with Pim, so ... in bed.
Pim?
The man from Zara?
Baby. But you can get something much better.
I was there just like it.
You did of me.
And I got it from Jimi Hendrix.
Was?
Well, we made the stop as an artist. So David Bowie made that too,
and the people of Duran Duran, the boys from Wham ...
Well, that made it different again.
What did you do then?
I just thought that all of life is a game
the women, the drugs, the alcohol, everything, you know?
And if you wanted to have sex with the girlfriend of his brother,
then made to the newly easy. So what?
Zara should not have.
Yes, my goodness, a number with his brother,
what are we talking about here? But we no longer live in the Middle Ages.
Bieb.
I will iron out this shit for you, yes?
My treasure.
Sit down with us. - Shut up.
Bibi! You breasts loose bitch.
Girls, we should talk about it in peace.
Du Furie!
I'll make you cold!
Stop it! It was simply just sex.
Now I've got you, you bitch!
Beib are! You bitch!
Let's talk, girls!
Zara! Zara! There auf!
No!
Zara! Liebling!
Bitch! When I'm done with you, you never fuck again!
I ask you to stop but only once this old white Indians.
What? You shut your mouth yet!
Papa! - Lass mich!
Paps?
Hey, Dad.
Hello sweetie.
How are you?
I'm feeling like I had something to smoke weed a lot.
Say, is not you dizzy?
No.
I was almost one real father.
Oh my God. Is he dead?
Of course not, silly goose. He sleeps.
Okay, then this is perhaps the right time to time to talk.
Bieb!
But I'm not so much for speeches. - Oh no.
This time you are but for once for talking, okay?
Sorry. Es tut mir echt resourceful.
It was my fault, I started.
Was it fun?
No, actually it was over before I had removed the bikini.
Typical.
Irma!
If Voque makes the photos tomorrow morning, I'll get it yet. Why did you do it?
I called and they offered to bring it over.
I get them from the same.
Well, then maybe we can still talk to each other.
Why do you plan our relationship crises
always in the most important moments of my career?
Perhaps it's because you're always obnoxious at times.
Oh ...
Sorry.
And.
Fuck!
Comm. - And, and.
Hey. I am Lars. Your mother's friend.
No, you're not.
Comm, Maartje, wir gehen.
It simply makes no sense.
Hey! Did you come with me?
Do you find me pretty enough as a birthday child?
And as an engaged couple?
Sag was.
El oh, you look beautiful.
Let's party!
It's my birthday! - A great Birthday Girl.
Happy birthday!
What is? Why have not you done? You must hurry, man
Make you ready, or do not you?
Leave me alone.
Happy birthday to you...
Happy birthday! Partytime!
Yeah! Party today is done!
Yeah, well. A soccer player? Is that really reasonable?
I mean, they are like their balls. The air but only in their minds, right?
Dear, I truly believe that he has only kidding yourself.
So these people are now times.
You only want to have a little fun before they get married.
He is the first.
Was?
In you're in love?
Really?
And all the others were the ... - This is different.
I did not think such a thing is possible.
Wow.
Shit.
What are you doing?
Going out. Just like you.
Dad, you're only just fallen into the pool.
But I'm also just turned 55, and we now celebrate.
Okay. Stop it.
You put on this suit.
Since you have always a very nice ass it.
I'm still your father.
Yes, but a father with a nice ass.
Hallo? - Mama?
Hi, sweetheart.
Dad is so funny and he has been crying for hours.
What's going on? Did he say what, honey?
He is now sitting here with a lot of women with long legs,
and I think that he just wasted all your bikinis.
Is he now completely bonkers?
Boyd, Dylan, ihr Seid see section!
Hi.
Wo ist Jacky?
Do not know, no idea.
Well, thank you.
It's all organized. The dancers are ready.
Armin then hangs up the music for you, and when you come,
you and he projected onto a large screen and Elza.
You hand her your birthday gift and then, well ...
Have a nice evening, Kevin.
Hey, Lizzy, well worth it.
And we?
We are not. We had sex, and sex is not so important.
Everyone who comes to the island having sex.
But I would still see you, Lizzy.
You know what I want? I so want a boy like you,
but for me alone. Someone I can imagine my family.
For you.
What's this?
Ein Smartphone.
But I have already a new smartphone.
This is for your birthday.
And what about the marriage proposal?
Comes after. After the dancers.
But the penguins? - They can not.
Are they at another party?
No. Penguins tolerate no fireworks. I had to decide
Penguins or fireworks. I decided for the fireworks.
Come on finally! The whole world is watching us.
I do not want to.
I'm sorry.
Kevin! Kevin!
Real madness!
Zhivago!
Pim!
Zara.
What is this? What have you done with my bikinis, du ..
Quiet, calm down.
What? I will not calm down. I can not get it to Ibiza ...
Das ist and ... Hi.
Baby, your bikinis are fan-freaking-tastic.
I want to have on the cover of Beau Monde.
I'll take you stand out. Huge!
I thought I had to make up something.
And what shall become of us?
I would like to do more, as before.
Even though I travel through the world with a suitcase full of bikinis?
In a hundred go to Milan. And to China?
And thus will always be obnoxious?
Ja. Auch dann.
But do you want to stay with me?
I ...
Fred, turquoise fits much better to purple.
Zara,
do not throw it all away.
Jacky?
Jacky, I beg you ...
Lizzy!
Go back again, Kevin.
I will not let you go.
I was just what organized for you. Now go back again.
I can not go back.
You belong there, that is your life.
And where do you belong?
Not in your villa and not in your life.
Come here.
Do not do that
Lizzy!
Was?
I stand here and hold my heart in my hands. And I give it to you.
Please do not drop it.
I admit it: Jacky, I love you.
I do not hope that you also bring out the CD.
A good idea.
You know, no idea how it will run, Grandpa.
But if you want, we could just try.
Only on one condition: that you never call me again Grandpa.
Ist gut. Opa!
I do not belong to the villa.
Or in such a life.
Even if you were to score three goals in a single game,
still always with me you have to put out the garbage.
Nothing I'd rather do than that
Ibiza!
Elza!
This is for my bedside.
Despite the qualities of their manager ...
Up ... the two young DJs ...
On ... the DJ Olympus.
Hey, I've heard, you're both DJs.
I love DJs.
Pope?
Mama ist da!
Mama! Mama!
Hello, you two. Hey ...
Glad you're here. I missed you.
They are naked.
Naked and hungry.
Hungry like a lion!
Hey, Bursche.
Hey Lex, Happy Birthday. - Well, at last you put it in front of us times.
I've actually also you always want to try.
Really? - Yes.
Well, here it is for you.
Is the strong stuff.
Here tried this. It tastes delicious.
Oh dear, I'm so glad that I have you,
after this terrible time with this football player.
Thank you.
With us it is different. Because we have two really love each other.
We do not want to get married? Yes ...
Here, I'll help you.
Hello?
Hey?
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player