Tell us,
Smaranda!
It seems like Old Ene
is passing us by,
because sleep didn't come,
although we have tried.
Come on, quickly!
You know how to tell stories like
nobody else, fairytales and jokes. ..
l don't believe in fairytales!
Ha, ha,
so that's what you think!
Wait until you hear,
and you'll believe in my fairytale!
- No, I won't!
- Yes, you will!
- Shut up, you!
Let's all be quiet and
listen to the story!
They say once upon a time...
- What time?
- Long ago, somewhere, there was a wolf.
- Who was there?
- A wolf.
- And he was scarring everyone..
- What was he doing?
- You'll see!
- He was big and he had some teeth...
- He had some what?
- Teeth!
We like it, tell us more,
tell us what went on!
She's making fun of us,
nothing went on!
- Yes, it did!
- No, it didn't!
- Shut up, you!
Let's all be quiet and
listen to the story!
One day, my grandpa...
What was he like?
Like that. As he was walking
towards his village...
- What was he doing?
- Singing.
l don't know how
that happened...
- What was that?
- Happened.
He met with the wolf himself.
Oh, what happened to him?
The wolf said
stay still, I'm going to
eat you right away! 
Look, I'm staying ,
the old man said,
But, you see, I don't want to be eaten
just like that! 
It's you I'm going to eat! 
You're bragging!
You have no teeth!"
You may think l have no teeth! 
Let's see who I'm talking with! 
The wolf widely opened his mouth,
and showed his teeth to the old man.
Then grandpa slightly threw his hand
Into the wolf's neck, this big!
He got to the poor wolf's tail,
Squeezing it so tight, therefore,
Just like that, he turned
the wolf inside - out!
My, oh, my, what a
power your grandpa had!
Even with a big fortune,
I don't believe a thing!
Perhaps it's unbelievable,
It happened long time ago,
Back when the fairytale goddess
Appeared, doing wonders.
It happened long time ago,
Back when the wolf was deaf,
But now, you must leave me alone,
It's time to go to bed!
A fairytale goddess is what
I'd like to see someday,
A fairytale goddess,
to see her coming in my way!
Never mind,
just listen to her,
I still don't believe a word!
Let's just all go to bed!
Ha, ha, look at her,
She could even sleep up on her feet!
There were also other times,
- I must tell you that.
- Tell us!
When grandpa was a child,
Little like you, even more,
How thin he was those days!
And he was handsome too!
He listened to the older ones,
Being respectful too,
And because he was so happy,
He would always run away.
So it was that one sweet day,
The dandelion- fairy came,
With the bag of wonders!
With one look she charmed me,
And laying her hand on him,
She put a spell that he would always win.
Yeah, yeah!
He seemed like he was dreaming,
looking at her amazed.
- A brave bag, I've never heard such thing!
- Shut up, you!
A story is a story, believe it or not,
We'll take it as you told us...
But what about the wolf?
He was left like that,
with the inside out.
But he kept on running, screaming,
and then running,
Then he would rest a while,
screaming like a child...
Hey!
A noise in the house,
what could it be?
A man from outside,
or a ghost, maybe?
At night, it is normal
to be very quiet!
I must see what happened,
and why is there light?
Ah, what's going on here?
Up-stairs and not
a word spoken!
Up!
What is it?
Why isn't everyone
sleeping at this hour?
Why, why, why?
Why isn't the window
shut up very well?
Why, why, why?
Why was there a screaming,
just like in the woods?
Why, why, why?
Girl, why do you stay with
your mouth opened wide?
Why, why, why?
Go to bed,
go to bed right away!
Look at me, look at me,
I'm in bed already!
Why do you tell stories
wit animals at night?
Why, why, why?
Why does so much dirt
come out of your duster?
Why, why, why?
Why, is the pillow on your
head when you're near me?
Why, why, why?
I want you to leave this
house right this morning!
Why, why, why?
Everybody, everybody,
go to bed!
Please, please, please,
forgive her!
You have to remember,
tomorrow it's your birthday,
But you weren't nice,
so we won't celebrate you!
Then, would you please,
at least make a cake for me?
It is not your birthday!
But I want it to be now!
Hurray, girls,
today it's my birthday!
Hurray girls, hurry!
Hurray, girls,
today it's my birthday!
So, what, you've been punished list night!
He, he, he!
Good morning, here,
comes the milk!
Who is in charge with the bread?
Good morning!
Excuse me!
A gardener told me this morning,
That, in the house,
among the children,
We might celebrate a birthday?
What we should do?
l have a suggestion to make:
I could even bake a cake.
Even if it isn't big!
You won't bake a thing!
The celebrated child
is Veronica today.
I still won't make
the cake anyway!
- But she has no one in this world!
- To bad!
Poor little girl!
Not even the smallest cake!
What!
No way!
We've all been kids someday,
Little children, just like them.
But when we had our birthdays,
There were no cakes for us those days.
One little mistake we made:
breaking something, broking something...
Our mother had her way
In showing us how to behave!
She was doing the right thing!
For playing, laughing
and singing along,
l don't see the guilt!
I said l won't bake a thing!
Where's the flour, where did I put it?
You're standing rig ht next to it!
Be careful when you're mixing!
I said I won't bake a thing!
We weren't receiving any present.
A present?
An egg, please!
Be careful when you're mixing!
Don't teach me how to do it!
If I hang around my mother
Speaking loudly, she would spank me.
She was doing the right thing!
Add some sugar on the top,
To make it even tastier,
I know how to make it good,
But I don't want to do it!
Besides, a promise is a promise.
I said I won't bake a thing!
All this time you kept bugging me,
And, look what we've got here!
Happy Birthday to you!
Happy Birthday, Veronica,
be always happy as today!
we wish you all the joy,
Happy Birthday, Veronica,
we wish you all the luck,
Now blow off the candles,
let's see if you can do that.
lf l were her, I would blow,
And instantly I'd cut the cake!
For how long will she wait?
We want to eat the cake!
Happy Birthday!
- Blow off, blow off!
- Blow off!
Blow off, off, off!
Veronica, Veronica,
you're a brave, good, little girl,
This is why my gift for
you is this pretty little bag!
It is full of good advices,
it is magical, you'll see!
It can teach you lots of things,
only if you'll listen to it!
It can belong to anyone, to him,
to you, but only if one day,
You'll all be able to say:
I'm hard- working, I'm brave,
and I'm kind. Respectful
and nice, I can be anytime! 
It is full of good advices,
and in any circumstance,
It can teach you lots of things,
only if you'll listen to it!
It's a present you can
get only on a special day
Because it's a magic bag!
It is yours, Veronica!
It can belong to anyone, to him,
to you, but only if one day,
You'll be able to say:
I'm hard- working, I'm rave,
and I'm kind. Respectful and
nice, I can be anytime! 
It is full of good advices,
and in any circumstance
It can teach you lots of things,
only if you'll listen to it!
It's a present you can get
only on a special day,
Because it's a magic bag!
It is yours, Veronica!
Fairy Goddess,
I'm so happy
For this joy that you have brought me!
And I thank you for the present,
I will always listen to it!
- She's gone!
- I know where she went!
No, you don't, she went...
l won't tell where.
- Big deal! A bag is a bag!
- What could be so interesting?
It can only make a wonder,
like I would believe a thing!
Hey, don't be naughty!
- What are you gossiping about?
- Who spoke?
It's me, the magic bag,
and I'm here for you to see
How wonderful I can be.
I'm a bag, and I'm charmed,
Like no bag in the world.
A wish, in a moment,
If you want, I can fulfill!
Oh, how I enjoy sometimes
Singing, dancing,
telling jokes,
I'm a magic little bag,
If you want,
I'll prove it now.
A minute, if l could ask you
To hold your eyes shut,
That's right, at least try!
Set free all of your
thoughts and your dreams,
And you will see right away,
that I guessed!
Now here is your
dream that's fulfilled.
Like a brave man from the story,
On top of the horse you are flying!
If you give me just one second,
But where is the cake?
Who ate it?
It can belong to anyone, to him,
to you, but only if one day,
You'll be able to say:
I'm hard- working, I'm rave,
and I'm kind. Respectful and nice,
I can be anytime!
Veronica, Veronica,
such a nice and tender girl,
From now on you are my master,
all your dreams I will fulfill!
But I feel that you still doubt me,
you still keep the thought in your mind.
Oh, don't try to hide it from me,
I can read it in your eyes!
I want the spring to come!
- What did she say?
- Shut up, you!
What did you say, Veronica?
Here comes the spring time,
all over hills and fields,
The whole wide place is
filled up with all the joy it brings.
The orchards are rejoicing
of all the songs we sing,
Oh spring, give us a sign,
if you hear our welcoming!
if you hear our welcoming! 
Here comes the spring time,
in spinach you should fall!
'Till the evening comes,
I'll clean the house by then!
Everything is ready now,
and about the spinach,
'Till it's boiling in the bowl,
I will play sotron!
Instead of playing now sotron,
you should watch the bowl!
Here comes the spring time,
the sky has no more clouds,
Look at my crown of flowers,
it seems more beautiful!
Nobody will dare today
to laugh in my face,
- l have by far the best voice!
- You sing with your nose!
I think you'll become an as,
at the double bass!
Be careful,
keep your head straight!
Here comes the spring time,
And I will learn to fly,
I still need a clock,
to wake me up in time!
I think we should have
by now a new set of fur.
- Hey, wait, where are you going?
-I want to get some sleepers.
I want my sleepers to be red,
So I could dance with them!
Here comes the spring time,
on the wings of wind,
I'll take the violin,
and learn how to sing!
Pop music is my life,
because I love it so much.
- Sing us something, anything!
- Beee, e, e...
- Any other lyrics?
- Beee, e, a...
Here comes the spring time,
with flowers everywhere,
The whole place is dressing
up in clothes of holyday!
The world is yours today,
So, smile while you're a child,
Everywhere you look, you'll
see people sing and dance!
Oh, little magic bag, look
at the bird how she flies,
Under the deep blue sky,
oh, how I wish I could fly!
Make me, little bag, so small,
and so light, just like a fly,
Like an arrow, like a swallow,
I would fly towards the sun,
Higher and higher, on the wings
of wind, the silver clouds to see!
Higher and higher,
higher and higher,
Oh, how great it feels!
I like it, I like it,
just like a dream it is!
She can fly!
Look at her!
Higher and higher, on the wings
of wind, the silver clouds to see!
Higher and higher,
higher and higher,
Oh, how great it feels!
I like it, I like it, just
like a dream it is!
Give it to me, too!
This is it!
It is mine and this it!
l won't give it.
Please, would you
lend me the bag?
l won't do anything to it!
I won't give it and that's it!
But I want to fly too!
l won't give the bag to you!
But please, won't you
give it just a bit?
I promise I won't ruin it!
Veronica, Veronica,
I believed you were a nice girl!
You are changed now,
and it hurts me,
- I can't stand seeing you like that!
- Magic bag! Don't leave!
You hurt me. I'm leaving,
so long and good bye!
From now on, you'll have
to find your own way.
You'll have to embrace some
paths full of silence,
That's when your thoughts
will crawl back to me.
The Fairytale Goddess
is asking me to leave you.
To go away from you.
I must fly away,
somewhere in the sky,
But when you deserve it,
you'll easily find me!
My little bag!
Don't leave!
Wait!
My little bag!
Don't leave!
Wait!
Don't leave, little bag!
My little bag!
- Who is there?
What am
to do?!
Look at here!
Such a little girl alone in the woods!
Why is she crying?
What happened to her?
She must have come after
wild strawberries, blackberries,
And perhaps she forgot the way home.
Hello,
I'm the Glow Worm,
And, as you can see,
I'm a piece from a star.
l have come to bring hope,
and to lighten your way anytime!
You will never see me sad!
This is me,
I'm always happy!
Would you like me to come closer?
Hold your hand,
but what a sad little girl.
And why is that?
l have lost my little bag,
The Fairytale Goddess gave it to me!
But you should better
tell me about you!
As I said before,
I am the Glow Worm,
And if you want to
come into my world,
If you want to be small,
All you'll have to do
is repeat after me:
Tiribomb, ciribomb, tiribomb!
Three times over your head,
halei - hop!
Tiribomb, ciribomb, tiribomb,
Where's the Goddess?
Where's my bag? Where are they?
Both of them, I guess,
are far away,
In a world where the sun
is always shining,
But I don't belong there, anyway!
I am the Glow Worm,
As you can see,
I'm a piece from a star.
And I can fly only at night.
What am Ito do,
because this is my life!
Tears are no good,
You should always be happy!
You'll always find a friend in me
to help you when you are in need!
You poor, little girl,
Whenever you want to call,
I'll come, no matter how far,
A whistle is my signal!
We are the inseparable brothers,
And if you want to meet us,
You should come in the woods!
Although we have a bad reputation
And we sing about our enemies,
We're hiding behind the nettles.
After they catch us cheat,
We always start to sing:
Bu - bu - bunny, we have
no fear of the enemy!
We are among the coward ones!
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Raven, dear!
Why are you in such a hurry?
Excuse me,
I don't think! know you!
How dare you?
You will get to know me!
Hey, old raven!
How was your
stealing today, dear fox?
Me stealing?
You're offending me!
Am I stealing?
Of course you are!
It's you!
How dare you speak
to me Ii e that?
It never happened
to me such a thing!
It is only by honest
work, that I live!
The whole forest knows it!
Almost everyone knows me!
Day by day, life in the woods
Becomes harder and harder to live!
The raven isn't used to steal.
But me, if l don't cheat,
I have nothing to eat!
When I see you walking slowly,
You are so full of yourself,
But one day I'll leave you
without feathers, yes, I swear!
You, where did you come from?
I'm looking for the Fairy Goddess,
To cry and ask for forgiveness!
Because I was mean and selfish,
I want to beg her,
to give me back the bag,
with its magic power.
All my sadness would be gone,
I want to play with the other children.
There's no such thing as magic bag!
But if it were, it would be
first an object in my house!
Of course it's true
what happened then,
And no one's guilty as I am!
She's a mean goddess!
No, she isn't!
And she taught me this:
A minute, if l could ask,
Hold your eyes shut.
That's right. At least try!
Set free all of your thoughts and dreams,
And you will see right away
that I guessed,
Now here is your
dream that's fulfilled!
This girl seems
to be pretty smart!
What if I took her in my class?
To help me at my
business  sometimes.
Or else, I don't know
what she could do!
I really don't know
what happened to me,
I admit I begin to like you!
I could keep you all
summer with me, if you want!
Now tell me, what
do you know to do?
Do you know how to steal?
Do you know how to lie?
Or maybe you know how
to flatter someone!
Do you know how to sneak
with the pray through the brushwood,
Without even making a noise?
- Do you know how to steal?
- I don't know how to steal!
- Do you know how to lie?
- I don't know how to lie!
Or, maybe you know
what revenge means?
Don't worry,
I'll teach you some things,
Because I'm the master
of all these tricks!
I want to go to the bag
and the Goddess!
This isn't hard at all, little girl,
Come on, come with me,
and just take my hand!
If you listen to me,
I'll help you myself,
I will protect you
from any danger,
When you're in need,
I'll keep you safe!
But only if you promise me
That you will always listen to me.
- And you would steal!
- Yes, I will steal!
- And you would lie!
- Yes, I would lie!
And you'd learn how to flatter,
- And also be sneaky...
- Yes, I'll be sneaky!
- Through the brushwood...
With the pray you would come,
Any word is a vow.
From now on, you must
only listen to me!
Don't worry, I'll teach
you some things,
Because I'm the master
of all these tricks!
- Are you with me?
- I'm with you!
She's with you!
Now listen carefully:
Your face must seem
so innocent,
When you prepare
to play the trick.
Did you see?
They really thought
that I was sick!
To know how to act,
and when to pretend,
It is indeed the biggest art!
What are you doing?
Look over here!
Don't run so fast,
there is no need!
Don't worry, I'll teach
you some things,
Because I'm the master
of all these tricks!
Look over here!
A green, stupid frog,
And my wish for a pickle
is starting to grow!
What do you want
to do with the bag?
Give it to her!
Oh, no, you won't, when
I've worked so hard to get it!
Such good smelling sausages!
Is that smoking ham?
It is!
What a flavour!
How to resist not stealing them
When the evening comes?
What have you learned
from what I've taught?
Right now you'll
give your first try!
Throughout the brushwood
you'll sneak with the pray,
- Without even making a noise!
- No noise!
Behold, here comes Danila!
He lives in his own world!
The entire wood is looking,
At the greatest fisher, now!
Mister Raven, with a cow- tow,
Tell me please,
what's going on?
You're not a bird,
you are a wonder,
Is it by magic that
you've changed?
Oh, milord,
what a beauty!
I've never seen
such thing before!
Your feathers seem
like pure gold!
You're simply gorgeous,
on my pride!
- Did you hear it?
- Yes, I heard it.
She has a hidden thought, the fox.
She will sing,
she will dance,
And let's see
what happens next!
You look so stunning,
even brighter...
Oh, it's the cheese
she's after now!
You look so stunning,
even brighter...
But the cheese is tastier!
You look so stunning,
even brighter,
but I've never heard
you sing before.
I bet that you can't sing at all.
Oh, its such a shame,
I'm dying with the thought of it.
My voice is very powerful,
And if l sing, I'm afraid
that I might kill!
Did you see?
Here, I proved it one more time!
You have to know
how to flatter him,
And it's the best
that you can leave!
I wasn't careful!
I wasn't smart!
It's with a flattery
that I got drunk!
Who knows,
maybe someday I will be
A hero from fable,
who knows, I might be!
Sure you will!
At last,
I see myself at home!
I feel so tired,
just a bit!
Still, I haven't brought anything,
Not even a chicken,
or a cockalorum.
But who knows?
Maybe next morning!
Maybe I'll have some more luck,
And in my way
I'll find a duck!
To eat it,
including the beak!
It's getting harder
and harder to be,
Versatile and careful,
To sneak each day,
To grab a chicken
as fast as you can!
You always have
to fight everyday,
The obstacles that
come in your way!
Night after night,
day after day!
To keep on smiling
throughout the bushes,
Throughout the brushwood,
Here comes another hunting day!
When will I see
my Fair Goddess again?
You don't deserve
yet such a thing!
Now, you must go
to the open road,
And wait there
for the cat to go.
As soon as he's left,
sneak in the garret!
And fast, you must steal
everything, all of it!
From the garret?
All of it!
Now I Runglo'
Mister!
The mouse Aurica!
Do you happen to know where Danila,
the famous cat lives?
I have a letter to deliver.
My name is Daniela, the cat,
And I'm the bravest of my kind!
I have no pity on the mice,
I keep them here, under my nose!
I see them; I hear them,
wherever they hide,
Even if they went to the Pole,
North or South!
My moves, they say,
are very fast.
I want my claws
to be the best!
My name is Danila, the cat,
And I'm the bravest
of my kind!
Mister cat,
I'm not your enemy,
I only brought
a letter to you!
What's in it?
Little maid, I'd have some work,
But what do you know
how to do, my dear?
I dust the floor,
and I even cook,
- I can dust...
- Never mind.
I think I need some help around.
Do you know how to drizzle
the flour and the maize?
- I would say... not really!
- You'll learn.
And now, please,
enter the house,
To see the place
you're working in!
My name is Daniela,
the cat
And my fist is like a mace.
I have no pity on the mice,
I'm the greatest cat of all!
I have to live again,
Now, remember how to drizzle,
Just listen carefully:
to the left...,
and to the right...
But, I really don't know
if I can.
My name is Danila,
the cat,
And I'm the bravest of my kind!
I have no pity on the mice,
I keep them here, under my nose.
With me they have no luck,
I don't like to play along!
I feel and hear everything,
And I grab them instantly!
My moves, they say,
are very fast.
I want my claws
to be the best!
My name is Danila,
the cat,
And I'm the bravest of my kind!
Be hard- working, did you hear?
Now start!
My, oh my,
how scared I am!
I have to run home,
But all the doors are locked,
And I cannot get out!
Locked in here, all by myself,
The cat wouldn't let me out!
I'm still small, that's my blame,
Oh, how hard became my fate!
Maybe for a little while
I'll forget about my fear!
I may be trapped here by the cat,
But I know how to become
even smaller than I am,
So, I could play with you, dear mice!
Tiribomb, ciribomb, tiribomb!
Three times over the head,
halei - hop!
Tiribomb, ciribomb, tiribomb!
Three times over the head,
halei - hop!
I have been chosen, my dear,
Among all the mice,
And I'm ready to present you
All of my friends!
As you can see, they are small,
You shouldn't be afraid!
There are many singers, dancers
In the who e wide world.
They are all mice, and they're my friends.
You have the chance to see a great show,
If you'd allow me
to present them:
The lead singer:
do - do - crunch,
Re - re - crunch,
mi - mi - crunch,
The dancer:
sol - sol - sol!
She is la - la - crunch,
The passionate guitarist,
The wonderful trombonist.
And the others, great actors,
As they stand in line!
Do - do - crunch,
Re - re - crunch,
Mi - mi - crunch,
Fa - fa - crunch,
Sol - sol - crunch,
La - la - crunch,
Ti - ti - crunch,
Do - do - crunch.
My name is Aurica
And I sing: Tra - la - la,
You've never seen me sad,
Tra - la - la- la.
If you listen to me,
You will know our story!
- Tell me!
- We are afraid of the cat!
When he's mad?
- He's a real dictator...
- He is angry too...
But the truth has come to light:
That he is fool and vain!
This is why,
when he is gone,
You will see us
in his home!
The table,
what a stage becomes!
And we start
to sing and dance.
My name is Aurica,
And I sing Tra - la- la,
I'm always happy,
Tra - la - la,
Even if you have
worries and needs,
You should happy like us!
If you allow me:
Veronica,
Just a girl,
like any other,
It fulfills you any dream!
- What's it like?
- It's wonderful!
It only comes once
in your life.
Please, tell us
one more time,
What's it like,
the magic bag?
Just a second, that's it,
If you hold your eyes shut,
The thing that you wished for
Is there in your face!
Anything that crossed your mind,
My bag would surely guess!
Take me with you, Veronica!
I want to go so far from here!
Maybe in our way we'll find
The Dandelion Fairy!
And now let's sing and dance!
Aren't you afraid of Danila?
Danila?
Of him we have no fear!
Let us all sing in choir!
Come on, bite, and bite!
Look in here,
great Danila!
the bravest cat!
I hear and smell from faraway,
And instantly I grab the pray! 
But he doesn't see me,
when I'm three meters far.
What luck!
So, slowly through the bushes,
now I will disappear!
My name is Danila,
the cat,
And I'm the bravest
of my kind!
I have the keenest eyes by far,
It's on the flue that
I have my house!
I don't run from mice,
I simply can't get them!
And I would like to make all of them
My friends!
My name is Danila,
the cat
And I went hunting
in the woods
I have no pity
on the mice.
Let's sing along together:
Do - do - crunch,
Re - re - crunch,
Mi - mi - crunch,
Fa - fa - crunch,
Sol - sol - crunch,
La - la - crunch,
TI - ti - crunch,
Do - do - crunch!
When the cat is gone,
The mice are on the table,
Life is so beautiful!
I would like some face powder,
So I could put some make- up on!
And so, in the flash- light,
I will sing for you all!
If the cat had bells
at her neck, to ring,
At night, a lot of mice
would keep her company!
But if she did the house- keeping,
Oh, how much trouble
would there be!
Throughout the house,
there are a lot of mice,
They could fall from any
corner right into her mouth!
But, there is no
if  for us, it is not our cat!
If the cat bells at
her neck, to ring,
At night, a lot of mice
would keep her company!
Life is beautiful,
and I'd keep on singing
From all my heart!
I forgot about the cat!
He is stubborn, and so mean!
I forgot it in a second,
Singing here with you!
When the cat is gone,
The mice are on the table,
Make room on the stage of the mill,
For, the dancers are coming!
And when we know the cat is gone,
You should see his home!
On the table up we jump
And we dance a ct!
Life is so beautiful and I'd keep on singing
From all my heart!
Hey, Miss Fox,
are you home?
I just want to have a word!
Have you come through all this heat
Only for a word?
So that you know,
I don't want to joke!
Today I am very upset!
Upset?
And for what reason?
- Hey, fox, you stole from me!
- How?
Yes, indeed,
you stole from me!
Look, my bag is empty!
I swear on what
I have more sacred,
I didn't steal a thing!
But what's flying in the wind?
- You will pay for it!
- What will I pay?
- Thirty fishes!
- Thirty fishes?
And on the top,
you'll get a fee!
I will tell you right away
Who tried to steal from you.
If I missed eating a fish
I would simply ask you.
And I would give
it if you asked me.
I'm not capable of stealing!
Bu I think! know who did it!
- That little girl...
- Veronica?
You should come
along with me,
To see the revenge
I'm going to take!
Mad, but fine!
Everybody,
everybody!
There is only one like Aurica,
And he has no fear at all!
Everybody, everybody!
Call all the cats in here,
To beat them and
to take their money,
Everybody, everybody!
When the cat is gone,
The mice are in the house.
Oh, how life is nice!
Everybody, everybody,
You say you sleep,
you say you're sick,
He thinks he's great,
just look at him!
Everybody, everybody,
On your poor little claws,
I wouldn't give a thing!
Everybody!
Why are you running from Danila?
I wouldn't harm you anyway!
You know how
I've always wished
For us to be best friends!
You know how much I care
For all the little mice, right?
And I've always wished them,
Only the best!
Is that so?
But who believes you?
I swear on what I've got!
I don't believe a
word you're saying,
You're just a cat!
Where is he?
He's gone.
Where, where is he?
He's, he's gone.
Where could be the big cat?
Let's go, let's go,
Let's go and find him!
He is dead, he is dead,
he is dead!
So what, so what,
so what?
- He is dead!
- So what?
He is dead!
Mercy !
Mercy!
Among all you must know best,
It was you,
It was you
I loved the most!
I hear?
Mercy!
Our cat is dying here!
We must go and save him!
We're not going anywhere!
Come with us, all of you!
Let's go and save him!
Oh, no!
Come!
Poor cat!
Let him die!
Oh my! Oh my!
He deserved it,
he deserved it,
He isn't worth saving!
We will go, we will go'
We want to save the cat!
To bad!
- Not that bad!
- Yes, it's bad!
- Aurica!
- Some space, please!
If I am to save your soul,
What will be,
what will be,
My...reward?
Mercy!
Oh, how low
your voice is now!
Mercy!
Your clock is ticking faster,
And if l am to save your soul...
Save me at once!
Which will be my reward?
Aurica, save me, please!
I want you to give your word
That you would leave us alone,
And you would keep the pact,
no matter what!
I swear I would do that!
I would never touch a mouse,
I would never harm them,
And in any circumstance,
I'd even protect them!
You gave your word, Danila,
That you'd leave us alone!
I'll know how to keep the vow,
If I could only be free at last!
Do - do - rup,
Re- re- rap,
Mi - mi - rup,
Fa - fa - rap,
Sol - sol - rup,
La - la - rap,
Ti - ti - rup,
Do - do - rap!
A pact made when in need,
To get rid of the pain!
The cat won't change
his way of life,
He's still our enemy!
My name is Danila, the cat,
But 'till now,
I've been to kind
Tolerating you!
I'm sick!
From now on,
I'll have no mercy,
And you'll see at once,
I will get my vengeance,
And you'll all be gone!
I have no pity on the mice,
I even made a plan,
My name is Danila, the cat,
And I'm the greatest of my kind!
With me, they have no luck,
For I don't play at all!
And I have no thought
of letting go of it!
Oh, everybody,
come and see
The bravest of my kind!
My name is Danila, the cat,
And I'm going to get rid
Of the enemies, you'll see!
I'll teach you good!
Veronica, Veronica,
You are such a nice girl,
Is there any hope?
To save little Aurica,
What are we to do?
We are small!
Wait, I've got an idea,
Right away I'll send the message,
And in a second
should appear,
Tiri - biri, the Glow Worm,
Sleep tight, sleep tight,
little cat!
I want you to sleep very deep!
Sleep tight, sleep tight,
little cat,
So I can get out of here!
Help!
She got away!
Wait!
Let me keep it straight!
It's so quiet in the woods,
I'm starting to be afraid...
Who knows, maybe an enemy
Might come along and steal me!
There's nobody next to me,
I've lost little Aurica,
Miss Fox lied to me,
I was afraid of the cat!
A lost child, a poor child,
Will make a hammock in the tree,
Because she didn't listen
to the good advice,
She is far away from her home.
It's so quiet in the woods,
The moon seems even bigger,
The stars are running slowly,
Everything is so astounding!
There's nobody here to tell me
Before I went to bed:
Good night'! Veronica!
Sleep tight , Veronica!
It's me, the Glow Worm
And, as you can see,
I'm a piece from a star!
Sleep tight, good nig ht!
Sleep tight, sleep tight, my dear!
I'll be hear, beside you,
And watch your restful sleep!
But I want the little bag
Be patient, she might sleep!
A minute if l could ask you
To hold your eyes shut:
That's right, at least try,
Set free all of your
thoughts and your dreams,
And you'll see right
away that I guessed!
Now, here is your
dream that's fulfilled!
Veronica, Veronica,
now forget of all the sadness!
I have brought the magic
bag once again, it is my gift!
Don't stay, run and play!
Live, don't dream of fairytales!
Halei - hop,
halei - hop!
Over your head,
With the magic little bag,
You'll fly all around the world!
And, whenever you are sad,
Dreaming will save the day!
Here comes the spring time,
with flowers everywhere,
And there's no time for dreaming;
When the whole world is yours!
Laugh with me, childhood,
Everywhere the children
sing and dance,
It can belong to anyone,
to him, to you,
But only if one day,
you'll be able to say:
I'm hard working,
I'm brave and I'm kind,
Respectful and nice,
I can be anytime!
Veronica, Veronica,
keep on dreaming and be happy,
any dream might become true!
Veronica, Veronica,
life can be so beautiful,
all the time you should rejoice!