Comrade
- Elena Pavlovna, please. - Yes...
-Says Captain Pancakes. I brought you a package.
-When is it convenient to deliver it?
-When you want, you can now.
-Better now, I’m on my way on vacation.
-Come, I'm waiting.
-Good.
-Who do you have?
-Elena Pavlovna Zhuravleva.
- And she left. - How? - Gone.
- I just spoke to her on the phone, she promised ...
-Hee. She promised ... She promised and left.
- She promised to pay for the light, and did not pay.
- Good. “Can I leave this package for her?”
-Not. I do not know what is in this package.
And I do not take responsibility.
- Here are the books. - Not.
-Listen ...
And you call. Maybe she will promise you something else.
The station.
-Shur, do you want carrots?
Then I’ll eat it myself.
- Well, you have teeth, mother.
- Well, I’m doing my own, natural. And you two are missing.
- Such water in the mountains, mother.
-Water ... You are your family matter,
do you think ever allow in the near future?
- Yes, I should. And the authorities recommend.
- Do you even have a girlfriend?
Huh?
We have one on the farm. She earns experience.
- He wants to do. -Where? - To the institute, where.
-Well mother, come on a verbal portrait.
-Yes no portrait.
-Well describe her, what she is, so that he can find out on the street there in the library.
-Cute!
-Well, they are all pretty, while young. Exact parameters?
- What? - Growth.
- And like this. - So 1.72 m. Breast size?
- Well, how can that be about a girl?
-Well, wait mother. If there is a girl, she has breasts.
If there is a breast, it is a certain size. How do I recognize a girl then?
- In! -Not exactly. Well, and special signs? - Little black one.
-Today is black, tomorrow is red-haired, not ...
-But it's not in your city. We have everything natural!
- But there are special signs. There is. - Well ka?
- She has a scar above her left brow. - A scar?
-When she was small, she fell off the porch.
-Hmmm ... what are you mother ...
- Do you palm off on me nuts? - Well, what are you, what are you?
- Well, just fell off - it means hit, and not with anything, but with the head.
- You say yourself, there is a scar. - Well ...
-And when a person hits his head, the consequences can affect after many years, mother.
- Shura ... - Ah ...
-A fool you are Shura, not a commander!
Oh mother, mother ...
- Mother? - AND...
- Where are you? - Yes, here I am.
- What are you doing? - I'm watching TV. - Yeah.
What if I ...
will I go for a walk?
- Go for a walk. - So.
Where is my white t-shirt?
Sorry uncle.
Song: "Rejoice at the people around, Do not rush to judge them.
If a friend called you - hurry to help.
Will you meet many good friends in your life
Good and honest friends. Goodbye!"
-Health Sanya. Came on vacation, home?
Hello to mom. Do not forget mother, you come in!
- OK Bye. - Be healthy!
Hello.
- Hello, Elena Pavlovna, please. - Yes...
-Says Captain Blinov, I have an assignment for you.
-And where did you go then?
- I was told that you are not at home!
I could not wait, the train was leaving me.
Now I am 54 kilometers from the city, the village of Krutoe.
When is it convenient for you to bring the package?
- Can you come now?
-Well, that's right.
Hello, I’m to Zhuravleva Elena Pavlovna ...
There is no such!
- Well, how is it not? This is me, hello. - Hello.
“Comrade, why are you misinforming?” - Listen, you know what ...
such people should not be on earth.
- Such as you should not be on earth. - Shut up!
- Yeah of course. - What are you doing?
-Allow comrade. Allow, allow.
-Well, what have you done?
- Everything is washed here ... Hooligan. - Come on in.
Do you have a tense relationship with a neighbor?
We have a war here!
- Come on in. - Thank.
-Sit down. You want to put it there.
Let's have breakfast. I had breakfast.
- No, no thanks. “Why, you are off the road.”
- How is my girlfriend? - Good.
- And how is her wonderful husband? “Ah ... already major.”
- Yeah. You don’t have a cup now.
-And why does a friend think that you should not be on earth?
-Because I smoke.
Because I listen to music that he doesn't like.
Thirdly, I am divorced.
And most importantly, he considers me a parasite.
When I explain to him that I am the face of a free profession ...
-Enough.
-He giggles disgustingly, apparently confused with the most ancient professions.
- And what ... - I have a profession?
I am a photojournalist. True, contingent.
But I can show help.
- No, I believe you, what do you ... - No, I can, why not?
I have it.
Please, here.
- Zhuravlyova ...
-Elena Pavlovna, artist-photographer, -Yeah, it's me.
Freelance correspondent, annual income of 600 rubles.
- So what? -Not much. “But what is it to him?”
The main thing is help. Yes? I then earn some more.
So now, I'm in a hurry to work.
I'm in a hurry to work.
No, you are sitting, sitting calmly.
But have you seen this?
- He tweaks. - How?
-Like this. And so it sneaks up, like it tweaks.
- Ah ... What are you? - What about me? What can I do?
What can I do? He's big and strong.
Very brutal. He used to be a great boss,
and then they shoved him into retirement.
And the wife left him, along with the apartment.
I complained to the police, but they do not believe me.
They don’t believe me. Spoken: Such a person cannot pinch.
“But he is pinching it!” - OK OK. - Yeah.
-Clear.
-And what documents do you have?
-I have? ID cards, here.
-The State Security Committee ... What you need!
- And what ... Why? “I need help.” -I AM...
don't understand now?
-You don't need to understand anything. Just...
you need to protect me if he tries to hit me.
- Will you hit? - Yeah.
- Well, in that case, you can count on my help.
- Then let's go? - Where? -There.
-AND?
-Go ... What is this?
- Elena Pavlovna, what are you doing? “It hurts, what are you doing?”
- Let go, let go! - Elena Pavlovna, what are you doing?
-I demand! What's this? Together for one?
-Stop it! What are you doing, calm down in the end, calm down comrade.
- Calm down! - I've calmed down.
-Sorry, I didn’t assume that everything would turn out like that.
-Now you will see how all this will turn out for you!
Now you will see, now you will see!
- Listen, comrade ... - Now you will see ...
Police ... Assault in the apartment ...
Yes! Robbery attack with self-mutilation.
Yes! Izverskaya 8, apartment 25. Urgent, urgent, let's get here!
-Well, how is our neighbor?
- You put me in a difficult position, Elena Pavlovna!
-And nobody will believe him anyway!
So that you, a border guard officer, take part in an apartment brawl? Yes, never.
-He blocked the exit.
-So now, the police will come.
Something I lost. I'm so forgetful.
Ah ... a tripod.
- ABOUT! Already! - I wish you good health ...
What do you have?
- You have to pay for pleasure! - Elena Pavlovna ...
-Let's go there, my captain.
-Here they are!
-So, you are in your room, and you are in yours!
- Allow ... - Follow the order!
“Lieutenant, you and I are in the kitchen!” - Wait a minute ...
-Yes. I will ask the tenants into the corridor!
It’s a pity, Kondraty Petrovich, that I was mistaken in you.
“Who did you believe?” - We will naturally check ...
But I have no reason not to trust Captain Blinov.
-This is to which captain?
-Capitan border guard, Blinov Alexander Petrovich.
-Sorry, I didn’t have time to introduce myself to you, somehow everything was quick somehow.
-You can of course write a statement to your neighbor next,
but if a medical examination confirms that you have plucked it,
we will prosecute you.
- Clear? - Will write!
-Write. I have the honor!
“Have a good rest, Comrade Captain!” - Thank you lieutenant, all the best!
-We will consider the incident settled, comrade?
- Goodbye. - What did you say to the policeman?
- Really. I said that the situation was unclear, but I defended your honor.
- For the first time in my life they defend my honor, by the way, I always defend myself.
-I called the situation unclear, just because I myself don’t like arrogance and optionality,
and these elements in your behavior apparently took place.
- Oh, you are? - Yes, such! Goodbye! - Yeah, yeah.
Wait!
But I got excited.
-Yes Elena Pavlovna, you got excited!
- Here you go, and he will start again.
He’ll come up with something to leave no traces.
- Let me put you on a tape recorder? - Not understood?
- I will turn it on so that he thinks that you live with me.
I will include it during the day - as you say, and at night - how to snore.
-Listen, I do not snore.
-No, listen, but you have to help me!
No, well, I don’t have to ...
I'm just begging you! You must understand me.
- I ask. - Elena Pavlovna, I ...
-Maybe let's do that?
I will ask you questions, you will answer them.
Only loudly. So he thinks that we have ...
Long-standing and possibly intimate relationships.
-What actually may be questions?
- The most different and possibly pleasant.
Only you do not say monotonous: Yes, That,
Use all your vocabulary.
- Well ... - Good.
-Let's start?
Sasha, will you help me bring the equipment?
-Yes. Yes!
- She's so heavy.
-Sasha, are you leaving soon to guard the border?
-Naturally!
-Sasha, will you often write to me?
-Well ... Of course!
-And I will write to you every day!
Do you want to know how we are doing here?
- With Kondraty Petrovich! - And how!
-Kiss me on the track.
-Do you want to kiss me on the track?
-By itself!
- Hurry up, honey? - By all means!
- I hope you correctly understood this kiss? - Yes, I understood correctly.
-Maybe he peeps, and one sound would not be enough.
- I needed a picture. - It was witty.
-And you carry all this on yourself every day?
- The costs of equality, then no one will drag me.
- Do you like a profession? - I am doing this business out of principle.
-I.e?
-At the 3rd year of university, I jumped out to marry a fool.
He considered himself a brilliant photo artist.
I asked for school, washed for him, cooked.
Later...
She began to earn money on trifles, there was nothing to eat.
And he is a lazy person and mediocrity, I could not stand it, filed for divorce.
Fundamentally sued him half of the equipment.
After all, we bought it with my money.
And in vain began to take pictures.
His photos for our entire mating season have been published 3 times.
And I publish regularly, almost regularly.
So we have come.
Comrade Captain ... Let's go.
Sit here, I am now.
-M ... Hello.
- At last. - I'm ready.
-Look?
-Who?
- Did the fashion model forget?
- I didn’t get through to him.
- You're lying.
-But you don’t think so, I found it better.
-Where?
- Where? -There! - Yeah. - There.
Well let's go.
- Meet me please.
Blinov Alexander Petrovich.
-Very nice.
-Original?
Okay...
Wait.
-Maybe for a moment. You know, this girl needs help.
She alone is simply embarrassed to be photographed, and her partner got sick.
- Who got sick? -Partner. - Lena ... Come.
Karinochka, then you stretch him a tie and smile.
No, better put a hand on his shoulder.
Like this. Good. Now you. What team do you support?
- I AM? -Yes. - For Kiev Dynamo.
- So you smile as if your favorite team won.
Lena, so we will shoot.
-One second girl.
What's happening?
-Advertising ties. Karina, a hand on his shoulder.
-Don't, girl.
-Elena Pavlovna ... What's the matter? What's happening?
-And what? It is only 2 minutes.
-I will not advertise ties, I am an officer!
-So what?
-I don’t think that a border guard officer should replicate his image.
-Yes Yes Yes. Your image is very necessary for the enemies!
-I'm sorry, Pavlovna, this time I can’t help. Goodbye.
-Elena! If you think that I will endure your antics endlessly,
if you think that I will not find this place
more grateful and disciplined photographer ...
-Well what a knight? Deprived a woman of a piece of bread.
I lost a quarter, understand? A good place.
- On. - Oh, thank you.
I thought I won’t take it? Look, what is right, what is noble.
-What do you need, Grandma?
You, smoking women and a non-smoking man.
- You certainly are not smokers? - No, not a smoker.
- In Paris, nobody cares. “Have you been to Paris?”
-Never mind.
-If you speak objectively, then you yourself poorly organized this photography.
Personally you.
-Lena, I will help you, wait.
-Rest on vacation!
- Wait Lena, well, wait, I can’t ... - Oh yes, you are right with us!
- Let's. - Well then, hold on.
- And so where? -There. - There?
“Well, captain?”
- Is our army the most enduring in the world? - Of course.
- And this is where we arrived? - This is television.
- Do you work here?
- For now, yes. - Clear.
- Elena? - Now.
- Hello. - Hello.
- Who are you with? - Yes, he brought the equipment.
- Selected photos? - Yes master, everything was done by the master!
-Well clever.
I can’t help with the cottage, once. Until the evening?
It's a pity. Yeah.
- A colleague? - This is Lyadov.
Was recently abroad from central television.
-Lazarev. Most likely in Bengaba.
-Yes, how do you know?
- Hello. - Salute.
-Hi. Listen, come to me. There is work. So here it is.
-Good.
- Hi Elena! - Hello.
-Healthy.
Are you crazy or a fagot?
“Is that idiot yours?” - Mine, assistant.
- We must warn you.
-Sorry, I won’t be, but you don’t beat me anymore either.
- Okay? -Okay. - Thank.
-Well done! You defended my honor for the second time.
Only this man came in, sometimes tossed me a job.
-How much?
-Don't bring me up! I'll take the second quarter.
- Hello Seryozha. - Oh, hi.
“You don't have anyone with a car?” “Why only me?”
-Oh, hi!
-Well, tell me how you rested?
-Alexander Petrovich.
-Let's go.
- What are they here, all the relatives or what? - Why?
-Everybody kisses.
- Helen, who is it? - My assistant.
-Where next?
-Mouse.
- I would have a cabin, for about 20 minutes. - Do not ask for urgent development.
-Unload.
- I'll write to your superiors ...
To you, awarded an extraordinary vacation.
-Officers, extraordinary leave is not allowed.
-Clear.
- What is clear? “Everything is clear with you.”
- Edik, are you here? - Yes. In half an hour, not earlier.
-Then sit down.
- No, let's go get some coffee.
- Hello, are you on wheels today? “Not today, Helen.”
- Salute Polina. - Hi. - Can I go to you?
- Meet me now. - Alexander Petrovich.
- Why Petrovich? A techie or something? - Not understood?
- Of the engineers? “No, officer.”
“How did you not guess?” It’s written on you! - Yes?
-The current man by the age of 30 is already loose, and the warriors are in uniform.
- Are you a correspondent here too?
-Not. I am a translator from French, and here I work in an agricultural editorial office.
-In the agricultural editorial office?
-And today I got rich, help yourself!
Are you versed in agriculture?
In agriculture, in general, everyone understands.
- Earned 25 durik fish. - Tell me how?
- I will not say. - A military secret.
- May I take to my office? - Yeah.
“Polina, do you have any acquaintance with the car?” “You know what is not, that is not.”
- It's a pity. “Have you forgotten about the evening?” - Yeah.
-Goodbye.
“Do you have any problems?” - Yeah.
- You need to transfer maman with suitcases to the cottage.
But these are complex problems.
-Transport, plus male power.
- Well, male power is available, you can take a taxi.
-Maman does not like to spend money on taxis.
- However, today I am rich. - That's it.
- And here is our academic yard. - Academic?
Yes, I’m a professor’s daughter.
- And this is us. - Finally.
-I'm almost ready, but you're still gone.
-Elena, let's make up the flowers, cover the furniture.
- Mom, Vera Semyonovna. - Alexander Petrovich.
“Is he with us?” - With us.
-Sasha, please, get 2 suitcases from the mezzanine: Brown and black.
- Ma, it’s not so right away.
-Well, we are in a hurry.
- With pleasure, I will help you. Vera Semyonovna, Lena said that ...
You have a car, you give me the keys, I'll see if it starts up somehow.
- She certainly won't start ...
But still you look.
And then they will tell me: -Change the wheels. I change wheels.
They say to me: -Change the motor. I am changing the motor.
- Here are the keys. Garage in the yard.
- The first boxing. - Good.
-Sasha!
-Well, did our car go?
-Go, go, only the muffler fell off.
-Elena, our “Victory” went.
- Helen. We drive in our car.
To his dacha.
How happy your father, Leonid Aleksandrovich, would have lived.
You know Sasha, my husbands were ...
Scientific adversaries. And you would reconcile them.
I buried them nearby, it’s easier to care for the graves.
-Sasha. Or maybe we’ll visit them now?
“Better another time, mother.”
- Please, in our penates.
Here we have a little bit running.
Sasha, bring things here!
But first, let's eat.
I scored all kinds of food.
Elena, products in a blue bag.
Sasha, help me melt a samovar, okay?
- You are welcome. - Come with me.
Here we have water.
- No water. - No water? -Elena!
-No water. How many times have I told her: -I must come check.
- Do you have any instrument? - There is. -Not!
-Is there. Lena, where?
- Put the suitcase over there. And take out the dishes.
And collect all the covers.
-Hooray.
- And he's nothing kid. - Nothing, nothing.
- Now they are called - No problem.
All my life I dreamed about this.
-As far as I know, you always dreamed about the opposite.
Everyone knows who the woman is marrying
and about whom she dreams, she knows only.
-This is something new.
-If I got married a third time,
I would marry ... a real man.
There are a lot of things in pundits
undemanding, intelligent, earns a lot, but ...
to ...
- Repair the gates, it is not necessary to marry a carpenter.
-Fool you, I'm not talking about that.
-And you saw how he picked up our suitcases when we trudged with you to the car?
So you asked your Lyadov to help, but where is he?
But real men come to the rescue without any call themselves.
- Who is he? Of the engineers? “He is one of the officers.”
Border guard.
-I am not very familiar with this area.
But you know, I heard that it requires personal data.
-And you know Sasha,
we have a ridiculously progressive family.
My grandfather was a political prisoner.
In relatives of my second husband, there were a lot of Decembrists.
And Lenka, she was born on May 1.
-You would at least take a little walk here, breathe.
-No mother, once. I’m in 3 more places.
-Sorry, last event.
- What? -It seems an anniversary. - Allow me!
-Only request: There are no knightly things.
- The young man is here!
-There are 3 people here, first we pay.
-And what are your tasks here?
-Elena takes pictures,
and after a banquet, I will translate a new video in a close circle, foreign.
Yes, eat, you are an assistant. And this is a service table.
Yes, they will figure it out without you.
-Arrived.
- Maybe you’ll stop by for tea?
-Now 0:37, probably not convenient.
- It’s always convenient for me.
-If you allow me, I will come to you next time.
-Well, of course.
-And let me ... raise the equipment?
- Captain, where will you spend the night?
-I don’t know, I’ll come up with something.
- And you spend the night with me. - Like this? -So.
-This is even necessary. Let Kondratius think
that I live under the vigilant guard of the border troops.
Let's go.
- Honey, hurry up!
- I'll bed on the couch, and I’ll lie down behind the screen.
I will disappear early, you are the boss here.
I have an exit task.
And you will slam the door.
Go freshen up.
-I beg.
-Comrade captain ...
Since you are serious about Elena,
must warn you!
That while you are guarding the border, men go to it.
I'll pinch you now!
Lena, are you far off tomorrow?
-There are more than a hundred kilometers.
And most importantly - on the chaise.
First to Antievka, and then to collective farms.
-Clear.
-Elena Pavlovna ... you are on the phone.
Male voice.
-Yes?
I remember that we agreed.
I am very tired and there were different circumstances.
But you call and appear only when it is convenient for you.
Yeah.
As you want. Good night.
-Lena.
Can I still leave?
- No, you are. In no case.
-Well, you need to go home! Your mother will be worried!
-Call you!
- And the car is old. - What?
- The car is old. - Nothing, fix it!
- But I do not know. - Sit down!
-Sit down, sit down! Now we will wake up the whole district.
-What is the purpose of our business trip?
- We need to take a photo essay. - So.
-Well, 20-30 photos.
-The rubric they have is - "Business trip by letter."
“Is the letter calling on the road?” - That's it!
The essence of the matter is: Today, a rich harvest of apples?
So.
Saw in the market.
Well in the market - yes. Dried fruits are in the store.
- What? - I do not know.
-Because apples are not taken out, they spoil, they are fed to pigs.
-Why not exported?
-I do not know. But this is not order!
- Here on these disorders, we will hit. - I see.
-And often do you have like this?
-Listen, come on "You."
- Personally, I say “you,” only to people over 70.
- Well, let's try. - Yeah.
-You know Lena, you can swim here.
-And I don’t have a swimsuit.
-And we will divide the zones.
You are on the right side, and I am here, here.
- Good. - Come on.
-Me brings to you.
- Lena, it's shallow here. You stand up. - It carries me to you.
- Stand up, stand up, shallow.
- Guilty.
- I can’t do it against the tide.
- Well then ... You need to learn.
-Sweet suffering came to the gardens of our area.
If you spoil apples, do not worry.
Homemade apples on jam, tasty and nutritious foods.
Having previously cleared the fruits, touched by decay,
cut them into slices, and boil in boiling water for 10-20 minutes.
2 glasses of water, per 3 kilograms of fruit.
-We will be like everyone else.
“They pay attention to you.” - Yes? - Yeah.
- Not ... It's on you. - What are our plans?
-See local attractions and the unofficial part.
-Received!
- Take the flowers. - I take it. - Take it. -These ones.
-And maybe this one? This one is prettier.
- I like all the same. - Thank you.
- Thank. - To health.
“Captain, some people really like you.” - Thank.
Why don't you ask who?
To my mom.
“Why don't you ask how I feel about you?”
- In my opinion, they don’t ask about it.
-Then I’ll say it myself: I’m calm with you.
Only 2 days have passed, and I ask myself
how will I do without you.
- Are you afraid it? - Not.
-Sasha, do you have any principle? Fundamental or what?
Based on which you live.
A friend of mine, for example, has this:
-Don't rush to this tram, because the next one will come.
-And you have?
-You know, with my father,
there was a soldier’s mug, even from my grandfather.
There is an inscription on it: "Honestly serve - do not bother about anything."
-Well is it for military service?
-Well immediately: Army, army?
-Can...
serve a woman, friends ... business.
-I want to dance.
-Here, in my opinion ... they don’t dance.
- Ladies invite gentlemen.
- Yes? - White dance!
-Well, they invite ...
- And you dance well. - Thank.
- In general, everything you have done so far, you did not do so badly.
- Thank you! “I have to drink with you at the Brudershaft.”
- Here? - Only soft drinks. - Never mind.
-Tell me, do you want to shock those present?
-And what if I just want to kiss you?
Not for a neighbor, I'm for myself.
“Order something else?” “Of course I want apples.”
- Apple? - Yeah.
- There are so many dried fruit compotes. - Here.
“Life doesn't fit your rules, captain.”
-Well nothing. As our major says:
"Wait and see".
- Lena? -Yes. - Climb!
-Now 7:50, at 8:15 I am waiting for you downstairs in the buffet.
-What should you take?
-Cold veal, Roquefort cheese, orange juice and hot chocolate.
- I see, it means like this: Fried eggs and sour cream.
-Come on, I'm waiting for you downstairs!
-Good morning.
-Good.
- I ask you to! - Yeah. - What is the action plan?
- Do not know yet. - What needs to be removed?
-Well, let's say: Canning factory, where there is a line for the machine.
- Yeah.
-Warehouse where everything is littered with apples, they rot.
- Well, first you need to come to the authorities and introduce yourself.
-ABOUT. That's right!
-But no one wants to make quarrels out of the hut.
They will immediately give a command, and no one will let me go.
- But why? - They won’t let it go like that.
-Warehouse will be closed, storekeepers hurt,
and the pigs will roar with hunger in their pigsties.
-What is the plan of action?
-No one!
-So this way:
Each operation requires preparation, first of all - this is information.
If we don’t get it from the authorities,
we will get it from interested parties. I.e...
From the people.
- And what is it? - I bought a card.
- Terrain. - Yeah.
“Where did you spend the night?” - I AM?
In a good place.
-Well, how?
- Wonderful. Keep it washed. - Thank.
- So, the object that interests us the most is the Pobeda collective farm,
falling gardens, pigsties, everything is compactly located.
- How much time do you need? - Minutes 15-20.
- Pure time? - Pure time.
- Until they reach the board, 15 minutes will pass.
While they find the chairman or someone from the authorities, another good half an hour.
- Unless of course the chairman has a walkie-talkie. - Take a chance?
- Take a chance! - Map?
-Here. Here, here!
So.
- Object number 1: Gardens.
For the entire operation I give 3 minutes.
- Object number 2: Livestock complex.
- Get ready!
- Why are you shooting here? I ask: Who allowed to shoot?
-Lena. Gazik.
-Let's go, go, go Lena, go.
All the same, the chairman has a walkie-talkie.
-It seems to be surrendering.
"Wait!" "Stop telling you!" Wait!
-Discharge the device, give me the tape.
- What for? - Just in case.
- It's all? -All. - Good.
- Hello. - Hello.
-Let us invite you for a cup of tea.
“With pleasure, but ... we're in a hurry!”
-You have already done your work,
I think it would be impolite to leave just like that.
-Oh well. You go ahead, and we are behind you.
-Ha. I’d better follow you, and he will go ahead.
- Is he? - Yeah. - I will show the way.
-Welcome, and you too.
-Please pass.
Make yourself at home.
- You? -Hi. - What are you doing here? -And you?
- I’m shooting from the satirical department how the crop is dying in this economy.
-And I'm preparing material about the chairman of this advanced economy.
- This is Alexander Petrovich. - I see.
He helps me.
-Very dramatic.
- Sit down ... Colleagues.
- Thank. - Thank.
- Thank. - Enjoy your meal!
- Delicious. - Hello dear guests!
- These are my colleagues, Andrei Stepanovich. - I see.
- Bon appetit, as they say.
-Well?
As far as I understand, there was a mismatch, so what?
One, you know, came to praise me,
and you mean scolding. Well, it happens.
We are used to it. Thanks Light, thanks!
Yes friends, it’s a shame at the expense of apples. Rotting. And why?
They called us to understand, to grow gardens,
raise their productivity.
But with the construction of storage facilities, factories, a little late.
And this is not only with us.
So it turns out, also a kind of - inconsistency.
It's a pity!
It is a pity for human labor, because people are not to blame here!
- Well, and you all the more.
A month later, Andrei Stepanovich celebrates his anniversary.
- He's here, 30 years old. 30 yes? - Yeah.
- Come on, don’t be modest Andrey Stepanovich, do not be modest.
-What idiot sent you here?
- Yes, in general, we ourselves are somehow accidental. - Ah, there it is.
- Well then, everything is much simpler.
You will have lunch now, get in the car, and go to another collective farm.
-Good. Yeah.
- I think the same thing there, if not worse. Yes? - Yes Yes Yes!
- Everywhere, absolutely the same picture. Yes!
-And you are removing the film ...
present to Andrey Stepanovich for the anniversary.
- Well there is no problem! - Good girl!
-Alexander Petrovich?
Sasha, please give me the tapes!
- The removed films Elena Pavlovna are with me, and I will give them to you ...
- Will not give it back! -But they are mine. - Lena, pity ...
bad adviser. How much is our lunch?
-What's wrong with you? Andrei Stepanovich is bad!
- Oh. - Drink water, Andrey Stepanovich, drink!
-Lena, we have to go! Lena?
- I'm not going with you! Give me the tapes.
- Well, in that case, I'll take them to television myself!
-Give the films immediately!
- Maybe call a doctor? - Sorry, I didn’t want to.
- I am also very sorry! - Captain, give me the tapes!
-You go with him, but act according to circumstances!
- How are you feeling? Maybe ... - Come on, you understand!
-You know, Elena. My father always told me:
"If you don’t know what to do, act according to the law."
I have a piece of the border that I have to guard. It's my duty!
If I don’t do it,
any links: For illness,
anniversaries, spoiled careers - will not help me.
Why should it be different here? AND?
-Because here is not the border.
- I hope you change your mind.
And I'm sure that, in the end,
you will understand me.
- Gave the tone.
-Do not. Leave in the car.
- Thank. -It's my pleasure. - Take the keys.
-Lena!
- That would not change your mind.
-Shura! I would go eat!
I didn’t eat anything in the morning.
-You know what, mother ... I'll go to the city.
I’m going for a walk.
-Take a walk, take a walk.
- Hello, can Elena Pavlovna? - Her not.
- Sorry Kondraty Petrovich, this is Captain Blinov says.
“Well, she really isn’t, Comrade Captain.
- Sorry, sorry.
-Captain...
- Hello. - Hello.
- What fate? - Here, I'm waiting for Lena.
- Waiting for Lena? - Yeah.
“So my chances are zero.” “They told me she was coming soon.”
-Coming soon? Wait, I recognize through my channels.
Hello, Marya Kirilovna.
- Hello, this is Pauline. Where is Elena today?
So. And then? And then? Thank.
- So, now she is at a conference in agricultural machinery.
Directly from there goes to the run to the drum theater.
But after the run, he’ll probably go somewhere with the actors.
- This is a tradition. - And ... - Is this for a long time?
“Well, you surprise me, captain.” This is not regulated.
-Thank.
-Capitan, sit down on the bench, huh?
- Are you in love or something?
-We quarreled.
But I think...
That I can convince her.
-Yes. But if someone else did not convince her, you turned out to be a catalyst.
-Lyadov, he.
- She loves him?
“Captain, you need to be shown at the museum.” - Loves.
- May I ask you one question? - You are welcome.
-Well, what did you find in her? Well, I'm pretty, I guess.
Well, the character is whacky, without a rudder and without sails.
The photographer, between us, is generally mediocre.
-Well, if you were in love and your chosen one would be ...
Well, let's say - an average accountant?
- I would not fall in love with an accountant.
- The profession determines. - The profession is taken into account.
Yes, and do not be ironic.
Because, marriages of convenience are no less lasting than of love.
And maybe even more.
If Elena marries Lyadov,
it will be, as they say now: "Packed."
They are doing one thing, he will help her,
and she’ll get to her feet faster.
-Well, I think: Families are not created to take over
jointly by profession.
For this, there are teams.
"Labor", as our mentors say.
“You like me, captain.”
- Goodbye. - Goodbye. Break a leg.
-You?
- Can I enter? - Come in.
-Hello.
-Hi, assistant.
-But you can keep these 2 photos for your family album.
Here, too, frank amateurism.
You neglect the possibilities of printing.
The left edge needs to be denser. Come here.
But why is everything so - crumbling, falling apart?
Here is a frank chernukha. There is no depth.
If your assistant is so persistent in persecuting compatriots,
then he certainly will not miss the enemy. Stubborn gentleman.
-Well, this is no longer your concern.
-You, in fact, in what case?
- The thing we have is actually one, only it will be decided individually.
Now is the time, so it’s better for you and me to leave now.
- Go away. - Nobody holds you.
“But I also consider your visit an accident.”
-From what?
-Lena.
- Captain, what do you want everything?
What are you climbing into my life?
I'm an adult. I was married.
You that don't know that single women
men visit sometimes.
“You were never married to me.”
And you never had anyone.
Except me.
No one.
I am without you,
I am...
Happily.
-Well, it's already masculine.
So where are you and I ... staying here?
Well, decent picture.
Although the right side, it would not hurt to print.
-I am asking you to leave.
- Cool down.
Helen.
Chill out.
Do you not remember where I got my umbrella?
-He's in the hallway.
- Make up your mind, call. Until.
“Sit down, captain!”
-I'm sitting, but behind the wheel.
“You seem to have a little drink today.” - As you wish.
-Don't worry, captain.
Anyway, nothing good would come of it.
By type of service, you spend your life at outposts, in villages and more ...
Well, unless of course you become - General. Do you have a chance to become a General?
- Small ones. - You see.
-And Elena got used to comfort.
- Yes, and your character ... - Where now?
-Left.
- I wish you success.
-In combat and political training.
-You take the keys.
-Just in case.
Type of outfit: Watch.
Tasks: To prevent impunity for violation of the state border of the USSR.
- Senior outfit: Sergeant Kovboshin. - I AM!
- Questions? - Outfit questions?
“Not at all.” - There are no questions, the order is clear.
There is a stand to guard the state border of the USSR.
- Follow! - Outfit, to the left!
- To guard the state border, step march!
“Comrade Captain, may I turn?” - Contact!
-Comrade captain, called from the squad,
Major Iosov flies out to us, and with him someone else.
- Allow me to go? - Go out. - There is.
- Well, let's go, Volodya.
-Comrade Major,
on the state border without incident.
- Hi. - I wish you good health.
-Elena Pavlovna Zhuravleva, photojournalist.
-Kapitan Blinov Alexander Petrovich, head of the outpost.
-Work.
-Elena Pavlovna is shooting here at your shooting range and her fellow countrymen.
- By the way, you are also her fellow countryman. “It's hard to believe that.”
- I have to believe, captain.
-Where do we start? We have 40 minutes at this outpost.
-I would like to talk with the captain, to interview.
-Come on Sasha, invite the correspondent.
-I ask you!
- Hello. - Hello.
-Comrade Major, Deputy Head of the outpost, Captain Ivanchenko.
-Comrade Major, deputy chief of the outpost for political affairs, Lieutenant Goulet.
“You think it was easy for me to get here?”
Why don't you answer my letters?
“There were reasons for that.” - What kind?
-This is a difficult question.
-Sit!
-Are you married? -No.
- Do you have another woman? - Not.
- Well then, this is not such a difficult question?
- They are waiting for us at the shooting range, Elena Pavlovna.
-Small! To the battle!
- Become here. - Fire!
- Alexander Petrovich? “One minute, I'm busy.”
-Thank.
- Hello. - Hello.
- Let’s shoot. - Do you charge?
“No, I think I can handle it.” - You are welcome.
-I saw it in the movies.
- Thank. - You are welcome.
-Comrade Warrant Officer: 8, 8, 9.
-Fine result.
- Have you been involved in shooting sports before?
- No, it's just that I have such a mood today.
- Excuse me. - Nothing.
-So how did your young soldiers shoot back?
- Fine, Siberians are good guys. - They shoot well.
- The hunters. - Comrade Major, may I turn?
- I’m listening to you, Elena Pavlovna.
-I would like to remove the captain, on that picturesque background.
- Comrade Major ... - I don’t need a major.
- Follow the correspondent. - There is.
- Thank. - You are welcome.
- Where are we going? -I am looking for the background. “Get over there.” -There?
-So?
- To take off? - Yes.
-Slightly to the right.
-So why do not you answer my letters?
-Because we are not suitable for each other.
You have a different life, different goals.
- I have no goals.
-What is Lena with you?
-I want to marry you.
-Why?
-Because I love.
-I have a bad temper.
-Me too.
-Comrade correspondent, you have to go! Time to fly!