(Silence)
(Dramatic Music)
(Street Noise)
okay tommy, what is it? what's what? the past two
days you haven't spoken five words to me now
what's eating you? nothing's eating me lieutenant
why should anything be eating me lieutenant?
i know you're better than that tommy now
we used to be friends what's happening?
nothing not a thing. you're lying. you're right
dan i am lying i'm fed up right up to here
follow me lieutenant keep talking you must be
pretty proud of yourself dan lieutenant dan lawton
whatever made you think you had the guts to be
an officer? i don't know why you should resent
me tommy i didn't ask for the commission
they gave it to me. big deal. think you
can order me now think i'm gonna follow you
just cause you're wearing that gold bar huh
don't kid yourself dan tell me you're
still a sergeant no more no less. i get it
you wanted the rank you wanted the commission
but i got it instead i've taken a lot of risks
for you dan made you look good more ways than one
you've had it from now on carry the ball yourself
(Pensive Music)
i don't want anybody going out on their own
all right you guys let's hit
it come on pick it up let's go
(Somber Music)
hello. are you frank garrick? taking a census?
hardly i was your brother's platoon leader
tommy's platoon leader in
korea? yeah he was my sergeant
come in won't you? i'm glad to know you i don't
know your name lieutenant lawton dan lawton
dan lawton. formerly lieutenant just plain
citizen now tommy spoke about you all the time
said you were the greatest guy in the world
frank your brother was a good sergeant
young a lot of drive full of vinegar we were
both up for a battlefield commission there's
only one opening i got it well he didn't always
see things my way we were in a wooded area one
day looking for snipers i told him to stay
back he disobeyed my orders machine gun
drink
thanks that's how it happened huh yeah
i'm sorry to hear it lawton i'm sure as an officer
your first concern was to look after your men
i feel badly of course that
was all the family time he had
i guess when your time is up it's up
i guess so how about you lauden come
out without a scratch no not quite one grenade
one slug you must have a charmed life could be
just one thing you don't mind how
did tommy get it did he suffer
no now it was fast it's over
in a second i'm glad of that
i couldn't have taken it if he'd
suffered when he felt pain i felt it
when he died a little of me died too if i ever
get my hands on anyone responsible for him getting
on a fellow no no discharged was over i'm not the
good well sit down or are you in a hurry no hurry
gotta catch your 11 15 train out though lots of
time almost three hours how does it feel to be
on your own again lawton no shells flying at you
no holes to dive into no attacks coming at you
do you think you can take
cervic again well it's rough but
i think i'll manage you don't seem too
happy about it i'm not what's the matter
i had a little business before i left
nothing big small sporting goods store
pardon him partner got involved in a deal he
spent more time with his stuff and with the store
he let it slide to the extent that the insurance
lapsed there was a fire no more store no insurance
five thousand dollars worth of goods on
consignment i've got to pay for it story of my
life sporting good store huh yeah you name it we
had it everything from ping pong balls to magnums
tommy was a great kid we had
some great times together
you know what he did had a piano act at the
hatton king he was their star attraction
i used to listen to him all
the time even now i go there
i get the feeling tommy's still around
like to hunt i've been
secretly admiring your trophies
like to hunt huh you know i don't you i live
for it oh what have you done big stuff i mean
oh couple of months in burma once in bengal
i got a few things myself nothing like yours
of course but i assure you i'm no amateur
maybe you're the guy i've been looking for
in what way a new type of hunt i'll tell
you about it later how would you like to
see some pictures i took last year and i'd
be very glad to as well sit right over there
you'll enjoy these dan
(Dramatic Music)
these are some of the finest pictures
i've ever seen frank. i envy you. I'm flattered.
when he spotted me he came charging
i had one cartridge and no time to reload
man that's what i call real guts
you certainly are a hunter frank
(Orchestra Music)
(Drums)
you see that head over the fireplace? spent three
months out of bombay safari you know that's always
been one of my ambitions. i've never been lucky
enough to go on one though. i'll tell you about
a better sport. want a refill? why not? yeah, what
i wouldn't give for some of your experiences
thank you
did you ever want to do something so badly you
were willing to gamble everything you had for it?
sure i want this to be my best hunt
where right here the good old usa
what can you find here that
you haven't already found?
man
man? that's right what better game
is there in the whole world than man?
you're gonna stalk and shoot
a human being? that's right.
you're out of your mind frank that's murder
not if you don't kill your man but if you
intend to hunt him and shoot him i didn't tend
to keep him killing him real simple with this
30 30. that's right and if you fire this
the guy's still gonna be alive that's right
because this is a camera gun. camera gun?
yeah take a look carefully see for yourself
blank? no film my own invention instead of
a real cartridge it's film no sound nothing
you develop the cartridge and you see
where you hit your victim and at what time
this is what i mean. that's my dog it shows where
i hit him at eight seconds 31 minutes past two
i don't get it for a man who's hunted
big stuff isn't this somewhat tame?
tame isn't the word but i'll have to do
from now on. my ticker began going on the
blink about a year ago the doctor told me
to cut out all strenuous activity especially
hunting. you know what that does to a man like
me? it's a strangle might as well stop living
but i wouldn't do it for one more hunt it's got
to be the best hunt the best game in the world
hey wait a minute how about you
and me lawton? in what way? a hunt
i thought you just said the doc told you not game
you and me hunting each other with two camera guns
well i think that's a great idea frank
but i've got some business to take care of
oh you mean that store of
yours? yeah what's left of it
how much would it cost to
straighten it out? about 5 000
okay i'll make it worth your while i love
to hunt you've got financial problems right?
right. all right i'll give you ten thousand
dollars if you fill my kill is it a deal?
well i get the money to match it i was a
second lieutenant not a chief of staff. all
right i'll give you odds ten to one my ten
thousand against your thousand. if you win
you'll have double the money
you need what do you say?
you've got a deal. one shot each the first
person to film a kill calls the other's name
then we'll develop the cartridge and see
who forfeits the amount. fine with me. great
maybe my last hunt will be my
best. where do we start and when?
in the city. let's mark the
areas so we don't chase all over.
here the first day. here the second. if
i can't find you in 48 hours i'll quit.
we'll start in this area at 10
o'clock wednesday morning all right
great with me i find jim aim the camera gun shout
out your name and i get ten thousand dollars
first you've gotta find me and hit me with one
shot or else you lose a thousand. real sporting
game. what if we don't uh what if we don't meet in
the in the time period? well then we'll meet back
here and the drinks are on me. great great just one
rule lord we do everything in our power to lure
the other fellow into a trap i'll do everything
i can to get you to my advantage. you do the same
no holes barred. anything goes.
okay. your gun fits into this.
one shot each. where's yours? only
two guns like this in the world.
same cases
same guns. quite a thing.
i just want to warn you lawton i have unusual
eyes by that i mean whether it's night a day makes
no difference to me i can spot you anywhere
any place so if you want to make it even
find places that are off the beaten path
stick to the alleys walk the dark streets
okay frank see you in town wednesday.
10 a.m not if i see you first lawton
here's your map i'll put the money in escrow
in the morning. thanks, i'll do the same.
you know something frank i think i could win
this hunt. maybe you can lawton, maybe you can.
(Dramatic Music)
like to dance? i can take it or leave it i
get off tonight at 8 30. good for you. married?
no i always look like this. well? look cookie
some other time okay yeah sometime in 1973
is there a dan lawton there?
do you have a dan lawton there?
(Dramatic Music)
do you have a dan lawton registered
lawton one moment i'll see yes we have
is he in no sir i'm sorry he went out about
an hour ago where to i don't recall exactly he
just gave me the key well if this is urgent i'm
his brother oh wait a minute i i i do remember
he said something about going out to catalina
catalina no no he said um let's see uh the avalon
he said he was gonna go out to take a look at the
animal i don't know what he meant by that except... (hang up)
(Whistle)
(Dramatic Music)
oh evening mr lawton hi what's this? oh some
sort of advertising we get it all the time
even now i go there i get the
feeling tommy's still around
mr
me the way you could love me
one were to say you could love me
say with a glance warm and thrilling
there's a chance you'll be willing one day
show me the way you are feeling
have i the right to possess
you i'm lost unless we'll show
one word to say you could love me
say with a glance
seem to have lost my life you mind not at all
you i'm lost unless you will show me the way
say uh why don't the two of us
get out of here? sure why not
(Piano Music)
what on earth is that? it's my lifesaver
i'm sorry mr garrick but you understand how
it is it's not against the law to walk around
with a weapon in plain sight it's illegal only
if it's concealed you're right i'm sorry if i
detained you but it's my job to check on these
things and now you're free to go anytime you
like drink sure
what would you like surprise me
all right
empty heart and
weary
you know i'm very flattered in what way what if
all the eligible bachelors to pick on you singled
i had my reasons
and leave this dark
and lonely stream
this is not a pickup dan
i know about you quite a bit about you mr lawton
well it's my pleasure i can assure you but
uh i still don't know why you picked on me
i was very much in love with someone
he was killed on lookout ridge in korea
yes i know
tommy garrick was killed there
well it's a small world i found out
about you i had someone find you for me
followed you into the hat and came
i hope you win dan i hope frank has
to pay you that ten thousand dollars
sorry miss um helen layton helen would
you mind telling me what this is all about
not at all i was to marry tommy when
he got back frank didn't approve of me
this gets more interesting as it goes
along i felt out of place with frank
ian is hold over tommy is there thinking for
tommy telling him how to live how to breathe
open house anytime thanks god lonely
sitting in my room by myself sit in mine
have a drink i'm over 21.
i'd have never guessed it you
should have been a diplomat
how do you know i'm not i don't
but you're not how do you
tell your approach to direct
should i change it not unless
you're interested in wasting time
i'm not finished with this yet don't let it age
(Stirring Music)
what do you do?
you tell me.
your eyes... they're cold
sharp what's that a sign of i don't
know for sure maybe you're a killer
keep your door locked you could be my next victim
this hunt how do you know that frank doesn't want
to get you out into the open so that he could
push me under a truck or uh off a high
bridge yes have you thought about that uh-huh
and also that the world will soon be taken
over by the people from the planet dopo
you haven't believed a word i've said
thanks for the drink dan just one
word of caution don't trust frank
how do i know i can trust you?
(Dramatic Music)
your heart won't take it frank. dan will win
and you know it. you're not the hunter you used
to be. you've got to kill dan because he is
the one responsible for your brother's death.
one more day but in your condition how do you
know you can hit with one shot? suppose you miss
and dan finds out you tried to kill him
you better make sure get another
bullet you need two bullets to be sure
this is your last hunt and you know it you want to
win it or lose it? i've got to win it and get two
bullets
well this is an early visit it's that dan lawton
we've got to do something about him in what way
if it wasn't for him you'd be marrying
tommy now instead of him being dead
you're out of your mind frank oh yeah
take a look at this
i don't believe it dad had tommy killed it wasn't
for him tommy'd be alive and dead in his place
did it ever occur to you that fate might have
played a hand let tommy drew the wrong card look
we can avenge tommy ellen you and me we can make
it up to him for both of us i don't follow you
because of dan tommy's dead a life for life
are you suggesting that i why not we can kill
him for both of us the odds are in our favor
i'm very sorry frank the feeling's
just a little out of my line
doesn't tommy mean anything to you
but you want to repay his murder
you'd better see a doctor frank you don't care
nobody cares about tommy and you loved him
you lied helen connie was
too good for the likes of you
all this time you were engaged
in how do i know you didn't
you're not good
hey taxi taxi hey taxi
knowledge you must have just got out
thanks
looks like i'm gonna need a
raincoat raincoat yes sir west side
come this way
sure need the rain give me a 30 30 show
yes sir they come in boxes of 50 or 100
one shell 30 30 that's all i want but
they're more expensive that way look
it doesn't matter please get me a 30 30 show yes
what's the sir my heart
can i get you a doctor no pills right two of them
is there anything else i
can do no i'll be all right
my case it's on the counter we get it please sure
yeah that's a good fit how much do i
owe you including decks five dollars
looks pretty good now you were right about the
size like i lost some weight thank you very much
hello did damn latin get in
yet sorry hasn't come in miss
thanks
who is it
i've been calling you all morning
look i've been giving this a lot of thought
uh something down the line isn't straight
what is it with you and frank he was just here he
tried to kill me he wanted me to kill you i'll cut
it out will you hell and i haven't done anything
to frank i've only known him for 36 hours frank
thinks that you killed tommy that you sent him
out to be killed he's crazy you're right he is
look look i've had it i've had all i can take
i don't know what's going on around here but i'm
sure gonna find out frank thinks that you were
responsible for tommy's death that you had
him killed purposely that it was your doing
he came in at five o'clock this morning
to convince me that i should kill you
it is all very interesting but i don't buy it he
even tried to kill me you had a great nightmare
does that look like a nightmare
frank's got a lot of explaining to do to me forget
frank you've got to get away the what he's done to
you not in your life it could be yours where do
i find them dan please don't try this is for the
police it's for me i don't like being hunted down
like a wild animal but you don't understand he'll
fight i'm trying to believe you now where is he
dan please time hotel santa monica and wilson
(Dramatic Music)
no dan don't shoot dan you win
dan your money it's all yours
no wounds must have been his
heart anything else to add
that's exactly the way it happened what's that
camera gun let's see it
that doesn't look like a camera gun to me.
nor to him either
(Dramatic Music)