- Hello.
- Mirko?
Is Bilal. I'm in France at Calais.
Mine is?
No, not in school.
How late?
Mina back to that time?
- At 5:00, I think.
- At 5.
- Good morning, my son.
- Good morning.
Mirko?
I can not speak,
my father arrived.
Call you back.
Do not call here anymore.
Write down my phone.
No, no phone.
00 ... 44 ... 78 ...
10 ... 506 ... 759.
Tell your sister
I'm in Calais ...
I'll take a boat
tonight or tomorrow morning.
I'll be in London tomorrow night.
Sure, but do not call it here.
But going to tell her, right?
Yes Bye.
- He took the bread?
- No, I forgot.
- Who was that?
- Nobody. A friend.
Please! Please!
- Where is the entrance to the port?
- Afghanistan. Not understand.
- The entrance to the port?
- Why? Where to go?
- England.
- England?
He was invited by the Queen?
- Where is it?
- There, 1 km.
Take the first class.
Better!
Take, good profit, enjoy the site!
Enjoy!
And you're cold?
- In the queue!
- Yes, all right!
- Not filling.
- What! Come!
Stop! Enough!
You go back there.
You, stand in line, no
please, where are you?
Zoran?
Go to the queue.
He is a friend!
- It Mosul.
- I do not care.
Koban, is a friend!
- What are you doing here?
- And you?
His mother told me
I was in London,
you called, I was fine.
Was not to worry.
Since when are you here?
Two and a half months.
I three months.
- Do you have money to go through?
- I'm under a truck.
- I do not need a middleman.
- Here, you take the dogs.
And to enter the trucks,
we need a middleman.
- How much did they ask?
- 500.
Euros?
Just to go?
Yes, if I borrow,
I paid in London.
And trains? The tunnel?
Yes! I held down
a train, in Albania.
Here, the trains go to 160.
Those who tried
the train passed over.
Hello! You're new!
Just get?
- Yes
- When you arrived?
Today, now.
What is your name?
Bilal.
- Good luck!
- Thank you.
- Good night.
- And the boats?
- What, boats?
Fishing boats, the sailing ...
We can not steal one?
There are police everywhere, in the port.
And the boats are tied.
The only solution
is the middleman.
For me, there are only a 50 Euros.
I love you I return in London ...
So? Can I borrow?
- We can cross tomorrow?
- I see. I return, I promise.
Is there a telephone nearby?
Aran!
Where?
England!
One minute, 10 euros.
At Pizza Hut,
are looking for couriers.
You do not know the streets.
You have to know them.
Yes, I know.
If I say ...
Osborne Road, as you get there?
Eye on the map.
Must have the map in the head.
I turn around.
It is always better
to dive in the Indian Ocean.
Eat your meat well.
Amed Darashia.
The part of whom?
Mirko ... Bilal.
You can not eat in peace!
I told you not to call here!
Your phone does not respond.
Mine is?
She can not talk.
My father is here!
You want?
You too?
Who is Bilal?
A friend.
Who is it?
The son of Kayani.
What does he want?
Must breathe through the hole
canvas, due to CO2.
When I say,
go into hiding ...
Keep this in mind,
and breathe in there.
Quiet, shut up!
Okay, I'm going to sleep!
Come! Fast!
- All right?
- I hurt myself.
Place the bag on your head!
Let us place!
Hurry!
Come on, come down soon!
Come on down!
Hurry!
Let us put.
Will make us pick up, you idiot!
Place.
Push!
Come on down! Hurry!
Papers.
License.
Where from?
Pelzni. Czech Republic.
What?
Make him shut up, gonna get us.
- What are you taking? Vessels?
- There are people in there!
There are some people!
You know how much it will cost you!
Open the door!
Where's your friend?
Damn! Son of a bitch!
Stop, Koban! Stop!
Everybody out! Come!
Eyaz!
Everybody out!
All this, it is your fault, stupid!
You owe me 500 Euros!
Silence!
Forget it!
Pay me or I'll kill you.
Know what I mean? Silence!
- Bathrooms, please. I am sick.
- Come on!
Kayani, K.. A.. Y.. A.. N.. I
- Bilal, Iraq, December 8, 1991.
- 08/12/91.
812.
Who is she? His girlfriend?
Answer is your girlfriend? Beautiful!
625 Euros and 40 cents,
exempt from fees.
- Return.
- And what else?
- Please.
- Let go! Go!
Enough, Francis!
- Ready!
- Enough! Next. Gathering all this.
- Next.
- Collecting all.
If next appears, Bilal Kayani.
Born on 8 December 1991
Mosul, Iraq,
illegally entered the territory
and was arrested on 15 February
when trying
embark clandestinely
for the United Kingdom.
You admit the facts?
- Say yes.
- Yes
In accordance with the provisions
for people
from countries at war,
you escape measures
Extradition across the border.
But know that here will be taken
stricter measures,
calling people like you
return to their country of origin.
I did it right?
Since no
offenders,
I will not hold it,
but do not want to see him again.
I do not know what you said, but
can not enter England.
Do not cross over, should return to
his country to avoid serious problems.
Sir, allow me to say that
this child is less
of age, and therefore
qualifies for a place
a public school.
You know very well that
not where to go,
let's not waste time
with it, next case.
Cometh Bafaoua Malman.
Excuse me, ...
Calais? Is there?
Calais is there, yes!
Thank you.
Come on, open your legs. So.
Like a frog.
Do not hold the line, please.
The line should not hold!
Come on back to the legs. So.
Bend, stretch, and join.
Bend, stretch and join.
Again.
Soft, soft, soft.
- Sorry!
- Yes?
- How much are the classes?
- What?
Classes. As the boy.
Want to learn to swim?
Yes, the crawl.
A class, 15 euros.
- For an hour?
- Half an hour.
And the package is 120 Euros.
For ten classes.
- Can we start now?
- Not now!
Tomorrow afternoon. 2am.
2am, agree.
Thank you.
Yes?
I said 15. Just a note.
Payment of 2 classes.
Where are you from?
Iraq, sir ... Kurdistan.
Do not pay to stay
calling, right?
One moment!
Hey, you!
Only one call!
Get out now!
Still owes me 500 euros.
Okay, let me!
You'll see if I let you!
Tomorrow, without fail.
Otherwise I will kill you. Idiot!
When I left Iraq,
Turkish soldiers captured me.
They tied my hands and put
a black bag on my head.
Left me with the bag for 8 days.
You took a shower?
It smells like soap.
Where did you shower?
Please! We have money ...
- What is happening?
- I called Marty. Not him.
Please, only one
shower. We pay.
- No shower.
- 10 minutes!
- I said no. Out!
- Why?
Why yes, leave
but call the police.
Is prohibited. It is
a public toilet!
Out!
I came to class.
Ah Yes, the classroom, he paid! Out!
Now come on, out, out.
But tomorrow will be 50.
But your friends ... should never return.
If I see one here, learn
swimming in the harbor!
Your ticket.
Not good.
First, his head
should be in the water.
Must blow into the water.
So ... one, two ... breathing.
Every three movements,
you breathe.
Loud. So ...
Once the left ...
once on the right.
And blows into the water, mouth closed.
How to make bubbles.
Right? ... What is this?
Nothing.
Come on. Show me.
ladies and gentlemen, we close in
20 minutes, please go to the locker room.
Okay?
No, the head is not going well,
should breathe higher,
and feet too, but
'll see about that tomorrow.
Time to leave.
One more!
Let's close!
Tomorrow at 2 hours?
How old are you?
17.
E. .. Why do you want both
learn to swim?
Come on, we are waiting to close.
Simon!
Sorry, we are together.
You okay?
- And you?
- Yes, waiting for the holidays!
38.30 please.
- Wait, let me pay!
- No, thanks.
Received the letter?
Judge ... I received yesterday.
It looked at the mail.
Attend the Thursday.
Thanks, bye.
I have to check my books,
I need them for my courses.
- Just a minute!
- I said no.
- Only for food and water.
- Come on, get out now! Let.
What did they do?
Why are prevented from entering?
Sorry, ma'am, but I do the
my work. Come on, please.
- Do not answer me, what they did!
- Come on, you can not talk to him.
Madam, please
he only obeys orders.
Oh? Whose? We know?
Management, irritate customers.
But do not bother us.
For you, madam, bother
people to do their shopping?
Well, please let the
customers in peace now.
Come on, get out now or
call the police, right?
Bravo!
You obviously did not say anything!
Lowers his head and back
home, is it?
What do you do? It's just not
back here and ready.
- Gimme!
- After.
You know what I mean when they
prevent people from entering a store.
Want me to buy
a history book?
What do you do?
Annoy me, hatred of
people and their indifference as well.
For books, I will after tomorrow
tomorrow, I have proof.
I'll put them in a box.
You are good on Thursday,
then go to court?
Yeah, okay.
We'll see after tomorrow,
after school.
I have a small office
the apartment, if you agree.
Yes, of course.
Go to your home?
I'm having dinner with Alain.
Give a hug for me!
Here it is.
Okay?
One must be very good swimmer
to cross the English Channel.
Did you know?
It is ten o'clock at least, to cross.
Understand?
And the water is 10 degrees
Think you can swim 10 hours
in water at 10 degrees?
Know what I mean?
- Yes!
- So?
Pay for classes, sir.
OK, swim! ... Let's swim!
Where you going?
Port.
Come.
I know him.
Come!
Thank you.
He also wants to go to England?
England, yes.
You took a bath, ... had
told not to take bath.
Does what I say.
- We hope you?
- Come on.
Come, come.
- Do you like pizza?
- Yes
Sit!
Seven degrees tomorrow. Not good for swimming.
- You?
- Yes
- You are a champion?
- No.
What would you drink?
Wine, beer, water?
Beer, yes.
Water for me.
Gold, Lord?
Gold medal?
Yes .. Leave it ...
Come on, sit down.
How long
need to come from Iraq?
- Three months.
- Walking the walk?
- Yes
- He fled because of war?
- Thank you.
Send money
for our families.
And sure you will find
a job in England?
A job, yes ...
His brother works in a
supermarket in London.
He found a job.
And you?
Find.
What do you do?
Football.
Want to play football in England?
Yes, there are good clubs.
I'll find a way inside.
He, good player. Quick ...
Bazda!
In Mosul, call me bazda.
The corridor.
Bazda?
Yes, bazda. The corridor.
In my house, I have many
trophies too.
Ten, maybe.
You are a champion, then.
My favorite club is Manchester.
- Manchester United ... know?
- Yes!
Beckham, Ronaldo ...
They are the best.
I try to play there.
Forget the idea of crossing the swim.
Only good swimmers do.
In the summer, with a good team ...
and a boat to follow it.
And a year of training.
Impossible for you.
It's too far.
The water is very cold,
strong currents.
Understand?
Large cargo ships.
300 meters long.
One every 10 minutes.
And you, so small,
alone, in front of them.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
This evening you can sleep here.
Your friend also.
- But not tonight.
- Thank you.
Come help me, do not be
arms crossed
Push the table ... the table.
Ready.
Thanks ... Thank you.
And do not say "thank you"
all the time, is annoying.
The bathrooms are there.
- Let them clean, ok?
- Yes .. Yes
- Good night.
- Good evening, thank you.
What is this shit you're doing?
Sorry ... I try
used to the bag.
What?
If you want to kill
go do it somewhere else, ok?
What do you want?
Get out of here, enough.
In that I got with you?
Sorry, I try to keep the bag
head for the trucks.
Go to bed alone
or want to help!
Trucks for England.
To control CO2.
We have to stay with the bag.
I could never, sir.
Never.
- You do not have your keys?
- Maybe she was not alone!
Who wants me to be?
- Want a coffee?
- No, I have time.
- Here, take mine.
- Thank you.
Was arranging the books.
Who?
- Good morning.
Are the guys that helped.
My wife, Marion.
What are you doing here?
Nothing, go to the pool,
take a bath.
- It will take these, too?
- No, only Whitman.
They are in his house since when?
I do not know, 3 or 4 days, maybe.
They were frozen out, I felt sorry.
We're leaving.
Bye. See ya.
- Where are you from?
- Iraq, ma'am. Kurdistan.
Thank you.
Are kind of crazy, great!
Want to go swimming there.
Where?
England. So, I'm training.
For the office,
how?
I do not know ... let it now.
Come back another day.
For that, Simon?
For nothing!
Yes?
Yes .. why? No. .. yes.
You know you can have
problems doing this?
- What?
- With its Kurds!
Of course not. The only problem
I have, is you.
- No, Bruno is down there, leave.
- We will not fight for so little.
You can hurt your back.
You can take my keys and open?
- Hello
And the office,
when will we see?
I do not know, Saturday morning,
is good for you?
- Bye.
What?
- Took a few Kurds in his house.
- What?
Ah, yes, I saw two out.
Does he know that
they risk doing this?
I do not know.
What nonsense!
Turn, I'm sorry.
Yes .. here it is.
We received this from the barracks.
Tuesday, February 18,
19:10, Plaza de Armas.
A vehicle of the Renault Clio Gray,
5433 RS 62 plate is yours?
- Maybe, I do not know.
- Yes, it's yours.
Loading 2 suspects;
probably immigrants.
Can you confirm?
What?
Have them collected.
And why? I'm suspicious of what?
Helping people
Illegal is a crime.
Where did it take?
Are you saying that you can not
help people, is it?
For these people, no,
more than 500 today in
coast seeking a
way to cross to England.
They arrive every day.
I pay for
the city does not become
a camp
illegal immigrants.
- So I ask another ...
- What does this have to do with me?
Is not I who bring them here.
No, but if you help them reach more.
We have strict rules for the
Calaisianos not start
to help these people.
So I ask again,
led them to where?
Cinema.
Went to see what?
British film, so
become accustomed to the language.
Knee, elbow! Come on, ladies.
Hello, sorry for the delay.
- Can I continue to want to ...
- No, that's fine.
Gentlemen Good morning.
Come for the abs now.
A float under each arm.
Lie on back,
raise your legs up high,
and count to 10. Let.
1 ... 2 ... 3 ...
4 ... 5 ... 6 ...
7 ... 8 ... 9 ... 10
Again! 1 ... 2 ...
In fact, I would like to continue,
I have to do something now.
Come with me. Come, come ... come.
Simon, I, listen, I thought well, not
should leave these people in your home.
No idea where you're getting into,
police guard around the world.
They do everything to get us, so
not hurt hot meals and clothing.
On Monday morning
got a volunteer who had
refugees in his house
you risk 5 years in prison.
is the price, now you know?
So there will be more
a burden to you.
Judges do not relax with it.
I do not know what I wanted to prove
with it, but now comes.
Receive them in your home
was very good, very
generous, but must stop
it now, even.
Good morning, everyone, sit down.
I can not say more now.
Promise you'll stop it?
Yes
- A hug.
- Me too.
Simon! Simon!
Are you done? ... Very good!
Many chains!
Get it now?
Impossible. I told you!
Good costume. Not cold.
My nose is not cold, is blue!
An hour and is already blue.
I have towels.
Want to go there for a girl?
Yes
Mina.
I met three years ago.
Is the sister of a friend.
A friend of football.
Is beautiful.
Very pretty.
His father works in England
long.
He got a visa for 6 months.
She knows that you go there?
Yes, but I could not talk to her
since I left Iraq.
Take, call her.
- No, no, thanks.
- Yes, call her.
No, seriously.
I'll call from a payphone.
Where to go?
- At the center?
- Yes
Has power everywhere?
- What?
- The currents in the channel?
Everywhere, yes.
Mr. Calmato by mutual agreement, put
income from the apartment in his name.
In the absence of children ...
it is not a pension
or a custody agreement.
Remains the provision compensatory
on which you agree
that there was great
income gap between the two
and therefore there is no need.
Is there anything more
to add, lawyer?
No, Your Honor.
- Madam: ... Lord? ...
- No.
- Aspirin. Take.
- Thank you.
How do you feel?
Over, then.
Sad.
No longer use your ring?
I can not find it,
For months I look for
I do not know what I did with him,
looked everywhere.
Anyway, that ring
means nothing now.
- I finished my turn, I can charge?
- Let.
Sorry, be right back.
What made her the Kurds?
We did a test at sea, fared well.
We must place greater emphasis on training,
but soon will be ready.
And then, I will train others, and more
other, is not very complicated, you know?
This summer, I double the pace.
- Madness!
- Here. Thanks
Know why he wants to cross?
To find your girlfriend.
He walked 400 km to go back to find it.
And now you want to cross the
English Channel, swimming!
I, when you left, I was not able to
cross the street to reach you.
What are you doing? Slept here?
Sorry, sir.
But you do not understand anything!
You want me to hold again!
The door was locked.
No, I do not want to hear anything,
out of here already!
I do not want to see more here.
Right? Right?
- What are you doing here?
- He will.
Slept here? Shit, that abuse!
Not want a coffee, too?
That's enough, do not fret for so little.
Marion gone.
What happened here?
Where is everybody?
The police came again, threw gas
tear, held 2 or 3 and went.
Just to keep them from eating.
- Can you help?
- Yes
- And the children, where are they?
- Scattered throughout the forest.
Can you help me put
others, too?
There are already two restaurants.
This, and a near Heathrow.
Will open another in Brick Lane.
And they want me to be the manager.
- That's good, right?
- So I take it with me.
Cool, huh?
Lounge. Not in the kitchen.
Of course, in the lounge. No more scrubbing.
- Where is Brick Lane?
- The East End
A large street full of restaurants.
Hasan, is a great guy.
I'm going with you?
- Let's see.
- You put me in the hall, too?
Of course, in the hall!
- Glad you're here.
- Good night!
- Good evening, how are you?
- Well, are you?
Hasan, his cousin.
- Remember him?
- No matter.
Make yourself at home.
- Hello
Good evening and welcome.
Come. Sit.
For middlemen
have to be six.
I am looking for people,
but no one has more money.
And you have?
I thought I had more.
I arranged.
But you can not come.
Do not want you in the truck.
You're here?
Here, Rogue?
- Stop, Koban!
- My 500 Euros.
Stop bother me with it!
- Will pay me!
- Stop, shit!
- I promise that I will pay!
- Leave it, damn it!
Stop, Koban!
Okay!
Bitch, you pay me!
- What?
- Who is Bilal?
Amed Darashia.
Hold on.
Put them in bed, please.
Mina ... Help your mother.
Listen carefully: Stop calling now.
Mine is not going to talk to you.
Understood? You are sick!
Now, leave her alone.
Over! Understood?
Who was that?
Who were you talking about?
Come.
Come on, come on.
Come, I say!
Between!
Sit.
Sit!
Do not want to eat?
You are not bazda? The corridor.
Have to eat.
- Thank you.
- You see, speak French.
Why not learn French and is here?
Do not know if it will get
the Manchester ...
but in water, to train law
I'm sure it will
achieve good thing.
And become a good swimmer.
A very good. Believe me.
Forget running ...
and become a swimmer.
If I am a good swimmer
I cross the English Channel
My medal, where is it?
My gold medal, where is it?
- Where is it?
- I do not know.
You mocking me?
Where, do not you?
I give you food and shelter, and the only
thing I think, is to rob me!
Here, put the bag in
head, come on
Take the fucking truck
and go away from here!
Come on, put, go get, shit!
You have to know what they want.
Want to go? So go!
Let us put.
Hold on!
Sorry, sorry.
Okay.
Sorry.
Forgive me. I'm nervous.
I also have problems. Sorry.
Come on, come on, sorry.
Come!
It is you who are crying so?
Know what time it is?
Has ended. Sorry.
Brought back
this guy into the building?
The building not, to my apartment.
It is forbidden! Here we are quiet
do not want problems.
What is the problem,
is a child, is 17.
You have no right to bring him here.
- Wait.
- What?
It turns out that this gentleman
brings immigrants to the building.
Okay, enough.
Of course not, look
that state is.
They are dirty,
have diseases and steal.
- I'm warning you, I'll call the liquidator.
- Call!
Oh, and call the Navy
also if you want!
But do not understand what
I say. Also,
I do not know what causes it,
but is suspect.
How is it? What say?
You can repeat what I said?
Between.
Come in!
Will there be problems because of me.
Lie. Let.
Good night.
Yes?
Good evening, sir. I speak
with Mr. Kayani, please?
How?
Bilal Kayani, in your home?
Ah, yes, one minute.
It is for you.
- Yes? ...
- Bilal ...
My father wants to marry.
Marry a cousin!
What?
A cousin, who owns a restaurant.
Do not know!
Bilal, what I do?
I'm going. Relax.
But when you gonna come?
I do not know. I'm going.
Tell me what to do.
He does not want to see,
not even talk to us!
- Bilal, I gotta go!
- Mine?
Good news, right?
An hour ago, you thought
she did not want to see you.
And now, she knows that you expect.
So it's good news.
Perhaps you could talk to her father.
If he wants to marry her, he will.
It is so.
To get to this one.
And to impress her father.
It's an antique ring.
Very nice.
Diamonds and sapphires.
She'll like it.
Take.
You will find a way to cross.
Take, we do not make undone!
But ... is his wife.
Take it and give it.
Invited me to your wedding?
- Mr. Calmato?
- Yes
We would like to make some
questions, we can enter?
- Are you alone?
- You do not have the right to enter as well.
Paul!
Please!
Can you tell us who slept there?
Eu Vi television is banned?
They say it is illegal
under his roof.
Well, you can see that!
It was that damned who called?
It seems that you wanted
beat him, too.
Of course not, is an idiot.
Next time will come sooner!
Bilal?
Pablo!
Come!
He wants you to play.
Want to play.
Where did you find it.
I do not know, that way. Why?
- Are you sure he was?
- Yes, of course.
Two hours, maybe three, I do not know.
If the beach
is wearing a blue and black.
Who are you? Your last name?
Simon Calmato. C-A-L-M-A-T
- And it?
- Bilal.
Is your name, Bilal?
And what is the surname?
Calmato, too! It's my son.
- How old are you?
- 17 years.
I hope.
Forgotten me ... office.
Ah, yes.
He did not sleep here?
Good morning.
Very nice, this, as always!
I told you to stop.
And why all this?
When he realizes that
will not succeed, will return.
When you notice, it will be late.
Not get more.
You call the police?
The Red Cross.
And maritime affairs.
For an illegal immigrant,
not make much effort.
Do not take it anymore, Marion.
Eat without you, sleep
without you, I can not.
Just got done nonsense.
Simon, stop.
Please.
Stop, please.
Simon!
Hello! ... yes ...
Again, why?
I do not know, later.
When I can.
What is it?
The address of the girl,
his girlfriend.
After all, it was without him.
We must no longer see us, Simon.
No more.
There seems to be a good environment
in your building! Come.
I have good news for you.
We fished her son!
This is a recent adoption, no?
How is he?
As a guy who
spent 5 hours in cold water.
Was a fisherman who recovered it.
Did not want to go, had
to carry him to power.
What are you doing
with that boy, Mr. Calmato?
What do you mean?
Well, you train in the pool,
everybody saw.
Gave two lectures.
Yes, and a swimming costume as well.
That he stole in my house.
Then recognizes
who had under your roof?
I have the testimony of his neighbor.
And that seems to be true.
Even told you
had a special relationship
with the boy, if you
understand what I mean!
We will arrest him, Mr. Calmato.
By helping illegal immigrants.
And trafficking in human beings,
what is even worse.
His wife is a volunteer
very active, no?
Stop it, it has nothing
to do with it, moreover,
is no longer my wife,
we separated eight months ago.
And divorced two days ago.
His neighbor saw them
in your home together.
For months I asked to
involve volunteers
Mr. Calmato do not give me peace.
And now, thanks to you, I'll get them.
At least one!
If legal or not his wife,
makes no difference.
There complicity
will not change anything.
Okay, I gathered
under my roof and the trained.
I gave him the suit and fins
put it in water and he paid me.
1000 euros, is good?
I slept with him too.
You are right the other, sleep with men,
but she left me.
So, leave it alone now,
has nothing to do with it.
You are under judicial custody.
Until it is called before the judge,
can not leave the region.
And it should go here
every day. Dismissed.
Dismissed.
Not so fast, and open the
legs like a frog.
Do not run, boys!
We, therefore, open the legs.
- Simon!
- Give me.
Knock there, and take another turn. Right?
Take a look, please.
Hallo!
Good morning sir, could
speak with Bilal Kayani, please.
Sorry, but not here.
It's Mine?
Yes
You know when
I can talk to him?
Are retained in a detention center.
What?
A detention center. It ...
as a prison for
illegal immigrants.
Why?
tried to cross the English Channel.
But the police caught him.
You know when they release it?
Soon, I hope.
A week, maybe. I do not know.
Want to leave a comment?
Tell him not to come.
I'm getting married.
You have to wait, Mina.
He can cross. I know.
Tell him to stay in
France, sir. Please.
How are you, bazda?
Seems tired.
Have to stay in shape
to play in Manchester.
He knew he had problems
my fault.
- Sorry.
- Do not worry.
You're a swimmer, now.
Lost her costume. I will return it.
Mina called.
When?
Monday morning.
What did she say?
He said to call her.
Anything else?
Can not stay here! If the police see,
complicit and close the soup.
What did she say?
Go, please!
She can not wait.
Getting married. Was very sad ...
She said you should not go.
Go now, we should not see it anymore.
Leave me alone.
Go away, Simon, will bring us
problems and to them also.
Are cold.
Stop, I'm responsible for it,
I get clothes. I'll take care.
Call me.
- So?
- Yes
Let's continue.
Is there someone in the water!
- A face in the water!
- Where?
There!
- There!
Right there! There!
200 meters.
Right!
Right in front.
Here!
Stop the engines! Stop! Turn!
Good morning.
Wait a minute, please.
What?
That's all.
You've been French champion
the 400 meters, I did not know.
Now, you know.
In 1984, the games were in Los Angeles,
why was not the Olympics?
Because the coach was a cop!
It was to ask that
I wanted to see me?
We found this with a
these middlemen.
A certain Zoran Makma
paid with this, you want it?
I gave him.
Managed to cross?
I do not know, probably yes.
He did it!
I have good news, Mr. Calmato.
Where is it?
Here. The British sent him back.
In a plastic bag!
Was found to 800 meters
the coast, English coast.
Is the first time
someone crosses that!
Had it with him.
I suppose it has given him, too?
- Mina ... You're Mine?
- Yes
'm A friend of Bilal.
I'm French.
Can I talk to you?
One minute.
I'm going home later.
Like him?
Pool.
Vine training.
He had bought it for you.
It's an antique ring. Very old.
Diamonds and sapphires.
I can never use it ...
The wedding is in 10 days.
Why not tell him not to come?
I said.
Gotta go.
Hallo!
me, Simon.
The police just called, it seems
nothing the police station for 2 days.
Had more things to do.
Where are you?
London.
Looking for you everywhere,
will put you in jail.
I know, but have to go back now.
It has to stop.
Simon?
Yes?
Go back ?
Sure, I'll come back.
Well
You know what?
I found your ring.
Not true? Where?
Between the couch cushions.
Are you happy?
Yes
I'm back. I will.
Manchester United 1-0 Olympique Lyonnais