A Nikkatsu Presentation
Listen! You have to hit on girls ﬁrst!
And think about consequences later!
The sun looks like a pachinko ball.
That's right. It looks like
a pachinko ball indeed.
Wet Lust:
Opening the Tulip
l am very honored to have
you here in person.
Let's start immediately.
Please do.
Pass.
Everything passed the test.
Okay.
Since it's after business hours,
I've brought my own balls.
Please.
Please check.
They are okay.
Let's start a 5-ball game.
- I accept the offer.
Okay! Game start!
Please start.
The game is over.
Another loss? You have lost
10 games in a row!
Sorry.
Sorry? ls that it?
10 consecutive losses!
Do you want me to bust your balls?
Or cut your thumb?
EXCUSE my manners.
Thank you very much.
Sirs!
Sirs! Can you give me one more
chance to play the game?
One more time, please...
Producer: Akira Miura Screenplay: Tatsumi Kumashiro & Rio Kishida
Welcome. Welcome. Today is Sunday.
Director of Photography: Yonezo Maeda Lighting: Haruo Kawashima
As the staff representative, I really appreciate it you visiting us today.
As the staff representative, I really appreciate it you visiting us
today. Audio Recording: Fumio Hashimoto Art Director: Hiroshi Tokuda
As the staff representative, I really appreciate it you visiting us today.
As the staffrepresentative, I really appreciate it you visiting
us today. Editor: Akira Suzuki Assistant Director: Koji Kamoda
Editor: Akira Suzuki
Assistant Director: Koji Kamoda
Pachinko is where you release your stress and anger and show
your skills. Editor: Akira Suzuki Assistant Director: Koji Kamoda
Pachinko is where you release your
stress and anger and show your skills.
Pachinko is where you release your stress and anger
and show your skills. Music: Masayuki Yamamoto
Music:
Masayuki Yamamoto
Every tulip blooms with your skillful
action. Music: Masayuki Yamamoto
Every tulip blooms with your
skillful action.
Once you get a thousand bulls in your box,
your heartbeats and we get excited.
Please relax and choose the machine made
by Heiwa Industry to enjoy your games.
Anyone younger than 18 years old
and those who use magnets...
or any other illegal tricks
are not allowed in here...
One more game, please!
Starring:
Starring: Please come in. Thank
you very much. Thank you very much.
Please come in. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Meika Seri / Masami Ishii Kiyoyasu Adachi Please
come in. Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
Meika Seri / Masami Ishii
Kiyoyasu Adachi
Naomi Tani /Akemi Nijo / Akemi Nara
Yasuko Matsui / Naomi Oka
Naomi Tani  Akemi Nijo  Akemi Nara Yasuko Matsui / Naomi Oka The
reason why I am not good at pachinko is that I am popular with girls.
The reason why I am not good at pachinko
is that I am popular with girls.
Jun Hamamura  Eimei Esumi Hosei Komatsu The reason why I
am not good at pachinko is that I am popular with girls.
Jun Hamamura / Eimei Esumi
Hosei Komatsu
Jun Hamamura  Eimei Esumi Hosei Komatsu The reason why you
are good at pachinko is that you are not popular with girls.
The reason why you are good at pachinko
is that you are not popular with girls.
Shit! I lost again.
Bloom! Bloom! Bloom right now!
Wow! You are good!
Akira Takahashi / Wataru Kobayashi
Saburo Shoji /Toshiro Nishizawa
Keisuke Amakawa / Rei Minami
I will come back with better skills!
Kanpei Hazama
I can do it!
Directed by Tatsumi
Kumashiro I can do it!
Directed by
Tatsumi Kumashiro
Attention! Staff!
Apparently, we have a magnet-cheater
in the shop. Please watch out!
Move! Move! Move!
Stop! Move!
What the fuck?
What did I do?
Say it!
Don't act innocent!
This machine is under my control!
You are not allowed to cheat!
Cheat?
What did you say we did?
You used a magnet, of course.
A magnet?
- Of course! A magnet!
- A magnet? What?
How dare you say such a thing?
This is interesting.
Prove it! Don't go!
How dare you claim that
I've used a magnet?
Hey!
Think again!
People may even assume
that you are the cheater.
Check for yourself!.
Do mine too!
ﬁnd them!
Check for yourself!.
If you can't find any,
you will be in trouble!
l am your customer after all!
Do you think it will be fun to be
humiliated by your own customer?
ﬁnd them now! Idiot!
If you are wrong, you have
to sell your cute wife to me!
What is your excuse after making
us take off our clothes?
Sorry! Forgive me please!
-Sorry! I was wrong!
- Hey! It's too late to apologize!
Please forgive me! Sorry!
It's my fault!
Idiots like you make me puke!
- Idiot!
- You have to be punished!
-You damn liar!
-Sorry!
Bastard!
Please forgive me!
I really thought that they
were using magnets!
Why do I always do stupid things?
It's okay.
Everyone has unfortunate experiences
from time to time.
It could've gone worse.
You...
You've always been kind to me, ever
since we had lunch together as 7th graders.
If you keep consoling me like this,
I might fall in love with you.
No, you're wrong.
I merely care about you.
There is nothing more to it.
I know.
I know I am popular among girls.
Well. I can't say this or that
about other people's business...
I might have to use magnets
one day too.
Did you know?
Yes, I am no novice to
the pachinko business.
I hope you don't turn into
a dubious person like me.
Why didn't you tell them?
Because you don't want to hurt
our relationship?
Do you really think our relationship
means that much to me?
We are just two lowlives.
If you get busted, you will
be beaten almost to death.
I didn't tell anyone because
I understood your situation.
But he was desperate at that time.
What are you going to do to him?
My plan is just to be nice to him.
Shit! Put this in...
What an idiot!
I've never seen any clumsier
ﬁnger work than that.
- Did you do it by yourself?
- Idiot!
At least, I enjoy doing it!
Your face makes me sick.
Please hide it.
Girls don't like that kind of face.
They would run away.
Idiot! It's not that I like
your face either!
Why don't you jump into
the water and die?
Shit!
Idiot!
Trash!
Fool!
You are damaging the valuable goods!
Asshole!
Shit!
Who is buying those nowadays?
You are crazy!
I can't believe you own
such valuable things!
Are you stupid?
These are the old man's!
The old man?
I knew you couldn't afford them.
- They look too expensive.
- Idiot!
I don't need a speciﬁc place to live!
Unlike you, I stay at one girl's
place, and then at another's!
You are saying this because
you don't know girls!
You are 25 years old!
Such a good age to date girls!
ls there something wrong with you?
Are you done talking?
- Follow me!
- What are you going to do?
What is this?
Didn't you tell me that you'd
bring them in the summer?
I'll store them now in advance.
I will bring you a kotatsu
and a heater next year!
You store them at my place,
and you go out earning money?
Take good care of them!
I got it. You don't have
to say it again and again!
What are you talking about?
I have the right to refuse
customers I don't like!
There are a lot of girls waiting
for me to stay at their place!
Okay! I got it.
- How about him?
- He is a virgin! Pathetic!
Idiot! You can't be a virgin at 25!
How come you know my age?
- Whatever! You pathetic idiot!
- Leave me alone!
Listen! You have to hit
on girls ﬁrst!
And think about consequences later!
Okay? Don't forget it!
First block, second block, third block,
fourth block and ﬁfth block...
Mean old man!
Why did he talk to me like that?
He's a faggot! He must
have fallen in love with you!
Leave me alone! You're mean!
Even the old man pitied you.
It would have been even
weirder if he had pitied me.
Hey! You have to follow me!
What for?
I appreciate the money
you gave me earlier.
Get in!
You just have to listen
to what I say!
-What?
- I am going to help you.
Idiot! What are you going to do?
- You want to have sex, don't you?
- Of course I want to!
But I am not like you!
Do you know how to talk to girls?
Actually, I don't. You just know
when you do it.
Leave me alone!
First block, second block, third block,
fourth block and ﬁfth block to make a bridge...
Hello. Thank you for having me.
Hello.
I am a tailor.
I make formal dresses.
You must have seen the suit
he is wearing.
I make all of them.
They are well-made, aren't day?
Hurry!
Yes. ..
Thank you for having me!
It hurts!
I am saying it hurts!
Sorry!
Thank you for having me!
Sorry...
Sorry... Sorry...
Calm down!
The only reason I do this
is because Hiroshi asked me to!
I know! Sorry...
I don't know what to do!
I don't know what to do! Please, tell me!
You don't know how to have
sex at all, do you?
Sorry! I give UP!
I can't put up with a guy
who behaves like a drugged dog!
I can't take it anymore!
What an uncouth guy!
I got it.
It's over.
But do me a favor!
What?
Could you tell him that I did
have sex with you?
Please!
ﬁne!
Thank you very much!
What did you do? How pathetic!
Idiot! Fool! Trash!
I know!
We‘ve been waiting for you!
Please, come in
I am Michiko, a female professional
pachinko player.
I am Hiroshi's friend.
I am sorry for telling you what
I want over the phone earlier.
Are you ready to provide
what I asked for?
Yes, they are ready.
Please start.
Okay, let's start the process.
Are you okay with starting
the game immediately?
I accept the offer.
3-ball game...
Are you okay with it?
Please check.
They look okay.
Please start.
Game start!
Jackpot!
I lost!
I've heard a lot about you
from him.
Apparently, you can't focus on your work
because you want to have sex.
Once you become a good gamer,
girls will follow you by themselves!
More girls! More skills!
- I pity him.
- But he must have good skills.
He will become big!
He is not like you!
How dare you say such things!
- Maybe this is not enough.
- Harder!
- Don't you feel it?
- Fuck me harder!
That's right.
Maybe that's the spot!
-This?
-That's not it!
Idiot!
-That's it!
-This?
Yes! Yes!
-No!
- Which is it?
Idiot!
You got it wrong!
That's it! Maybe that...
That's not it... That's not it...
That's it! That's...
That's not it! That's not it!
I failed.
You were very close though!
What?
I used to be the girl boss
of a gang in my hometown...
but I want to become a proper
woman from now on.
- Thank you for visiting our business.
- You look very excited.
The staff at Heiwa is excited about
improving our business...
with the help of the best expert
in Japan.
Please follow me.
Mister! Nice to have you here today!
With your help, I've earned a lot.
- Really?
- You may go now.
- I will call you if I need you.
-Yes.
Hey, we can't relax here.
Why don't you go to the 2nd ﬂoor?
Let's go then.
Please go downstairs.
I see...
I followed you because you
told me so earlier.
And it's noisy downstairs.
Also, please don't use that
formal tone.
Hey! Spank me!
Slap me! Slap me!
Spank me! Slap me!
Spank me! Spank me!
How's that?
Slap me! Harder!
Spank me!
No! Hit me harder!
Slap me!
- Like that?
-Spank me!
No! That's not it! That's it!
That's it! Harder!
Harder! That's it!
Like that?
Spank me!
That's it! Harder!
That's it! Spank me!
Harder!
Spank me! Spank me!
Spank me!
Harder!
That's it! That's it!
Spank me!
Cigarette!
Lighter!
Although you can easily open the girls' legs,
you can't make the pachinko tulips bloom.
I am sorry.
My own teacher rejected his pupils
immediately if he thought...
they'd never be able to make
the tulips bloom.
sir!
Long time no see...
That's what I want to say.
Do you know how hard
I tried to find you?
What have you been doing
all these years?
Since you kicked me out
to make me independent...
I have been trying hard
to improve my skills.
Anyway, We can't talk here.
Let's go somewhere more comfortable.
Please, after you.
No.
I can't go now.
Please.
sir!
Ramen
My teacher used to tell me that
the left hand that inserts the balls...
and the right hand that snaps,
should work in sync at all times.
The harmony between the left hand and the
right hand brings us more balls in the end.
I think he couldn't accept people who
play pachinko without using their left hand.
As he got older, he must have felt that there
was not much time remaining for him.
He must have despaired when he found that
he couldn't use the old method anymore.
It's a depressing story.
It sure is.
Men's life is just too short.
Sex is not so different.
The amount a man can release
during his entire life is limited.
After releasing the full amount,
red balls come out in the end.
That's the end of it.
Moreover, "The End" is written
on the red balls.
That's the very last ball he can
use for his last game.
Follow me.
Yes.
Wait a sec.
Are you coming home tonight?
Isn't this where your girlfriend works?
She works here! What am I supposed
to do when I see her face?
Horny Gentlemen's Magic Hall
I know it is difﬁcult for you,
but I have my reasons.
In that case,
please tell me the reason.
I will tell you after the show.
Would you follow my instructions?
Yes.
So no more complaints. Got it?
Say it!
Be a man!
Mister! Mister!
It's your fault! Idiot!
This way! This way!
Here you are.
Sayuri! Look at us too!
Come to us now!
Hurry over here!
Yes, please enjoy.
Look at us too!
I would rather die than break up
with you - because I am a woman.
Here you go... Please enjoy...
Look!
- Does she know that we are here?
- Of course.
No way!
What the hell is going on?
Stop complaining!
Look!
Look at it!
I did.
- Did you?
- I did.
Did you?
I did.
Now you saw it.
Sleep with her tonight.
What did you just say?
Sleep with her.
Why?
I already have my red balls.
I can't do it.
Thank you for having me.
Nice to see you.
- Honey...
- I am going to start.
I am going to start.
Too much pachinko play made me
incapable of having sex with girls.
The open tulips might have
sucked my energy.
Good!
Does it feel good?
Honey... Honey... Honey...
- Does it feel good?
- It does... It does...
Honey... Let's cum together.
- You have to cum too.
- Together! Honey!
Together...
Honey...
Together... Honey...
You have to cum too.
Now... Now...
Hey! I want to become
a proper woman.
I really want to become
You have to hit on girls ﬁrst!
And think about consequences later!
To make girls like me!
To make girls like me by all means!
This is a once-in-a-lifetime favor.
Okay.
Thank you.
I love you so much that my body is burning.
Please have a date with me for once.
-Good morning, Mister!
- You must be Akira.
- I am.
l don't know why but it
doesn't open.
- Nice to meet you.
I think I am your 4th father.
What are you doing here?
I drank too much last night.
I didn't know what to do
when I woke up.
It opened.
One. two. one. two...
Oh! You're ﬁnally here!
How dare you!
We are a newly married couple!
You spent the whole night outside!
We registered our marriage
not long ago, didn't we?
Akira?
I wanted to talk with you too.
Do you want something?
My payday is soon.
I am going to have dates now.
I need some money.
You??
Honey! Honey!
Give him some money, okay?
Get it from your father.
Don't waste it!
Tsutengaku Main Street Arcade
Chinese Style Soba Noodles
Jiyoken
Let's go.
See you soon.
What?
This again?
You look good.
Where are you going?
It doesn't matter where you are going.
What do you want to do?
You still don't know how I feel?
Honey!
Aren't you supposed to have
a game with him?
Yes.
Then why are you here pushing
a food truck?
Why didn't you ask for a day
off instead?
Do you know what you are
talking about right now?
I would rather go somewhere else
than deal with your pathetic behavior!
I have been putting up with you
for 11 years!
Are you serious? I won't let you!
I only say this kind of thing
when I am serious!
Honey! Honey!
What are you doing?
Honey!
Honey! Honey!
Honey! Honey! I don't like this!
Hitachi Pump
Makiko! I am waiting for you!
As you see, Hiroshi has dozens
of other girls waiting for him.
That's not true!
You only believe what you
want to believe!
I am going to tell you the whole truth!
He mostly stays at the house of
a pachinko girl named Michiko.
Basically, he lives there having fun with her.
Honey!
He also has a tailor girl named Yumiko.
She gives him free clothing, including
suits for weddings and funerals.
Honey!
So what do you do?
The only thing you do is to cook
and provide meals for him!
You are the least attractive one
among Hiroshi's girls!
In other words, you are nothing
but a "rice-cooking girl" to him!
- A rice-cooking girl?
- Yes, that's what you are!
Honey! ls it true? Honey! Honey!
Human beings need something more
than luxurious clothes and houses.
The meals you make are delicious!
You are the only one who
can make them.
That's enough. Don't you think?
That means I am just
a rice-cooking girl, right?
No! You are not!
If no one made meals for me,
I would die.
What can you do other than
cooking rice?
Rice-cooking girl?
You are laughing at me!
I don't want to live anymore!
l am going to die!
I won't let you die!
I would rather die than be called
a rice-cooking girl!
I have nothing to say to you anymore!
I am going to die!
Bye!
- I am going to die!
- That makes me so happy!
- Die!
- Hey!
- I am going to die!
Makiko!
I can wait here forever!
I am going to die!
- I am going to die!
- Idiot! Wait!
Just let her die!
If you have time for this stupidity,
why don't you go...
to the pachinko parlor and
practice some more?
Let's go to the pachinko parlor!
Do you really want to be killed
by me?
- I am going to die!
- Idiot! Wait!
- I am going to die with you!
Honey! Idiot! Fool!
Honey! Help me!
Honey! Help me! Honey!
Makiko... I know you will come.
I know you will deﬁnitely come.
Makiko! I am waiting for you...
Honey...
If love is this painful,
l don't want to love anyone.
I can't forget...
Honey! You are a good guy...
Honey...
Now I know you love me!
It's so hard!
Yes, I love you.
You really love me!
You followed me into the water
because you love me!
That's right.
But having sex in a situation like this
is nothing but a hellish experience!
I am okay.
I am in a paradise!
She hasn't come, despite the fact that
I've been waiting for her this long!
No matter what I do,
I am just not popular with girls!
This is hell!
A living hell!
Shit!
This is hell!
Girls! Girls! Girls!
Akira!
- Akira!
-What’s up, mom?
People are looking at us!
Stop it!
- Akira! He is dead...
-No way!
He looked very healthy the other day.
A car accident?
-No! That's not it...
-Suicide?
That's not in.
I am talking about your real father.
There is nothing I can do
about him though...
Such an idiot!
Idiot! What's up?
What?! What's up?
My father passed away!
This shop...
He was the owner of this shop!
This is very overwhelming!
Please come with me.
Come in please.
Please go ahead.
What is this? I have no tears at all.
Say something.
Please.
- He is the lawyer.
-Yes.
Please read this.
- What is this?
-This is his will.
- Am I supposed to read it all?
- Yes.
Please explain it to me.
What am I supposed to do?
To make it short, he bequeathed
everything he had to you.
But this will be valid only
if you get married.
- Marry?
- Yes.
He lived alone since he separated
from your mother.
He had been very lonely,
and he knew about you.
He felt bad about you being a virgin.
- A virgin?
- He didn't want you to live like that.
So he wanted you to use
the money to get married.
You have to get married by the deadline
if you are still single.
In other words, the deadline is Tuesday,
November 11 at 9 AM.
If you get married by this date,
you will inherit 88,700,000 yen in total.
- I see.
- Here it is.
Thank you.
88,700,000. ..
- What date is it today?
- It's November 10.
- It's tomorrow!
- By 9 AM?
9 AM, the time when the city
ofﬁce opens.
It's 88,700,000 yen!
I wish he had told me that he was
my father when he was alive.
Why didn't he tell me?
But he left you 88,700,000 yen
anyway.
What are you going to do?
You have to get married.
Can you do it by tomorrow morning?
I can make it!
There must be at least one girl
I can marry!
Well... You have 88,700,000 anyway.
There must be a girl or two
who would marry you.
All girls are the same.
I don't need relationships!
I can live alone!
I want you to marry him.
Hello? Isn't it a sweet deal?
It's Akira. Akira.
If he marries a girl, he gets the money.
88,700,000.
A total of 88,700,000.
I see. Please consider it.
Thank you.
Sorry.
It turns out I had a father after all,
but he passed away.
Come here.
I've heard you are going
to inherit a fortune.
I am happy for you.
I am really happy.
But I don't know if I can
get the money.
This might sound stupid, but I have to
get married in order to inherit the money.
- Come here.
- Yes.
What's the problem?
Just do it.
Do you know a good woman?
Yes, I do.
Please introduce her to me.
I have to get married
by 9 AM tomorrow.
Well... I can marry you.
But marrying you is not an option.
Please forgive me.
That's not the right thing to do.
Sorry, please forgive me.
-What's the big deal?
- It's not right. It's not right.
- Please forgive me.
- Why!
- It's not right! Please forgive me.
-Why!
It's not right! Sorry. Sorry.
Please forgive me. Sorry.
Please forgive me.
It's not right.
Hello! Hello?
First block, second block,
third block...
First block, second
block. third block... Well...
Well...
Maybe it's time for me to clear
all of the girls on my list.
I have to give all of them to Akira.
When I view the orher side of the bridge, 17- or
18-year-old girls... I have to give all of them to Akira.
When I view the orherside of the bridge,
17- or 18-year-old girls...
When you measure the weights of loyalty
and humanity, loyalty is heavier in men's world.
When you measure the weights of loyalry and
humanity, loyalry is heavier in men's world. Go away!
Go away!
Akira! I've heard the news
from my friend.
Idiot! Stop it!
What are you doing? Leave me alone!
Marry me!
- Stop saying stupid shit!
- What's the matter?
I can serve you right. Akira...
I will never give Sayuri to you!
Answer me! Answer me right now!
You have to hurry!
Go away now!
Why does it have to go like this?
Sorry! I am really sorry!
No matter how hard you try,
I can't marry you.
I am really sorry!
I am going to give him everything!
Girls are not much different from
pieces of underwear to me anyway!
I can't take it anymore!
Akira!
Wait! Akira!
What?
Would you marry me?
I can become a good wife for you!
But you are his girlfriend!
I don’t care about that pathetic guy!
Okay! Okay!
Just let me consider it!
They all say they'll consider the offer,
but they don’t respect it in the end.
Who do they really think I am?
How miserable.
Sorry.
It's an airy, white body...
It's about time to do it right
and with guts.
God is not always generous.
- How about me?
- I can't marry you!
I know you are frigid!
Okay! It's ﬁnished!
Makiko...
First block, second block, third block,
fourth block and ﬁfth block to make a bridge...
You have a childish bitch nearby.
Why do I...
l give up!
I can't do it anymore! Makiko!
I am coming!
Mahjong Shibata - Open 24HR
Personal Loan - Itoman
Hey! Ladies! Where are you going?
in Kagoshima, Kyushu, he cut his stomach.
Hey! Ladies! Where are you going? In Kagoshima,
Kyushu, he cur his stomach. Move! Out of my way!
Hey! Ladies! Where are you going?
in Kagoshima, Kyushu, he cut his stomach.
- Let's go everyone!
- Let's go! Let's go!
The one you saw was a ghost.
It has an airy, white body.
The town of darkness is very distant,
like a dream.
We go over the rocks and the sky.
People say a generous Buddha
lives there.
She looks like someone from
the village of Buddhas.
First block, second block, third block...
Shibata
First block, second block, third block.. I said that
I could marry anyone, but actually there is only one.
I said that I could marry anyone,
but actually there is only one.
Makiko is the one!
Mahjong Shibata
Makiko!
When I view the orher side of the bridge...
-Makiko!
The 17 or 18 year old girl's hold ﬂowers and incense sticks in their hands.
-Makiko! -Makiko!
The 17 or 18 year old girls hold ﬂowers
and incense sticks in their hands.
and incense sticks in their hands. Makiko!
The 17 or 18 year old girls hold ﬂowers
and incense sticks in their hands.
and incense sticks in their hands. Makiko!
Makiko!
Hey! Ladies! Where are you going?
-Makiko! -Makiko!
-Makiko!
We are going to the grave...
He cut his stomach...
He cur his stomach...
Makiko!
He cut his stomach...
- Didn't you tell Makiko about the offer?
- I am here to tell her!
You are going to tell her for me, right?
l will.
What's up?
Akira is going to inherit a fortune.
Ah...
It's 88,700,000 yen.
Impressive!
But he needs to get married
to inherit the money.
Who?
Akira...
-So what do you think?
- About what?
Would you marry Akira?
It's 88,700,000 yen.
It's not a bad deal.
Say it one more time.
I mean...
To get 88,700,000 yen,
I marry Akira? ls that it?
Yes. So what?
How dare you disgust me like that?
- The one I like is you!
- I like you too!
- Then why did you tell me to marry him?
- It's 88,700,000!
That's irrelevant!
Do you know how much I have
been struggling because of you?!
You suck at playing pachinko!
You are a playboy!
I know that you are a pathetic guy!
But I didn't know that you
would sell your own woman!
Whatever!
I am going to do it if you want!
Akira!
Do you like me?
Of course!
Wait!
I like you too! I am serious!
How much do you like me?
I like you as much as I like pachinko.
Okay then.
You two have a game.
You are a pachinko engineer and
a professional pachinko player, right?
Play a gamete win me.
The winner will have me.
I can't do that.
But I can.
Let's do it.
I don't need razors anymore.
I am burying the razor.
Hiroshi! I hope you win!
Okay. This is our last moment, right?
Yes. No!
l don't want it to be!
I buried the razor.
I don't want to!
I have no one else to turn to.
Why did you make me play
a losing game?
What did you want me to do?
Dango, Dango
Do you want to watch the game
together?
- I might disturb you.
-No way.
I am very honored to have
you here.
sir!
Let me watch the game!
Yes.
Let's start.
Pass.
Everything passed the test.
Everything passed.
Use mine.
sir!
Let's start the ball game!
- I accept the offer.
Thank you very much.
I am going to start.
Game start!
No way! The machine must
have been rigged!
Idiot! You are not allowed
to rig the machine!
You are not allowed to rig the machine!
Idiot! Idiot!
This is your life!
You are supposed to stake your own lives
on each game!
You insulted me!
- Idiot! Apoligize!
- Stop!
Pachinko games are always like...
Thank you...
The old man was genuinely satisﬁed.
They are still young.
Let them bloom.
This is merely their starting point.
The professional pachinko player started
his eternal journey from then on.
Thank you very much.
First block, second block, third block...
Why did you rig the game?
I didn't, it's your skill.
I can't play an unfair game.
Thank you very much for giving
me Makiko.
You're welcome..
I am going to leave town to undergo
extensive training myself. So...
What?
Let me have a game with you in 1 year.
I am a man.
I am going to try hard to become
the best professional pachinko player!
In 1 year?
You can leave now!
I will be waiting for you!
The one you saw was a ghost.
It has an airy, white body.
I hope it isn't a practical joke.
Makiko!
It isn't.
- Thank you very much.
Bloom! Bloom! Bloom right now! Tulip!
That's not it.
Where is it?
That's not it! That's not it!
- Where is it?
- That's not it! That's it!
That's it! Honey! That's it!
That's it! That's not it!
That's not it!
-That's not it!
- Where is it?
That's it! Honey!
That's not it! Idiot!
- I said that's not it!
- So where is it, exactly?
That's not it! That's it! Honey!
Bloom! Bloom! Bloom right now! Tulipl