EVERY DAY, CRUEL AND APPARENTLY
INEXPLICABLE THINGS HAPPEN.
ONLY THROUGH A FAITHFUL
RECONSTRUCTION OF THESE INCIDENTS...
IT IS POSSIBLE TO UNDERSTAND THEIR
DRAMATIC AND DISTURBING SIGNIFICANCE.
Come on, harder.
Kick it in.
Come on, men, let's start.
Call the pathology department.
And somebody writes this down:
School books and notebooks...
cardigan, blouse, blue trousers.
White nylon briefs.
- Half-boots...
- The public prosecutor is here.
Show him in.
- Well?
- It's a lady...
It's a young girl.
No more than fifteen.
She tied the rope
around the beam...
put her head into the noose...
and down.
- Do you know who she is?
- Not yet.
We couldn't find
any papers.
The pages of the notebooks
with her name on them were ripped out.
- Who owns the garret?
- We're checking it out now.
Who knows why she did it...
We had to break the door down
to get in.
Why did she undress herself?
Who knows what goes through
a girl's head...
- who decided to commit suicide.
- How did you find out about this?
An anonymous phone call.
A men's voice.
He only said that
somebody hanged himself here.
May we take the body away now?
Inspector, please write your report
as quickly as possible.
Of course.
Let's get her down.
Yes, sir, a minor.
Perhaps she ran away from home.
- One of many.
- And the parents?
So far we know nothing
about them.
And no girls were reported missing
in the last few days.
But considering I've only been here
for a short while, I've already settled in well.
Thank you anyway.
I'll keep you informed.
Now take a look at this.
Wouldn't it be enough
to only photograph her face?
Yes, I've seen it.
But in cases like this,
the photographers can't believe their luck.
- What have you got, Valentini?
- The results of the autopsy.
The girl wasn't older than fifteen.
She had complete
sexual intercourse...
shortly before
she killed herself.
Integral intercourse.
So she didn't use any contraceptives.
They found traces of sperm in the vagina,
as well as in the anus and the stomach.
Death occurred yesterday afternoon,
on Tuesday.
Between 5 and 6 p.m.
The girl was expecting.
- She was pregnant?
- Yes, about two months.
- Did you call the police?
- Yes. It's her, it's Silvia.
How horrible.
I immediately recognised her in the papers.
My God, the poor thing.
- Where are her parents?
- In Africa.
They own a factory down there.
They departed a week ago.
- Since when has she been missing?
- Since Tuesday afternoon.
Why didn't you call the police
right away?
It wasn't the first time
this happened.
Also that she stayed out
all night?
When her father wasn't home,
it happened.
Silvia always managed to get everything
she wanted from her mother.
- How old was she?
- Not yet fifteen.
Did she have
any acquaintances?
By that I mean...
did she have a boyfriend?
You know anything about that?
When she was little,
she used to tell me things...
but she stopped doing so when...
when she became a woman.
Someone's calling all the time.
I'm so afraid.
What am I going to tell
her parents?
We'll take care of that.
And what's this?
She always wore it around her neck.
Until recently.
This is footage shot
by our undercover officers...
during a demonstration
and the riots...
in the centre of town
a few days ago.
Watch carefully here.
We have to take a closer look
at the shots of these three.
Rewind.
They can be identified here,
Ms. public prosecutor.
Stop here.
Mario Felici.
- Student?
- Part-time student.
He's a professional agitator.
- Alright, let's go on.
- Play.
An old acquaintance,
you might say.
An extremist, on record.
- Violent.
- Please go on.
- Excuse me, I was at the girl's house...
- We need to finish this first.
Giovanni Vici, nineteen years old.
- May I see the scene before this again?
- Rewind.
Stop here.
Can you enlarge it?
isn't that the girl
who hanged herself?
- Russo, when was this shot?
- The day before yesterday.
- On Tuesday. What hour?
- Must have been around 5, 5.30 p.m.
That's when we started
to observe that house.
Nobody left it again until midnight.
I was there.
Do you understand, Valentini?
Neither did Silvia
leave it before midnight.
But Silvia was already dead then.
She wasn't already dead.
She had already been murdered.
Did they give you my report?
I already took a look inside.
An ugly affair.
I'm sorry, but the case
is now within your jurisdiction.
It first looked like suicide,
but now it's clear that she was murdered.
And during the night,
they shifted the corpse into the garret...
at the other side of the town.
- Are you going to take me or not?
- Wait in the car. I'll be there in a minute.
In a way, I'm relieved
that the case is with you now.
This girl, Silvia...
was the same age as my daughter.
Let's go, Giardina.
We'll start with the garret.
Alright.
The coroner is already waiting for us.
There, you see?
The body was hanging here, next to the table.
The thing is:
The killer did everything
terribly impeccable.
He didn't only strangle her
before he strung up her body on that beam...
but must have also pulled the body down
with all his force...
until the
cervical vertebra broke.
Now, according to the results
of the autopsy...
- he consequently...
- Stop, don't move.
I said, don't move.
- But it's the assistant public prosecutor.
- He mustn't move either.
Somebody's watching us
from the balcony of the opposite building.
With a binocular or something like that.
Top floor. Go, Giardina.
I'm the assistant public prosecutor,
Vittoria Stori.
We'll have to reconstruct the girl's life
minute for minute.
But this has got to be a joke, inspector.
Are you trying to tell me...
that someone who photographs as a hobby
is committing a crime?
Why did you pick that garret
as your target today of all days?
I didn't pick anything as a target.
This is not a cannon....
Here, inspector.
We've printed the film.
Well, Mr. Paglia,
take a good look.
This girl was killed.
Now I'm asking you
to collaborate with the law.
But look, I...
I took them by sheer chance.
And when I saw that thing -
terrible, I must say...
- Did you call the police?
- But of course.
- There, you see that I am collaborating.
- And this photo? And that one?
And this one?
All of them by chance?
Well, first off, it needs to be assessed
whether a free citizen may or may not do this.
Indeed, it has to be assessed.
In the meantime,
you're in investigative custody.
Call your lawyer if you like.
These are enlargements of the photos
we found in Paglia's apartment.
This is Silvia Polvesi.
The boy is always the same.
They must've been certain
that nobody could watch them.
But Paglia could shoot them
from the opposite building.
They look so happy.
I'd say they had no inhibitions.
They're just two youths.
Yes, two youths.
But they did things for adults.
Now it won't be difficult
to find that boy.
You know this man?
- Yeah, that's Marcello.
- And where is he?
- He's underground.
- Underground where?
In the grotto.
Almost 300 feet down.
- How long has he been buried there?
- For four days.
- Tell him to come up.
- And why?
Because I need to talk to him.
Police.
What does Marcello have to do
with the police?
Make him come up,
I'm asking the questions.
Fabio. Call Marcello.
- Come on, call Marcello.
- Marcello, you hear me? Over.
We've found him, but I don't think
he has anything to do with it.
I'm excluding him.
He's been underground since Sunday.
Underground?
What do you mean?
He's a cave explorer
or something.
But Silvestri,
the girl had intercourse...
shortly before she was killed.
And that was on Tuesday.
Indeed.
But then Silvia
had another lover.
Yes, a lethal lover.
She wasn't even fifteen years old...
It's enough.
What else do you want from me?
I don't even want to hear
her name anymore, understand?
Ask these questions
to the other chap.
I only know...
that she disgusts me.
Don't you understand
that Silvia is only the victim?
And her murderer
is precisely that other fellow.
And you're the only one
who can help us finding him.
Did you know that Silvia was underage?
You realise what that means?
For how long did you have
a sexual relationship?
We met each other
three months ago.
By chance.
- We fell in love on the spot.
- And the garret?
That was a surprise.
A surprise she could afford.
I knew little
about Silvia's family.
But they had to be well-off.
Silvia had enough of everything.
Be it money or time.
Of which I surely have much less.
But I liked her, and she liked me.
And that was enough for me.
She had rented that garret.
It was our hideaway.
Where we made love.
- Is that where she was killed?
- We don't know yet.
Was she a virgin?
- Why is that important?
- Were you the first?
Would you please sign here?
Seems like we've found the apartment
where the girl was killed.
We need your authorisation
to break the door open.
- You have it.
- Go ahead, Giardina..
Are you sure, though?
We searched the building
top to bottom.
Luckily we found out the name
of the tenant.
You found the tenant?
Well, then...
He's someone
who pays on time every month.
It's just that he's been dead
for three years.
Call Pathology, Giardina.
It's just a formality.
We don't need them to see
that this is blood in saliva.
I'm sure that the girl
was strangled right here...
and then taken to the garret
when she was dead.
Search the entire apartment.
A tape-recorder.
It was hidden inside this wall.
And no tapes, of course.
I bet forensics
won't find a single fingerprint.
Inspector.
Inspector, take a look at this over here.
But this is horrible.
This makes it two crimes.
Now we have to find out
who's the second victim.
- Sign here.
- What is he, your brother?
Sign here, Mr. Paglia.
Sign it.
And my best regards
to the inspector.
- What is this?
- The lawyer...
This is the chief prosecutor's
realisation...
- that this has been a misunderstanding.
- Which means?
Well, my clear inspector,
times have changed.
In the past, the suspicion of a guard post
was sufficient to bring a respectable citizen...
I've never met
a respectable citizen...
who took pictures of dead bodies
by sheer chance.
Anyway, you're free to go.
For now.
Does he expect me to be grateful now?
Finally. Can it be possible
that you can't tell us anything?
We have to write
something about it, inspector.
- Do you have a lead?
- Tell us something.
- In what state is the investigation?
- Inspector Silvestri.
Why did the police suppress the story
of this new killing for 24 hours?
Because forensics
had to make absolutely sure...
that it's actually human blood.
You tried to solve a crime
and accidentally came across another?
- Is there a link...?
- Are you certain...
that little Polvesi was killed
in the same apartment?
One question at a time, gentlemen,
or I will refuse to answer.
It's fact that
you have nothing to tell us.
I'm telling you everything I know.
- You don't even listen to us.
- You ask the questions for all of them.
Inspector Silvestri, the fact that
two people were killed at the same place...
allows for the presumption
that you're dealing with a monster.
- A maniac.
- There's no reason to presume this.
Sure, these are conjectures.
But they're quite justified...
considering the sparse facts
you're supplying us with.
First of all, we have to identify
the second victim.
Don't you think the second victim
might also be a girl?
That might indicate the existence
of a madman, of a sex maniac in this city.
If you want to know
whether it's a girl...
you'll have to wait
for the histological evidence.
Regarding the theory
of the monster:
Since you have to sell newspapers...
just go ahead and publish it.
You will cause a panic
among the public.
We will take care of the public.
You better think about
finding the killer.
We will find him...
as long as
you don't tie us in red tape.
This is a disgrace.
Lovers, a double life, even drugs..
She was just a child.
How can you permit such a thing?
How can these people be allowed
to print articles like that?
You're right,
but the press is the press.
And naturally they like to embellish things
with lots of fantasy.
Your daughter's a victim.
But unfortunately,
it's my duty to get to the bottom of it.
What do you want to know
from me?
Did you have the confidence
of your daughter?
Silvia adored me.
I asked you if she confided in you.
With me,
there was always fighting...
but adoration for her father.
I thought it was just a phase
all girls go through.
But then...
Then...
when I accidentally
found out...
that Silvia
was not a virgin anymore...
I became frightened.
You knew it?
Since when?
One day I found pills...
in her jacket pocket.
Pills for birth control.
I refused to believe it.
She was still a little girl.
What is it?
Silvia, where did you get these?
In a chemist.
That's where I buy them.
Silvia... But...
- Mother, please don't make a drama out of it.
- What are you saying?
- You're still a little girl.
- Of course, a little girl.
Only that I'm capable of
bearing a child every nine months...
When your father
hears about this.
Because I will tell your father.
You'll see that I'll tell him.
Just try it.
Then I will cut my throat.
She told me
she'd carry it always with her.
"If you tell my father,
I will cut my throat."
Of course I would've never had the strength
to tell it to my husband.
I even hired a policeman.
I didn't know what I should do.
I was desperate.
- A private detective, you know?
- What's his name?
A certain Talenti.
At first he calmed me down,
but then...
after a few days he told me
he couldn't take care of it anymore.
He had other things to do.
At heart I was almost
pleased with that.
The man seemed
a little shady.
- Talenti you said?
- Yes. Ruggero Talenti.
Talenti, Ruggero, thirty-four years-old,
born in Schio, gun license...
married...
background check in progress.
- So, did you find him?
- His office has been closed for five days.
I made an inquiry at headquarters.
Here.
Married...
Look for the wife?
- They've been separated for two years.
- Well... find her.
She surely knows something.
Perhaps he has a girlfriend, a mistress...
Or did he stop?
Alright.
Get me Polvesi on the line.
No, I didn't know that my wife
hired a private detective.
Well, to tell you the truth...
I never had the time
to take care of my daughter.
Only last year I noticed
a strange, alarming change...
in the girl's personality.
She was usually so open-hearted and happy...
I then took her to Beltrame -
you know professor Beltrame, I imagine?
- Yes, by reputation. What did he say?
- Well, he calmed me down.
He said that this change
of personality...
is quite normal
for girls of that age.
I'm sorry, but I think
we'll have to pay him a visit.
Why? Do you think he might have
withheld something from me?
No. But we need
to pursue every detail.
Even the smallest one, to which
a year before nobody in the family...
attached much importance,
but maybe a doctor did.
No, I don't remember anything special.
And here?
I can't find anything else I noted down
apart from what I've already told you.
I can assure you
my overall impression was...
to be faced with an adolescent
who's very sensitive for her age.
- Maybe a little frustrated.
- Frustrated?
I'm not allowed to tell you anything more,
you must understand.
If you knew
how many girls of that age...
can cause their parents
great problems.
Take a look at this.
These are some other girls...
who might turn into tragic cases.
Thank you, professor.
Should it be necessary,
I will ask you for a formal statement...
and will free you
from certain professional restrictions.
Alright.
I'm at your service.
There she is.
I'll see you this afternoon.
- Mrs. Talenti, is this your husband?
- That was my husband.
- What do you want from me?
- We need to talk to you.
I don't want to hear
the name of that pig anymore.
- He's a private detective?
- Yes, the private detective...
Could you tell us,
where we can find him?
Me? How should I know?
- Ask his secretary.
- Who's that?
A whore.
Who goes to bed with him.
- And where is she?
- In hospital.
They had an accident.
Unfortunately, they're not dead.
Come on, let's go, Napoli.
Whoever this secretary might be,
she can only be better than that one.
Drive.
Did his wife send you?
- What do you want from me?
- We have to ask you a few questions.
We were told that Talenti
used to visit you quite often.
That's him, isn't it?
Is he?
When did you last see him?
What are you, a policewoman?
- I'm the assistant public prosecutor.
- Silvestri...
It's possible we've found the car
of that Talenti.
- Could you proceed?
- Of course.
So?
I haven't seen him
in two days.
That never happened before.
He hasn't even called.
According to the license plate
it belongs to Ruggero Talenti.
The car has been parking here
for two or three days - locked.
Come on, force the lock.
Open the trunk.
There we have the second body.
I'm sorry, but I have to ask you
a few questions.
May I continue?
Did Talenti ever tell you about
a new, important assignment?
Doesn't the name
Silvia Polvesi ring a bell?
Talk, Rosa. I have to know.
Have you ever felt threatened?
No, I don't know anything.
You work for Talenti,
you were also his secretary.
- So how can't you know anything?
- I haven't been to the office in months.
Ever since the accident.
You had three operations.
These operations were expensive.
How did Talenti pay for them?
Ruggero... was so good...
But he needed money, is that right?
A lot of money. And how did he get it?
You know it. Did he blackmail someone?
You know it, and you have to tell me.
He found something out
that made him money. A lot of money.
That's why they killed him
in that manner.
- What manner?
- It's enough, Silvestri.
The law forbids me
to say and ask you anything else.
Isn't that right, Mrs. public prosecutor?
The law only forbids you
to apply certain methods.
I'm positive she knows something.
Something that might help us
to find out...
who killed a girl
and murdered a man.
It's not important.
- The murder weapon?
- An axe or something like it.
He was probably still alive
when they started.
- What tells you this?
- Well, everything. Also the blood.
Maybe he tried to defend himself.
Are you ready for the identification?
Cover him up and let the wife in.
Mrs. Talenti,
do you recognise your husband?
We need your official identification.
- I want to see his body.
- That's not necessary. The face will suffice.
I want to see him.
I want to see
what they did to him.
Please...
I'd like to talk to the police.
- That's not possible, Miss.
- I know it's late.
But it's really important.
I'm begging you.
As you wish.
One moment.
Put her through.
Yes, it's me.
Tell me, what is it, Rosa?
Come over right now.
I think I kept something from you
that might be important.
Maybe also important for others.
And I'm afraid.
Come right away, I'm begging you.
Of course I will.
Calm down now. I'll be right there.
Let's go, Napoli.
What is going on?
Aren't you feeling well?
Come on. Let's go.
To bed, yes?
What were you planning to do?
You could have called
if you needed something.
Now I will give you a nice injection,
then you can sleep soundly.
No, I don't want to...
Call me if you need something.
Now I will chop you to pieces.
Just like I did with your boyfriend.
But first you will tell me
where you hid the stuff.
After him, Napoli.
Take care of her.
Go.
Notify Giardina and send all cars
that are in this area.
I repeat, all available cars
to the city centre.
He's driving towards
Old Station Square. Over.
O Kappa: Car 3 and 7.
Drive to Old Station Square. Over.
Car 3, driving towards
Old Station Square.
Car 7, we're on our way.
We're now at Old Station Square.
We're closing in on him.
Giardina, he drove to Fountain Quarter.
Block the exit.
He's coming towards us.
There, I can see him.
I repeat:
Drive to the highway.
They're forcing him out of town.
- Are you there too, Giardina?
- Right behind you.
I could shoot him, that bastard.
Yes, great, good idea.
Then you'd go right to jail.
Better in jail than driving like this.
We forced him onto the road
leading to the lake.
- Try to cut him off
- O Kappa, inspector Silvestri.
At least two cars are driving
for support into this zone.
We're at the tunnel.
Did you set up a road block?
Yes, inspector.
About half a mile ahead of you.
Send all available patrols
to this spot.
Turn this area upside down
even if you sweat blood.
But find me that son of a bitch.
Can she talk, doctor?
Well, what didn't you tell us?
What did they want from you?
- Very good. So you were right.
- It's not important.
We cut the sections together...
in which the voices
are recognisable.
Come in.
- It's open.
Hello, dear.
Let's have a look at you.
You know that you're very graceful?
Really.
I've waited for so long.
- Have you never been here before?
- No, it's the first time.
Don't be afraid.
Don't just stand there so stiff.
Come here.
- I won't bite you...
- What do you want me to do?
You seem to be in a hurry.
Relax.
I am going to show you.
- But I have to go home.
- I know, I know.
You're just coming from school,
and they're waiting for you at home.
But I'm sure
you can think of a nice excuse...
for being
half an hour late.
Well, let's get started.
Take off your clothes.
Off with the smock.
Just like that.
And now... the blouse.
Good.
The skirt...
Come on...
What's the matter?
- You see, I...
- Come on...
Don't be afraid.
Wait...
I will take off
the knickers myself.
You're lovely. Lovely...
Walk a few steps.
You're the sweetest thing
in the whole world.
And now...
we'll get to know each other
a little better.
Here, you see?
Come on...
Sit down...
No... here.
Sit on my knees.
Like that...
Yes, just like that.
One leg there...
and the other one here.
That's it.
These are two more voices
from another recording.
What are you doing?
- Easy, you're tearing up my blouse.
Now take off your clothes.
Do it quick.
-What do I have to do now?
- Lay on the bed.
No, wait.
Put these two cushions under your legs.
But... what is this.
What is this thing?
Listen, less chatter, please.
I paid a lot of money...
and they told me, I could do what I want
with the girl they send me.
- So be quiet and let me do my thing.
- Quiet?
- But what is this?
- That thing that frightens you so much...
will give you a lot of pleasure.
You'll see.
- No, I don't want that.
- Now stop it. Come on...
- Yes... just like that...
- Yes. You like it.
Well, did you find anything?
A tire print of the motorcycle
on soft ground.
- The plaster cast is with forensics.
- Good. And how's Napoli?
The poor chap,
they operated him.
Come in.
Here, inspector.
The cast turned out very well.
But the tire
is a very common type.
One thing's for sure:
It's from a motocross bike.
That's something.
Now it's your turn, Giardina. We got work to do.
Search for all stores
selling, producing or mounting this tire.
I want a complete list
of all persons...
who bought a bike like this
over the last three years.
- And the hatchet?
- Here it is.
No fingerprints, of course.
But it's a special type,
a cleaver for butchers.
- Look, I...
- Sit on my knees.
Like that...
Yes, just like that.
One leg there...
and the other one here.
That's it.
Come here.
Let's have a look at you.
- It's not so bad, is it?
- Could we talk a little less...?
- That's Silvia.
- I don't have much time.
That's my daughter.
But what's she doing on that recording?
- Silvia...
- What is this?
I know this is a painful matter.
Silvia was in a ring
of underage prostitutes...
for men of a certain age.
And not only your daughter.
On this recording
we have voices of six more girls.
- All of them very young.
- But Silvia is dead.
That's exactly
why we must save the others.
- Silvia was beautiful, happy...
- Let's talk about the phone calls.
I wanted to also talk with her mother
about the calls Silvia was getting.
But she told me to stay out of it.
Try to remember
something specific.
For example,
have you ever picked up the phone?
Silvia did everything she could
to keep me from doing so.
- But then suddenly something changed.
- In what way?
Recently she stopped
picking up the phone.
She had intense crying fits.
You see, I had the impression
that she's in love.
One day I spied on her
and frankly asked her if she was threatened.
She didn't tell me anything but she was
downright terrified and ran away.
- What day was that?
- Tuesday.
The day she was murdered.
Santelli, Zeno: Tramway employee,
Saccio, Annamaria: Student...
Melchiorri, Roberto: Butcher.
Wait a minute.
Come in.
It's open.
- Good morning, my dear.
The list of everyone
who recently bought a bike like that.
Look at the bottom.
A butcher, my God.
Have them track him down immediately.
No, you go personally, Giardina.
And please report in right away,
no matter what time it is.
Let's have a look at you.
You know that
you're very graceful?
- Chin up.
- The same goes for you.
I keep asking myself
why I chose this profession.
Although, this one or another,
it's always the same.
- You just have to believe in what you do.
- And you believe in it?
Of course.
Even if I sometimes have the feeling
that I do everything wrong.
That's probably only because
you got involved in a case like this one.
Probably.
Did you hear that, Silvestri?
What my colleagues say?
That a case like this
is too tough for a woman.
Because women are weak.
So you probably need muscles
to take care of a case like this.
- You think so too, don't you?
- I never said that.
After everything that happened,
you actually seem to have proven the opposite.
Thank you.
I had to get this off my chest.
Yes, Silvestri here.
- It's me.
- Go ahead.
This might be a promising lead.
The butcher disappeared.
But I have a photo of him.
- Can you come to the office?
- Be right there.
From his father.
He said his son left home
almost three months ago...
and he hasn't seen him
ever since.
- Which of these four is he?
- That one there.
At least we know
what he looks like.
Have a few enlargements made
and sent to all precincts.
Wait...
He doesn't know
we identified him.
Have them watch the butchery
and tap his phone instead.
Already done.
Pathology, send in Fasanelli.
Come on, spread your legs.
- No, I don't want to.
- Well, now stop it... Come on...
- Yes, just like that...
- Yes. You like it.
Come in.
It's open.
Good morning, my dear.
You know that you're very graceful?
- Have you never been here before?
- No, it's the first time.
Don't be afraid.
Don't just stand there so stiff.
- Come here.
- What do you want me to do?
- You seem to be in a hurry.
- I have to go home.
- Yes, just like that...
- Yes. You like it.
Come in.
It's open.
Good morning, my dear.
You know that you're very graceful?
LAST WARNING
Would you mind
coming up for a minute?
I'd like to talk to you.
- Did you find the letter yesterday?
- The letter?
- You put it there.
- It was delivered very late yesterday.
And not to disturb you,
I thought...
- I'd slip it under the door.
- Who brought it?
A young man.
The Polvesis... filthy rich, scatterbrained -
but no, it has to be someone like me.
Condemned to this rubbish job
for a few blasted lira.
And all that just for my daughter,
who's the light of my eyes.
But who are they?
What do they want? Why?
That's Patrizia.
That's the voice of my daughter.
That's my daughter on these recordings.
My daughter with these pigs.
Find me one of them, Silvestri.
I will kill him with my own hands.
But you need to help us.
Go and pick up Patrizia from school.
We'll talk together.
And try not to frighten her.
What's that?
- Not important anymore.
- An anonymous letter?
In the last one I got...
they threatened
to blow up the headquarters.
Come on.
The papers
won't leave us in peace.
The commissioner called
two minutes ago.
He said those in Rome
are already driving him mad.
And why don't they
search him themselves, those in Rome?
They only need
to show it on
- and the butcher will come on his own.
- TV, that's an idea.
Take this photo
and have them make an enlargement.
Hello.
Give me the commissioner.
Would you like a cigarette?
I asked for
a public announcement on
to support
the search for the killer.
I know, commissioner,
but I can't leave any stone unturned.
I'm sorry.
Did you hear?
TV suggests to show
the public announcement during a show...
on police work that will be broadcast
in two days. Understand?
They're doing us a "favour".
Listen, I forgot something.
Listen....
Are you mad?
Stop it
Everything's fine.
I'll take you to your apartment.
- Was it the same man?
- He only confirmed our assumptions.
- How's the public prosecutor?
- Is it true that she was raped?
Hey.
They're bringing the body of the driver.
The deed prompted a manhunt
of unforeseen scale.
Not only the city but also the surrounding
regions are being combed by the police.
After the terrible crimes
of the last few days...
the assistant public prosecutor Vittoria Stori
was attacked last night...
when she returned
to her apartment.
The public prosecutor
was miraculously saved...
thanks to the intervention
of her building superintendent.
But the driver of her staff car
was unfortunately ferociously murdered.
Due to this clustering
of criminal incidents...
the police asks for
the collaboration of all citizens.
Reliable evidence
allows for the conclusion...
that the culprit
is a certain Roberto Melchiorri...
of whom we will now
show you a picture.
Every clue could be helpful
to the police.
You only have to call 112.
Repeat everything you've told me.
Tell them how you came into this work.
But I...
I was only there one time.
On this tape is your voice
and that of a man, Patrizia.
Did you know him?
I had never seen him before.
And I haven't
seen him again afterwards.
- How were the appointments arranged?
- By phone.
BY whom?
I don't know.
Bigi told me
that somebody would call.
And who's that Bigi?
Giuliana, a classmate of mine.
You know her, father.
I've known her since she was little.
I never liked her much.
Who's Giuliana Bigi?
- That's me. Why?
- You'll have to come with us.
- What do you want from me?
- Come along.
Lucia, see you later at your place.
They also caught Bigi.
- How do you know?
- How do I know?
I'm standing in front of the school
and they just took her away.
Does she know you?
Did she ever meet you in person?
Of course not, never.
But the others have.
Now don't get on my nerves
like that idiot.
Yes, but excuse me,
if one of them spills the beans...
eventually someone will get it
and we all go to jail.
What are you saying? The more are in on it,
the more relaxed we can be.
If Bigi tells them
all she did and with whom...
no one can get to us,
understand?
- But I...
- Enough.
You know there are people who'll protect us.
Don't leave town.
Trying to run is the only thing
that makes you suspicious.
Yes, but it would be better to stop,
now this thing with Polvesi happened...
Not at all.
You're foolish.
I decide whether we stop,
when and how.
Damn you...
I didn't want to...
Calm down, Patrizia.
Take her home, Valentini.
Excuse me, dear.
I'm a little late.
Your loss and your problem.
Now you'll have to settle
for half an hour.
What, half an hour?
I paid for one hour.
And I want to spend
one hour with you.
I don't care if you're late.
Just go
and complain to Bruno.
Who is Bruno?
Well?
Such a fuss over
four times fucking...
I asked you who Bruno is.
I've never seen him,
he always calls.
You've never seen him?
- Never met him?
- Never.
He told me on the phone
where I have to go and when.
Do you know other girls
from the ring?
- No, nobody.
- And how did you get into it?
It was Bruno.
He called me every day.
He said, I could earn
a heap of money.
- So you do know him.
- No. I've never met him in person.
Who is it?
It's me, open up.
- Who?
- They arrested Bigi.
Open up, quick.
Be quiet.
Don't talk in the hall.
Car 4, are you there?
- Yes he's wounded, loses lots of blood.
- The ambulance is coming.
- Does he have any papers?
- Yes, a mail subscription. For Bruno Paglia.
It's Bruno Paglia, inspector.
He was already arrested in the Polvesi case.
- We know that. Nothing else?
- Only that he was interrogated...
- and released again.
If they tried to eliminate him,
he has to know something.
They're afraid he'll talk.
If you consider
that we already had him...
But the chief prosecutor,
the protocol, police ordinance...
- Step back, step back.
- What happened?
Please step back.
- Will he make it?
- I don't think so.
He was stabbed five times
in the stomach.
It would be a miracle
if he'd make it to the hospital.
- They messed him up badly, the poor man.
- Do something, doctor.
I do what I can,
but I can't perform miracles.
This man knows important things,
and he has to tell them to me, doctor.
At any cost, even if I have
to beat them out of him.
Did you call these girls?
- Answer.
- He's lost lots blood...
- and still does.
- But I have to interrogate him.
I can't allow that in his condition.
It's very serious.
Nobody cares
if that son of a bitch dies.
The only bad thing is
if he dies without talking.
Talk, for God's sake.
He's dead.
- Gentlemen, the case is solved.
- Solved, how?
Would you tell us how?
In a few hours I'll be able
to tell you names, all names.
The ones of the executors
as well as the masterminds.
They tried to get rid of a witness
and accomplice.
A certain Bruno Paglia.
He survived and is in hospital.
Nobody can get near him.
As soon as his condition allows...
he'll tell the chief prosecutor
everything he told me.
Please tell us something.
- Did he reveal a lot, that Paglia?
- Unfortunately...
I can't say anything
ahead of the official statement.
The case... is solved.
- Can we publish that?
- Yes, of course.
You said the case was solved.
That's outrageous.
Don't think about
dragging me into this.
I didn't want to drag
anybody into this.
You promised the press
to make a corpse talk.
I don't want anybody to know about
Paglia's death until noon.
I need to buy time until the papers
have published the false story.
Alright.
I got a lot of work on my table.
I'll delay the interrogation
of your corpse until noon.
That's all I want.
Someone's behind that whole story
who's now lost his head.
The murder of Bruno Paglia
proves this.
The papers have to make this someone
believe that the man has talked.
Silvestri, you're gambling
with your career.
Don't you think it's worth it?
POLVESI CASE:
THE NAMES OF THOSE RESPONSIBLE
IN THE NEXT FEW HOURS
UNDERAGE CALL-GIRLS:
SENSATIONAL DEVELOPMENT
IN POLVESI CASE
BRUNO PAGLIA HAS TALKED
POLVESI CRIME:
SUDDEN TURN IN INVESTIGATION
You know very well that the fact
that Beltrame killed himself...
doesn't prove that
he was involved in this story.
Yes, of course.
That's why I asked you...
to authorise
a further investigation of the case.
I don't have a problem with that.
But don't forget
that we need crucial evidence.
I hope to deliver you some soon.
- So have you identified all of them?
- Everybody.
Except for that girl
who was there alone.
But that's exactly the one I want.
Find her and take her to the public prosecutor.
Let's go, Giardina.
- Where are we going?
- To that fine gentleman, Beltrame.
But he's dead.
Dead he'll tell us more
than when he was alive.
We still have to get rid of the nightmare
of that madman with the hatchet.
- Did anybody call?
- Dozens, it's a chaos.
- As usual, people saw everything everywhere.
- But nobody can say something specific...
You're Laura Bolero?
Why have you been
to professor Beltrame's funeral?
Since when do you know him?
I'm afraid.
- They will hurt me.
- And who are you afraid of?
They kept telling me
I mustn't say anything to anyone.
They... they will hurt me.
But there's no need
to be afraid, Laura.
Nobody can hurt you.
Because we will protect you.
You're completely innocent.
You're a minor.
Be brave, Laura, talk.
Where and when
did you meet professor Beltrame?
When did you visit him
the first time?
My mother took me.
Two years ago.
The professor was different
than the other doctors.
I trusted him.
He had me come to his office
several more times.
He said it's to continue
with the therapy.
He gave me pills.
Then...
I remembered nothing.
Sometimes...
Sometimes I fell asleep.
Then I realised
that he made me do things.
I didn't want to.
I didn't want to...
but I always felt so weak.
One time...
I noticed
that there was another girl.
About my age.
She started to scream.
I was so frightened.
One other time
the professor wasn't there.
There was another man.
With white hair.
He also gave me some pills.
And I had to do the same things...
as with the professor.
Take a look at this girl.
Did you see her that day
in Beltrame's office?
Have you ever seen her?
No, I've never seen here.
At least I don't think so.
But I was so confused
when I was there.
I couldn't swear it.
Search the office.
Take a look at this, Giardina.
It's all here. We don't need anything else.
Now we got names
for those voices.
- From the tapes?
- Of course.
It's unbelievable.
He wrote everything down.
It's terrible.
Beltrame was a monster.
Insane, perverse and impotent.
He corrupted that girl.
And probably many others.
He raped them.
Didn't you say
he was impotent?
He did it with a bottle.
A harrowing story.
He managed to get them to do
whatever he wanted.
Sometimes for free,
sometimes for money.
And sometimes he beat them bloody
until they lost consciousness.
And then came
the appointments.
A ring of old men
with horrible vices.
They're all in here.
With first names, surnames and addresses.
It's incredible,
he wrote it all down.
And here's a namesake...
He's the minister.
He was a friend of Beltrame's.
He was also at the funeral.
The minister...
- Hello. Is this the police?
Are you still looking for the man
they showed on TV yesterday evening?
- Yes why? Have you seen him?
- I just saw him.
- He went into a cellar.
- Are you quite sure?
Of course.
We are really sure.
- He wore black leather things.
- And what's your name?
- Marcia.
- And where do you live?
Piazza Matteotti.
Very well, Your Excellency.
I'll be in Rome the day after tomorrow
with a detailed report.
Don't worry.
Goodbye, Your Excellency.
Congratulations, Miss Stori.
A textbook example of an investigation.
And my compliments
also to you, inspector.
Mr. public prosecutor,
the evidence we have is... irrefutable.
But I seem to understand
that we can't prosecute the culprits.
Those who started the whole thing
and particularly those who picked the girls.
Ms. Stori, you understood that perfectly well.
Which I never doubted.
There are names among them
that are untouchable.
You can't get to them,
not without orders from the very top.
Which means never. As usual.
It's always the same old song.
First we're accused
of incompetency and inefficiency.
And when we've solved the case,
nothing happens.
Wrong.
There's still someone running around
who kills people with a hatchet.
Try to catch him,
and I will try to convince Rome...
to get to the bottom
of this case once more.
And I assure you that my task
is more difficult than yours.
What is it, Giardina?
Central received a call.
Maybe it's the right track.
Let's go.
- Did you know Bigi?
- Sure, she was at my school.
- Is it true that she was in that ring?
- What ring?
- Why do they want to interrogate us?
- How should I know?
We're at Piazza Matteotti,
All four access roads are blocked.
We're at Piazza Matteotti.
The four access roads are blocked.
We're awaiting orders.
Silvestri here.
Nobody may leave or enter the square.
I'll be right there.
Avoid the use of arms.
Get back.
Please, step back.
Don't shoot.
Give orders not to shoot.
- What have you got there?
- My resignation. I'm going.
Please wait a moment.
- Well, Mr. public prosecutor?
- I already told you, Silvestri.
You know it perfectly well.
Bringing everything to light...
- would take months.
- Mr. public prosecutor, we have the lists.
- The true culprits are on them.
- Come on, Silvestri...
you've captured the killer
and found the masterminds.
You managed to restore confidence
in the whole town.
What else do you want?
Blow it all up?
What are you saying?
I say go to hell.
I agree with that.
IN ITALY, 8,000 TEENAGERS DISAPPEAR
FROM THEIR HOMES EVERY YEAR.
ONLY A SMALL PERCENTAGE
EVER RETURN TO THEIR FAMILIES.
OTHERS ARE FOUND DEAD
OR UNDER THE INFLUENCE OF DRUGS.
THE MAJORITY, HOWEVER,
DISAPPEAR WITHOUT A TRACE.