Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Please, just let her go.
You, kid.
Here, please.
Now!
Fucking now!
No!
Shut up!
Put your hands up!
So I reach in my back pocket.
Nothing.
I check my other pocket.
Then it dawns on me.
I left my wallet at home.
And the waiter's coming
by every couple of minutes
to pick up the check
and I'm just sitting there
drunk out of my mind,
processing this mistake.
He graciously continues to
offer me more time to pay
but I only had pocket change for this guy.
So my drunk-ass self somehow
comes to the conclusion,
my shirt costs the same as this meal.
So I proceed to start striping,
placing my shirt in the
middle of the table.
Oh, that poor waiter.
Always was a complete idiot drunk.
Excuse me?
Cute.
Cute idiot.
All right, all right, all right.
- All right, all right.
- Cool, I'll take that, yeah.
O-M-G, my dudes.
Jason texted me.
I told you it was serious.
God.
What?
It's a dick pic.
You know what,
I am so glad to see real
romance still exists.
Okay, hold on, hold on.
Last week, I mean, he bought me flowers.
That's pretty romantic, right?
You're right, I remember that.
Yeah, you were like
highly allergic to them
- and your face...
- Okay!
- Just disgusting.
- Okay, yes!
My point exactly, look.
- Oh.
- Look!
Oh, that's a bad angle.
You guys are missing the point entirely.
If he's still sending me
pictures of his precious cargo
after seeing my face blown
into horror shit show.
She's right.
I see marriage in your future.
Yeah.
Wait, shut up!
But yes, me too.
Didn't you guys like meet online?
Yeah, whatever.
Isn't that like how
everyone meets these days?
That's a fair point
but I feel like divorce
rate's also going up.
It's like a huge percentage
- of people get divorced...
- Screw you!
In that online section.
Right?
What?
What, nothing.
Just...
I'm gonna make you my wife one day.
Oh God!
Oh my God!
Oh, this is happening right now!
Okay, I am gonna go back here.
Kara!
I'm fine.
Don't mind me, I'm not even here.
Are you good?
Has he done it yet?
No.
He's not proposing
tonight, are you serious?
What the hell?
Okay, no more alcohol for her.
Bring that over here.
You know I wasn't just
saying that though, right?
I'm gonna make you my wife.
One day soon.
You can't do that,
I'll take you serious.
- Well good.
- I will.
I want you to.
I've never been more serious
about anything in my life.
Well you would make me the happiest wife
that ever existed.
So,
I'm just clarifying but
when I ask, it's a yes, right?
Oh my gosh, yes.
Yes?
Yes!
- Woo!
- Yes, yes!
- It's a yes!
- Good.
That's a, you know, pre-ask.
Get all the jitters out.
That is so pathetic.
Really, oh, pathetic?
Yeah.
Who told you to stop?
Why do I feel like
this is the only reason
you keep me around?
She's on to me.
You all are corny as fuck.
Do you think she knows?
Of course she
does, she's ignoring it.
Let her be, calm down, everything is okay.
Do you hear that?
What, Kara?
- Yeah, she's humming whatever.
- No, no.
Those voices.
They're like whispering.
I don't hear anything.
Nope.
Hey.
We aren't there.
What's going on?
They're watching us.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, what's going on?
What's going on?
Kara!
Kara, help!
You okay?
What's going on, hey.
Baby, look at me, look at me.
Everything's okay, all right?
Oh my God, how can you not hear that?
They're so loud!
Is she hearing things?
No.
Babe, no one else is here, I...
Stop it! Stop it!
Bella!
Bella! Bella!
This isn't where you wanted to be.
Enjoy those moments.
You wanted to be happy.
Is this a dream?
A dream?
A dream, she knows.
Let her think what she wants.
What is it that I know?
Okay, it's just a dream.
It's...
It's just a dream.
Where are you?
Bella.
Bella, Bella, Bella.
What?
Bella.
Stop!
Stop.
Bella.
- Bella.
- Stop!
Bella.
- Bella?
- Stop!
Bella!
Bella.
Bella
Bella, Bella.
Bella!
Bella?
Bella, wake up.
Oh my God, all you do is sleep.
Get up.
Finally.
Come on, Frank said I can't
open any of my presents
until you get out.
Presents?
My birthday.
Are you serious?
No.
Of course I'm not serious, I remember.
What're you doing in my room?
You know you're not allowed to be in here.
Get out! Get out!
Well maybe if you slept a night...
Shut up!
Oh, that time of the month?
Explains a lot.
You asshole, out!
Bitch!
About time you got up.
Good morning.
You just wake up?
Yeah, do I look great?
Oh, fantastic.
Mmmmm.
- Hey, question.
- Yeah?
Did we go to the beach yesterday?
- Happy birthday to you.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday dear Mason ♪
- Gosh.
- Yay.
So, what'd you wish for, Mase?
Was it a date with that pretty girl
you've been waling home from school with?
Ew, Aunt Karen, no!
Of course not.
All right, shall we open gifts?
That's a yes though.
Oh, they grow up so fast.
Yeah, I know, can't
play tricks on him anymore.
What kind of tricks?
Oh, you know, like the basic kind
of sibling rivalry kind of stuff.
Like convince him he was
adopted for a good six months.
Oh, and then I told him worms
were like a huge health benefit.
He ate a good like seven of them.
Oh my God, you're sick.
This is why I'm happy
I didn't have sisters.
It's all psychological warfare, it's sick.
What, and your brother
didn't do anything to you?
No, he did, but it's
all physical stuff, like,
I don't know, noogies and wedgies
and twisting my nipples till my nose bled.
Bella, didn't you have
something for Mason?
Yeah, yeah.
Read what it says.
"Fearless."
Yeah, fearless.
The necklace Mom and Dad
gave you said "brave," right?
I know this isn't the same.
This is the necklace they
gave me when I was little
but I never wore it.
I just thought if you were scared or
if you're having any
bad dreams or anything
that maybe this will help a little bit
just to know it's there.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hey, can I cut the party short?
I really wanna play my new video game.
Oh yes, of course.
Do you think he liked it?
I mean, it's a pretty
deep gift but, yeah.
Yeah, I think he liked it.
Might even make up for you thinking
he was adopted for six months, who knows?
I feel bad now.
I mean, if you put on the
card it was from both of us...
I'm gonna get some drinks.
Okay.
Do you want anything?
Scotch, actually, would...
It's too early.
Oh, come on,
- it's a party though!
- It's too early.
Ugh, fine.
Water.
- There we go.
- Ugh.
Don't be afraid.
You enjoyed that moment.
You were happy but it's over now.
Somebody!
Let me out!
She doesn't know.
No, she knows.
She wants to be happy.
She's refusing to remember.
She doesn't have much time left.
- Enjoy the moment she has.
- Shut up!
What?
Please, please don't hurt me.
I didn't mean it.
Please.
You need to listen to us.
Where am I?
What are you?
Just let me understand.
Okay, please, just...
You understand.
Hello?
Bella?
Bell.
You okay?
I heard yelling.
Bad dream?
What is it?
Um...
Something weird's been happening.
It's in my dreams.
No, no, no, I
understand, it's your mind.
Your mind is just playing games with you.
It's gonna take more time
to get over what happened.
- Oh, no, no.
- You're just...
That's not what I was talking about.
You experienced the
kind of traumatic event
that no one should ever have to deal with.
Nobody ever said this would
be easy, did they, Bell?
I miss Lisa so much.
She was the best sister
a brother could have.
And a wonderful mother.
I see so much of her in you.
You know, your Aunt Karen and I
weren't able to have a family of our own
but helping her raise you and Mace,
just being part of that, has
made us feel like we did.
Thank you.
We'll get through this.
Together, okay?
Hey, is she in her room?
Yes.
Well,
good morning to you at
4:30 in the afternoon.
Okay, so, I need some advice.
Jason asked me to hang out again
and when I asked him where
or what he wanted to do,
he was like, oh, I was
thinking maybe we can just
hang out in my car for a few hours.
Winky face, winky face.
Hey!
You listening?
No.
Wait, but seriously, he said that?
Yeah.
That tool-bag move.
I know.
What do I even say back?
No?
Or...
I'm classier than that or something.
No, it's gotta be
something heavier than that.
Okay, something that's gonna
really put him in his place.
I mean, I have been trying to think
of a savage response for hours.
I'm gonna blast his ass all over Twitter.
Yeah, and I'm sure
all 32 of your followers
will really appreciate that.
Okay, anyone can go viral on Twitter.
Just watch, girl, it's gonna be me.
Jeez.
All right, I wanna help but get up.
I think better when I walk
and I've been meaning to
check out the new park.
No, um...
Not my fault.
Do you want me to help or not?
Do you know how much I spent on these?
Don't know, don't care.
Fine, whatever.
Let's go.
Don't care, don't keep me waiting.
So.
So?
You and Adam?
Things going well?
He wants to make me his wife.
Oh my God.
I know!
I didn't even have to say.
I said, you know what,
I'll say yes when you ask.
Oh, no way.
Oh my gosh.
If he would've ask me right
there, which he should've,
it would've been a yes.
Wow.
Real love still exists.
I'm so jealous.
Yeah, you know,
I didn't actually ever think
I was gonna fall in love with anybody.
But I fell in love with him.
It sucks, you know?
What?
Why?
He fell in love with that
Bella that was confident
and always had her shit together.
Was always this
happy-go-lucky carefree girl.
And after everything, look at me now.
- Like, half the time...
- Hold on, hey.
If the same situation
had happened to Adam,
you'd be there too.
You guys are a team.
One person follows, the
other picks them back up.
Aw.
That's so cheesy.
Oh my God, all right!
It was a rare occasion.
Yeah, those heels look like they suck.
So how's his dick?
He won't stop sending pictures.
Well, obviously, because
you're always sending him nudes!
Oh, it was one time.
Ow!
What, you okay?
- Oh, come on.
- Ugh, seriously?
What the hell?
People littering all over mother earth.
It's disgusting.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Did you cut your hand?
I thought I did.
Guess not.
No, not again.
Are you the ones that
have been talking to me?
Look, I can't do this anymore.
Okay, this needs to stop.
Whatever you want me to do, I'll do it.
What do you want?
We don't want anything.
You already know what you did.
You want to remember.
I'm not afraid of you!
You never should have been.
We aren't the ones that
are going to hurt you.
Then who is?
Where have you been?
We were about to leave.
Leave?
Hey, if you're gonna take one of those,
at least help me carry with the bags.
The beach, it's family
beach day, remember?
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Come on.
Banana.
Yeah, yeah, I'm gonna have a banana.
The water is a bit warm.
Yes?
Yes? Yeah?
I can't interpret that.
I got them.
Crackers.
Fine.
Are you gonna do it?
Jeez.
- No, no, no, I'm the baker!
- All right, here we go!
Here we go!
- I'm the baker.
- Throw them from top.
No cards from the bottom.
I think we have to match it.
Does everyone here
know how to play poker?
Or you can raise it.
Or you can raise...
Do your nails later, come on!
I don't wanna do my nails later!
I'll be there in a minute!
We're going, let's go!
Hmmm.
Is he asleep?
Yeah, out like a light.
We should probably be
heading home soon, then.
- Yeah.
- Before it gets dark.
It's a long drive.
You two remind me so much
of us when we were younger.
Did I ever tell you the balcony story?
Oh.
Only a million times.
No, no, no, I haven't heard it.
All right, what happened?
When we were kids, her uncle,
being the romantic that he is,
climbed up the side of my
house and knock on my window
just to five me a flower
before I went to bed.
He always
was as quiet as possible so he
wouldn't wake up my parents.
One night...
Yep, I wore the wrong climbing shoes.
Slipped.
Fell off, messed up my ankle.
Aw.
Woke up the entire neighbourhood.
I'm very glad you guys
don't have a two story house.
What a pain in the ass that would be.
Wait a minute.
Are you?
We should be heading back.
I'm a little tired.
He comes over every night.
Dude, she's boring.
Frank, that beer earlier was, I mean,
it was lovely, really.
Full body but light.
Did you notice how light?
I mean, I could drink it all day.
It was great.
All day?
No, no, not like I'm
an alcoholic or anything.
Like, my uncle was but...
- Oh my God.
- Other side.
- We're gonna head out.
- My mom's side of the family.
- Again, I'm tired.
- So it didn't really.
Yeah.
- We will meet you.
- A lot of traffic.
- Thank you, again!
- Yeah!
I never heard anything.
Me either.
Bella, I'm so sorry.
I did not think that one through.
No, you didn't.
You gonna unlock it?
You okay?
Yup.
Bella, that's a lie.
Come on, what you thinking about?
You can tell me.
It's hard to...
I think...
I don't know what's real.
What's real?
I'm hearing things.
Insane things.
But I don't know if it's
actually happening though.
Okay.
What're you seeing?
This room.
It's this white room and
I keep ending up in it.
This thing, this...
These monsters that...
Are talking to me or yelling at me
and I think they're trying to
tell me I'm gonna die soon.
You don't believe me.
Adam, I think I'm really in danger.
They keep telling me that
I don't have much time left
or something or someone
is going to kill me.
Okay, stop.
You're safe.
No one is out to get you
and even if someone was,
I would never let them touch you.
The therapist said this
would be a long road
with a lot of side effects.
This will probably come
and go so you don't...
No, no, this is nothing
to do with that because...
Yes it does, okay?
You're stressed thinking about...
No, Adam, this has nothing
to do with my parents.
Okay, this...
I'm in danger.
No, you're not in danger.
Okay, it's all in your head.
PTSD symptoms.
No, this is not PTSD!
Before you know it, everything
will be back to normal.
It's a lot more
complicated than that, Adam.
Your therapist said a lot of
stuff like this would happen.
Please, just listen to me.
Let me at least explain right now
because I'm really in danger and...
No, you're not in danger!
You just think you are.
Just listen to me!
Maybe you should just
start taking your meds...
Listen to me!
I tell you I'm in danger
and you pull this mental health card?
Tell me to go just take some fucking pills
and everything will be all right, right?
Even after I repeatedly tell you that this
has nothing to do with my parents.
You want my help and I'm being honest.
I'm not pulling any card.
I'm telling you exactly
what a trained professional would say.
But I didn't ask for a
trained professional, Adam!
I asked for what you
would say, so be Adam.
Be my boy friend for just a few
freaking seconds, would you?
Because I'm so scared.
I'm sorry.
All right.
I want to help but I don't
know how and it's frustrating.
Tell me what you want me to do.
Just listen to me.
Trust me.
If you can, I'm not
asking you to be discreet.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe it's all fake.
But to me it feels beyond real.
I feel like I'm going crazy.
You're not crazy.
It's time to go back.
There's nothing left of this moment.
It's over.
- You don't wanna...
- What?
Stay for the rest.
Is it happening?
Is it happening right now?
They're gonna take me back.
Where?
That room?
Are you hearing voices right now?
Just close your eyes.
- You can come back.
- I'm not going back.
- You don't wanna
- stay for this.
- Bella!
- Don't do it.
- Listen to us.
Bella!
No.
Shit!
So,
you still okay to drive?
Do you see that?
That light?
Adam.
Adam?
You stop.
Stop.
You stop!
Listen to me!
Leave me alone!
Put me down.
Why are you doing this?
The waiter's coming
by every couple minutes
to pick up the check and
I'm just sitting there,
drunk out of my mind,
processing this mistake.
He graciously continues to
offer me more time to pay
but I don't even have
pocket change for this guy.
So my drunk-ass self somehow
comes to the conclusion,
my shirt costs the same as this meal.
So I proceed to start striping...
- Yes!
- And placing my shirt
in the middle of the table.
Yes, yes!
You good?
When did we get here?
What?
When...
You told that story already.
Maybe.
Have I told that story before?
Yeah, you did.
It was on this beach.
Like, a couple nights ago.
You sure you're not just a little drunk?
I mean, you've been hitting
that bottle pretty hard.
Dude, 20 bucks says she's super high.
You look super, like you're
floating on another planet.
Yeah, you pop a pill or
something before we got here?
No.
I don't remember what
happened before this.
But this, this...
This happened, this already happened.
Maybe I have told that story before.
All right, just a little deja vu.
I like to hear the sound
of my own voice sometimes.
What can I say?
O-M-G, my dudes.
Jason texted me.
I told you it was serious.
Baby.
Dude.
It's time to go.
This isn't happening.
- This isn't happening.
- Hey, where you going?
This isn't happening.
You are worrying him.
- No!
- Bella! Bella!
Hey, what's going on, what's the matter?
You can't run from this.
Please don't let them get me.
I got you, I got you.
It's okay.
You guys good?
Hey, look at me, look at me.
Hey.
I'm always gonna take care
of you, no matter what.
Soon you're gonna be my
wife, so I can't have...
Are you gonna do that right now?
No.
I'm gonna go
back here just in case.
I'm always gonna take
care of you not matter what.
I don't...
Okay.
We're gonna talk now
and you're gonna answer my questions.
Are you gonna hurt me?
No.
Are you ghosts?
Am I going crazy?
No.
Then...
can you leave me be?
If I'm not going crazy and
you're not gonna hurt me,
can you tell me what this is for?
You already know.
Deep down you go.
But I don't.
So please just help me understand.
Hi, sweetie.
I love you so much, okay?
Karen?
Can she hear me?
I don't wanna say goodbye.
I'm right here, Karen.
Where is she?
Karen, I'm here!
Bella.
Karen, I'm right here!
Mason?
Bella.
Bella, wake up.
Oh my God, all you do is sleep.
Get up!
Finally.
Come on, Frank said I can't
open any of my presents
until you're out.
Your birthday?
How old are you?
Are you serious?
Wow.
Whatever.
I'll see you out there.
About time you got up.
Good morning, love.
Oh, still in your PJs, I see.
Luck for you, I don't
think Mason will care.
You just wake up?
I mean, you look great.
Hey.
You good?
No.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday dear Mason ♪
He's growing up so fast.
You okay?
You look a little sick.
I'm not okay.
Oh.
What's the matter?
It's everything I told
you in the car before.
What?
What did you tell me in the car?
In the car.
After the beach.
The beach?
Family beach day.
When did all this happen?
No, you were there.
You aren't Adam.
You aren't Adam, you aren't real.
- What are you talking about?
- Why the confusion?
No, you stop it!
We aren't doing anything.
Shut up!
I have a birthmark.
Where is my birthmark, huh?
It's on your left shoulder blade.
What're you talking about?
Hey, Bella, Bella.
Bella, didn't you have
something for Mason?
"Fearless."
Yeah, fearless.
This looks so much like...
Yeah.
Thank you.
Are you even real?
Uh...
Could I cut this party short?
I really wanna play my new video game.
- Sure.
- Yes.
Yes, of course.
It's quite a deep gift.
I'm pretty sure her likes it.
All right, look,
I don't know what all of this is about.
Okay but I'm real.
You're real.
Okay?
Can I get you anything?
Water?
Yeah, water.
Okay.
She's confused.
Oh, can you just shut up?
We can't.
We're you.
We can't leave until you do.
Wait.
Until I leave?
Bella, can you hear me?
Are you in there, Bell?
So I can make this stop.
I can make you leave.
We leave when it's over.
When what's over?
When it's over.
We leave when you do.
Are you?
Take me back.
No, no, no, no, no.
No.
You fucking bastard!
Oh, fuck.
No.
Take me back.
Take me back!
Bella?
Bell, are you okay?
I heard yelling.
Fine.
Bad dream?
Yep, bad dream.
Oh.
Well, let me know if
you need anything, okay?
Hey, is she in her room?
Yes.
In bed.
Good morning to you at
4:30 in the afternoon.
All right, I need your advice.
So, Jason texted me
about hanging out again
and when I asked him what
or where we should go...
Let's go for a walk.
Um...
Walk carefully.
One of my professors once told me
that our lives are just a dream.
That those dreams
are just a figment of
someone else's reality.
We're not even alive.
We're just a figment of
someone else's imagination.
Then he laughed and said,
oh, it's fun to play
with bullshit theories.
I don't know.
Maybe he's not too far off.
Wow, that's really deep.
Maybe.
Maybe
it was all just a lie.
What do you mean?
Ugh, seriously?
People littering all over mother earth.
It's disgusting.
Goddamn it!
You leave when I do!
That's what you said,
that's what you said!
So just let me go and then you can.
Why not?
You want me to die, right?
That's what you wanted, right?
Enjoy what you have.
It's not going to last.
Be happy for now.
Just let me go!
Bella!
Bella, what're you doing?
Bella, stop!
Stop!
Puke it up now!
Puke it up!
What did you do?
Is it over?
I need someone to send help now!
- They're gonna be gone.
- Please, I need help!
They're gonna be gone.
Please help me.
They're gone.
They're gonna be gone.
What do you want?
I've done everything, everything
that you've asked me to do!
What do you want?
Okay, so maybe I'm panicking a little.
Doctor is saying that
- it's not looking...
- Kara?
That great but we're still optimistic.
Jeez, you really actually don't look good.
But I'm here, we're all here.
Not gonna leave you.
You're my best friend.
Can you please, please figure this out?
Please?
Wait.
Wait!
Where have you been?
We were about to leave.
Hey!
If you're gonna take those,
at least help me carry one of these bags.
The beach?
It's family beach day.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Okay, handing
waters out, who wants a water?
- Yes!
- Yes, yes, who wants a water?
- Yes, please, thank you.
Mase, do you want a water?
I have one, yeah.
Honey, do you
want one, you got one?
I got water.
Anyone want a banana?
I have a half open banana,
does anyone want this?
I don't think
I feel comfortable...
No time for your pie, right there.
Banana cream pie.
All right, talk to me.
No, come on, what's going on up there?
You're not even gonna remember.
What're you talking about?
That's exactly my fucking point.
Okay.
Okay, come on.
No, come on, come on.
No.
What's your Aunt Karen doing?
Stop!
Wait, wait, put me down, right now!
I'm not!
You don't want it?
Oh my God!
How did you not see that coming?
You guys planned this, didn't you?
Plan?
No, no, no, no planning.
Light discussion but, yeah, we planned it.
No, no, no, no, no!
We should probably be heading home soon
before it gets dark.
It's a long drive.
Oh.
You two remind me so much
of us when we were younger.
Did I ever tell you the balcony story?
- Oh.
- No, never heard it.
What happened?
When we were kids, her uncle,
being the romantic that he is,
would climb up the side of
my house, knock on my window,
just to give me a little
flower before he went to bed.
He was always as quiet as
possible so he wouldn't
wake up my parents.
One night...
Yep, I wore the wrong climbing shoes.
Slipped, fell off.
Messed up my ankle.
I woke up the whole neighborhood.
I'm glad you guys
don't have a two story...
I think that we should be heading out.
I'm getting a little tired.
So can we meet you back?
Yeah, traffic and stuff.
I am so sorry, that was close.
I saw it coming.
Mmmm, so...
Feeling better?
Yeah.
What was all that about?
Doesn't even matter.
I'm just excited for tomorrow.
Yeah, me too.
What's tomorrow?
Actually, nothing really of importance.
Ah.
I'm gonna be with family,
I'm gonna be with you.
It's gonna be a new day.
I'm looking forward to the future.
The future?
Yeah.
I've been thinking a
lot about the future.
Oh, really?
Really.
What about?
Adam Ray Colton, you
are not proposing to me
- in the freaking street.
- Bella Diana Lana.
- No.
- Will you...
Please help me get this
kink out of my neck?
Oh my Gosh!
It's been bugging me all day, what?
Oh, you didn't actually think
I was gonna propose in the
middle of the street, right?
You're a dick.
Am I that low on your scale?
You're only getting lower.
Ugh.
You took that personally,
- that's on you.
- Yeah, I did.
I had the best of intentions.
You tired?
- You want me to drive?
- No.
Not even a little tired.
- You look a little...
- No, I'm fine.
You know I love you, right?
Yeah, of course.
I love you too.
You can't figure this.
Don't fight this.
Especially now.
- Don't fight this moment.
- No.
- What that a cop?
- No, no, it's fine.
It's fine.
Stop!
Don't!
I'm not going back.
Close your eyes.
I'm not going back!
She's lost too much blood.
Not breathing.
Started CPR.
That car hit us.
And...
Am I?
No, you hit the curb.
It's a hospital.
We can do it.
You stay with us.
Don't even think about
going anywhere, Bell.
You be here, all right?
You stay with us.
No, no, no, no.
That wasn't real.
This...
This is real.
We wanted you to be happy.
Dreams.
My memory.
What happened to my other memories?
How do I get back?
How do I wake up?
So, as per your request,
we are going to stop
the machine momentarily
in order to see if her body's
able to breathe on its own.
If she is able to breathe, then
we can keep the machine off.
But if she's unable to,
then we will have to start
the machine immediately.
Just to double check,
do you wish to proceed?
Wait, what?
Yes.
I'm right here!
She isn't breathing.
Please hear me.
We are you.
Your thoughts, your imagination.
You created us to protect
yourself from the truth.
We are not in control of your future.
I don't wanna die.
We're all here.
It's gonna be okay.
Please.
What can I do to make them hear me?
Bella!
Bella, wake up!
Oh my God, all you do is sleep.
Get up.
Finally.
Your birthday, huh?
What're you even turning now?
Not even dating age, right?
That sucks.
Well, actually, I've
been going out with a girl
for a couple of weeks now, so, yeah.
Really?
Oh, crap.
Please don't tell Aunt
Karen because if you do,
she'll never let me hear the end of it.
Okay, okay, I won't tell her
but you tell me about
the lucky lady, okay?
Fine.
I love you.
I wish I said that more.
I wish we went all those
places we talked about.
I wish I was more serious but...
I just wanted to make you laugh.
I just wanted to see you smile.
I wish I met you when I was younger.
I wish I could've grown old with you.
I wish I could hold you tight every night.
Most of all, I wish I
could've called you my wife.
But it looks like I won't get that chance.
So,
for what it's worth,
I love you, Bella.
I'll see you on the other side, okay?
About time you got up.
Good morning, love.
Good morning.
You just wake up?
Don't I look great?
Fantastic.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
Actually.
♪ Happy ♪
Can we do gifts first?
Sure.
Cool.
Hey, come here.
Read what it says.
"Fearless."
Yeah.
Mom and Dad got that for
me when I was little.
I lost it.
Never had a chance to wear it.
But I really think that they
would've wanted you to have it.
So if you're ever scared or
if you feel alone,
just remember that you have it, okay?
So,
memories.
Dreams.
That's what they were this whole time.
You knew all along.
But I clearly wanted
to know the truth again.
Why didn't you tell me?
You knew.
Can I go back?
To dreaming?
You were right.
I'm happier there.
That is your choice.
Do what makes you happy.
You are in control.
And I'm just sitting
there drunk out of my mind,
processing this mistake.
He graciously continues to
offer me more time to pay
but I don't even have
pocket change for this guy.
So my drunk-ass self somehow
comes to the conclusion,
my shirt costs the same as this meal.
So I proceed to start striping,
placing my shirt in the
middle of this table.
Oh, this poor waiter.
I wasn't going out to the gym.
I mean, it was all bad.
Not a good scene.
Whoa, what's all this about?
Sorry.
I just, I love you.
Ugh, here we go again.
Why did you wait so long to propose?
You think I waited too long?
I could change that.
Oh God.
Oh my God, it's happening right now.
Oh, wait, Kara!
No, you keep going,
don't you ruin this moment.
Keep going.
Please be okay.
No, I have two memories left.
I wanna see them.
It's time.
You can feel it.
I don't wanna die yet.
Well, how do you know she's gone?
We ran an EEG, as you know.
But unfortunately,
there's only a small
amount of brain activity
which, unfortunately, is
considered brain dead.
So you'll have a decision.
So,
we need to decide if we wanna stop?
When, it'd be when you'd
like to stop the ventilator.
Will she feel any pain?
Hey, we're gonna take
great care of her, okay?
I'm gonna give her a
medication to make sure
she's as comfortable as she can be.
Now, the morphine will take away any pain.
It will remove any feelings
of air hunger if she...
Look, folks, it is impossible to say
if there's anybody in there anymore
but to be on the safe side,
we will make sure that she is comfortable.
It's just that we don't know
if she's really in there.
We don't know what happens
before someone passes away
but we will do our best.
She just looks
so much like your sister.
Looks of her mother.
Sarcasm of her father.
Wherever they are,
I know you'll see them soon.
Well,
when...
When you said
if I was having a bad dream
I could put on the necklace.
Without you, I would have no backbone
through this time.
I would have no one to help,
no one to give me any sanity.
I'm gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss you a lot.
You be fearless too.
Hey, Bella.
You're okay.
Adam, I'm so sorry.
I know you think that I
took too long to propose.
For what it's worth...
I love you.
I dumped Jason.
You were always right, Bella, you know.
He was such a tool.
I'm sure we can
remove some of the bandages
so you can see her face.
I am fearless.
You're all in my head, right?
So I can make you whatever I want.
Right?
I don't need to protect
myself from the truth anymore.
Please, just let her go.
You,
kid.
Necklace!
Take it off now!
Bring it over here!
I said valuables!
Stop wasting my fucking time!
Wedding ring, take it off,
toss it over here now!
Okay.
Here.
Please.
She can't breathe.
Let her go, please.
You can have anything you want.
Don't do something you might regret.
You think you're in any
position to tell me what to do?
You have five minutes, you hear me?
Five minute to gather all
the valuables in this house.
Cash, jewellery.
Now.
Fucking now!
No!
Shut up!
No.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
It's okay, it's okay.
I'm so sorry.
I told you not to move.
Shit.
What?
What have you...
What have you done?
No, don't.
Hands up!
Drop the gun!
Drop the gun now!
This is Officer Green
requesting immediate backup.
Put your hands up!
Drop the gun.
- Sir.
- You son of a bitch!
You fucking bastard.
Mom?
Dad?
I missed you guys so much.
We love you so much.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull