25.000 English RETAiL
sync © 18.11.2021
White Fang (1991)
Give it some slack.
Careful, boy.
You could be his breakfast.
- Hey, don't do that.
- Why not? He's mine.
Shipped him all the way
from San Francisco.
He was a family dog.
I'm gonna teach him to fight.
Good fightin' dog
can make a lot of money up here.
Hey, you up here for the gold?
- You got that right.
- Well, it's out there just waiting
for somebody to pick it up.
These are friends of mine.
This here's Luke, Tinker.
Didn't get your name.
- Jack.
What's your hurry?
You guys ever heard of a man
named Alex Larson?
- Alex Larson? Why, he's my old pal!
- Practically brothers.
- Why, Beauty here's saved Alex's life
more than once. Ain't you, Beauty?
- He'd do the same for me.
Back off, man.
- You fellas don't really know
Alex Larson, do ya?
- What did I tell ya?
You can't fool these city boys. Nah, we
don't know him, but we could find him.
If he's a gold man...
and who ain't up here...
he'd be on his way
up the golden staircase.
- Golden staircase?
- Yeah.
- Chilkoot Pass.
About two or three miles
outside of town.
- You'll need some help
hauling your gear to the top, though.
- Hey, I said back off.
Hey, easy. Sorry.
We don't mean to crowd you, boy.
- Good luck to you, Jack.
- See you later.
Hyah! Hyah! Get along now! Hyah!
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
- I've been robbed.
- Welcome to the Yukon.
- How high is that golden staircase?
- About a mile.
- But it'll seem like more.
- Yeah, well, I can make it up that far.
Hey, I'll sell you a map of a place
where there's plenty of gold.
Keep moving, you men!
That's it. Keep goin'.
Go on! Keep going!
Kid, move it!
Hey, do you know
where I can find Alex Larson?
- Yeah.
- Over there.
- Are you Alex Larson?
- Depends who's asking.
I sent you a letter.
Anybody who knows me knows I can't read,
so they don't write.
Anybody who writes me,
I figure I don't know him.
Well, I'm Jack,
Scott Conroy's son.
I'm looking for somebody
who can take me to my father's claim.
- Who's in there?
- Name's Dutch.
My father sent me his maps
before he died.
And he sent something else.
He sent me gold.
There was gold dust in the envelope.
If you take me out to his claim,
I'll cut you in.
- What's so funny?
- Everybody finds a little gold dust.
That's what keeps you digging.
But you have to strike it.
And your father didn't.
Go home and find a regular job.
You wouldn't last a day out here.
I'm a good worker,
and I just want what's mine.
I'm asking you to give me a chance.
- Skunker.
- Damn! What is it?
Alex, I was dreaming you, me and Dutch
was living it up in Frisco.
Get the dogs ready.
I hope Dutch appreciates this ride.
'Cause you should've died at your digs
and saved us a trip back.
- Are you going near my father's claim?
- Scott Conroy's boy.
What?
Let me see that face, kid.
Come here.
My God, Alex, he's the spittin' image
of his old man. And I knew your pa well.
- Clarence Thurston.
- Jack Conroy.
- You throwin' in with us?
- Yeah, I'd like to.
- No.
- No?
What, you're taking him with you
and you're not gonna take me?
He looks half dead already.
- Hey!
- I'm s... No offence.
Give me a stick of that gum
and I'll forgive you.
It's hard to get it up here,
and it makes my breath smell real fresh.
- Yeah.
- Hey, don't worry about him.
- He's just tired, that's all.
- Yeah?
Yeah, or he knows there's gold there
and he wants it for himself.
Whoa, boy. You got the harness
on the wrong dog.
Listen, if you don't want to take me,
then I'll go by myself.
I'll get rich by myself too.
I think he's crazy enough
to do it, Alex.
And you know he doesn't stand a chance.
Come on, Alex, he's Scott's boy.
Look at him, huh?
How much trouble could he be?
All right.
I'll take you as far as Klondike.
Fall behind,
and I'll leave you where you drop.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
- I'm going to regret this.
- Nah, Alex.
Pull, Digger! Come on, boy!
Attaboy, Digger! Pull!
Mush! Mush! Come on, boys!
Come on, boys! Pull, boys!
Whoa! Alex.
I got a loose harness on Blue.
Okay, mush! Come on, Fritz!
Attaboy! Mush!
Pull, Digger! Come on, boy!
Attaboy, Digger! Pull!
Mush! Mush! Come on, boys!
Whoa!
- Are you all right, kid?
- I saw something.
In the woods.
Wolves. They've been trailing us
for a couple of hours now.
Game's scarce.
They must be starving.
- Think they're after us?
- The dogs.
Wolves won't jump a man,
unless hunger's got them totally crazed.
- Let's get going.
- Wolves be the devil on earth.
Kid, give me a piece of that gum again,
will ya? It calms me.
I'll carry it for ya, okay?
- Come on!
- Mush, Digger!
Mush! Come on, boys! Pull!
Mush! Let's go!
All right. Mush. Come on, pull, Fatty.
Quit playin' around.
Got that tarp a little close
to the fire, don't you?
Well, I don't want to freeze to death.
- What's he doing?
- Cleaning his teeth.
How'd they get dirty?
Oh, Jeez!
Watch it!
Whoops.
Yeah, I know it's a little fishy, but
you can put your head at the other end.
Told you.
Too close to the fire.
Nice weather.
- What are you doing?
- The only things my dogs drag
are things we need.
That's my property.
You want 'em?
- You carry 'em.
- Hold it, hold it, hold it.
I'm gonna feed the dogs, fellas.
You're not gonna kill each other
while I'm gone, are ya?
We'll wait till you come back.
Oh, boy. Here comes the fishies.
They smell good too.
You guys know who loves you, don't you?
Here you go. Here's one for you.
And here's some fish for you, Fatty.
Oh! Don't bite the hand that feeds you.
Seven pieces of fish for seven dogs,
and you didn't get any.
- What are you mumbling about?
- Seven fish for seven dogs.
And Digger didn't get fed. I swear
there was a wolf in with the dogs.
- And I fed the damn thing.
- Well, how would a wolf
get in with the dogs?
He's dreaming again.
Relax.
The fire's going.
They will keep their distance.
Alex, I ever tell you my uncle
was a wolfer down in Montana?
When I was little, he used to
lower me in the hole and have me
shoot the cub puppies for the bounty.
I hated doing that.
Get some sleep, Skunker.
- Whoa!
- Whoa.
- We gonna go around?
- Yeah, the dogs can handle that.
Just go slowly and stay to the left.
Help me balance this.
Come on.
Let's keep it nice and slow.
Oh. Oh! Easy! Oh!
Oh!
- My-My books!
- Damn it, kid, forget the books!
Look out!
Hang on, kid. I got ya!
Hold on there. Now stand up.
Dig your feet in. Just stand up.
Get your feet up. Come on.
I gotta get the rope untangled.
- Stay!
- All right, come on, Jack. You can
do it, kid. Come on, reach up there.
Get clear!
Get clear of the sled, Jack!
Jack, stay right there!
Don't move on that ice!
Don't move! Jack!
I'll get the ammo.
Jack! Come back!
Jack! Don't move!
Hurry up! Help me!
I told you not to move!
Help!
- Hold on! Hold on!
- Help me!
- All right.
- Take this rope!
- Come on, kid.
Attaboy.
Jack, get these clothes off!
That's it! Keep moving!
Take it easy.
Attaboy. You get this off, and I'll
get the blanket. He's turning blue.
Take it easy.
We'll get you warm soon enough.
Get a fire going
before he freezes to death. Hurry up!
Come on, take your shirt off.
Help me!
- It's gonna be too wet.
- Come on. Keep moving. That's it.
Books. There we go.
Keep moving!
That's it. That's it. Come on.
- Now we're cookin'. That's it.
- Come here!
- Come on, get him over here, Alex!
Here. Sit down there, boy.
- Put your hands under your arms.
- Keep your fingers moving.
Now, let's get the rest
of these wet clothes off.
That's startin' to feel good, huh?
- I'm sorry, Alex. L... I was trying
to get the ammo, and l... I thought...
- Stop talking and drink this.
Drink it. It's pine-needle tea.
It tastes like hell,
but, uh, it keeps the heart pumping.
I'll get Dutch.
- What's left?
- Three cartridges.
Damn. It's like
being naked out here.
"He's Scott's boy.
How much trouble could he be?"
We've got company.
Shield the firelight from your eye.
Look hard.
Let's get the dogs safe.
George. Digger.
- Got Fritz and Fatty. Move it.
- Settle down. Settle down.
Get down in there.
Look.
It's a female, Alex.
That bitch is part dog.
- That's why she's afraid of the fire.
- She's a decoy.
She draws the dogs out
so the pack can eat them.
Digger, come back here! Digger!
- Digger! Damn! Come back!
- Damn you, Digger, come back
or I'm gon' whup you!
Digger, come back here!
Digger!
Digger, come here!
Damn you, don't be fooled!
Get over here!
- Digger, come back!
- Digger! Digger!
- I know where one
of these bullets is going.
- Hey!
- Are you crazy?
- He's my best dog!
- Skunker! Skunker, come back!
- Digger, get out of the way!
- Don't waste the bullet!
My God. Digger!
- Digger, come back!
- Skunker!
- Stay put! Skunker!
- Digger!
- They're right behind you!
- Come back here!
- Skunker!
He's gone.
There's nothing we can do.
Sorry, Skunker.
I didn't have a chance
to say goodbye.
Go to sleep.
Help me. Come on.
Let's pack up.
- Hey! You all right?
- Yes!
- But how did you find us?
- Saw the smoke from your fire.
Thank God.
You saved our lives.
What chance would a wolf cub have
of surviving on his own out here?
None without the pack.
Come on. Come on.
Whoa.
Is there any good reason
why we can't just bury him here?
L... I don't think
he'll know the difference.
I gave him my word.
Okay! Okay!
Look. The white fang.
This wolf is part dog.
You know, I'm glad Dutch is dead
'cause I'm ready to kill him.
Whoa! Whoa!
Look, you old weasel!
Look at that! You're home!
You're home now! Home!
Okay, okay! Come on!
Let's move out.
Klondike is still
a good two days away.
You gonna say anything?
- You know what?
- What?
I never really liked the bastard.
Come, come. Come here.
Over here. Good. Good.
Bring it. Over here.
Looks like he's gonna be
a good working dog.
- Hey, Ned!
- Over here! Come on!
- Come on.
- Okay, Harry.
- Hi, Joe.
- Hi, Alex.
- Take good care of them. Okay?
- Sure will.
What are you going to do
for money?
Well, l...
I got 50 bucks in my boot.
You'll be all right. You can get a dry
bed at Bradford's at the edge of town.
Tell Dave I sent you.
He'll give you a good rate.
Okay. Uh, where, uh,
where are you going?
- To see a friend.
- Okay.
- Listen, get yourself a partner.
- Yeah, sure.
- Don't go off on your own.
- Hey, don't worry about me.
- Good luck.
- Yeah. Thanks.
- Is this okay?
- It's fine.
- Do I look all right?
Hyah! Go on, mule!
Heather, sit on my lap here
and give me a kiss.
- Shut up, Clyde. I'm workin'.
- In pants.
Why don't you put on
a pretty dress for us?
- 'Cause I couldn't do this.
- Whoa!
Don't you love me any more, Heather?
It's a miracle
how beautiful you really are.
Oh.
- Who's that?
- He's Scott Conroy's son.
- I brought him up here.
- How remarkable.
- He even looks like Scott.
- Mm-hmm.
- Belinda Casey.
- Jack Conroy. How are you?
- Nice to meet you.
- Uh, do you work here?
- I own the place.
- Oh. Great.
- Would you like a drink?
- Yeah, I'd love one.
- Shouldn't you be at Bradford's? Hmm?
Yeah, uh...
Uh, a pleasure meeting you.
Uh, bye, Alex.
Bye.
- Right. There you go.
- Three more.
- See you at the bar.
- Sun never shines.
- He wants you back tomorrow.
- Hey, pass me down the counter.
Comin' through.
Joshua!
- Miss Casey.
- Oh, Jack!
- Hi.
- Hi!
- How are you?
- I'm well, thank you.
- Can I get that for you?
- Yes, you certainly can. Got it?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- So, how'd you make out?
Did you find someplace to stay?
- Yeah, I did.
- Uh-huh.
- Do you know anybody else here?
- Uh, just you and Alex.
Uh-huh. Well, would you like
to join us for dinner?
- Yeah, I'd love to.
- Good.
- Come by in an hour.
- Okay.
You heard they made Alcatraz
into a prison, didn't you?
- No!
- Yeah.
- When I lived there it was
used for immigration, I think.
Uh, not any more.
Now they've got federal prisoners
there, uh, you know, uh...
soldiers that deserted during the war
and some of the Indians from Arizona.
Indians? Oh, that's horrible.
- I'll get some dessert.
Would you like some coffee?
- No, thank you.
Get out of here. Now.
- Take me where I want to go.
- No.
Then I'm stayin'.
I'll think about it,
if you get out of here in two seconds.
- You're not leaving.
- Uh, yes, ma'am. Thank you for dinner.
It was delicious, uh...
Can I borrow that book?
I promise I'll return it.
- Good night, Alex.
- Good night.
You know, I think
he really likes you.
And how about you, my dear Belinda?
Then he said, "If I could walk that way,
I wouldn't need the talcum powder."
- That'll cover me.
- Get out.
Hyah, mule! Come on, mule!
Giddap! Giddap!
The lines are wrong.
- What makes you the expert?
- Experience.
It'll be hard for us to control.
- Does that mean we're partners?
- It means that I'll take you
to your father's mine.
That's all it means.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you too. Next year
we'll have that hotel in San Francisco.
Come on, Alex, kiss her.
I won't look.
This time. You'll see.
- See ya!
- Bye!
- Belinda!
Feed the dogs.
Boy, you are a romantic, aren't ya?
- Who are they, Alex?
- They are Han Indians.
I know the chief of this tribe.
We'll stop here for the night.
We've come to see Grey Beaver.
- Good to see you, my friend.
- And you.
It's been a long time.
Jack, this is Grey Beaver.
The boat is taking water.
We have to re-tar it.
Fine.
- What's his name?
- Mia Tuk.
- What does that mean?
- White Fang.
Hi, Mia Tuk.
Can I pet you?
- No.
- I just wanted to pet him.
- Dogs are for work.
- Well, maybe they'd work a little harder
if you were a little more friendly.
We make fire.
Kill with sticks.
Cause stones to fly.
We are their gods.
That is why they obey.
Not because we're friends.
Mia Tuk.
You boys want a stick of gum?
Well, here you go.
Thank you very much for dinner.
It was very good.
- I can't sleep when it doesn't get dark.
- You'll get used to it.
They never let you forget.
Now listen, it's not food. You're
supposed to chew it, not swallow it.
All right?
I won't forget you.
Thank you so much.
You're here.
Your father wanted to be buried
on the claim.
When I was younger,
I used to think he was a hero.
My mother would tell me
all these stories about where he was...
and what he was doing.
I never knew what was true.
He said he wanted
to give us a better life.
All we wanted was for him to stay.
What took you so long getting up here?
It's been a year.
My mother got sick.
She pull through?
Nah.
Sorry.
I know you want to keep moving, but...
but I've gotta try it here,
settle in here.
The gold is further north.
Why don't you try it here, Alex?
There must be gold here, and I know...
I know we can find it.
It's not a bad spot.
I'll get you started.
Holy biscuits!
Look at that dog.
That ain't no dog, you idiot.
That's a wolf.
Come on.
Let's go!
Take him down there.
Let's see what happens.
All right, come on.
Go get him! Go on!
Damn! I want that animal.
- Get Buck out of there.
- Buck!
- Buck, easy, boy.
- Get back.
- Easy, Buck.
- Easy.
Sorry. I'm overstocked as it is.
Down, boy. Sit.
Sit! Easy.
Mia Tuk, no!
Is he yours?
Well, look what your wolf
done to my dog here.
Who's gonna pay for the damages?
You know it's illegal to bring
wolves into town, don't you?
Luke, go find us a Mountie.
He'll straighten this out.
Wait.
Here.
Not interested in furs, Chief.
But I'll take that wolf
off your hands.
- No, it's not for sale.
- Well, that's too damn bad.
'Cause now you're gonna spend
some time in jail.
Go find him, Luke.
No!
How much?
You know something, Chief?
You're shrewd.
Come on!
This wolf's gonna make us
a lot of money.
Get in there!
Looks like he's takin' to the place.
Come on.
I'll buy you a drink.
I don't believe it!
Hey, wolf.
Show those teeth!
Go!
My hands hurt,
my head hurts, my feet hurt.
Let's-Let's get some dynamite
and blow the whole damn mountain up.
Huh? What do you say?
That would be too easy.
- What's the story in that one?
- Well, it's about this man who...
He builds a machine
that takes him into the future.
I can teach you to read.
You teach me to read...
I'll make you a miner.
Deal.
All right, wolf.
Let's see what you got.
Come on, wolf!
Come on! Yeah! Yeah!
Come on! That's it!
Look, wolf! Yeah.
Come on, wolf!
Hold him!
Come on, wolf! Come on.
Come on, come on.
Come on! Let's see what you got.
Come on!
Come on, wolf! Come on!
Come on, wolf.
There you go.
That's it. That's it.
Come on!
Yeah! Yeah!
Ow! Oh.
I think he's ready.
Wolf, don't you let me down.
Get mad! Come on, get mad!
Get in there and kill him.
You understand?
Come on!
Come on.
Come on. Let's go.
Come on, get mean.
Let's get mad.
Come on!
Let's get him!
Gentlemen, on three.
One, two, three!
Kill him! Tear him up, wolf!
Tear him up!
- Kill him, wolf!
- Tear him up!
Get in there!
Get in there, wolf!
- Yeah!
- Yes! Yes!
Yes!
- Come on! Come on!
- Come on, wolf. You did good.
It's a pleasure
taking your money, Sykes.
- I'll be back, Smith.
- Next time, bring a live dog.
Okay, wolf, come on.
I want you to get mad.
Now, I want you to get in there and win,
you understand me? Understand?
All right, on three.
One, two, three!
Come on, quick!
Quick! Yeah!
Yes.
One, two, three!
- Come on! Come on!
- Go get him!
Easy, boy.
You done good tonight.
I brought you something extra.
Take it easy.
Here you go.
You just keep on hatin' me, wolf.
"It took days
for the boys to reach...
the secluded...
hideaway.
No one had set foot
into the 'housie'...
- House.
- For years...
- Into the..."
- Not "housie." House.
- House.
"For years.
When the door was finally...
opened and, uh...
the fou... fou-fou..."
The fowl?
Like the birds?
No, no.
Fowl like the birds is F-O-W-L.
This is F-O-U-L.
Foul.
Like-Like a bad smell.
Like rotten.
Like your socks smell foul.
- I wash them.
- Yeah, well, use some soap, would you?
If you'd spend as much time digging
as you do washing, then of course...
l-I do more than my share around here.
That's a laugh.
Who do you think does all the cooking?
You do. You definitely do.
And with the way you cook,
I'm lucky to still be alive.
Then do your own damn cooking!
I'm not your wife!
Yeah. Yeah, that's for sure.
You're too damn ugly.
That's U-G-L-Y.
Maybe we ought to
head into town tomorrow.
We need supplies anyway.
Good idea.
I tell you,
that wolf's unbeatable.
Unbeatable!
Get away from that cage!
Get him away there, Tinker.
- Get back!
- You wanna lose a hand, buddy?
Mr Sykes.
Step aside, gentlemen.
What have you brought for us today?
- Where's the rest of him?
- That's a bulldog.
- He's pretty.
- They're killers, you moron.
- Look at them jaws!
- Shut up!
- It's Cherokee. I've seen him fight.
Your dog's unbeatable, right?
I've got 5,000 that says
he won't be after today.
What's the matter, Smith?
Too rich for your blood?
Let's do it.
Gentlemen, on three.
One, two, three!
Get him!
Come on, wolf!
Cherokee!
- Cherokee!
- Wolf!
Cherokee!
- Come on!
Aw! Damn!
- Flip him over!
- Come on, wolf, get up! Get up, wolf!
- Come on! Come on!
- Get up!
- Hey, that's White Fang.
- Get up, wolf!
- Stay out of this.
- It's over!
- Not yet it ain't.
Come on, wolf!
Get up and fight!
Will somebody give me a hand here?
- Get this dog off of him.
- I'll help you, son. I got him.
- Let go, there.
- Hey, don't break those teeth!
Let go, dog.
- Mounties! Mounties!
- Hey, kid! Hey!
- Kid, that's my wolf!
- Yeah, he was.
I paid for him when you robbed me
in Skagway. Remember me?
- Oh, yeah?
- Easy.
You stay.
Hey, you two, keep an eye out for me.
This ain't finished yet!
He's lost a lot of blood.
At least he won't have
to fight any more.
Good night, Jack.
I remember the good old days
when dogs used to pull men.
He needs to be in the cabin
so I can take care of him.
I'm not sleeping
in the same room with a wolf.
- You're wasting your time.
- He was tame once.
- You saw him.
- He was.
He's not any more.
Don't give up on me, you hear?
Congratulations. You've got
a healthy wolf on your hands.
Now get him outside.
I can't do that by myself.
Hold out a piece of meat.
I'll unhook him.
Look at him watching my hand.
They beat him bad.
There is no taming him now.
He was taught to hate. All he needs
is a little bit of kindness.
- Try it without the wood.
- You try it without the wood.
Easy. Easy.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
- Are you crazy?
- No.
I know what I'm doing.
I hope.
Just gonna untangle this.
Here we go.
Turn him loose.
He belongs in the woods.
I know you don't want to hurt me.
But you're right.
I shouldn't have done that.
I shouldn't have tried to force you.
I don't know what they did to you,
but everybody's not like that.
I promise.
It's gonna be all right.
So you come on out
when you're ready.
- You forgot something.
- Just wait.
Now what?
You hungry, boy?
Yeah, of course you're hungry.
You're always hungry.
Where you going?
Looks pretty good, huh?
Hey, White Fang. Hey.
See? That was pretty good, huh?
Hey. Hey.
It's not so bad, huh?
Want a little more, maybe?
Hey, hey!
Come on, boy.
It's okay.
It's not so bad.
I'm a pretty nice guy.
Maybe a little more?
Hey.
Come on. Hey!
White Fang, hey, look at this.
Want a little more, maybe?
Hey, hey!
Come on, boy.
It's okay.
Yeah, not so bad.
Not so bad.
Don't tell me you're not hungry.
Here you go. Here you go.
Here you go.
Moving slow.
Come here.
Huh? Huh? Huh?
I'm sorry.
Huh? A little more?
Here you go.
I ain't gonna hurt you.
Not so bad.
Good? It's all right.
It's all right.
We're gonna be okay.
Hey, hey, hey!
That fool.
Watch out!
Put the rifle down!
Put it down!
He won't hurt me.
See?
You scared the hell out of me.
I told you he was intelligent.
All right, come on.
Come on!
Up. Come on.
Come on, get it.
All right, come on.
Hey.
Oh! Oh! Hey, hey!
Hey, whoa. Whoa. Get back here.
I'm gonna go back in
and get one more load.
- Don't. It's late.
- Come on, boy.
Jack! Jack!
- Alex!
- Jack?
Alex, help!
- Help! Alex!
Hey, buddy.
- Are you all right?
- Oh!
The sky never looked so blue.
- No, it can't be.
- What?
Holy mackerel!
We're-We're rich. Aren't we?
- It's just like we dreamed of.
- It's gold, all right.
If the quality is bad,
it won't be worth much.
No sense getting crazy just yet.
Good boy.
You're sure you don't want
to take him with you?
No. There'll be too many people.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Listen, don't get caught up
in anything there.
Just get in, get it tested...
and get back here.
As soon as I can.
What are you gonna do without me?
I'll yell at the wolf.
I guess he's coming with me.
I'll pick up a new window.
How you doing?
I'd like to have this tested.
I'm on claim number seven...
right below Discovery on Blue Creek.
I assume you want
to deposit this with our bank.
Yes. Yes, you assume correct.
I don't know...
What is it, huh?
I hope he's been fed.
Here it is.
Fee and deposit paid for...
by Scott Conroy
in his name and his son's.
- You Jack Conroy?
- Yeah, yeah, that's me.
I'd also like you to add Alex, uh...
Alexander Larson's name to that.
It's your gold.
Oh. He's completely recovered.
- All right. We gotta get going.
- How you doing, fella?
- But you just got here, Jack.
- Well, we've got some, uh, things to do.
- All right.
Don't forget what you came for.
- Oh, right.
- Come on, White Fang.
- Take care, Jack, and be careful.
- I will. Bye-bye.
- Come on.
- What did they say?
- Who?
The assayer, who else?
What's wrong with you?
Well, read for yourself.
"The...
quality...
of gold found at the claim...
of Jack Conroy and Alexander..."
"Larson, tested and weighed by
the assayer at Klondike City...
on the 11th day of August, 1898...
is found to be 98% pure."
We're rich.
We are rich!
Very rich. That's what the guy says.
The guy says very rich.
He says we are filthy,
stinkin' rich!
While you were gone...
I did some thinking.
I'd like you to come back with us
to San Francisco...
to be part owner of our hotel.
So, what do you think?
Well, l-I think
it sounds like a good idea.
I'll name it after your father...
The Royal Scott Hotel.
To your father.
Good friend.
Dream on, boys.
There's something on the roof.
You must have been followed.
I was careful, Alex.
I did what you...
White Fang, get under here.
Come on.
They stuffed the pipe!
Stay down!
Put this over your head.
It will help you breathe.
They can't stay in there much longer.
Hold your fire till they come out.
Maybe they're dead.
That's "Coming 'Round The Mountain,"
ain't it?
I hate that song.
That'll keep them guessing.
They ain't takin' the hint.
Let's move in.
Get in there, Tinker.
Well, earn your keep!
Hey, get him off of me!
Get him off of me!
Hey!
Easy, easy, easy.
Come on. Easy. Easy.
Hey, look at this, now.
Look at it. Look at it.
Well, will you look at this now.
- You had it comin' boys!
- Yeah, you sure did!
- Hey, go get us the Mounties, would ya?
- Yes, sir!
- Hey, wait up!
- Come on, everybody. Free drinks.
- Hey, let me in there.
- Come on in.
- Free drinks?
- I'm right behind ya!
- Free drinks on Alex Larson.
- Set 'em up, will ya?
- Don't ask me twice.
Bring another keg of beer.
If we are going to catch
that boat in Skagway...
we've got to leave soon.
You know you can't take him with you.
He'd be miserable in the city.
He has to run free.
That's his magic.
He thinks you are a wolf.
Come here.
All right.
You take care of yourself, all right?
All right, go on.
You're free. Go on.
Go on!
Get outta here!
Listen to me!
Go, go! Go!
Go!
Go on! Go!
Listen to me! Go!
Get outta here! Go!
Go on!
Just get outta here!
Oh, here he is, Alex.
Where's the wolf?
I let him go.
Bye, Heather.
Don't let them get away with anything.
I won't.
I can't believe
this is actually happening.
Alex, I gotta tell you something.
I'm not... I can't leave.
Not yet.
I'm gonna go back to the claim.
Miss Casey.
So long.
Your father would be proud of you.
- I'll keep an eye on your gold for you.
- You better.
- And leave a room open for me.
- I have to.
You're part owner.
White Fang!