FRANCE
Police!
Everybody on the floor!
All to stay
in their places.
These are the cops.
Stop!
CELEBRATE
Take as needed
painkillers.
And a cold compress,
if you're in a lot of pain.
You need to keep track
and your weight.
Important.
That's it.
I'll see you on Monday, right?
Is everything okay?
I would like
to extend my sick leave.
We have already extended it
last month, Samuel.
It is all up to you.
Okay, we'll see
next week.
Is it possible or not?
- We did a good job.
The important thing is not to
strain too much, right?
Play.
- Let's go, Leah.
Is everything okay?
- Is she well?
Yes, we were painting.
Right, Leah?
Come on, Leah, let's go.
- Wait for me to draw.
You will draw it at home.
Let's go.
Leah?
Let's go, I said.
Leah, your father is waiting for you.
Come on, let's go.
See you soon.
Merci.
- Have a nice day.
Bon Appetit.
Was it nice at the pool?
Yeah.
I told you not to come in
in my room.
Why did you come in again?
Don't touch my stuff.
I told you not to touch them.
Don't touch them.
This is not yours.
But it's not yours either.
Cedric, can you open up?
Hi.
- Hi.
Say hello to Uncle Cedric?
- Hello, Uncle.
Hi, honey.
Inside it is complete chaos.
Go to your cousins.
Did something happen?
Can I leave it with you
for the weekend?
What's going on?
I will go to the hut.
Wait, I'll come with you.
- No.
No, everything is fine.
Not a good idea
to go there alone.
I need it.
You... you can't
wait just a little?
Now I have time.
- On Monday you're at work.
I'm on sick leave.
- What are you talking about, Samuel...
Can you watch it or not?
Did he talk to her?
I'm just asking you
whether you can or not.
Okay.
Merci.
Can you give her that?
Will you call
when you arrive?
Gendarmerie, good day.
Ladies and gentlemen,
check the documents.
Monsieur, may I see
your papers?
Hey, where did you go?
Where are you travelling to?
For Italy.
- Boss?
Welcome.
I'm coming.
Give me your hand!
Samuel, what a surprise.
We haven't seen each other for a long time.
Hello, Stefano.
- Victor and Justine, my friends.
They are French like you.
- Hello.
Is that your dog?
- Yes, it's mine. German Shepherd.
We hunt together.
My dad and I do hunting trips,
you know?
No, I didn't.
With all this going on...
business is going badly.
He wants to leave,
but I'm staying.
On the other hand...
this is our home.
- Yes.
Come a little closer.
My father asked me
to tell you that...
very sorry about your wife.
- It's all right, merci.
Give my regards to your father from me.
Of course.
- Goodbye.
I was cold.
France?
No, there is Italy.
France is not there.
Do you know the mountains?
Will you show me?
I have 300.
300, I can't give you more.
I don't need money.
I don't want trouble.
How much?
You came to the mountain alone
in jeans and sneakers?
Wait.
Get it.
Get them.
I'll show you.
Where are you going?
To the border.
Yes, and then?
Brianson.
- You're all going to Brianson.
Was that the police?
Why don't you answer me?
After the forest
you're gonna go on by yourself, okay?
Hi.
- Good day.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, what about you?
Are you walking?
I walk, yes.
- There are a lot of refugees in the area.
The Franco-Italian
border.
Will you come down and look around?
Where are you going?
Back home...
but I'm going around from here.
Do you still live here?
I thought you left already.
What do you care?
I'm curious.
Where is she?
- Please?
Your girlfriend, where is she?
- Why are you smiling?
Did you not understand what I asked you?
- I'm walking, okay.
And you're out of breath.
- Now I understand why you came back.
Do you think,
that you'll help her?
Hey, I'm talking to you.
What will the cops say?
- Don't you have another job?
Do you know how many years they give
to traffickers?
We have filmed everything.
Enough.
- No, you will stay here.
You probably don't understand
what's going on.
This is our home, Samuel.
Do you know how many there are?
Are you going to translate them all?
Stefano told me everything.
About the unfortunate case.
You drove...
You replaced it very quickly.
There is nothing.
It's not there.
She crossed.
- It's probably around here somewhere.
Have a nice walk, Samuel.
Who were these people?
We will go through the high.
You should not stay here.
Have you ever done that?
- They can come back, come on.
I used to do it before
every summer and I know.
If they come back they will take you away,
do you understand?
You should not stay here,
come on.
If we climb higher
we won't meet anyone.
Come on!
Anyone?
No!
Don't.
No.
Listen to me, listen to me.
Listen to me.
Listen...
Trust me.
Easy, easy.
Relax.
My name is Chehre.
Samuel.
Where did you learn French?
From my husband.
Ali.
He was...
translator in Kabul.
We worked with the French military,
until they left.
In Greece we were separated.
Why did you leave?
Because of the Taliban.
To them we are traitors.
They attacked our school,
but we managed to escape.
I am a teacher.
Do you have a family?
I have a daughter.
Her name is Lea.
Why are you doing this for me?
You walk with me.
Because you need help.
Hi, I am.
I'm a little worried
about you, frankly.
Lea is fine.
You should know, Samuel,
that she needs you.
Come here, Lea.
Do you want to say something to Daddy?
No, I don't.
Felix, wait!
Lea wanted to say hello,
but...
The main thing is to call me,
when you get a chance...
Search!
Stefano?
- Fuck him!
Search!
- Why didn't he tell us he was translating them?
These things are theirs, aren't they?
Right?
- Yeah, I do.
Come on, Lee.
- Last touch.
One, two... three.
Stefano!
Oh my, what beauty.
Burn this garbage.
Victor, this way.
Come and see.
Let's go inside.
Justin.
Wait, damn it!
It's a trap.
Samuel!
Sorry.
Forgive me.
When with Ali
we got lost in Greece...
I looked everywhere for it.
In all camps.
I kept looking for it
for a long time.
Then...
then I left.
These are the keys
of our house.
So she is always with me.
And if he's not in Brianson
what will you do?
I will continue.
And you?
Chehre?
They are here.
Come here.
Come here, son of a bitch!
Where are you going, trash?
I'm going this way.
I go upstairs.
Victor?
Oh, motherfucker!
Victor!
This asshole...
look what he did.
Where are you going, they are down there.
They're down there, I told you!
Samuel!
Stefano!
Damn,
tell me where they are.
Victor, damn it!
Victor, he's slipping away.
Stop!
Stop, I said!
Turn around!
What the hell,
did, huh?
What did you do?
There you are!
Will you tell me?
Did you translate it?
Did you, eh?
What's that, huh?
Is it from my dog?
Who did it?
Did she kill him, huh?
Where is she?
Where the hell is she?
Where's your bitch?
Get out!
Where is she?
Where the hell is she?
She's gone.
Justine, stop!
Don't shoot!
It doesn't.
Don't shoot.
Listen to me.
It doesn't.
Listen...
We will not go to jail
for a Frenchman, are we?
Let's disappear.
Leave it.
Now you will die alone here,
son of a bitch.
Samuel?
Samuel!
Please.
Please...
Help!
Stop!
Do you hear me, Monsieur?
Do you hear me?
Are his eyes open?
- No.
Stay with us, Monsieur.
Stay with us.
Merci.
Follow
not to close his eyes.
You are not the first,
that I take.
What the hell are they doing here?
Fuck him!
We must pass.
- We can't.
Do you have any documents in your possession?
Do you have documents?
Good evening.
- Start the engine.
Good evening, madam.
We need to get him
to the emergency room.
What happened to you?
- There was an accident while walking.
Monsieur, can you hear me?
What happened?
He fell.
- We must pass.
Already lost a lot of blood.
Can I see
your documents?
Do you know where
to take him?
Hurry up.
- Thank you very much.
When was the last time you ate?
- Last night.
Then you can
have something to eat.
Your condition is stable.
You've lost a little sensitivity,
but it'll come back.
Can you put
your feet on the stool?
Merci.
Ah, did you wake up?
Are you better?
How do you feel?
How is your hand?
Is it better?
I'll give you a crutch.
Welcome.
Where am I?
- At Gregoire's.
Near Brianson.
We accept refugees.
Samuel?
I am Gregoire.
How are you?
Did you see the nurse?
There was a woman with me.
Chehre, yeah.
I know you wanted
to say goodbye to you,
but we managed to get her
on the train.
This morning set off
with a group
and now you must
be in Paris.
We took advantage
of the opportunity...
Was she okay?
- Yes.
And left.
It was better than you.
Will you stay for lunch
with us?
Yes, I'm fine.
Excuse me for...
Can you come
to pick me up?
I will come.
Send me the address.
I will try to come
as quickly as possible.
And Leah?
Is she there?
- Yes, I give it to you.
Hello?
Hey, Dad?
Hi, honey.
How are you?
When are you coming back?
Your uncle will come and get me
and we'll sleep in tonight.
They were gone a long time.
I know, yeah.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
I think about my mom a lot.
I miss her too, but
she'll always be with us... always.
Something happened yesterday
very funny.
With Leon and Felix we set off
for a walk
and we pushed all the buttons
on the elevator, and it got stuck.
The neighbor smoked like a fish.
Uncle Cedric scolded us.
I'm glad you'll be back.
I love you.
And I love you.
Translation and subtitles
Ivon