To arouse the people, the elder
Brutus accused Tarquin the tyrant...
...of having made artisons and masons
out of free citizens. Livy
Paul Lafargue "The Right to be Lazy"
Anatomy of a delivery man
It's very simple. There are the brakes:
hand brakes, foot brake. All easy
The throttle here works like this
And there's gear-changing, of course
Got it, have you? Sure?
You take my place, then.
I'll start it up.
Not too tight?
There's a shoulder pad on the satchel
strap. Tuck the sleeves up
Never heave: always lift carefully
We'll try with ten bottles first
That's only ten bottles
Fifteen
Petty cash: 150 francs
No, in the satchel.
Put it in the satchel.
Now put your change in
I forgot to tell you:
you're always marked, always
You run after the ball, but it should
come after you when you're not marked
You had a good game, though,
very good
Now I'm working. I'm going to drop it
- Drop what?
- Football
What'll we do on Sundays?
What about your bill?
How much?
- No it's not... it doesn't matter
All right?
Do you always work here?
I start there and finish there
Is it dirty here?
Cigarette ends, bits of paper,
dog shit
It's not a street, it's a dog bog
You might at least pay for the wine
All right?
I'm going to try to get married
It's quite normal, you know
At your age, it's quite normal
Of course, at your age it's quite normal
Aren't you coming up?
No, you don't need us
I can't leave your mother alone
too long
I'd sooner have this than
the new models
It's a good little car
One shoulder's higher than the other
It's best for her
Good, keep it going like that
I'm getting the license...
it's for lorries
They're difficult, lorries are
Especially as I don't know anyone
at the head office
Well, if you don't know anyone...
Listen!
Tomorrow I'm going to head office
Maybe they'll let me have a lorry
Come in.
-Are you the driver?
- Yes
Come in.
Close the door.
Sit down, young man
You put in a request for a lorry,
didn't you?
It isn't simple as all that
You need...  seniority and...
... and the confidence of your superiors
The drivers are on strike today
We'll give you a trial
Right away
Give me deliveries
Will you come up, Monsieur Gaspard?
If you go on strike, now or
ten years from now...
...you'll lose your lorry
There'll be no excuses
Find him a lorry; he's starting today
You can go
Come here, I won't eat you!
We'll run through the controls
What do you want for sweet?
Again?
Great, eh?
Yes, what a nice lorry
I fancied a trip to the country
Not just now, I'm busy cooking.
He said: "If you go on strike now or ten
years from now, you'll looe the lorry
"There'll be no excuses", he said
That's disgusting
I wouldn't have got the lorry
otherwise
What would you like for sweet?
You're just in time for sweet
You can sleep there, can you?
Well, I'll go to my cousin's
Right, kids...
...it's all happening
I didn't feel like clocking in,
that's all
Just like that? All of a sudden?
I was just thinking...
I was just thinking to myself: you
retire in ten years time
Well, then, why not quit now?
So, of course...
...I stuck to my guns
I waited till I was sure
I watched them clocking in
for ten minutes
Ten minutes at least
After that I was sure,
so I cleared off
Tidy the couch, kids
I wonder wheter you ought to have
kept on the safe side, you know?
In these circumstances I should have
refused the lorry, you mean?
Is it spades again?
If it's money...
No, that's no problem...
as long as you're working
What's the matter then, dad?
You let me share your house
and your food...
You're not letting worry you?
I haven't got a woman
I'm not thinking of your mother
At least, I may think of her...
...but not that way
Not that way?
A woman...
A woman now and again...
A sort of mistress, you know
So I was wondering...
What can we do about it?
Well, exactly
You see...
Just friendly like, now and again
I'm trying to think
Don't track your brain
Germaine
Germaine?
Yes
Everything all right, you two?
Dad and I...
...want say to ask you something
Done the washing up?
We could have given you a hand
A hand?
Dad's very happy here, but
there's something he needs
Just now and again, you know
We mustn't over do it
What is it? What does he need?
Dad isn't old, you know
Well, not old enough to...
Especially now that I'm not working
That's right he's not tired
or anything
So...well...why shouldn't he?
Now and again
When it suits
In the daytime
Or in the mornings
That's right
Not too often
Just friendly like
What a carry on
The fact is...
At last
Of course I will
Is it really so difficult to ask?
Of course I don't mind
I can't ...
Go back to sleep
I can't get used to getting up late
But I really get a kick out of
staying in bed
Stay were you are, I'll do it
Aren't you having any?
No, I'll eat later, with Germaine
-What time do you clock in?
- Six
How's your lorry going?
You'll catch a cold like that
I'll take off my slippers
What were you saying about the lorry?
When?
Give dad some money if he
wants to get out
Isn't he fabulous?
You both are
You're both fabulous
Would you hand me the crate,
please?
Enough?
Yes, I'm just going out to get
a bit of sun
How do you like it? It's very pretty
It's not my size
Don't you like it?
Petrol I don't mind;
it's the diesel oil
Twenty-five years I've inhaled it
and I can't stand the smell of it
Twenty-five years I've worked here;
never missed a working day
Fancy that, boss
In my cap...I put it in my cap!
She couldn't get over it
He's really great, your dad.
Look what he stole
I stole the dress, just the dress
My son
It's the same every evening
Right, kids, it's all happening
Four times a day
Twenty-five years minus holidays;
tell me how many times I clocked in
What's more, my father's the managing
director of your factory
Keep your nose to the grindstone, son
The pleasure's all mine
We met in a shop window, too
I saw your legs, and decided
to give up football
Tomorrow we'll lift some champagne
and celebrate
It's Sunday, tomorrow
It's all happening
Do you play pinochle?
Who wants sweet?
Guess who?
My boss's daughter?
When I think...
I bought the bread,
but stole the croissants
We're all thieves in this family
Listen...about your mother...
Let's not talk about that, dad
You were right; she was
worn-out and unhappy
But her accident...
didn't it surprise you?
It's very strange. Everyone
finds it quite normal
All the same...
...I did wonder a bit
I wondered if maybe she'd
killed herself
She was worn-out, unhappy,
always complaining, you know
Always snivelling, poor soul
There was nothing to be done about it
You think so?
I'm sure of it. I go for
the accident idea
She didn't know what was happening
You think so?
I'm sure of it
It wasn't an accident
It's turning out nice
Not an accident?
It was me
I assumed my responsibilities
How did it happen?
Well she'd taken pills
to make her sleep
I turned on the gas
Then I hid in the bog
I'd opened the fanlight
I wondered about going with her, but
I was afraid. I wasn't asleep, you see
Did you wait long?
Yes, a long time
It was tough
I assumed my responsibilities,
you see
Do you understand me?
Don't call me dad anymore
I share your home;
yes, I share your home
I killed your mother
I make love with your wife
Call me...Paulo
Tomorrow I'm going to get my record
player and give it to you
Happy birthday!
She's very sweet
We make a great foursome
To clocking in!
To shoplifting!
To all four of us;
don't be exclusive
It's incredible
Can't anyone go?
Then I will
Isn't your father awful?
Hearts are trumps, eh?
I don't want to go work
Look
Isn't she sweet?
I'd like some marmalade, please
Is there any coffee left?
Do you want a croissant?
A little butter with it, please
I`ll use your spoon
Can I borrow your knife, please?
I want some butter
This bra's the wrong size
Do you wear a bra?
Of course I don't
You can't always choose what you steal
It would fit you
- I'm bigger than you there
- I think you've a lovely bust
Don't touch your hands are cold!
Are you going far?
To Kremlin Bicêtre
I'll take you there
What are you going to Kremlin-Bicêntre for?
To look for a friend
A black
A black street-sweeper
Are you in a hurry?
It's a present from my boss
To all who clock in!
Listen, kids...
What I suggest is...
Isn't your father awful?
Tomorrow...
...quite soon, that is...
...if it's fine...
...we're off to the south
You can't really see
If it was full moon,
we could see if it's fine
I can't see a thing
It's going to be a terrific day,
I tell you...
...but I've really no idea
That's it
I'm sure
Have you lost something?
On the contrary
I'm going to have a baby
What's the matter? What's going on?