THE FEWER CHILDREN YOU HAVE,
THE BETTER THEY ARE
CONTRIBUTE TO YOUR COUNTRY
SHU NA
SUCH NICE WEATHER TODAY, GREAT FOR MOVIES.
AS A VIEWER, THE MORE YOU WATCH,
THE MORE YOU COMPREHEND.
THANK YOU TO THE DIRECTOR
AND ALL THE STAFF!
WE HAVE TO ACCEPT IMPERFECTION,
AS PERFECTION NO LONGER EXISTS.
Where did you go?
I got lost.
Are you sure this is the place?
I'm very sure it's here.
Why are the lights off?
It's a power cut.
Aren't you used to them yet?
Nurse, we are here to sell.
Of course you are here to sell.
- You can't be here to buy, can you?
- You don't have to be so loud.
What are you shy about?
All these people are here
for the same reason.
Fill out this form.
Wait over there.
That's right.
This is not an ordinary love story.
Don't misunderstand.
I don't mean the two of us.
My name is Hui. I am a blogger.
My online nickname is "Frog Prince."
This one who looks more like a toad
is my uncle, Mark Gao.
How did we end up here?
We will have to start this story
28 months ago.
Stop running! Stop! Give me back my money!
- Pay me back!
- Stop running!
Pay me back!
Granny!
We're in a pickle!
Pickle's good. Come on, let's eat.
That's not funny.
We really need to be on the run now.
You say that every time,
but you've never run a single time.
Even this time, you swam.
Granny! Stop kidding!
Now what have you done?
The number given by that
don't-know-what temple struck third prize.
But I forgot to place my bet.
Amazing!
You're even greater than the deity.
How could you even forget
the number given by the deity?
What should I do now?
Granny, I'm going to bathe.
Tell me what to do after that.
Help me think about it.
Although I'm called "Frog Prince,"
I don't want to be "a frog in the well."
Of course, I will take this opportunity
to go see the world!
But I didn't expect that this would be
how I'd eventually meet my destiny.
Hey!
Get in! Or are you waiting for
the cops to come?
Like I said, he's my uncle.
And he's a very troublesome uncle.
Uncle! This is cool!
How's the car?
It's really not too bad.
It's clearly written.
Here, see for yourself.
If any more new cars come in,
remember to call me for a test drive.
- No problem.
- Otherwise, I'll be angry.
- It's a deal then.
Let's go!
- Mark!
- What?
So that supercar is not yours?
Now, I want to get a Ferrari. Can't I?
Sorry! I'm sorry, sir. Sorry. How are you?
Did you think you were Alonso,
to be speeding as fast?
Of course not. I'm shooting a film now.
- Shooting a film?
- Yeah.
- Where are the actors?
- Me. I'm the actor.
- And the cameras?
- Cameras are there. There.
There's one there. There's one here.
There's one more there.
Technology has become very advanced.
There are wireless cameras everywhere.
Yes, our crew is the best
of the best in Asia.
Our boss is Andy Lau from Hong Kong.
- Andy Lau?
- That's right!
- Andy Lau, I know him.
- Our producer is from China.
Feng Xiaogang!
Do you know Mr. Feng?
- Mr. Feng, I know him too.
- You know Mr. Feng but not Feng Xiaogang?
Our director is famous.
He's the Singaporean director, Jack Neo.
- Jack Neo?
- Yes, that's him.
- Do you like him?
- A lot!
- I know him well. You want his autograph?
- Yes.
Okay, I can do that, I'll get it for you.
What is your movie about?
I cannot tell you. It's a secret.
Just reveal a bit.
Okay fine, fine.
Since we are best friends now.
This movie is about a race car driver.
A race car driver.
- A race car driver?
- That's right!
- I know.
- One day, he joined the gangsters.
- Wow, that's very dangerous.
- Yeah, but that's how the script goes.
One day, his boss tells him to
smuggle illegal substances.
- And after that?
- Drugs and other things.
- Unfortunately, he gets caught.
- What happens in the end?
Go watch it when the film is released.
- Then you'll know.
- Tell me a little.
Okay, okay. Apparently, the cop
who stopped him was a good person.
- Like me. I am also a good person.
- Yes, but you are more handsome.
- How do you know?
- For sure.
Then the kind cop let him go.
Is that okay? Can I go now?
Here, smile at the camera.
So I'll go now, okay?
SUMMONS
By now, you'll have understood the reason
we ended up having to go sell
is definitely because of this Mark Gao
who thinks he knows everything
and is filled with crazy ideas.
With Super Marky,
you will all be Super Pretty!
He looks as if he needs a makeover,
yet he dares to sell beauty products.
I smell trouble!
Free of charge! Free product
demonstration. Who would like to try?
Ladies, how can I help you?
Mark Gao, your "Snowy Cream"
has caused my face to bleed!
And your "Whitie Mask"
has caused blackheads all over my nose!
We want a refund!
Ouch!
Not a single cent left for me.
Yeah. All we have is this useless piece.
Where there's a will there's a way.
Sell your car and we should be
covered for a while.
I only missed one payment
and you tow my car?
Egg roll, lotus cake, yam cake, egg tart!
- Hey!
- What?
Can you not mention food
at a time like this?
- What should we do?
- What do you mean what should we do?
Earn money to buy food.
Back to my old trade.
How do you survive on
one vacuum cleaner sale per month?
Finally, my chance to show my prowess.
This is not style!
Goodness, is there a job in this world
where you're paid for idling?
There is. Rob someone.
Rob someone?
- No way!
- Correct.
We could be arrested by the police.
The police don't have time to arrest you.
If that's the case...
- Okay then. Let's go rob someone.
- Where should we do it?
Here.
Are you robbing us?
We don't have money.
- Ouch!
- Don't try us!
I know Snake Palm.
- Dragon Fist.
- Praying Mantis.
And also Tiger Strike!
To pay off our debts and buy food,
we had to resort to selling.
Does it hurt?
Here are your chocolates and biscuits.
- Miss.
- Yes?
- Is this all?
- It's done.
You must be kidding.
Let me give you another pack of biscuits.
Stop kidding.
We get paid, right?
No payment will be made.
Thank you for your charity.
Charity?
This is absurd!
We give you charity,
but who's going to give us charity?
I donated so much blood,
even squeezing out a few large drops.
- We really don't get paid?
- Yeah?
Are you sure we don't get paid?
Are you really sure we don't get paid?
Fine! I'll take back my blood!
Sir, you can't do that!
You!
- Thank you for your charity.
- Sir!
Now what else can we do?
See if there's anything else we can sell!
BE HANDSOME, SELL HANDSOME,
BE PAID HANDSOMELY.
Nurse, we are here to sell...
Of course you are here to sell!
- You can't be here to buy, can you?
- You don't have to be so loud.
Fill out this form.
Wait over there.
Whoa!
What?
- I can't do it!
- You can't do it?
No, the DVD player in my room
is not working.
Mine isn't working either.
- Your isn't working either?
- Not here, over there!
- What now?
- Read the magazine!
- I can't turn the page.
- Give it to me!
Didn't make it?
The mood just isn't right for us.
Nurse, this needs patience.
What?
We're not perverts who go crazy
at the sight of a woman.
Actually, she's my dream girl,
my princess.
We have a destiny!
What kind of destiny?
I have to thank Mark Gao for that.
If not for him,
my princess and I wouldn't have met.
Hello?
Can you let me drive the car?
- No.
- Why not?
No means no.
If you make any more noise,
I'll throw you out of the car.
Stingy.
- Why is it so jammed?
- There are lots of cars.
You think I can't see that myself?
I meant, why are there so many cars?
Drive! Quick!
- Miss, how can I help you?
- Drive! Don't talk!
- I'd like to, but it's jammed up ahead.
- Have you stared enough?!
Isn't there a space over there? Quick!
- Okay, okay.
- Quick!
What are you staring at?! Quick! Drive!
Quick!
Quick! Drive!
Miss, this guy is jinxed.
If I were you,
I'd use five types of ingredients
to wash off the bad luck.
Use coriander, lemon grass,
grasshopper, butterfly, and bees.
Blend them together and then...
Hey, miss!
We met her at the same time,
and you claim to be the lucky one?
Who told you to say "no" earlier?
Otherwise, you would have
been the lucky one.
LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT WITH MY PRINCESS
Where did you go?
Hang on.
I think I saw something
that shouldn't be her,
but I wouldn't mind seeing it every day.
Look!
It's her again!
Miss, remember me?
Who would remember a common face
like yours?
Miss, remember me?
The one who drove you this morning?
Xiao Hui! It's me!
She's smiling at me.
Are you sure you are the one
she's looking at?
LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT WITH MY PRINCESS
Meeting once can be an accident.
Twice can be a coincidence.
But three times in a day?
That's definitely destiny!
What are you looking at?
Come in!
- Quick!
- What are you doing?
Do you know the limit of
a man's alcohol intake?
- What is it?
- Ten glasses.
- What about women?
- For women, it's...
For women is eight and a half glasses.
She should be reaching her limit soon.
What do you want to do?
What? When she's drunk
and I'm not drunk yet,
I will...
You'll what? I'm warning you,
don't try to be funny!
I'll take her home.
What did you think I was thinking?
Stop being dirty-minded!
I'm being clear-minded.
She's your future aunt,
so don't act funny!
Say that to yourself!
Miss Shu.
- What are you doing?
- Take care of her.
Here's your bill, RM 1,350.
Whoa!
Move away!
Ouch!
THE FOURTH MEETING
WITH MY PRINCESS WAS FASCINATING!
Miss Shu Na.
What are you doing here?
Oh right, why did you suddenly disappear
from the Karaoke room?
- Where did you go?
- Hey! I don't know you!
How come she doesn't seem to recognize us?
She says she doesn't know you.
What is she doing here?
If men are here to sell,
women should be here to buy.
You mean artificial insemination?
Looks like you're the one who needs it!
In order to need this...
A, her husband "cannot."
Or B, her husband is dead.
Thus, she wants to be a single mother.
It must be one of these.
It's so pitiful.
Being a single mother is tough.
Yeah.
Why go through so much trouble
with artificial insemination?
Just sleeping with me will do it.
FORBIDDEN APPLE
KING OF FORBIDDEN FRUIT
I'm going to the toilet!
I somehow feel like I've disgraced
and defied our ancestors.
Why?
You were great!
You've finally become a true man.
Your semen is getting a woman pregnant.
Impressive!
Yeah, but who will be bearing my child?
Where will he be born?
I don't think he'll ever have the chance
to call me "dad."
Think big and become great.
Think about this.
What if a multi-billionaire
bought your semen?
Your son may become her heir!
If that happens,
share some of the money with me.
Do such coincidences exist?
Is that really possible?
If it isn't, why are you smiling so slyly?
I was just thinking, what if it's Shu Na
who gets my semen?
- Impossible!
- Why not?
Didn't you just say dream big
and become great?
That ain't a dream.
That's called a daydream!
Even if it was going to be
so coincidental, it would be me!
Little mice, climbed up the lamppost,
ate some oil,
can't get down,
and came rolling down.
Are you not daydreaming?
Nope! These are dreams!
Yeah, only in your dreams!
I won't give up!
I will continue my visits
to the sperm bank.
This will increase the chances
of Shu Na buying my semen.
Where there's a will, there's a way.
Mark, why are you here too?
Shu Na needs high-quality semen, okay?
We can also make some extra cash
at the same time.
What's that?
- Chicken essence.
- What for?
It's good for your "health."
I want some too!
It's all gone!
You are so selfish!
WORKING HARD, SAVING UP!
For the future of my princess
and our child,
I'll work extra hard.
Even if I have to take up several jobs
at the same time, no problem!
Hello, everyone. We are performing
a live radio broadcast.
Hello, everyone!
For our special segment today,
we have an audience member on the line
ready to perform.
Hello, how are you doing?
Hello? I'm telling a very colorful story!
Do you understand?
Ladies and gentlemen!
Come take a look! Grab a good deal!
- Eat more Bird Nest products.
- Babies will become smarter!
- Eat better with Bird Nest.
- Mommies get prettier.
- They're good for you!
- The price is even better!
Don't miss this great deal!
- Hey, it's Shu Na!
- What?
Can such coincidences really happen?
This is not a movie!
She appears in front of us
every two minutes.
You don't believe me?
Let's go and find out!
- Let go of me! Go to hell!
- Shut up!
- Go to hell!
Bitch! If you have time, why don't
you keep an eye on your husband?!
- Stop your rogue behavior!
- What a slut!
So, you're here.
Who are you calling "slut"?!
Say that again, I dare you!
Let me tell you, I am not scared of you
just because you shut down my boutique!
Cut my credit card
and then I'll be scared of you!
- Stop messing with me!
- Shut up!
What are you laughing at? Stop laughing!
Your husband loves kids
but you can't have any.
I can give one to him!
What did I do wrong?!
Why are you treating me like this?
Oh, so Shu Na is a mistress.
What do you want?
Then why she did need
artificial insemination?
I've seen many sluts, but I've
never seen anyone as crazy as you!
It's your husband who sends me
a hundred roses every day
and a diamond every week!
He even gave me houses and cars.
I didn't force him to do it.
He did it willingly.
- Slut!
- Shut up!
As long as your child is not born,
don't ever dream of becoming a Lee!
Then go ahead and kill me
and my baby! Fool!
You think I don't dare?
Friends from the media,
inside here is the tycoon's wife!
- Here she is!
- Don't shoot!
Her husband impregnated a young lady,
and now the wife wants to kill them!
This is headline news!
You watch your step!
- Move away.
- That's her!
Take photos of her! That's her back,
put photos of it in the news!
- Don't shoot!
- Enough, let's go!
- You're safe now.
Don't be afraid. They're just extras.
I called Orange and asked them to come.
Yes, that was my idea. Aren't I smart?
You are very forgetful.
It was me who made the call to Orange.
It was only a few of them.
I could have dealt with them with my fist.
What if they'd had backup outside?
- Safety first, safety first.
- I am sure you can deal with a few.
But we weren't sure if there were more.
I could have dealt with them
even if there had been.
I am afraid they are the ones
who would have been dealing with you.
Okay, I remember.
I am free next week.
We'll go for a meal and a movie together.
Okay. You'd better keep
your promise to me.
Okay.
- I am going to make that bitch pay!
- You're going for revenge?
I can help you. Let's go.
Ouch!
What's wrong?
- Ouch!
- She must be injured!
- How do you know?
- She screamed so loudly just now.
She can't possibly have just
been singing, right?
Stop talking nonsense. Get your guys
to take her to the hospital. Quick!
- It hurts!
- Stand up. Be careful.
Don't follow us! Otherwise, I won't
have time next week to see you.
Be careful.
For all my destined meetings
with my princess,
Mark has also been there.
How can I be so sure this is my destiny?
Because Mark has a girlfriend already.
What's going on?
Open the window.
Soup with cordyceps.
It's good for your liver.
I've already got someone
to fix the toilet at your house.
Remember to put away your clothes
when you get home.
It's been raining a lot lately.
Clothes are hard to get dry.
Also...
don't leave your pants lying around.
Okay. Dismissed! Go!
Okay.
Hey.
I've told you many times.
Don't come in without my permission.
This is my house!
I can come and go as I like.
What else?
Pay your rent!
Rent?
I have a relative coming
to see me, I'm busy.
What relative?
Have you got your period or what?
Hello, Aunty.
Uncle, Aunty.
Good boy.
How much rent does my uncle owe you?
Five candlelight dinners,
six movies,
and seven nights of karaoke.
Those are rent?
Do you really think
he can afford the rental?
Come!
Three days.
If you don't pay me in three days,
you will have to...
marry me.
Marry you?!
Three days!
You will be marrying me in three days
MARK: SHAMELESS!
SUSIE: SISTER! CONGRATULATIONS!
- Thank you, doctor.
- Goodbye, nurse.
You heard what the doctor said.
Although the baby is fine...
- Do not get too emotional...
- Or argue with anyone.
- Or even fight with anyone.
- Do you understand?
Do you want to play tennis?
What is she doing?
Put it away properly.
You're not a kid anymore.
Oh no, not again! What are you doing?
Enough! Cut it out!
Let go!
You didn't see anything. You see nothing.
Don't be impulsive!
Relax! Breathe!
Breathe. Let me tell you,
the most important this now is
the safety of you and your baby!
Come! Create out, breathe in...
It's been six months since I last saw her.
She is pregnant!
Is this our destiny?
Could my princess be carrying my baby?
HAPPILY EVER AFTER
MARK: PLEASE RESPECT YOUR AUNT
SHE HAS YOUR FUTURE COUSIN
INSIDE HER TUMMY.
This is my room.
Actually, I have a bigger house,
but it's under renovation.
Once it's ready, we can move in.
Yeah, right. This fool!
He's always daydreaming.
Hey, mind your manners.
Be careful, or I will beat you up.
- I am so scared.
- Scared, right?
My apologies for the mess here.
But don't worry.
- Mark! Look at your stuff!
- Be careful!
- Those are branded!
- I don't know how you live your life!
Be careful, that's imported from Italy.
Don't worry, I'll tidy this place
for you tomorrow.
Right! That's his job.
Why are you guys being so nice to me?
Because fate brought us together.
Yes!
The first time,
you hopped into my sports car.
The one you were testing for the showroom.
The second time we met at the mall.
The third time, at the karaoke bar.
That day, we were running around
and met each other, remember?
Nope.
Well, it was either Wednesday or Thursday.
There was lightning in the sky, remember?
I don't remember.
Whatever. The point is, the baby
in your tummy could be mine.
- It could also be mine.
- It's mine.
- Mine.
- Mine. Because mine was thicker.
We don't have any bad intentions.
Really.
Right, this room seems a little small.
Shu Na says she is tired
and she needs some rest.
- Pregnant women need to rest early.
- We are going to rest too.
- Good night.
Shu Na.
Let's sleep together.
That's my room.
Why do I have to take the floor?
- What's up?
- What do you mean?
The house is mine!
Why can't I sleep on the bed?
Fine. The house belongs to Orange.
What now!
Now, there's a pregnant woman
in the house.
Who will handle the housework?
Simple! I'll do Monday,
Wednesday, and Friday.
Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday are yours.
Sunday we do it together.
- What about looking after her?
- That's even simpler!
Whoever is not doing the housework
can look after her.
Okay. I heard that taking a walk
is good for a mother and child.
Who's doing it?
You are so detailed.
Does even this need to be split?
Fine, we'll take turns. I'll go first.
- Me first.
Xiao Hui, I'm bored.
Come and walk with me.
Out the way!
Is the weather too hot for you?
A little.
What's wrong?
My leg hurts.
It hurts?
Come, let me give you a massage.
It's lucky that I am the one
who came with you.
If it had been Mark,
he'd definitely have been panicking.
Let me tell you, he may look smart,
but he's actually very dumb.
He always tries to show off.
He's full of nonsense.
- Is he?
- Yes!
I'm his nephew.
No one understands him better than me.
I'm his uncle. Of course I know him best.
Don't be fooled by his nerdy looks.
He's completely different inside,
very scheming!
YOUNG MARK
It's very painful!
YOUNG HUI
What's wrong with you?
Can't you see that
I've been stung by a jellyfish?!
Don't worry.
What are you doing?
My mother told me that urine
can cure the poison.
No! Stop!
I didn't want to say this,
but there was once when he peeked at our
neighbor, Flower, while she was bathing.
And he accused me instead.
- Did he?
- Of course!
He didn't only do that to Flower,
but also to her mother.
And he even did it
to her grandmother once!
- Uncle, Uncle, I'm scared.
- What do you want?
I will let you peek later
and you won't feel scared.
- I don't want to. Please, come down now.
- Be quiet!
What if we get caught by my mother?
Be quiet!
Young kid!
Who taught you this?!
Peeping at me in the shower!
Say something!
No way! I thought he was a good person.
You say that because
you are a good person.
Actually,
having had such a close friendship
from when you were young,
you really need to treasure each other.
People are afraid of loneliness.
I've been alone since I was young.
I only had this old,
broken doll by my side.
True, we grew up together.
That's how I know him so well.
I think from now on you should
lock your door when you sleep.
No, that's not enough.
I think you should change the lock.
It would be safer.
- What are you doing here?
I'm here for the same reason as you are.
Didn't we agree to stop fighting tonight?
- Yes, so let's do this together!
- Okay.
Wow.
- Ghost!
- Don't look at me!
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
Come, let's take some pictures.
Me first. Come. One, two, three.
Come, me too. One, two, three.
What pose do you like? Cool looks!
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten.
Birthday meal!
The dish has a special meaning.
This is a "Happy Meal."
May you and your baby be happy and lively!
Let's eat.
Eat after me!
Cheers!
Happy birthday,
and may your wishes come true.
May your baby be as handsome as me.
Hey, that's more like a curse!
The baby has to be healthy!
SHU NA: I FINALLY HAVE A FAMILY.
Hello.
Hello?
Why aren't you talking?
Is that you? Xiao Na?
Birthday girl, why aren't you in bed yet?
- Are you crying?
- No, I'm just feeling too happy.
- You're crying.
- Too happy?
Is this the baby's ultrasound scan image?
That's right.
Wow.
It's my first time seeing
the little living thing inside me.
It feels so real.
Which part of the body is this?
The head?
- It's her little hand.
- Hand?
- That's her head.
- I thought the other side was the head.
A tiny sperm can grow
into such a big living thing.
So amazing!
Stupid! It's a close-up shot!
This is amazing.
What?
I think you guys are too noisy
- so she kicked me.
- You.
- Right, she kicked me!
- Can I touch it?
Sure.
You can touch and feel it.
She kicked me again.
Smack him!
She kicked me.
The baby is amazing.
It's really amazing.
Did you see the baby's
head shape is a little sharp?
So?
Mother said my head was
the same shape when I was young.
- So?
- So, the baby can be mine!
Yeah, but did you feel the power
of the baby's kick?
And?
Mother said my legs were strong
when I was young.
And I kicked well!
So, I can be the father too!
Yours is an "if", mine is for sure.
I'm definitely the father.
I'm 100% sure it's mine.
Let's not fight over it now.
Let's wait until the baby is born
and then do a DNA test.
Then you will know I'm the father.
Hello, this is Mark Gao.
I'm busy right now.
Please send me a voice message,
SMS, or email.
You can also WhatsApp or WeChat me.
Otherwise, please call me back later.
It seems that you haven't
visited for a while.
Why should I?
Don't you feel that I'm the odd one out
among you guys?
Actually, I really envy you.
Both of them are crazy about you.
Crazy about me?
Who can guarantee that
they will be crazy about me forever?
That's why I feel that only money
can really be relied on.
To have someone totally in love with you
is true happiness.
If you can't even feed yourself,
how can you fall in love?
Whatever it is,
you're going to be a mother soon.
A woman needs a child to be a true woman.
I can't even find a man
who wants to have a child with me.
A woman needs a child to be a true woman.
Just promise me.
Don't embarrass women.
Why are you here this time?
Why are you here then?
I am here for the same reason as you.
Don't tell me you are
still thinking about...
that?
What is "that"?
You know, that!
Oh, that. No, I'm not thinking
about that anymore.
Then what are you thinking about?
Me? Then what are you thinking about?
I'm wondering if Shu Na
is sleeping well or not.
Exactly.
I'm also wondering the same thing.
- Copycat.
- Why can't I be?
Hey, can you two stop thinking
inside my room?
I'm going to the toilet.
Did she scare you?
No, of course not.
Can you hear that?
Even her pee sounds like a melody.
- You are disgusting.
- What?
I just feel that she is
not as pretty as before.
In fact, she's ugly.
How can you say such a horrible thing?
That's so mean!
What I'm saying is,
she is willing to sacrifice
her beauty for a child.
She's so wonderful.
I have no idea what you are talking about!
Let's go to bed!
Tomorrow, we have to sell DVDs.
Everyone! Come and take a look.
It's a good deal, three for RM 20.
This is good!
No one is blocking the screen.
Even if you don't buy, come and look.
We have everything from 3D to Cat.
Get out, get out of our way.
This is nice.
- It's you!
- It's the two of you again?
- Are you here to rob us again?
- Robbery doesn't earn much these days.
I've changed my job.
Today, I am here
to help you not be robbed!
- Not be robbed?
- What does that mean?
I'm here to collect money, idiots! Pay up!
- He is so cute.
- He's here to collect money.
You are so cute!
Don't you know we are under Orange,
the queen of pirated DVDs?
Don't you know who Orange is?
Orange. I'm Apple!
Or do you prefer soursop?
Let me tell you, there are rumors that
Orange has officially announced that
she has nothing to do with you anymore.
Don't speak Hokkien. I don't understand.
Orange has nothing to do with you anymore.
What is he saying?
Are you acting stupid?
We'll talk in gangster language!
- Beat them up!
- Pay up!
- Stop it!
Don't get aggressive!
- Orange.
- So powerful.
Well, let's talk. I'm sorry.
I did say I had nothing to do with him.
But did I say
you could collect money from him
or that you guys could beat him up?
Nope. We can't.
Another thing.
How dare you wear the same outfit as me?
No, this is a pussy cat.
What took you so long?
All my things are damaged already.
- Yeah.
- What has it got to do with me?
What has it got to do with you?
From now on, even if you get beaten,
owe people money,
or become a beggar,
I'm not going to help you.
Are you guys leaving without paying
for the damage you did?
Is that how I taught you guys?
Okay, we understand.
- Come, two hundred dollars for you.
- What?
I mean, two thousand.
Looks like Orange will be
disappearing for a while.
But then, someone even
more troublesome came to us.
Mother, what brought you here?
Didn't I WhatsApp you earlier?
- I didn't receive anything.
- No.
- I did.
- Nope.
- No?
- Who's at the door?
Who is she?
Mark, you are the oldest. You tell me.
She is my friend.
- Correct!
- Friend?
Why didn't you tell me that
you were married?
No, she's not Uncle's wife.
Not his wife? Then she is your wife?
No, that's even more unlikely.
Sorry, I need to go and lock up my car.
- I need to go and watch him lock the car.
- You...
Are you coming in?
If not, I'm closing the door.
SHU NA: "I'M NOT LETTING ANYONE
DESTROY MY HAPPINESS!"
We just ran out like this.
Are Shu Na and Grandma going to be okay?
Don't think like that. Mother has
experienced a lot of things.
Shu Na can pretty much
handle anything too.
They are probably
having tea together by now.
Who is the father of the baby?
Mark or Hui?
It's none of your business.
If we can't say she is our girlfriend,
shall we say she is
our primary school classmate?
You might as well say
she is a single mother
and ditched by the father.
That's too mean!
Don't tell me you were ditched
by some heartless man.
I won't believe that.
And, who is the father of that child?
To be honest,
I don't know either.
Let's just be honest with Grandma
and say that we sold our sperm.
Mother is very conservative.
She will get a heart attack from this.
I thought you had a good new idea
since you raised your voice,
but it turned out to be useless.
Why don't you think of something?
Although this squid is only so-so quality,
it doesn't seem like he'll lose his mind
when he is drunk.
This is even fresher and greener.
Such a pity
that it has been ruined this way.
If you don't like me,
you can go back to your own place.
Why are you still here?
I'm deaf. I can't hear you properly.
So, any ideas?
How are we going to explain it to Mother?
You think of something.
She left.
- Shu Na.
- Chicken soup, good stuff.
- Good stuff.
Come quickly.
Go away.
Use this for her. That's yours.
It's the same.
Sit down.
Drink while it's hot. It's nice.
Grandma spent so much time on this.
Chicken soup?
Let's eat.
How is it?
It must be good.
What's wrong?
Grandma, what did you put
in the chicken soup?
Mother, even if you don't like her,
you don't have to do this.
What are you two talking about?
Who dislikes who?
I bought some pork belly
and some Chinese herbs.
You can take a look and check
if you are okay.
I will use them to make some soup for you.
It will be good for the baby.
It's better for you to check first. I
don't want to be accused of poisoning you.
Why? Are you feeling guilty now?
Don't you like asking me
who the father of the baby is?
You think I am senile or something?
When the baby is born,
we can do a DNA check.
Then we'll know who the father is.
I'll still love the child
no matter who the father is.
Whether it belongs to Mark or Hui,
it's still going to be my grandchild.
Come with me!
Let me go!
What are you doing?
What do you want?
Don't be scared.
Let's go!
How dare you run?!
Luckily, we could get away like this.
Are you okay?
- I am okay.
- Good.
Be careful.
Look ahead. Walk slowly.
What's the matter?
I think I've got a cramp in my leg.
Bear with me.
Are you feeling better?
Grandma.
I'm sorry.
I had been mean to you
and you still protected me earlier.
I think you are a decent girl.
Look at you.
I'm sure you have suffered a lot.
Why are those people after you?
I had a hard life as a child.
I used to look at those rich people,
showing off
and always getting what they wanted.
I promised myself that I would marry
a rich man when I grew up.
Why did a nice girl like you
put yourself through that?
Grandma, I didn't mean
to trouble Mark or Hui.
It's all because that woman
tries everything to hurt me.
She's the one who cannot give birth,
and I am the one who carries
her husband's baby.
She comes and attacks me.
I really had no choice,
so I ended up here.
Enough. I understand now.
Grandma, wait over there.
Hello?
What?
Say that again!
How can you do that to me?!
Do you know how much
I have given in for you?
- What are you doing?
- I don't want this child anymore!
Stop! You can't do this!
Her water broke!
Help! Hospital!
I'm going to a father!
It's me who's going to be a father.
- It's me!
- Come!
- Grandma! How is it?
The baby is coming out.
Why did Shu Na suddenly go into labor?
Mother, don't tell me
you did something to her again.
Scoundrel! Blaming everything on me again?
She answered a call
and her water broke, and we're here.
Wow! What a powerful call!
Grandma, I heard that it's tough for
a first-time mom to go into labor.
Does it hurt?
Oh, my little Hui has finally grown up.
Now, you know how to be considerate.
Good boy.
Grandma, this is not
the right time to tease me.
It's Orange.
Orange?
Cheap woman!
You told everyone that we have broken up,
but you have been following me around.
His ex-girlfriend.
Who is following you?
You, obviously! Otherwise,
why are you here at the hospital?
Do you own this hospital?
Why can't I be here while you can?
I came here to be a dad today.
I came here to be a mother today.
To be a mother?
Are you pregnant?
Why?
- Why can't I be pregnant?
- Of course you can have a baby.
As many as you want. You can have a
dolphin, a shark, anything you wish.
Ouch! It hurts!
- Don't think I am unwanted.
- Of course not.
They will travel by yacht, taxi, and bus,
just to come and have you.
They will even line up for you. Ouch!
It hurts! Can you let go now?
Orange said she's pregnant.
Your girlfriend is good for you!
- She's so cool!
- Yes, a good match for you.
What? You both like her?
- Then you should marry her.
- No way!
Either his arms
or his legs would be broken.
- He still has his head.
- No! That one is for me!
Doctor.
Is it a fried cake of fried sticks
(Is it a girl or a boy)?
Is it in one piece or one stick?
Abalone (Girl).
Great! It's worth some money!
It's lucky that it's not clams.
OUR CUTE LITTLE HONEY!
Look at Honey.
I'm sure she is going to be a supermodel
when she grows up.
Look at her long arms and legs,
she looks like me! Right?
If she looks like you,
then she'd look like a drag queen.
She looks like me more, right? Honey?
Don't speak nonsense in front of the baby.
Looks like you? Her skin will be so dry.
Look! Even she is objecting!
Flat chest!
Honey doesn't look like either of us.
She looks like her mother, right?
- Hello?
- Bitch!
I checked and found out that
you had miscarried our baby
and then went for artificial insemination.
Are you trying to make a fool of me?
Let me tell you, you won't get
a single cent from me!
What? Say that again!
How can you do that to me?
Do you know how much
I have given in for you?
Guys, your voices are so unbearable.
- It's you!
- You made her cry.
Honey, let Grandma feed you, okay?
Honey, how can you be so cute?
Honey, smile!
To change diapers, open up the legs.
You wrap this up,
slip it under this side, wrap tightly,
and secure it when the safety pin.
- Are you nuts?
- Mother,
I'm worried that you might hurt her.
It looks painful!
If you are so good, you do it!
You can't see me.
Open the legs, and then fold this up.
Pull this from the right,
and then from the left.
Done!
How smart! Everything comes out!
Smelly!
Honey looks like me, she's so cute!
Enough. Stop playing with her,
come and eat.
Honey, let's go and eat.
What a luxury meal!
Of course! It's Honey's baby shower today.
A good day for me, as a grandma.
She's so cute!
Our little Honey is the prettiest baby.
Honey looks like her mother.
Honey is a month old now.
It's time for me to leave.
Grandma.
I know this is not easy for you.
But you should do your best
to bring up your daughter.
I believe you can do it.
Although this is not an expensive pendant,
it has been with me for many years.
Let's give this to Honey.
Hopefully, it will bless her
with good fortune.
Grandma.
I may not know
what really happened to you,
but your daughter is definitely
your new future.
A new beginning.
You should cherish it.
SHU NA: WHY DO MOTHERS ALWAYS
CHOOSE TO LEAVE?
Hello?
Is that you, Xiao Na?
Xiao Na.
Mother knows it's you.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Xiao Na?
Hello?
Hello, Producer Jiang.
How are you? Yes. I am Shu Na.
Not Shu Qi.
Is it? Mr. Yang.
No problem, whatever you say.
I heard that you are starting a new film.
Jumping off buildings, jumping off trains,
being a stunt double.
Hello, Director Neo.
A prostitute, gigolo, I can even go nude!
Right. I'm Shu...
Basically, I would like to...
Hello, Director Fung.
Audition?
JOINT ACCOUNT: SHU NA, GAO XIAO HUI
JOINT ACCOUNT: SHU NA, GAO DA WEI
I would like to withdraw
all the money from these two accounts.
Honey.
My little dear darling.
Your life will be full of happiness
with your two daddies.
And Grandma. She will love you a lot too.
Now, Mommy has an opportunity.
And I can't let it pass by.
Actually, I don't want
to leave you either.
But I have no other choice.
When you grow up,
please don't hate Mommy.
You will understand me.
It's lucky that I'm so handsome.
Otherwise, we wouldn't be getting
such a good deal.
- I'm leaving.
- For where?
I'm going to Shanghai for an audition.
If I make it, I won't be back for a while.
You are a mother now.
Why are you still filming?
You should concentrate on
bringing up your daughter.
Yes. Are you short of money?
- You can tell me.
- I am leaving Honey with you guys.
Honey is your daughter!
- What are you doing?
- I don't want you to leave.
- I don't want you to leave!
- I want to go!
- No!
- Get out!
- Bitch!
- I won't let you leave!
- I want to leave!
Honey needs a mother!
Honey is good having
you two as her fathers.
- Then what about me?
- And me?
Where's my bag?
- Give it back to me!
- You can't go!
You can't leave!
We have been doing good as a family.
Why are you tearing this family apart?
Right, it's painful!
I don't have a family.
I've never had a family.
Never! This is not my family either!
This is not my family!
You can't leave.
We really need you.
You're nuts! What kind of mother are you?
Can you really just leave us like this?
I'm sorry.
The little girl has a temperature
of 39 degrees.
It could be dengue or meningitis.
The doctor says she has to be
put under observation
before we can tell you her condition.
Which one of you is her father?
- I am!
I'll call you again later.
Thank you.
- Actually, Honey is my daughter.
She's my daughter.
- Honey is my daughter.
- She's mine.
You listen to me. Honey is my daughter.
That's impossible. Shu Na told me herself.
Shu Na also told me herself.
Handsome, it's been a while
since we last sang together.
Who has the charm? Who is exuding heat?
My heart begins to miss you
I think Honey needs a father.
I've done the DNA test.
Apparently, Honey is your daughter.
I have a daughter! Honey is my daughter!
- Is Honey really my daughter?
- Yes!
We need to celebrate! Cheers!
Yeah! We can live happily as a family now!
"But you have to promise me,
do not say this to Hui."
"I'm worried that he will get upset."
- "You know how vulnerable he is!"
- "You know how childish he is!"
"Men are usually not good
at managing their money."
"Poor money management skills."
"For the benefit of our family..."
- "Let's have a family financial plan!"
- You've opened a bank account too?
I bet our accounts now have zero balance.
It took me a long time
to save up that RM 40,000.
I can't believe that
we have both been cheated.
You're an idiot!
Driver, can you please
pull over for a while?
Xiao Na.
Mommy is leaving.
There are many brothers and sisters
who play with you here.
Take good care of yourself.
Mommy, take me with you.
Xiao Na.
Our family is too poor.
I can't bear it anymore.
Now, Mommy has an opportunity.
And I can't let it pass by.
Mommy loves you.
But I don't have a choice.
Please, don't blame me for this.
When you grow up,
you will understand.
I love you.
Honey's fever has subsided.
It's fortunate that
it's not meningitis nor dengue fever.
I wonder if Shu Na's flight
has departed yet.
Why did you bring up that woman?
Don't be like that.
After all, she is Honey's mother.
Let me ask you, have you slept with her?
I did...
I thought about it.
Let me tell you, from today,
Honey should be the only woman
you can think about.
- We have to take good care of her.
- Sure.
I'll be the father. You can be the mother.
Why can't I be the father
and you be the mother?
The muscle that you've built up from
your workout makes you look like a mother.
And, don't be lazy.
We need to make lots of money.
For Honey to do her bachelor's degree,
master's, and PhD.
Let her study all she wants.
And make her our country's first-ever
lady prime minister!
- First lady prime minister?
- Yeah. Lady prime minister.
You're the lady prime minister.
Xiao Na.
I know you are there.
I also know that you have called before.
Xiao Na.
Why are you keeping quiet?
It's really cold here.
I feel really lonely.
I shouldn't have just left.
Xiao Na.
Please forgive Mommy. Please?
Can you please say something
to me, please?
Hello?
I'm hanging up.
Careful.
Honey!
SHU NA: MOM, I'VE DONE
WHAT YOU COULDN'T.
Mom, this is your granddaughter, Honey.
After two years, Shu Na is back
in the movie industry.
With her Stunning performance
in the movie Paper Sun,
- she has won the Best Newcomer award...
- Honey look! Mommy won an award!
Quickly, clap your hands.
Winning this award was possible
because of my hard work
and the support of my fans.
But there are two people
I need to thank the most.
Without them, I can tell you that
I wouldn't have been able to win this.
Good girl, Honey.
Mark Gao!
Ah, hi. Long time no see.
- Long time no see. How are you?
- I'm good, and you?
- I'm good too.
Since we are both good, goodbye!
- Let's get married.
- What?
I conducted a DNA test.
Apparently,
my baby is yours.
Ma'am, are you crazy or something?
The other day you shouted that if I could
be a father, you could be a mother.
That you were not unwanted!
You must have been dumped by someone else,
so you now you are here to look for me.
Actually, I didn't hook up
with another guy.
I only went for artificial insemination.
Coincidentally, I got your semen.
Don't you think this is our destiny?
Wow, look at the baby!
- Yes!
- She's so cute and she looks like you!
Quick, call Daddy. Mark Gao!
Mark Gao! The baby needs a father!
Who is the idiot who invented
artificial insemination?
I'm going to kill him!