Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
["FunMi Lowo" by Aramide plays]
[narrator] Families all over Nigeria chose
Coca-Cola because we know what matters.
Coca-Cola, putting families first.
And we leave them happy,
and secure, enjoying the beverage.
[Liah] This is Hauwa Ashinwole,
one of the greatest
advertising executives and my boss.
This is the campaign
we've been looking for.
What do you call it?
Family first campaign.
[Liah] That's me, Liah. The one in yellow.
And today is the most
important day of my life.
Today, after two years,
I am finally going to be promoted.
Now, this is what we've been looking for.
Okay, what you'll do is send the paperwork
over to my office.
Okay, then. Thank you.
-Okay, shall we? Let us go.
-Alright, have a nice day.
Um... you were right.
It's a beautiful idea.
[sighs]
Thank you, ma'am.
Um, your refinement made the difference.
Fine. Take my bag.
[Liah] After today,
no more assistant work for me.
Alright, Liah, it's time
to ask the question.
Spit it out, Liah.
Is it about the senior creative
executive role?
You were a corper two years ago.
And you're technically still an assistant.
Listen,
that role is four places above
your current grade.
So you don't think I'm ready?
Senior creatives run their own briefs.
Their own clients,
effectively independent.
The question is, are you ready?
[Liah] Oh, yeah,
my boss is a bit of a bitch.
This is Apex, where I work.
And that's Tunde Esan, my boss' boss.
[laughs]
What an attack.
Wawu!
-Sorry, I'm just dealing with something.
-[Liah] And that's Jumoke, my best friend.
Lekan sent me a dwarf.
A what? Like, why would
he even do that?
You know what?
Please, never mind.
That's your friend.
Um, I was calling to ask about the grant.
Have you heard back?
Um... it's my birthday,
I'm trying not to think about it.
[sighs]
Alright, then. Fine.
-Don't be late. Okay?
-I won't be late.
Happy birthday, boo.
[chuckles]
Bye. [chuckles]
[phone beeps]
[sighs]
Hauwa, look, why don't we
just promote this girl already?
She's too good to be an assistant.
Okay.
Promote her to creative executive.
-[Liah] What?
-Come on, you would rather
promote her to creative executive,
not senior creative executive?
Tunde, she hasn't earned it.
But she's done the job.
Look, would you rather she gets
impatient and leaves?
Then you'll get the next person I train.
Hmm...
-Interesting.
-Yeah.
-[laughs]
-Later.
[Liah] Oh, shit!
[Hauwa] Liah?
Are you still in there?
Liah?
Are you purging?
I told you not to take those small chops.
Small chops? I'll give you small chops!
-I will give you small chops!
-[gagging]
Small chops that you have been giving me.
[choking]
[Hauwa] Are you still in there?
[sobs] Yes, Hauwa.
[breathes shakily]
Hurry up and finish.
[breathes shakily, sniffs]
Goldmyne has finally sent the brief.
You have to prepare the concept,
so we can show it to Tunde tomorrow.
Okay?
[Liah sobs]
-Yes, Hauwa, of course, Hauwa.
-Hurry up.
[sobbing]
[breathes out, sniffs]
[sniffs]
[Liah] And that's Lekan.
Jumoke's, ugh... friend.
[phone rings]
[Lekan sighs]
Jumes!
Hey, dear.
[Jumoke] A dwarf?
There's a dwarf at my clinic.
Happy birthday!
I'm sure those pregnant women
have seen a dwarf before now.
Or at least a child,
which looks like a dwarf.
Are you serious right now?
[Pidgin]
Yes, of course.
[in English] Jumes, it's difficult
to give you birthday gifts,
you're too rich!
So imagine my luck when I remembered
that you like dancing dwarfs!
I was six!
And that was Snow White.
You don't like dancing dwarfs anymore?
[sighs] Are you coming tonight?
Of course now, it's your birthday.
Where will I be?
Good. So I can kill you.
[laughs]
Aren't you one of his actors?
Ugh, why would you even agree to do this?
I lost a bet.
[Lekan] So...
where were we?
Dear? Birthday?
I don't do married men.
Neither do I.
[woman] Hmm...
That was my best friend.
[Lekan] My chairman.
I have agreed to do this.
I have agreed to go
and study for three years.
But surely...
there's a problem!
I mean,
to be without a woman...
eh?
For three years!
Ha!
Surely not!
[laughter]
To fast...
once a week...
for three years.
My chairman, surely not.
[laughter]
To eat one meal a day,
when I'm not fasting,
for three years!
Ah!
My chairman, surely not.
[laughter]
And on top of that...
sleep only three hours...
a day for three years!
So, wait.
No food...
no sleep...
no woman...
for three years!
[in Pidgin] Come on, chairman,
think about it, surely not.
[laughter]
[in English] Surely, yes.
You swore.
It is done.
-[laughter]
-[applause]
[cheering]
[party music playing]
It's my birthday party!
[cheering]
Liah!
What took you so long?
What's wrong?
Talk.
Can't I even get a drink?
Fine.
[chuckles]
So I walked in on Hauwa and Tunde
having a conversation
and she basically sabotaged my promotion.
Wait, what do you mean
she sabotaged your promotion?
She blatantly told him I wasn't ready.
What?
She's such a bitch!
Well...
-in her defense...
-No, don't you dare defend her.
You have to quit your job.
And harvest money from the tree
that grows in whose backyard?
-I mean, I could always just--
-No, you would not!
-Liah, I don't--
-No!
So what are you going to do now?
I don't know, I'm learning so much
from Hauwa, she actually is the best--
-Wait.
-[phone ringing]
[Lekan] Where are you?
Where am I? Where are you?
You're supposed to be at my party.
I am.
[Jumoke] I can't see you.
I'm throwing a party for you at mine.
You're crazy.
And you're missing out.
Get over here!
[laughs] He's crazy.
-Who's that?
-[inhales sharply] Lekan.
[party music playing]
[piano music playing]
[cheering]
[indistinct chatter]
[all yelling]
[music continues]
[Jumoke] You have to be kidding me!
Lekan, what is this?
Jumes!
Go, go, go!
You said this was my party!
Well, it is now!
It looks like a prelude
to a freaking orgy!
Let's go upstairs, let's go upstairs.
Upstairs is saner!
Get up. Get more shots, of course.
Okay, sorry, now,
let's go, let's go, let's go.
Go, go, go!
Sorry, now!
I'll meet you upstairs! I'll meet you!
I'll meet you! I'll meet you!
[party music fades]
[indistinct shouting]
[sighs]
[moaning]
[screams]
[chuckles]
I wasn't expecting anyone to be here.
It's your house.
You have a bedroom.
This is your house?
I thought you said you're from America!
Is your name even Charlie?
Asshole!
Thank you, cock blocker.
Why are you even lying about
something like that?
She felt like a gold-digger.
So then what is she doing here?
Because she looked like that.
And that's my book.
[scoffs] Finally,
I've been looking all over for you.
-Hey, Lekan.
-Hey.
I have someone I want you to meet.
[scoffs]
God, no, not that!
-It's about work.
-Oh, okay.
-Bye, Lekan.
-Bye.
-[man laughs]
-[Jumoke] So... tell her what you told me.
The worst pitch ever story.
Oh! [laughs]
So, this one time at my office,
we have this--
No, not that part.
The part about you agreeing
to have my friend pitch you an ad.
I did?
You totally did.
[laughing]
-[laughs]
-Oh, I-- I guess I did then.
-Good.
So just enter it into your calendar
for you and your boss. Okay?
-Jumoke, what are you doing?
-Okay.
Shhh...
[chuckles]
[typing in phone]
Umm...
-Perfect.
-[chuckles]
So Francis is the EA
to the chief marketing officer
-of Cars45.
-[Liah] Hmm...
And he just set up
a meeting with his boss.
-For me?
-Yeah.
-Amazing!
-[Jumoke] I know!
Hauwa will be so thrilled
when I tell her about this.
[laughs]
[Jumoke] Hell, no!
So you actually think
I did this for Hauwa?
Jumoke, I already said to you
that I don't want
to talk about this. I said it.
Well, unless you're working, darling,
you do not have a choice.
Just...
take the meeting.
Jumoke, you know me.
I can't be someone that I'm not and
I can't even take a job from my company.
She doesn't deserve you.
The whole damn company
doesn't deserve you.
Now that I agree with.
Hmm... you don't want to know
what happened to me in Lekan's library.
-[Liah] I'm worried about this pitch.
-[Hauwa] You're always worried.
That's because this ad
is supposed to appeal to women
and it honestly doesn't feel like it.
That's because you don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm a woman, it's appealing to me.
It's also appealing to women,
by appealing to the men
that the women are attracted to.
-It's a win-win.
-Hauwa, I'm simply--
Shut up.
Listen, I've been selling beer commercials
when you were in secondary school,
drawing hearts around boys' pictures.
[screams]
Of course, Hauwa.
Whatever you say, Hauwa.
[man 1] Ooh!
See these girls, man!
-[man 2] I got your back.
-[man 1] You sure?
[man 2] Yeah.
[man 1] I got this, bro.
Hello...
-[laughs]
-You're blocking my light.
Can I meet you girls?
Monsieur, fuck off.
What? Are you mad?
Who do you think you're talking to?
-[man 3] Hey!
-Get your hands off me!
[man 3] What do you think you're doing?
What the fuck?
[woman] You have associated my brand
with women being harassed?
Oh, well,
the women are saved and then--
How would reminding these women
of some of the worst
encounters of their life
make them drink my product?
-Err--
-[Tunde] I'll take it from there.
[chuckles]
Thank you, Eniola, for your remark.
I think we'll go back and retune
and then we can meet again.
I don't think so, Tunde.
This is so out of parameters.
It's clear that we
have a different vision.
Eh, we-- we have an al--
an alternate idea.
[Liah] What do I have to lose, right?
[female narrator]
The modern woman is resourceful.
She does anything to get the job done.
No matter the cost.
She is a go-getter.
An overachiever.
[cheering]
But even overachievers need a break.
Buzz... the beer
for the overachiever in you.
It needs work.
But I'm happy to go in that direction.
[Liah] I am so screwed.
You must be crazy.
I don't understand.
If you ever pull such stunt again,
you'll be fired.
Don't come into my car.
Find your way to the office.
[woman sighs]
Thank you for coming.
Not a problem.
I... like to get my good news in person.
So, it's not good news?
-Our background checks have come back.
-My grandfather?
[Liah] When did your grandfather
steal this money?
In what? 1982?
That's what, like, forty years ago!
Yup.
He was a minister.
And what did he steal,
like, five million dollars?
-Fifty million pounds.
-Oof!
Still! All of a sudden
they're-- they're blacklisting you.
That is bullshit!
Here, here.
-You know what?
-What?
-To not dealing with bullshit.
-Yes!
-[phone ringing]
-[sighs] Hold.
[sighs]
It's Hauwa.
Ugh.
What does she want?
Yes, Hauwa.
[whispers] Tell her to fuck off.
No, Hauwa, I'm at lunch.
Alright, Hauwa.
[sighs, clicks tongue]
Got to go. Pfft!
I hate your boss.
[chuckles]
I know.
Fine.
Don't forget, fashion show tonight.
You're still up for that?
They have very good wine.
Hmm.
-Alright, see you then.
-Bye.
[Hauwa] Tunde's PA is going for maternity.
That's great, congratulations to her.
Yes, indeed.
Tunde needed an EA for three months,
so I offered you.
But I am a creative executive.
Acting creative executive.
For over two years!
And before then,
you were my executive assistant.
It's just for three months.
Hmm?
Besides, we all have to make sacrifices
for the good of the company.
I'm doing that by letting go
of a skilled hand for three months.
[Liah] Yeah, whatever.
And...
the senior creative
executive role you want,
will likely be filled.
[sobs]
Not to worry,
other opportunities
will arise in the future.
[sniffs]
Thank you.
You're welcome.
[indistinct audio on PA]
[Jumoke] This...
is literally the worst day ever.
Girl, tell me about it.
The only good thing that can come out
of this is you quitting.
[gulps]
Quitting?
Please, why would I do that?
Uh, 'cause they just demoted you.
It's just for three months,
it's really not that deep.
-Liah.
-How can I be quitting?
That would be horrible
if it was for three seconds.
She's punishing you
for no reason!
It's vindictive and you shouldn't
put up with it.
I can't quit.
I cannot afford it.
Not all of us have your stolen money.
-[laughing]
-Really?
Yes.
-I will have you know...
-That?
-That my father and his siblings...
-Mm-hmm...
-...multiplied that money ten folds.
-Yes, of course, my love, they did.
[chuckles]
-[clapping]
-[Jumoke] Oohh...
She was my favorite.
[Liah] Yeah.
Actually, this was really good.
[Jumoke] Oohh...
So don't quit.
Go... do that pitch
and when you win, quit.
[sighs]
I don't have a company.
I have a guy that can get
you one in two days.
Jeez.
-Next excuse?
-Okay.
-Shoot me.
-Yeah!
-[laughing]
-Boom!
Can I just have more wine?
Are we doing this?
-[squeals excitedly]
-[laughing]
Want more wine.
[laughing]
[Liah] You can do this, Liah.
[female narrator] Selling a car
in a hurry can be stressful.
It's easy to be taken advantage of.
[car honks]
However, with Cars45 pickup service,
you can get exactly what you need.
Cars45...
the buyer you can trust.
You were right.
I felt this was a waste of time,
but you were right.
You captured the essence
of the offering perfectly.
You wouldn't believe
how many people don't.
I can imagine.
I don't see why we don't do this.
But your CEO would have
to meet with my CEO.
I'm sorry?
It's no big deal.
He's just old fashioned.
He likes to meet with the head
of the company face-to-face.
Your CEO still pitches, right?
Oh, um... yes, he does.
[Liah] What did I just say?
And he will be available?
Um... yes, he will be.
[Liah] What am I saying?
Do set it up.
Thanks.
[Liah] What did I just do?
Why didn't you just tell them
you were the CEO?
I don't know. Obviously, I'm stupid.
Can you still tell him you're CEO?
How can? I'll be a joke.
I wouldn't even hire me.
[screaming]
-This is bullshit.
-It is!
We can't come this close
and settle for nothing.
There has to be something we can do.
[sighs]
There is something we can do.
Like what? What do you mean?
All we need to do is find a CEO.
-Right?
-Mm-hmm.
How about someone who looks the part
and has acting experience?
Where am I going
to get someone with that--
No!
You're kidding!
No.
And then I saw a caterpillar!
And I put it in my mouth and I ate it!
And I shat in my pants for a week!
Until I wised up and got diapers!
Which, by then,
I started wearing it for fun!
[laughing, clapping]
Okay, take five and we regroup
for... the next phase, yeah?
Thank you.
Jumes!
[sniggering]
What are you doing here, fine girl?
-[laughs]
-It's urgent.
I have rehearsal.
[scoffs]
It's not going to take long.
You must be joking.
You want me to what?
To pretend to be Liah's boss
so she can close an advertising contract.
[laughing]
I'm sorry, that's the most
ridiculous thing I've ever heard.
You see? I told you
he was not going to agree.
I did not say so.
I only said it was ridiculous.
So?
Turns out, I happen to like ridiculous.
[snickers]
This, this is a mistake.
He's going to mess it up.
I'm better off letting it go. Jumoke--
No, you're not.
You're going to allow him do this.
And, you,
you're going to do this
without screwing it up.
[laughing]
Are you fighting me now?
[laughing] It's your friend that
invented a boss for no reason.
I'm not the one to worry about.
Thank you.
Okay.
It's one time, right?
Jumes?
[In Yoruba]
Is it only once?
[Liah] Yes, it's one time.
[Lekan sighs]
Okay. No problem.
It's just one time.
-Bye.
-See you later.
-[chuckles]
-Jumoke, this is a mistake.
[sighs]
Probably, but that's life.
Let's go.
-No!
-[laughs]
This isn't going to work.
What isn't going to work?
Are you going to glare at me
throughout the presentation?
I'm not glaring at you.
I am not glaring at you!
Young lady, listen,
-you need to learn...
-Mmm.
...how to be an employee.
Employees don't glare.
You are right.
This isn't going to work.
What are you scared of?
Success?
Because people like you are.
Um, what do you mean
by people like me?
Poor people.
This guy.
I am not poor.
Uhh...
Aren't you the scholarship girl
from Jumoke's secondary school
-or am I mistaken?
-That was me.
Exactly.
Poor people are so scared of success,
that they self-sabotage
I've seen this thing happen
time and time again.
I'm sorry. Not everyone
can be a lazy playboy.
But everybody wishes they would.
Liah.
Liah!
-Liah!
-Lekan, what do you want?
[Lekan] I said I'll help you.
[Liah] You call this help?
Listen, I know you don't like me.
You think what you're doing is wrong,
you need an excuse to get out of it.
But don't let my being--
-Being a dick?
-Oh, I was going to say attitude,
but, yeah, being a dick stop you.
You know what?
-Maybe this is a sign.
-That?
Because if you're the only person
I can get to play my boss,
then I don't deserve to do this at all.
You know
I'm a very successful actor, right?
[chuckles]
I've been in tons of plays.
Lekan, plays that you fund.
Plays that nobody sees.
Turns out I'm not
the only one being a dick.
You see why we'll work well together?
Young lady,
let me help you.
-Lekan, why do you care?
-Oh, no, I don't.
Jumoke does and she's been
my best friend since we were six--
Err, please,
how is she your best friend?
Because technically, when she was six,
you were ten.
Eight.
Eight and half.
Whatever. Just...
blame our mothers for plotting
our marriage since birth.
Thank God Jumoke had more sense.
Most likely.
So, are you going
to let me help you
or you're going to go back to doing
whatever it is you know how to do?
Come, let me help you.
Hey!
So...
How did it go?
Girlfriend... [sighs]
-I hope he wasn't too much of an asshole.
-[chuckles]
He called me the poor scholarship
girl from your school.
He-- Li, did you slap him?
[chuckles]
No.
Wait.
-You're-- You're smiling.
-Yeah.
Oh, okay, so you didn't slap him.
Nope. I didn't.
Because he apologized and the rest of
the day went on pretty much smoothly.
-So...
-Okay.
Yes.
So you guys are ready for tomorrow?
As ready as we'll ever be.
I'm actually quite happy.
[chuckles]
I'm so relieved.
-Uh, Jumoke?
-Hmm?
What's this?
I know you don't need the money.
But just let me pay the way that I can.
[groans]
Is this because of what he said?
Look... look...
You know that this apartment block
is owned by my family, right?
-Yeah.
-And they cover all the expenses.
Like, I don't pay one Kobo
on this apartment.
Like, besides, you've already paid
for half the wine.
-Jumoke...
-Stop, no!
Take it.
And make sure you cash it.
[laughs]
Cashers!
[chuckles]
I can swear
you're not going to cash it.
Of course
I'm not going to cash the check!
[laughs]
You actually have no respect for me.
-[chuckles]
-[Indistinct mumbling]
[scoffs] Why are you in jeans
and where is your suit?
Where's your suit?
-I don't own one.
-[exhales]
Why don't you own a suit?
Because I don't need one.
[sighs]
And they're even ripped!
Please, we have time. Let's go.
We'll get another one on the way.
Let's go.
Ah!
[laughs]
[no audible dialogue]
-That was a great presentation.
-Thank you, sir. I'm glad you liked it.
I look forward to working
with you sometime.
-Thank you.
-[phone ringing]
-Oh, it's Lekan.
[chuckles]
Why is he calling you?
I'm sure he's cancelling.
Let me guess,
he's cancelling
'cause he's meeting some girl.
[sighs]
No.
It's not about a girl.
Are you okay?
[Lekan] Like, my phone
has been buzzing non-stop.
It's not been, what, a month?
And I've gotten invitation
to what, five pitches.
[Liah] Liah, what have you done now?
There is no way Hauwa won't find out now.
I-- I think she's just
overwhelmed with the news.
Liah?
Sweetie, are you okay?
I'm supposed to be upset.
Stop it.
What's wrong with this one?
You want to talk about it?
Liah...
talk to me.
Well... [sighs]
There's really nothing to talk about.
-Nothing to say.
-[phone ringing]
How is she five centimeters
dilated already?
I'll be right there.
I have to go,
but we'll pick this up later, okay?
Alright.
[knocking]
What do you want?
Follow me to a show.
You're kidding, right?
[sighs] Listen,
you can sit down here and stew over
whatever it is that is driving you crazy.
Or you come with me.
And listen to the best music
you have ever heard in your entire life.
[sighs]
As long as you don't ask me about it.
What's my business?
♪ Boy, I got one problem ♪
♪ I know you can solve it ♪
♪ Many men they call me
but I don't want nobody ♪
♪ Boy, I got one problem ♪
♪ I know you can solve it ♪
♪ I don't see nobody
And I don't want nobody ♪
♪ So, baby, tell me
What you do when you alone? ♪
♪ Do you touch your body
And think of me? ♪
♪ Baby, I could be your fantasy ♪
♪ Just lemme know
Just lemme know ♪
♪ Tell me what you do when you alone? ♪
♪ Do you touch your body
And think of me? ♪
♪ Baby, I could be your fantasy ♪
♪ Just lemme know
Just lemme know ♪
♪ Oh, baby, listen to my song ♪
She's good.
Very good.
And pretty.
Stunning, actually.
And you're trying to get with her?
[laughs]
No...
Hmm...
Not this time.
Let's just say I'm not her type.
Let's leave it like that.
Ah... right.
[chuckles]
Okay.
I could introduce you, if you want.
Why would I want?
[chuckles]
I just assumed that... you know.
You know...
What? Why would you assume that?
You never gave me the look.
You know, like...
You know, the look.
[laughing]
Sorry. So...
I am not attracted to men
because I am not attracted to you?
[laughs]
Please.
-[Lekan] Don't blame me now.
-[laughs]
-All my life, every straight woman...
-Hmm...
...gives Lekan the look.
[laughing]
You know, you're an idiot.
-I know.
-[laughs]
♪ Just lemme know
Just lemme know ♪
♪ Tell me what you do when you alone? ♪
A lot of people would actually
be ecstatic that they're getting calls.
But you, you truly went catatonic.
-What's up with that?
-Catatonic? That's a bit much.
What else do you call not
saying a word and running to your room?
Oh? That.
You said you wouldn't ask.
I lied.
Okay.
How come I have never met this Liah?
I've only met disapproving, scowling,
secondary-school-friend-of-Jumoke Liah.
I have never met insecure,
afraid-to-know-how-good-I-am Liah.
It is what it is.
"Our deepest fear...
...is not that we're inadequate."
[Liah]
Is he kidding right now?
"Our deepest fear is that
we are powerful beyond measure.
It's our light, not our darkness
that scares us."
[laughing]
Really? An inspirational quote?
[laughs]
Who's that? Um, Marian Williamson?
-[keypad tone]
-[laughing]
Oh, Lord, you actually made my day.
[laughs]
-Hello?
-[chuckles]
Is this Morenike of Right Pizza?
What are you doing?
Yeah, sorry--
Sorry for calling this late.
Are you crazy?
My name is Lekan
from Aniya creative agency.
[Liah] Is he kidding right now?
Yes!
Thank you for inviting us for a pitch.
I'll be there.
See you then.
Lekan is the most annoying
despicable asshole
-I have ever met!
-What happened?
Oh, my--
He didn't try to kiss you, did he?
No.
No, he didn't.
So what did he do?
He took a pitch without my consent.
Can you imagine?
So what?
You don't want it, just ignore it.
What's the big deal?
[sighs]
You do want it.
But you don't think you should want it.
-Please don't start this.
-I'm not starting anything.
Look, I...
I just had a difficult delivery.
I'm trying to relax.
[sitar music playing]
Do what you want.
[sighs]
What are you doing here?
[in Yoruba]
Have you eaten?
[in English] I brought apology breakfast.
Okay.
First of all,
I had no right to do what I did yesterday.
I apologize.
But you need to do this!
Those Cars45 guys were literally
eating out of your hands!
Your hands.
Err... my voice. Your pitch. Your ideas.
[sighs]
Lekan, please, why do you care?
Like...
we don't talk.
And you know that I don't like you.
And then, yet here you are being all
"Liah, you must do it." Why?
[sighs]
When I was 24 years old,
I invented a software that
automated a decent proportion
of illicit content monitoring.
What's that?
Porn. Mostly.
Oh...
And other stuff.
Okay.
Before my program,
you needed about a hundred people
to monitor one million users.
But I cut it down to ten and sold
the company for fifty million dollars.
Wow.
Apparently, the company that
bought mine got bought
for half a billion dollars a year later.
Wow.
[scoffs]
No wonder you're such an asshole.
Oh...
It gets better.
Both companies
were backed by my investors.
They owned only 20% of mine
and 80% of the other.
Maximizing their earnings
at my expense.
So you see, even though you're very,
very annoying and very judgmental,
my case reminds me of yours.
Your company uses your ideas,
and undervalues you. So...
I'm here to help in every way that I can.
Um, so how do you envisage this working?
[chuckles]
I have no idea.
I'm just the talent.
Okay, but you're definitely
getting better suits.
[chuckles]
Okay.
[Hauwa] You're late.
Tunde doesn't get here until 9:00
and it's just 8:30, is there a problem?
I came to look for you,
and you weren't here.
Is there something
you need me to tell Tunde?
You've had a long enough holiday.
-I don't understand.
-What don't you understand?
-[phone ringing]
-I said I'm taking you back.
Unless you want to be stuck
on Tunde's desk.
Of course not.
Good.
Go grab your stuff and let's go.
Right Pizza has requested for a pitch
from Aniya creative agency.
Aniya? Um, who is that
and how do you know?
A wannabe agency.
And why do you care about
a wannabe creative agency?
Because wannabe agencies grow up
to become big agencies.
So it's always best to nip
that shit in the bud.
I see.
So cancel any plans you must have had
because you're working late tonight.
Damn it.
I know.
-You were home free.
-I know.
[sighs]
But...
I guess it's confirmation
of your talent...
that she wants you.
[sighs]
Right now, it doesn't feel like that.
And since it's you, you're pulling Aniya
out of the running.
Jumoke, I really don't have a choice.
I hope you're not closing, Aniya?
-No. Ugh.
-Good.
I just need to find a company
that Apex isn't interested in.
Okay, that makes sense.
[sighs]
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
[Lekan] Odeh Holdings.
[Liah] Client.
[Lekan] Hmm.
Desire Foods?
Clients, for sure.
Farmer Inc?
Client.
Tarzan Motors?
Client, client.
Wait, wait, wait.
Is there anyone who isn't Apex's client?
We've been running
this for over an hour now.
Um...
You know what?
Let me...
Is everything okay?
Um, SupaPhone.
Really?
Yeah.
Apex isn't pitching
to a fit phone company?
Well, we're a bit conflicted because
we're working for their competitors. So...
-Okay.
-Yeah.
SupaPhone it is.
Right.
[camera clicks]
And so I'll say,
SupaPhone,
the difference is clear.
[laughs]
[Lekan] What's funny?
Because that's a famous 7UP slogan.
Like, everybody knows that.
Okay, so we need another slogan then.
Yes.
We do.
But you're very good at this.
Well...
I must have done a million pitches
while I was trying to raise money.
Okay.
And one time, I actually pitched
with full-on malaria.
-Hmm.
-Believe it or not.
So what happened that day was that...
What?
Go on, say it. I promise you
I won't get offended.
So how did you know that
what I'm going to say is offensive?
[chuckles]
Fine.
Okay, so I wanted to know...
How did you go from building
a multimillion dollar company in your 20s
to...
ugh, I don't know...
whatever this is?
Retiring early is living the dream.
Hmm.
I couldn't.
You couldn't what?
I couldn't try anything else.
-Hmm.
-[chuckles] I mean, I tried.
Others tried.
I even came back to Nigeria
for a clean slate. But I just...
...couldn't.
So then, why the theatre?
Well, my therapist actually...
suggested improv. But then...
I fell in love with acting.
And bought a theatre.
-Perks of being rich, baby.
-[scoffs] Please.
Who's your baby? Ugh. Anyways...
Thank you.
Back to work?
Yeah, back to work.
[Hauwa] Hello, Liah.
Where are you going to?
Good afternoon, Hauwa,
I was just heading for lunch.
Lunch? You have a pitch
which is due for tomorrow.
It's irresponsible to run off.
I already sent it to your email.
I know, I have to review it.
And I'm sure you want
to be around for that.
Yes.
[Hauwa] Come on!
[mumbling]
Okay, you know what, Liah,
you just have to go at her.
[sighs]
That's it. I'm telling her.
[Hauwa]
This meeting must hold.
I-- I'm sorry I have to leave.
My-- My aunty is sick.
-[sighs]
-I almost lost my mind.
It's fine.
-No problem.
-[sighs] Okay, fine.
So, yeah. What do you think?
-Uhh...
-Oh, shit!
-What is it?
-Don't move. Don't move.
-What do you mean "don't move"?
-Just don't move!
[mumbles]
[footsteps approaching]
[Tunde] Liah?
Err... [sighs] Hello, Tunde.
This is my friend, um...
This is my friend.
[Tunde] Hmm...
How are you, friend?
Nice to meet you.
Carry on.
[sighs]
Who was that?
That's my boss' boss.
That is Tunde.
Hauwa's boss.
Hmm...
We're ready for you now.
[sighs]
-Can you see that?
-[Liah] See what?
She's secretly judging you
for putting your tongue in my mouth.
Err, there was no tongue, please.
-I felt some tongue.
-Ugh, please.
-You want to try again?
-[Liah] Definitely not.
[Lekan] He said we should carry on.
[Liah] Please.
[laughing]
-I can't believe this.
-Stop laughing, it's not funny.
-It really is!
-How is it funny?
-You, Liah! You kissed Lekan! On purpose!
-I didn't--
I didn't kiss him on purpose!
[laughs]
You're annoying!
Stop!
I'm going to stop doing your hair.
Yes, please stop doing my hair.
[laughing]
-Did you actually call me Lekan's--
-I swear!
Wow!
Put your head down.
-You're bullying me!
-Sorry.
[Hauwa] This is crap.
This is the most useless pitch
I've ever seen.
If I wanted this crap,
I'd have kept you on Tunde's desk.
Do better!
I sincerely thought
this was what you wanted.
Oh, really?
I wanted crap?
Fix it! Nonsense.
Talking shit.
[Jumoke] Of course you're going to use it.
You think this is the way to go?
Right?
Yeah, so...
So... you can use the idea, guilt-free.
And Hauwa might be right.
The pitch might be shit.
I mean, what do you have to lose?
Just think about it.
Okay, fine.
[party music playing
over speakers]
So forceful.
-Uh, hi.
-Hey, Liah.
Hey.
Um, can we talk?
Somewhere else.
Really, Lekan?
Your make-out spot?
Don't worry, my hands
will be kept to myself,
except, of course, you want them to move.
Can I just stab myself in the eye instead?
[laughs] If you want to.
[clicks tongue]
So...
Wassup?
I came here to discuss the pitch.
[laughing]
What's funny?
Ah...
-You came to discuss the pitch?
-Yeah.
[laughing]
Just say... you came to see me.
No... yes... it's just...
it's just that you have,
you have to do the pitch alone.
[Lekan] Wait!
It's okay.
I shouldn't have asked.
-I know what it will take for you to--
-I'll do it.
What?
[sighs] I said I'll do it.
I mean, you have to...
you have to die of something, right?
Lekan, thank you.
Do you know him?
Uh... No, he's-- he's so pretty.
Hmm, girls.
Always led by their hormones.
That's the CEO of Aniya.
Oh...
Go say hello.
Um, what? Why-- Why would I do that?
[sighs]
[Lekan] What are you doing?
Ugh. Well, Hauwa sent me to come over.
What? Why?
No idea. How did it go?
Don't mind.
[chuckles]
It was crazy but,
-I really need you in there.
-Liah.
Won't you introduce me to your new friend?
So that's why she told me to come over.
[Lekan] Right!
Let's go.
Lekan Davis.
Tech millionaire,
trying his hands at advertising.
Interesting.
Well, you know techies, we try everything.
[Hauwa] Cool, of course.
Always cool to have new blood
in our industry.
-Thank you, ma'am.
-I'll take my leave, Liah?
Excuse me.
[sighs]
-[Ndidi] Hi!
-Hi, Ndidi, how are you?
[Ndidi] I'm very well, Hauwa,
you look good!
Thank you and you too.
-So how's Chidi?
-Great!
Okay, good.
I hope you guys are on point.
Because the last guys were good.
Really? Who are they?
Aniya.
Um, new guys, but really hungry.
Okay.
So...
[laughs]
So, shall we begin?
-Let's get started.
-Okay.
[party music playing]
[narrator] Right Pizza...
the right way to live.
So that's the future we have for you.
Fun, fresh, millennials for life.
-Wow. I love it.
-Thank you.
I absolutely love it.
It, it fits the brand
and it hit the right notes.
Good. So can we get started on legals?
Err...
-[chuckles]
-Um, is it too soon?
You want us to discuss? Not a problem.
Shoot.
[chuckles]
So, Hauwa, it's not that.
I mean, before the last guys,
I would have just said yes.
But the last guys pitched a nostalgia play
that we couldn't say no to.
I see.
Um, don't you think you should do both?
Like, um, cater to your target audience
and also do this
nostalgia thing you mentioned.
I wish I had the budget.
I truly do.
Hauwa, you know how these things go.
Please, it's not really my place.
Okay. I truly understand.
[sighs]
-We'll take our leave.
-Okay. [chuckles]
We lost to Aniya again?
Sir, we came second.
That's nonsense. Second?
Second? That's not who we are!
That's shitty! It's nonsense!
-It won't happen again.
-It better not!
-I'm sorry--
-Eh, no!
Would it be rude if I asked you
to leave my office?
-You see I--
-Leave my office now!
I'm going to destroy that boy.
[Liah] I can't believe it.
I'm actually winning!
To Aniya! Long may reign!
Yaay!
[laughs]
-Eyes?
-Oh, yeah.
-Eyes.
-Seven years, guys, seven years.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Did that woman actually say she
wanted to what? Destroy me?
[in Yoruba]
Me?
Olamilekan Davis.
-Boy, you scared?
-No, baby, I'm turned on.
[scoffs]
Of course.
It's work now.
[chuckles]
So when are you leaving Apex?
What do you mean?
Once, a fluke.
Twice, strength.
Three times? Baby, three times is destiny!
It's time to focus on Aniya!
But you know I'm not going
to do this forever now.
That is so true.
I know.
Why don't you hire Liah
-as creative director?
-Hmm...
And then quit and then
she takes over as CEO.
Mm-hmm.
-[in Pidgin] Sense will not kill you.
-Right?
-Thanks. Smart.
-[Liah] Yeah.
Could you guys be any more obvious?
-What?
-You too, what?
What? You think we planned this?
Of course I know you planned it.
Mmm.
I told you this girl
would figure this thing out.
Whatever.
See, this is it.
You've proven yourself.
It's time to leave the nest, baby eagle.
Please, can I at least think about it?
-[Lekan] Of course.
-No.
Just remember...
I bore easy.
Of course. It's you.
Ah, there you are.
We have a problem.
Is that right?
Uh...
[clears throat]
I'm sorry about my outburst
earlier in the day.
I-- I was totally out of line. I'm sorry.
The thing about apologies is that you're
not expected to repeat the crime again.
Look, my friend Chidi,
who works with Drip mobile
sent me a message earlier in the day.
They want Aniya.
Impossible! Tunde, we've had
that contract for four years!
No!
I can't lose that contract!
Especially not to that asshole!
I was hoping you'll say just that.
Now, let's get back to work.
Right.
[chuckles]
Thanks. I'm so full.
-[in Pidgin] Don't fall.
-It's...
-I'm fine, Lekan.
-Please!
-[phone ringing]
[chuckles]
It's Hauwa.
At 10 pm? Don't pick up.
-[scoffs] I have to.
-Why?
[sighs]
She wants me to come in.
It's 10. You're quitting, tell her no.
I can't, I'll just get a cab.
[both] I'll take you.
You want to drive on
third mainland at 10 pm?
Fine. Take her.
-Let's go.
-I said I'll get a cab.
[in Pidgin]
What's wrong with her?
What took you so long?
You called me in at 10 pm.
Don't you ever take that tone with me!
Okay?
Sorry.
You need to put together a brief
for a Drip mobile contract
and it has to be fire.
They want Aniya but we just have--
They want Aniya?
How-- How do you know?
Doesn't matter.
We need a pitch that
would blow Aniya out the water.
I don't care if you're going
to work all night, weekend.
We must win this pitch. Okay?
[sighs]
I can't.
What do you mean?
I said I can't.
What do you mean you can't?
Because... because I am Aniya.
You're what?
I said, I am Aniya.
Get out of my office.
-I'm sorry, I--
-Get out of my office now!
[laughs]
You're crazy.
Hey.
What are you still doing here?
That you wandered off,
doesn't mean the party should stop.
You want to talk about it?
Liah!
I quit tonight.
Oh, shit.
She wanted me to work
on the Drip mobile contract.
And apparently, they want Aniya.
I just couldn't see myself
working on two pitches again.
I-- I just couldn't.
Oh, okay, maybe we should calm down.
I can't believe...
I can't believe I did that,
I can't believe I told...
I told Hauwa that I was Aniya.
[Liah hyperventilating]
Jumoke, what have I done?
-Oh-- Woah!
-What?
I've spoiled everything.
-I've-- I've ruined everything.
-It's going to be-- Liah!
Liah! You're finally free!
-[breathing heavily]
-Okay?
-[sobs]
-It's okay.
Just breathe.
-[crying]
-Just breathe
Liah, you're okay. You're okay.
You're okay.
[Lekan] What are they doing here?
-What is this?
-It's a cease and desist letter.
[Liah] What does that mean?
If you go ahead with the pitch,
I will sue you for all you're worth.
No matter how small it will be.
-[Lekan] You can't do that!
-Oh, yes, we can!
[Lekan] Who's this one now?
Barrister Emeka Nwosu, Apex's lawyer.
Oh, by the way,
Miss Liah here is an employee of Apex.
So whatever pitch she produces,
belongs to Apex.
Mr. Davis, we're ready for you.
-Liah, let's go.
-He's a rich boy, he has nothing to lose.
Can you say the same?
You poverty-ridden little nonsense.
[sniffs]
Liah, Liah, don't listen to them.
Don't let them get to you.
They don't have any case,
they're bluffing.
I'm sorry.
I can't.
Good decision you've taken.
See you at the office tomorrow
for a settlement conference.
Hello, I'm here to see Bode.
[Liah sighs]
I'm sorry.
What are you sorry about?
You didn't do anything.
I pushed you to quitting.
Lekan, I'm not a child!
I make my own decisions.
I'm not saying you don't.
-All I'm trying to say is--
-Shut up.
Listen, you're not going
to take this lying down.
I promise you, I'll ge--
[instrumental music playing]
I... I, I said shut up.
Okay...
That's one way to do it.
Ow! Ow!
[Jumoke through walls]
I'm actually being serious.
You will never guess what happened to--
What the fuck, Liah!
Jumoke...
-Jumoke, I can explain. I--
-[Jumoke] What?
-You tripped and fell on his dick--
-Jumoke!
[chuckles] I actually can't believe
you were dumb enough to fall for him.
Um, I'm an adult,
and I make my own decisions.
Oh, please.
What do you even mean by that?
-Hm?
-I love, Lekan.
But he is broken.
And if you stay with him,
he will break you.
I know exactly what he is.
-And I definitely can handle--
-Fix him?
How about you join the queue
with the other girls?
Anything else, Mom?
-I just want what's best for--
-No!
Jumoke,
you want what you think is best for me.
What is that supposed to mean?
Do you know I'm being sued by Apex?
And somehow that's my fault?
What happened to being an adult...
who makes their own decisions?
You know what, I don't have time for this.
[whispers] Don't start judging me
for that, bitch.
[door opens, slams]
[Lekan] That didn't sound like fun.
Are you okay?
Liah.
Say something now.
Listen, Jumoke will be fine.
Liah, talk to me now.
[Liah] Look, Lekan, I know that...
this doesn't sound right but...
I need to be alone right now.
[chuckles]
That's usually my line.
I'm sorry.
[door opens]
[door closes]
She kissed me.
Did she force you to kiss her back?
Look at her now,
does anybody need forcing?
[in Yoruba]
What's wrong with you?
Look, we've been friends
since we were kids.
-And I love you like a brother.
-I know.
Sorry.
If you act like you always do
and she cuts you off,
I will too.
[laughs]
And what if she dumps me?
Well, then, karma is a bitch.
[laughing]
I hate you.
-I love you, too.
-I'm serious.
[laughing]
So you thought you could get
away with it, right?
Liah, how dare you?
After everything I've done for you,
you became the competition?
You refused to promote me.
I earned that promotion.
You ungrateful little shit!
You piece of rubbish!
Hey, hey, hey, ladies. Calm down.
We are not here to fight, alright?
You threatened to sue me.
You used the company's property!
Pitched an idea we worked so hard--
With an idea you rejected.
Well, Liah, you are an employee.
Whatever ideas
you generate are our property.
Liah, nobody is going to sue you.
We're here to chart a new path.
A new, a new path,
what does that even mean?
Well, you are going to sell Aniya to us.
You will be made the creative director.
And if I refuse?
Then I get to destroy you.
[Tunde] Think about it.
Just think about it.
It doesn't have to get this ugly.
-[Jumoke] Of course you should take it.
-How can you say she should take it?
Because they're paying her for Aniya
and making her creative director.
Because she's worth a lot more!
Listen, go at it alone, I promise you,
you won't regret it.
And when they sue her?
We have money now, the case will be
in court for a long time.
And who will hire her then?
Exactly.
She's right.
I'm sorry.
You have nothing to apologize for.
Jumoke, can you just give us like,
two minutes please. Please.
[sighs]
I know how this makes you feel.
Don't let them rate you less.
Lekan, this is more
than I ever dreamed of.
And it's still not enough!
Please, Liah,
don't do this.
Do what?
Make me watch them destroy you.
They aren't destroying me, they're giving
me everything I ever wanted.
You gave it to yourself!
And this way I get to keep it!
Lekan, I know you.
I don't know how
to withdraw from the world.
This is actually what I want.
I hope this makes you happy.
Lekan, you can make me happy.
[sighs]
I'm sorry.
You don't deserve this.
I said, you don't deserve this.
You know, I was happy working with you.
You're going to fail.
-You got lucky.
-Hmm.
But, Liah,
you will fail.
And Tunde will fire you.
And then, you will run back
to your village where you came from.
Trust me.
You will fail.
[no audible dialogue]
-[quiet chatter]
-[no audible music]
[music plays through headphones]
♪ 'Cause I did die for you ♪
♪ Baby, I did try for you ♪
♪ I want you to love me ♪
♪ Baby, I did fall for you ♪
♪ You know it's true
I want you to love me ♪
♪ Oh, nah! ♪
♪ But you are far away from me, baby ♪
♪ You no go look my side, baby ♪
♪ You're far away from me, baby ♪
♪ See, baby
you're far away from me, baby ♪
♪ I'll be on the good
lookin' side oh, oh ♪
♪ You're far away from me, baby ♪
♪ See, baby, you're far away, far away ♪
♪ Baby, you're far away, far away ♪
♪ Baby, you're far away from me, yeah ♪
♪ See, baby, you're far away, far away ♪
♪ Baby, you're far away, far away ♪
♪ You're far away from me, baby ♪
♪ I just want you to look at me
I just want you to want me ♪
♪ Now the reason for
you notice me ♪
♪ I got happiness to give you
But, baby, would you love me? ♪
♪ Cause your love
it give vitamin C-eh-eh ♪
♪ Now me and you supposed to
the ball around the town ♪
♪ Show the other men say
you got a trophy wife ♪
♪ Let me be the one
that you're coming home to ♪
♪ You know I got happiness to give you
but I just want you to love me ♪
♪ I want vitamin C-eh-eh ♪
♪ 'Cause I did die for you ♪
♪ Baby, I did try for you ♪
-♪ I want you to love me ♪
-♪ Want you to love me ♪
♪ Want you to love me... ♪
[music fades]
Hey.
Liah.
What are you doing here?
Okay, that wasn't the welcome I was...
hoping for...
Please, tomorrow is my first presentation,
I don't have time for this.
I turned down sex tonight.
I'm sorry, what?
I turned down sex
with a girl so beautiful,
she would make your eyes hurt.
But not as beautiful as you, of course.
You too are...
beautiful.
[chuckles]
You're babbling.
Why are you babbling?
I don't have time for this nonsense.
It was because of you.
Listen, I didn't realize it until...
I was looking at her
and all I could think about was you.
I didn't even have sex with her.
I want to have sex with you.
Lucky me, Lekan.
Li, I don't care about your job
or anything. I just want you.
Hmm.
I know you're going to be so miserable...
-Yeah.
-But it's...
As long as you need to do this,
I'll be here to make you smile.
Get out, Lekan.
[in Pidgin]
What?
-Lekan, do I look stupid to you?
-What?
Do I look like a helpless victim to you?
[in Yoruba]
What is wrong with you?
[in English] What are you talking about?
You know what they're doing to you!
Nobody did anything to me!
-You're not listening to me!
-No! You aren't listening to me!
But, Liah, I'm just trying to let
you know that I choose you.
Lekan.
Lekan, you should have... should have
chosen me when I asked you to.
When I needed you to!
Liah, I wasn't ready.
I can't.
And I can't do this when you can
just walk away from me so easily!
Liah... Liah...
-Lekan, leave!
-Liah, please.
Leave me, get out!
-Give us a chance.
-Get out!
Just...
[sobs]
Lekan, go.
Liah, please.
Leave.
[crying]
How are you feeling?
A bit nervous.
It's to be expected.
You see, the bank contract
is worth billions to our company.
No pressure.
No.
I want you to feel the pressure.
I want you to understand what is at stake.
I'll tell you what...
If you win us this contract,
you will not only be
Aniya's creative director,
but that of Apex as well.
What of Hauwa?
What about Hauwa?
Her best ideas were yours.
I would want your ideas as you.
[Liah] Hmm.
-I'll try not to let you down.
-Good.
Do you have a minute?
I just had a conversation with Tunde.
Good for you.
[chuckles]
He offered me your job.
Is that why you sabotaged me
and tried to hold me back?
You thought I'd replace you?
How could you think so little of me?
Maybe I misjudged you.
You're not the first I mentored
who tried to take my spot.
I didn't try to take your spot.
I couldn't risk it.
You were too good for that.
So why did you fight for me to come back,
if you knew that this would happen?
Because Tunde was going to fire me anyway.
I've given 15 years of my life to Apex.
The least I could do was to
ensure I have a worthy successor.
I'm sorry, that doesn't make any sense.
Only because you're still a child.
You have no sense of legacy.
[woman] Doctor Cole.
Doctor Cole!
[sighs]
You've been avoiding my calls.
I think we've said all we need to say.
I sent you an email.
I read your email.
$20 million can go a long way.
You can help save the lives
of a lot of women.
Not on those terms.
-[knocking]
-[Jumoke] Can I come in?
I'll take that as a yes.
I got the grant.
Wow, Jumoke...
that's awesome.
I've been so caught up in my own shit
that I didn't even realize
we were still talking.
They made me an offer.
Renounce my family,
return the money and...
get $20 million
to change the world.
And you said no?
-I said no.
-Why?
Because...
I'm starting to believe Lekan was right.
What do you mean?
Doing the right thing
the wrong way will destroy you.
I mean, look at you.
Liah, you hate yourself.
I don't hate myself, it's j--
I'm hoping that it will pass.
What a way to feel
when you get everything you want.
You had gamed it out.
The smart decision was staying.
I know, I agree but...
Sometimes you have to not be
smart to be happy.
Huh?
[laughing]
That doesn't even make any sense.
I know, it sounded better in my head.
Clearly.
[sighs]
But it's true though.
I'm not sorry, by the way.
-Pushing you to do Aniya.
-Oh...
You proved that you were great.
[sighs]
Thank you, Jumoke. Like...
you've had my back and
thank you for always pushing me, like,
you're always there for me.
You're amazing.
[chuckles]
[laughs]
We have to move.
I thought you just said
you didn't take the deal?
I didn't take the deal.
Renounce my money? My family?
Am I mad?
Okay, then, what did you do?
-Well, I...
-Mm-hmm?
I agreed to live off of my salary
as paid for by the grant...
for five years. And since this place
is rent free, we have to move.
Okay, so... how much is this salary
that you agreed to take?
-Two hundred and fifty thousand dollars.
-Huh?
A year?
-What?
-What, it's a sacrifice!
Such a sacrifice.
[sighs]
It's fine.
-I might need that check though.
-[laughing]
-It's fine. Your girl is rich now, so...
-We'll be fine.
-[sighs]
[Liah] When Tunde gave me this brief,
I wanted to know one thing.
How do I achieve the vision
that you have for the bank?
How do I show
that this is not just a bank,
but a partner in achieving dreams?
It's a mother paying
for her child's school fees.
Or paying for that last minute training
to help her son win a race.
It's a lawyer starting a firm.
It's a banker working tirelessly to ensure
that his customers succeed.
Or all the women who come together
to make something great.
And a bank that sees that greatness.
[man] And the winner is,
"A Woman in the Day"
by Apex Aniya creative director,
Liah Attah.
[applause]
[crying]
[Hauwa] Hmm...
[crying continues]
You got what you asked for.
And you're here, crying like a baby.
One more advice,
if you want to succeed in my role,
do not let them see you cry. Okay?
In your role?
Does that mean it's official?
He told me today.
Tunde has a great sense of timing.
You know, I'd rather have worked with you,
than replaced you.
Is that right?
[sobbing]
Wow-wow-wow-wow...
[chuckles]
Oh, wow...
It was a lovely evening, wasn't it?
It's about to get better.
Oh, well, uh,
let's not create a scene here.
Oh, not at all.
I just wanted to tell you
I'm starting a new agency.
Hmm... interesting.
You'll lose your severance.
I'll survive it.
If you say so. All the best.
But Liah here and I, will crush you.
Probably.
But she's coming with me.
Impossible!
You've got to be joking.
I'll sue the two of you.
-Tunde, there's nothing to sue for.
-Mm-hmm.
You own Aniya.
And all the work from it.
We'll be starting from scratch.
So, we wish you all the best in life.
And we'll try not to crush you.
The look on his face was everything
-I could have hoped for.
-[sighs]
[chuckles]
I'm glad I could have given you that.
You're not joining me, I take it?
No.
No, I'm not.
If you had apologized at least once
for everything,
I probably would have considered.
So what are you going to do?
Whatever I please.
Hm.
Can we talk?
I see a man upon the shore.
And he's limping,
with blood gushing from his legs.
And his mistress
is dressing him with a bandage.
Talk to me. Please.
He chooses to ignore her
and focus on what's important.
Trying to stop the bleeding
after she shot him.
She tries to explain
that it was a mistake.
And she didn't mean it.
It's not about intentions.
It's about what you do.
That's why her paramour
is running from her.
[Liah sighs] Can you just stop, please,
so I can apologize, Lekan.
He realized that the apology was a trap.
He let her kiss him anyway.
Lekan, I won an award today.
Best Ad Of The Year
for Access.
Awards are not important.
Lekan, as I stood on that stage,
in front of that crowd,
I realized that nothing mattered,
because you were not there.
And so, I came here... for you.
You're supposed to throw the ball.
And you're supposed to kiss me.
Her asking for a kiss,
surprised,
but awakened a greater passion in him.
[applause]
[Liah] This is Lekan, my friend.
[cheering]
My name is Liah,
and I can be anything I want to be.
[applause]
["Vibrations" by how Dem Camp
Feat. Tomi Thomas playing]