Next stop is Luxemburg.
Passengers arrive at Luxemburg please go to the exit.
Oh, good job!
Yellow is just so so, but red...
Hello, guy, paint with more red color...
so that this picture can be more attractive.
What the hell are you guy doing here?
What do you know about it? Do you understand it?
You are always drawing pictures which nobody wants to buy.
What do you mean? These drawings are priceless?
Yes, that's what I just meant! Anything wrong?
The guy who stole the passenger's wallet.
What can you call them besides cheater? Ok...
Do not lose face here, let's go home!
You fucking guy, damn it!
Oh! You guy
What do you want? Come on! Head's up!
Fuck you, I don't mean to beat you.
But now it's you who threatened me to do.
Are you ok? What's wrong with you?
Why did you do that?
Don't you think what he said was too tough?
Go away, he was just in the point! Go out!
Please don't come over again! Never come back!
Fucking guy!
Excuse me, passport please.
Thank you.
It's you, isn't it?
Yes, remember to come again.
Thank you, passport please.
What are you for in France?
He comes along with me.
Sorry, goodbye.
Hey! You fucking guy steals again!
You are a thief.
That's why I don't want you to come with me.
Wake up, boy! You suck.
Do you dare steal again?!
Hello, are you hot, cute girl?
No! Don't do that.
Thank you, what's your name?
My name is Qinghai, and you?
Colin.
Colin?
Qinghai, thank you again for what you did moment ago.
Do you like that sculpture?
No, I just enjoy her expressions.
I want her head.
That's the national treasure!
You will be put to jail if you steal that.
Anyhow I really want that.
Come on! The guard is drawing near.
Come on!
You are Korean? Is that right? Haha! Put the coin here.
Like this...Oh, by the way it's not mine.
Open it in the same way for the next time.
It's called Bigo, Bigo, understand?
You don't have to pay. It's pleasure to help the Korean.
Remember it's called Bigo. You may have a try yourself.
Come on, the performance here is wonderful.
Open your eyes wide! Come on!
I will drop in whenever I have time.
I love you.
But don't ask me to do the same thing again.
It should be the last one.
I see.
Stand still.
And stop fighting.
Shit.
Where did that guy come from?
Great! Excellent job.
Let's introduce ourselves formally. My name is Qinghai.
You are a fucking thief.
Go away. I just want to return your stuff.
That's why I went there.
Coincidentally I met them and the money.
I didn't want to lose the money so I put it in my pocket.
I didn't use even a penny.
Fucking guy.
Count the money yourself.
Hey! Are you a spy?
What did you say?
Maybe the spy can't be so poor.
Have you made any artificial medicine?
and sold them here, is that right?
Shut up, fucking guy! Or I would kill you.
No, don't describe it so terrible.
Then why did you come to Paris?
Why did you come here?
You can have a comfortable life in Korea with such amount of money.
Do you know why I didn¡¯t use any of the money?
Oh, fucking guy! With the people like you,
the South and the North Korea can never be unified.
Fuck you!
Open the door quickly.
He was making trouble here and there, and beaten me.
Shit!
I'm innocent, I didn't do anything wrong!
Fuck you, what the hell are you doing here?
That guy seemed to have some word to say.
It was my fault to beat you, open the door please.
He said he would kill me after I was released here.
What do you plan to do? Do business with me?
Or stayed in the prison for the whole life?
Do you really want to die?
Beat me, kill me!
Can we really stay in Paris?
Of course, trust me.
How can you such a foreigner...
put up here!
This is my last choice.
Ok! Although I don't want to wallow in the mire with you,
I trust in you this time.
Great, this is what we have got. Wait a moment!
300 Francs is too much, just give you 50 Francs.
Hey! Is that right to follow my orders?
It's piece of cake for me to cleave the brick in two.
This can be the art! Not only singing,
but dancing, drawing as well can be described as a kind of art.
When we eat,
don't make any noise.
Follow me, hold the glass gentlely.
Then close your eyes like this.
You should learn to be Paris' citizen.
Hey, guy, I wanna ask you
whether you are good at fighting.
At teenager, that's the only thing I have learnt.
There's no place in my country to earn money.
Come to see my performance tomorrow.
Shit, must I?
Don't be afraid, I am ready for that.
Let him do that.
What quick movement! Think it over to work for me!
Work for you?
Don't you say that you come here to earn money?!
It's a loss for such talented people to be a street-performer.
Now you have got a good chance,
to show your talent, is that right?
It's the chance granted by God.
They come here to employ you
but I still don't want to accept.
This is a golden chance for us to cooperate,
to earn huge quantity of money in the future.
We won't do that. Cleaving the brick in the square can also earn money.
You can earn lots of money just for cleaving once or twice.
Then we can buy house and car.
and other goods. Take my advice.
I come here not for fighting.
Ok, then we can do it just once.
I take full responsibility.
A car in the square was pressed flat,
but no one was injured. Let's do it only once!
Come on, he's coming! Go out quickly!
Fucking guy, do it quickly!
Hi, let's have a chat.
How are you? Are you ok?
Wipe the blood away.
It doesn't matter...give me handkerchief, it hurts...
Hongshan, Hongshan, you have so much money.
Let's divide it into two, one million for both, let's go!
Let's go home.
I should compensate for you.
It's ok. Please don't leave me alone.
Ok, this is our room, come in please.
It's a skilled chick. I have paid the money.
Use your man's vigor.
For only 500 Francs!
What the hell are you doing here?
Is this kind of making love? You looked like a bull.
Fuck your asshole.
Who's that?
Hey, wait! Have you fucked Colin?
When I wasn't here, have you made love with him?
Go away!
You will be arrested while you don't have any card.
I was the only man who can give you living.
But for me you are already prostitute.
You can never be out of my control.
Boss, there are show of many beautiful girls.
Come in please, and enjoy yourself.
That's fine.
You can get...
whatever you want here.
It's over there, come with me.
Excuse me.
Come over here, there's nobody here.
Fucking guy.
You shall pay for having sex with other one's woman.
What's more, I have enough money.
If you dare to approach Colin again,
I will kill you and take your heart out.
Ok, Emie.
Honey ,kiss me.
Rola,Rola
Rola, give me some money.
The man who abandon his child...
can be said as a qualified father?
When you leave a 14-year old girl...
in the streets,
have you regard her your daughter?
Rola, Rola, Rola
You should do me another favor.
What? I said that was the last time.
Please, this time is the last one.
No! Please don't do that business any more.
Rola, I love you! Just once.
I will never do that business again.
If I did, I would feel anxious
Sure the last time?
Is that a Korean?
Where are the Korean? They are all mixed blood.
Please help me! I give you the money and you help me.
This...is for you, help me please.
I won't do that! Won't!
You beat your countrymen just for money.
Do you feel sad about that?
I'm not willing to do that.
Other people ask me to do so.
Then you have alibi to beat them and to gamble money?
What you said suggests that...
to beat someone to the ground means
" How are you? Sorry for that." Is that right?
Fuck you.
Fuck you!
Let me go! Quickly, or I will beat you.
You are now a favorite!
I have made a mistake!
Don't come again, fucking boy!
Hongshan, I made a mistake. Don't leave me alone.
Hongshan, do you really quit?
What can you do besides that?
Hey, well done! You should do this.
We have to make the business.
This is what we gambled today, take it!
But I want you to do a favor for me.
Don't do any job related to taking off the clothes, what's that in French?
What do you want?
You don't need to take care of that.
Do you still remember me?
We met in the train.
Qinghai is a fucking guy.
You stupid, look at me.
Are you insane?
Fuck you asshole! Dare you bully my brother?!
Come over here, you fucking pig.
You are too excessive. Apologize to Hongshan.
I'm sorry, Hongshan.
That's not enough.
I said that I will decorate a drawing room after I buy a boat.
A drawing room? Some one paid the boat for 70 Francs.
You even didn't pay the rent on time.
Wait a moment, I bid for 100 Francs.
Do you peddler have 100 Francs?
Give me 1-month time.
Ok, accept.
Ok! Shit, that's too bad.
I want to paint it as the sculpture in the square.
Is that your lover?
Not now. Now the enemy.
Do you really love her?
Sure.
For just once in bed? You are so decent in love.
I was just such person.
Ok, I give her to you.
It's fresh for you.
I'm so tired of that.
You give me 100 thousand Francs. Remember, that's 100 thousand.
What do you do tomorrow?
It's none of your business.
She's coming, I'll wait for you in the first floor.
What? Got beaten?
You are seriously injured.
We trust them too much.
I thought there was already a trap waiting for us.
You mean there's a hidden traitor among us?
No,  I doubt it was Hongshan's friend.
Every time when we divide the money, they feel some what envious.
Sorry! You were seriously injured! What a shame!
What a shame! How strong your fist is!
Only the body is strong.
Sure, we have regarded it too easy.
I don't want to do the same thing. Now I want to see you drawing.
What? See me drawing?
What's up? Won't you draw?
Do you want to have a portrait?
That's great! I am very much honored to have that.
It seems as if I were drawing a portrait for beast. Does that hurt?
A little. I can still remember when I was fighting in the United States,
I was also injured.
But it's the first time I didn't fight back.
When you draw me the picture, please make it fancy.
Besides, the portrait of smiling.
Shut your mouth, and wait like a baby.
I am drawing carefully.
Who's that? What are you doing? Where are you going?
He ran away.
Son of bitch, you hurt him too much.
Shit, are you kidding?
We don't have money for a bitch who repelled to his friend.
My friend repelled me today.
But I understood him.
He didn't want to lose his lovely boat.
He dreamed of having a drawing room in that boat.
This picture is drawn for me. How do you like it?
Boss, what do you want?
Rola,Rola.
Rola! Ok. I will give it to her, please trust me.
That's fine.
You came back at last.
I have been waiting for you for a long time.
The guy who just came in gave this to you.
That's not enough, take some more with you!
I want to see Colin.
It's impossible without sufficient money.
Just once.
I'll take all money from his life.
With more meat.
Get away! Get away off me! Son of the bitch.
You let him go just because you turn soft-hearted to him?
He had stolen so much money from you,
and brought us into trouble,
we must give him a lesson.
Forget it, let him go!
I won't see you again.
I'm sorry for beating you. It's just because...
Please stop doing the same business.
I don't need any help from you.
You needn't have worried about that.
Don't touch with the hand. It's poisonous.
Why do you take care of me?
Go away! Son of bitch,
That's enough! I'll beat you back if you don't leave now.
Who made you feel so glorious today?
Think it over! What a fancy clothes you are wearing!
What did you wear when you arrived in Paris?
Sure! I feel wronged to you.
Is that enough to just say a sorry?
You are the guy who merely knew how to fight.
These meat is for you.
I ate just a small piece! Son of the bitch.
Am I beggar? Give me money! Go! Go!
Leave me alone here.
Have a nice life all alone!
Help! I can't swim!
Why did you rescue me? You have lost your shoes.
That's Italian brand.
Shit! Shit!
Honey, give me a kiss.
I love you, you are so cute.
You son of the bitch.
Annie.
What's wrong here?
How much money has this guy taken with him?
Don't move!
My money...
Look at your face.
Don't you feel ashamed?
Hongshan, I adore you.
The decent eyesight is seldom to see in Paris.
You eyes won't lie.
Please take me in again.
Drive him away!
I can do whatever you want.
You are kidding! What can you do?
Drive him away.
Stupid guy, what are you doing? Does it hurt?
Did I do a good job? It fucking hurts.
What are you doing? Don't run.
When can I genuinely belong to you?
Don't say that! Leave me alone please.
Don't you like me?
But you have... which is not durable for me.
At least before I die I can't accept that.
You should behave like the chair in that picture.
accompanying me at any time.
Qinghai, Qinghai! Open the door.
My brother.
What's up, boss!
I heard that band has evil intentions against our entertainment place.
Go and fix them!
That's too risky, because they are all...
When did you learn to talk back to your boss?
Do what I order you to!
You said you would do whatever I want.
Yes.
Then?
Emie, I love you! I derivate from the organisation.
I am happy to hear that!
The organisation will kill me, while they can definitely find me.
God bless us.
I will kill whoever wants to kill Emie.
I'll go with you.
Nothing can stun our love.
Just to watch the door?
Yes.
That's enough.
Hongshan, I forget it! Let me take something with me.
What?
I will be back soon.
Emie, what's up? Emie, Emie...
Why can I hear a woman crying?
That girl has just bathed, and she has beautiful chest.
I can't help feeling it! Let's go.
What the hell were you doing since yesterday?
Did I ? I bought a watch.
It's for you! Rolex!
Rolex?
Yes.
Thank you.
It suits you.
Did you make trouble in China restaurant?
Look at your face?!
I knew from the beginning that it would be crisis for me.
So you were beaten like this?
It's a shame, shit!
Hongshan, come here.
Hongshan, before this candle is burning off,
kick them ass! Do it quickly.
Quickly.
No, not like this.
Look at me.
Take off the hat.
Excuse me.
Does the candle dies off itself?
This time I want Hongshan to kill someone.
I want you to kill a man.
I don't want to kill anyone.
He refused to do so.
Ok! I'll give you time to think it over.
I will do it.
You are not qualified.
It's impossible even if you're willing to.
Why?
Wasn't it just a threaten to them?
Do you really regard it such simple stuff?
It's bloody! To be,
or not to be!
Forget it if it's no big problem.
We have come to the end! We can never turn around.
You have changed so much and become very horrible.
Yes, I did it, not you.
They were all killed by me! I would take the full responsibility.
It's my fault if there's any problem.
The boss becomes aware of it, let's make it soon.
That won't be easy! He liked us.
I'm afraid we will be embarrassed at that time.
Whom will you support at that time?
Of course you.
Then we should kill Hongshan first.
which cannot be easy at all.
What are you doing now?
It's you who don't keep your word.
Wait a moment! I will take the money, you bitch.
100 Francs.
You think I'm for just 100 Francs
to retreat my friend?
Do you like eel?
Eel? Which eel?
The fish which has never eaten a man,
can watch the stomach of a man, is that interesting?
Shan, if a man was thrown to the sea with handcuffs,
what will happen?
What?
He would survive under some special conditions.
What are you now talking about?
Ok, give me your hand.
Our friendship will never change!
We live together,
and also die together! Prost!
I'll get some food.
These are the keys.
I will be back soon.
Open the handcuffs. It's not some kind of joke.
No, I won't untie it! You should do it yourself.
You can surely survive, because I trust you.
Are you kidding?
No, you are now crazy! Calm down.
It's not the right place for you who look like the man from village.
I can rescue Colin only when I kill you.
Then I can take the sculptures which favors Colin.
You really want me to die? I will commit suicide if that's your willing!
I hope you a happy life!
And there's nothing to feel guilty! The future will be bright.
Room 307...two men?
Come in!
I will do that.
It' 1500000 Francs, in room 307 Bica Hotel.
Kill that guy.
Honey, honey! Wake up.
Come in.
Do you still remember?
When I retreated you, you beaten me to die! At that moment...
I wanna get beaten from you! Beat me.
The heart will break when you beat someone.
Please.
Really?
Can you withstand it?
Hold on!
This boat will be yours.
Hold it! Quickly.
It's  fairly good work, isn't it?
Finish it.
Come out quickly.
Quickly...
Come in quickly.
Quickly.
They seem to kill us.
What can we do?
The fucking guy.
An idea comes through my mind...
that it's lovely days when we perform in the street.
That's right.
Let's sleeve the bricks in the square.
Is that ok?
Of course.