♪ Never get too big ♪
♪ Never get too heavy ♪
♪ Never get too cool
you stop paying your dues ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ What can a poor boy do? ♪
♪ Better go back
to your mama ♪
♪ Oh, she'll take care
of you ♪
Christ, I won't miss
that country rubbish
first thing in the morning.
I bet you'll
miss me though, eh?
I hope a get the chance to.
♪ Stay out drinking
till the morning comes ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ What can a poor boy do? ♪
Autograph, please.
You're gonna be
the next Dolly Parton!
Enjoy yourself, hen!
♪ Cheerio!
Cheerio! Cheerio! ♪
Fuck! Go on, girls!
♪ Country girl,
take my hand ♪
♪ Lead me through
this diseased land ♪
Keep your foot still, please.
♪ I am tired, I am weak ♪
I've appealed it,
so it'll be off before it's on.
Well, while it's on,
you cannot leave
the registered address
after 7:00 at night
until 7:00 the next morning.
Is that me?
♪ Country girl,
got to keep on keeping on ♪
Fuck's sake.
♪ Crazy woman,
mess your head ♪
♪ Wake up drunk and bleeding
in some strange bed ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ What can a poor boy do? ♪
And don't come back!
♪ You better go back
to your mama ♪
♪ Oh, she'll take care
of you ♪
♪ Oh, country girl ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Lead me through
this diseased land ♪
♪ I am tired, I am weak ♪
♪ I am worn ♪
♪ I have stole,
I have sinned ♪
♪ Oh, my soul is unclean ♪
♪ Country girl ♪
♪ Got to keep on keeping on ♪
♪ I go out walkin' ♪
♪ After midnight ♪
♪ Out in the moonlight ♪
♪ Just like we used to do ♪
♪ I'm always walkin' a... ♪
He's in his bath.
"Hello, Rose-Lynn.
Would you like a cup of tea?
How are you?"
♪ I'm always walkin' ♪
♪ After midnight ♪
- ♪ Searching for you ♪
- Oh!
Cover yourself,
for God's sake!
Cover yourself!
Oh!
Oh, fuck, yeah.
All
the way from Glasgow, Scotland,
please welcome a little girl
by the name
of Rose-Lynn Harlan
to the Opry.
Rose-Lynn Harlan,
ladies and gentlemen,
performing for the first time
here in Nashville, Tennessee.
Whoo!
Fucking "A."
Right. I'll see you.
When?
Mum!
Ooh. Hi.
- Come on, Lyle.
- Come.
Where do you think
you're going,
all done up like a fish supper?
I see he's got you down,
so he has.
That's scary.
Don't do that.
Anyway,
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm having
my dinner with you.
"No, down this way."
"No, go this way."
He never shuts up;
you never speak.
What's going on in there, eh?
Sponsored silence?
Did you miss me? Hmm?
Rose-Lynn!
I thought you were
your mum there.
That can't have
been 12 month.
The time's went by like that.
Yeah.
Hello, Marion!
Night, both of you.
She looks good, Amanda.
Oh, so she should.
Enough time at it.
Does she still lie
out here on tinfoil?
Oh... one peek of the sun
and that one's in a bikini.
Other day, she was in
after my butter.
- Your butter?
- Puts it all over.
"It's natural, Marion."
Aye. Natural if you're a roll.
Mary was gonna come tonight
and see you,
but she's awful bad
with her arthritis, so...
Och, that's a shame.
Aye.
It's in her knees now,
so that's her had to retire.
So...
£8 an hour.
Holidays.
Says she'll see you into it
as a favor to me.
Cleaning, ah? Aye.
Very good.
Why? What were you thinking?
Thinking? No.
I wasn't thinking.
I just got out.
Don't you worry about me.
No, I wasn't.
I was thinking about your kids.
I'm going to Nashville.
Well, you better mind
your tag doesn't go off
when you're going
through security.
First thing the morrow,
I'm going down the Opry,
I'm gonna get my job back,
and I'm gonna work for it.
There's nothing for me here.
See, there, I can be
honing my craft.
I can be out gigging
every night.
Honing your cr...
Do you not think
you've sacrificed enough
for that fantasy?
Have we all not sacrificed
enough for that fantasy?
It isn't a fantasy.
It's the only thing
I'm good at.
Learn a trade, Rose-Lynn.
Go to college.
- You're not listening!
- Cut hair... I don't care
what you do,
but do something.
I've got my talent,
and I'm gonna use that.
Have you not
been watching telly?
'Cause I'll tell you something:
there's no shortage
of folk who can sing.
By a distinctive whistle...
As they fly home
over the water.
Sake!
- ♪ I beg your pardon ♪
- Here we go!
Step and swivel.
Back and back.
Out, in.
♪ I never promised you
a rose garden ♪
- ♪ Along with the sunshine ♪
- Here's the turn!
Come on, Sandra.
Watch your feet.
Ah, the Lone Ranger
rides into town.
You wanna get me
a wee beer, Jackie?
Come on, Laurie.
You can't afford to chat.
Watch me.
Don't watch your neighbor.
Eyes on me, not your neighbor.
So what have I missed?
Well, was there mice
when you were here before?
Aye.
Well, then there's
nothing new under the sun.
Hear you're on the tag.
Can't fart round here.
Aye, I am,
but I've appealed it,
so a couple of weeks,
I'll be brand-new.
Fridays and Saturdays.
Boom.
Rocking chair!
Fridays and Saturdays,
we've got Mississippi Tundra.
- Who?
- And swivel.
Back and back. Out, in.
Oh, you must be desperate.
Nobody wants to see
a convicted criminal up there.
Folk come here
to get away from all that.
Johnny Cash is a convicted
criminal, you bawbag.
Go on away...
away back to your mousetraps!
I need this job, Jackie.
It's my fucking band!
It's the house band!
You're your own worst enemy,
you.
I wouldnae agree.
There's strong competition.
- What the fuck?
- You stupid fucker!
Jackie!
You nicked my job,
you ratcatcher!
Get off me!
- Get off!
- Get your hands off me!
Get out.
Ten years,
I've been working here.
- What am I supposed to do now?
- You're barred. Get out!
Fucking no-fucking-hopers
clubhouse.
- You're an animal!
- Bunch of cunts.
An animal!
Fuck!
Didn't know you
were on mornings.
How's your lassie?
Ugh. Ask me tomorrow.
He lives in the bottom half,
um, of the house,
and then there's
another house up the stair.
My mate Angie lives there.
And then they bought
the house next door.
So Lauren lives next door,
where wee Doug...
♪ I've been living
on the wrong side of Memphis ♪
♪ Really breaking away
this time ♪
♪ A full tank of gas
and a '69 Tempest ♪
♪ Taking me
to that Nashville sign ♪
♪ No turning back ♪
♪ I've come too far ♪
♪ Headed down 40
with my old guitar ♪
♪ I ain't driving
no pink Cadillac ♪
♪ I've been living
on the wrong side of Memphis ♪
Fuck's sake.
♪ These cowboy boots
are getting kind of restless ♪
♪ They ain't got
a single thing to lose ♪
They've got CCTV,
so anything you do
to that gate,
we can see from in here.
I've not done
anything to the gate.
You were effing
and blinding at the gate.
Shoes off.
No, it's far too much.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
What? He's got a Kindle or...
Yes.
What, will you...
Look, I only sent
the email round
because it feels like we're all
just buying too much plastic.
Aww, that's so sweet.
No, yeah.
That's fine. That's fine.
Come in. Sit down.
Yeah, I've got to go.
I've got somewhere here.
Aww. Okay.
Pleasure.
Speak to you later. Bye.
Hello.
I'm Susannah.
- Hi.
- Thanks for coming.
So, um, where have you been
working before now?
She's been up in Stirling.
Haven't you, Rose-Lynn?
But she's no plans to go back.
Oh, it's beautiful
up there.
Majestic.
Right.
I'm off to spend a penny.
So it's £12 an hour.
£12?
Actually, Mary gets...
£8, right,
but she can afford
to go that low
because she's on
the brew as well.
Brew?
She drinks?
- I don't think Mary dr...
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
The brew is, like, you know,
the dole.
Like, on welfare.
Really?
Whereas, you know, I'll not
be up to anything like that.
It's just not me.
Know what I mean?
Don't embarrass her
by mentioning it.
Oh, you'll be needing
more bleach, Susannah.
I'll give you
the receipt for it.
Okay. Thanks.
Rose-Lynn?
- Oh! Jeez.
- Rose-Lynn?
Sorry.
Um... um, I'm just gonna pop out,
and, uh, I'll be back
in about an hour, okay?
Okay.
Oh, uh... or maybe less.
I...
I don't...
I'm in and out all day,
so I... I don't know
when I'll be back.
Just, uh...
Great.
Right. See you in a bit.
Ah.
♪ Well, you've broken your vow,
and it's over ♪
♪ But someday, baby,
when you've had your play ♪
♪ You're gonna want your mama,
but your mama will say ♪
♪ Keep movin' on ♪
♪ You've been away too long ♪
♪ Well, I'm through with you ♪
♪ It's too bad you're blue ♪
♪ I'm movin' on ♪
Hey!
♪ That big eight-wheeler
rollin' down the track ♪
♪ Means your true-lovin' mama
ain't coming back ♪
♪ I'm movin' on ♪
♪ I'll soon be gone ♪
♪ You were flyin' too high
for my little sky ♪
Oh! Jesus fuck!
You gave me a shock.
Where's your mum?
- Parking the car.
You're like something
out of "The Shining."
What's "The Shining"?
Well, you coming in?
There's a yeasty
smell in here.
Right, what kind
of smell is it?
Yeasty.
What smell?
Well,
I don't know what it is,
but it sure as hell
isn't somebody baking bread.
Okay, bear with me a minute.
She won't touch ham,
and he won't eat
anything else.
And they've both now decided
they don't like yogurt.
Have you got a calendar?
You need a calendar
for putting down their gym days
and their holidays
and if they're needing
to bring something in.
Nine times out of ten,
they won't tell you.
- Yeah.
- So you need to go
through their bags
once a week.
And you need to pay these.
You can do it.
You've got a wage now,
and you can pay
in installments.
Your gas, your water,
and your electricity, and...
there's your TV license
as well.
Okey-smoky.
Well, that's you set up here.
Now, remember, you have to be
in immediate range of that
from 7:00 at night until
7:00 in the morning, okay?
Hello?
- Aye.
- Excuse me?
Aye. Yeah?
Is that your wee boy
out here?
- Hiyah!
- Lyle.
Open up! It's the police!
- Hiyah!
Lyle.
- Hi...
- Get in here!
Right now.
Right. That's me away.
You know where I am
if you need me.
No, no. You're staying here
with your mammy,
but you'll see me every day.
You'll see me every day,
you daftie.
I'm coming home with you.
No, you stay with your mammy.
Now, be a good boy
for your mammy.
Come on.
Take hold of him now.
Keep hold of him.
I want to go with my granny!
No, you're not...
Shh.
No, Lyle.
I don't wanna stay here!
See, on Friday,
will we go out for our dinner?
I remember
what your favorite is.
It's pizza.
I like sausage,
cheese, tomato.
She likes cheese,
tomato, and cheese.
Are you coming with us?
Hmm?
- Right. That's me done.
- Okay.
The kids tell me you're
a country and western singer.
You taking the piss?
No.
Not at all.
Why do you say that?
"Country and western"?
No, it's just country.
I didn't realize.
You must be very good,
because all I've heard all week
is Rose-Lynn, Rose-Lynn,
Rose-Lynn.
Why country?
'Cause it's three chords
and the truth.
Wow.
Yeah. It goes like that.
Just gets
whatever's in there out.
Anyways,
I'll see you next week.
Thanks very much.
Bye!
Bye.
All right. Thanks.
Oh, sorry. After you.
Him? That fucking prick?
Oh.
Shit. I'm sorry, mate. Fuck.
Fuck.
- Watch yourself.
- Sorry, pal.
- Sorry.
- Ah, I don't mind. It's fine.
Ah. I'm all right, Davey.
- That's me.
- No, no, no.
I just fell on the floor.
- Where are you going?
- I've got my curfew.
Never mind the curfew.
Come on. Stay.
Here, take it.
Drink mine.
Stay. Oi!
Fuck!
Hello, Galloway's
the butchers.
What can I get you?
No, I'm playing with you.
I'm playing with you.
I'm only kidding you on.
Aye, yeah.
Rose-Lynn Harlan. I'm here.
All right. Okay. Bye.
What happened to pizza?
You can't promise them
something
and then just disappear.
- You cannae do that.
- I didn't disappear.
I... I was at my work,
waiting on my wages.
Oh, please.
You're not fooling anybody,
Rose-Lynn,
and you cannae fool me.
If you tell them something,
you don't go back on it.
That's basic.
Right. Pizza.
Come on.
You don't like pizza.
Oh, don't you worry
about me, darling.
I'll have something else.
You can get chocolate pizza.
Did you know that?
- Chocolate pizza?
- Aye.
♪ I am an old woman ♪
♪ Named after my mother ♪
♪ My old man is another ♪
♪ Child that's grown old ♪
♪ If dreams were thunder ♪
♪ And lightning was desire ♪
♪ This old house
would have burnt down ♪
♪ A long time ago ♪
♪ Make me an angel ♪
♪ That flies from Montgomery ♪
♪ Make me a poster ♪
♪ The jukebox playing ♪
♪ The tune about ♪
♪ The wild side of life ♪
♪ As I listen to the words ♪
Kitty Wells.
What a trailblazer.
I've been listening
to this stuff
since you left on Friday,
and I can't stop.
It's a revelation.
See you in a bit.
♪ It wasn't God ♪
♪ Who made honky-tonk angels ♪
♪ As you said
in the words of your song ♪
Come in.
Yeah, I... I was, um...
I was just thinking I could
give you some recommendations.
Like, strong women
and all that.
Oh, I'd love that.
I'd love that.
I'd love to hear you sing.
Where do you sing?
Is there, um...
is there a scene?
Oh. No, no.
No, there's fuck all here.
It's actually... I'm...
well, I'm actually trying
to get to Nashville, you know.
Oh.
Yeah, I'm needing to raise
a couple of grand
so I can get flights
and hotel and...
well, I can't drive, so I'm
needing a driver as well.
And it wouldnae be
more than two or three.
Definitely less than five.
Oh.
Rose-Lynn, I... I'm sorry.
I can't just give you money,
if that's what
you're suggesting,
which I'm sure it wasn't.
No, it was.
I can't do that.
How no?
I'm not being funny,
but I just kind of thought
with all the wee smelly candles
burning everywhere
and bottled water
and all that, you know,
you wouldn't miss it.
I'll be old and gray
before I save the money,
whereas you... you could just
drink out of the tap.
Anyway, never mind.
What are you actually doing
while you're waiting,
saving to go?
I've been
the star fucking attraction
at Glasgow's Grand Ole Opry
since I was 14.
- And?
- And what?
And nothing.
Well, haven't you gone in
for one of those...
those TV talent shows?
They're not for folk who can
sing, those programs.
They're for folk
who want to sit in
on a Saturday night
and watch the TV.
Yeah, but isn't it a way
of meeting someone here
who can introduce you
to someone over there?
There's nobody here.
That's why I'm away.
No one in the whole of Britain
knows anything
about country music?
- Except me.
- Except you.
Yeah, and Bob Harris.
Who's that?
Well, he's a DJ
at BBC Radio 2.
Pure legend, man.
Ancient wee guy.
And he knows everything about
country music... all the stars.
They're his pals.
That's great.
That's who you need
to write to.
Aye, yeah.
It's good thinking.
I'll just away
and pop round his house.
No, I can't do this.
- Why not?
- 'Cause I feel like a fanny.
- Okay, you two.
- Go on outside.
- No.
- Yes. Ten minutes.
All we're gonna do
is listen outside the door.
It's... it's fine.
- It's fine. It's cool.
- Sure?
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
♪ Hey, kids,
turn off the TV ♪
♪ No, I don't wanna
watch the evening news ♪
♪ So come on over here ♪
♪ Sit down next to me ♪
♪ And let your mama
look at you ♪
♪ And you and you ♪
♪ Your beautiful faces ♪
♪ That I wanna keep safe as ♪
♪ Long as I can ♪
♪ I'm telling you right now ♪
♪ There's gonna be
peace in this house ♪
♪ There's gonna be peace
in this house ♪
♪ Gonna be some
tender talking ♪
♪ And some sweet
little nothings that ♪
♪ Add up to the somethings ♪
♪ We can't live without ♪
♪ There's gonna be
peace in this house ♪
♪ Some belief
in this house ♪
♪ Every good thing
that ever happens ♪
♪ Happens from
the inside out ♪
♪ I'm telling you now ♪
♪ There's gonna be peace ♪
Goodness.
Amazing.
You have such
an incredible voice.
Wow.
How do you do it?
Do you want to stay for dinner?
Oh, no, no. Thank you.
Thanks.
So where do you stay,
Rose-Lynn?
Priesthill.
Ah, Pollok way?
Aye, yeah.
Sam's from Clydebank.
Clydebank?
How'd you get here
from Clydebank?
Break in through a window?
Learned a trade
from my father,
and then I started up
on my own.
Ah. What trade?
Conservatories?
What, as in
they big glass things
stuck on the side of houses?
- Hmm.
- I'm not being funny,
but who needs
a conservatory in Glasgow?
You'd be surprised.
Aye. I would be.
- What are you looking for?
- iPad.
Did Mum say you can have it?
- No.
Tell you what: let's go
play some football, eh?
Oh, you're getting heavy, boy.
Out of that uniform
and get some socks out.
Do you want kids, Rose-Lynn?
Aye, yeah.
Just not yet.
How was school today?
Is Mrs. Pat still there?
Ah, sh... she hated me, Mrs. Pat.
Is Ms. McDonald
still your favorite?
Ms. McDonald left.
You hungry?
- Mm-hmm.
- Hmm?
I've got something.
"Dear Susannah,
"so wonderful to hear from you
after all this time.
"I passed your email on to Liz.
Remember, Liz used
to piss in the sink."
She... um, oh, she works
on "The Today Programme,"
and she sent the link
to her husband,
who covers sport for Radio 2,
and he forwarded the link
to Bob Harris' producer.
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my fucking God.
- Wait.
"Bob will be very happy
to meet her
"if she fancied coming
down to London
- to watch a live recording."
- What?
Do you know how many times
I've written
to that wee bastard
and how many BBC pens
I got back in return?
How'd you do that?
How'd you even fucking do that?
Sent a few emails.
I can't... I can't believe it.
I'm fucking shaking.
Like, that is just...
- Aww.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Yeah, y...
- That is fucking mental.
Brilliant! Whoo!
Bob Harris?
"Whispering Bob Harris"?
Aye.
♪ BBC Radio 2 ♪
I know. I know.
It's mad.
That'll be some doors
he could open for you.
Is... is it all right
if you babysit?
Oh, of course she will.
How did this come about?
Susannah.
Oh.
Very nice of her to help you.
Can she unlock tags as well?
You served 12 months
for attempting to smuggle
a package of heroin
into Cornton Vale
by throwing it over
the perimeter fence.
I didn't know it was heroin.
But you were reckless as to
what the package contained.
Well, if you mean
I was off my face
and didn't ask what was in it,
then aye.
But I had kids and everything,
and they put me in jail.
It's pure ridiculous.
And that's what
my advocate said at the time.
It's not my fault.
Well, whose fault was it?
Well, it was
the judge's, obviously,
for giving me the sentence.
Your Lordship,
a more contrite young lady,
it would be hard to find.
Miss Harlan has done
a lot of soul-searching.
She has dug deep...
and she's put her childish ways
behind her.
She now works full-time
as a daily woman,
and her children are living
with her once again.
Though Miss Harlan
is no longer in prison,
neither is she free.
Wearing a tag means she
is unable to seek employment
in her own line of work.
You just told me
she's a daily woman.
Yes, but if you
turn the page, sir,
you'll see my client is also
a promising young
country and western singer.
It's just country.
My Lord,
this young lady must be
allowed out in the evenings
if she's to make a new start.
- Yay!
- Yeah!
You are barred.
Ah, you can take that up
with my lawyer,
who'll be having
a whiskey and Coke.
Oi, you.
Oi, you, what did I just say?
She's barred!
"Outlaw State of Mind"!
- Jackie!
- ♪ In no time at all ♪
- Go back to your rat traps.
- What is this?
- Go. Get off.
- What the fuck?
- Sort that out, you.
- This is a joke.
- Off you bop.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
Rose-Lynn Harlan!
- Come on!
- Disgrace.
♪ Cut my teeth ♪
♪ On Daddy's old LGO ♪
♪ And I lost my mind
somewhere in New Mexico ♪
♪ And TW put a snake
on my back ♪
♪ I keep a redbone on my side ♪
♪ And there's people
all across the land ♪
♪ From east Kentucky
down to Alabama ♪
♪ Whole lot like I am
all the time ♪
♪ I'm in an outlaw
state of mind ♪
Come on, Glasgow!
Whoo-hoo!
♪ I got friends who know ♪
♪ How to have a good time ♪
♪ Yeah, they roll their own ♪
♪ Drinking Carolina shine ♪
♪ I've seen the devil ♪
♪ In a dark coal mine ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ I've been higher
than a Georgia pine ♪
♪ And there's people
all across the land ♪
♪ From west Kentucky
down to Rio Grande ♪
♪ Just don't give a damn ♪
♪ All the time ♪
♪ I'm in an outlaw
state of mind ♪
Yeah!
Sorry, sorry.
♪ And there's people
all across the land ♪
♪ From New York
down to old San Fran ♪
♪ Just don't give a damn ♪
♪ All the time ♪
♪ I'm in an outlaw state of ♪
♪ Mind ♪
Whoo!
Oh, here's your ticket.
Oh, thank you very much.
What? First class?
I hope you're not
expecting me
to give you the money
for that.
Ah, gracious as ever.
There you go.
Just in case.
Oh, God.
Thank you!
Fuck. Fucking... this is
fucking me off the blocks.
Right.
I'll see you
when I come back, yeah?
Bye. Bye.
We'd like to welcome
passengers
traveling with us today
from Glasgow Central...
Ah, that's good, isn't it?
You get your breakfast.
In coach E.
We'd like to remind passengers
that in the quiet coach,
all electronic devices
should be on silent mode,
and please make your way
to the vestibule
if you need...
- Oh, you're lovely.
- You're fine.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you.
- Don't you worry about it.
- He sweats around girls.
- Shut up.
- Free toast.
- You can get free tea.
Free bacon rolls.
And nobody's touching it.
- Not bad, eh?
- No, it's all right.
- It's a waste.
- You want one?
Here, I'll get you one, here.
One sec.
♪ Bacon rolls,
bacon rolls, bacon rolls ♪
♪ Bacon rolls, bacon rolls ♪
bacon rolls ♪
- Jump in.
- Go, go.
- See you later. Good luck.
- I'll see you later.
Bye.
You seen my bag?
- Sorry?
- I left my bag here.
I left my bag
and my jacket on the seat.
Um, I think you
took it with you.
No, I didn't take it with me.
I left it here.
It can't just disappear.
Did... did anyone come
and take it?
Shit.
How is it not
your responsibility, right?
'Cause this is all I've
got now... that and these.
Just tell me... tell me,
what is it I'm meant to do?
Okay, as I've said,
the train was thoroughly
checked,
and nothing's been handed in,
so you might be best
talking to the transport police
and getting
a crime reference number.
Are you okay?
Do you need to phone someone?
I'm only trying to help her.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Sorry. Sorry about this.
Hi, I'm looking for the B...
um, I'm looking for the BBC.
Right, well, okay,
you'll need to take the Tube
- down to...
- What?
- Down to...
- No, I don't have any...
Do you know where the BBC is?
Oh, thank fucking God.
Hi. Rose-Lynn Harlan.
- Who are you here to see?
- Bob Harris.
- Have you got any ID?
- No.
No, some bastard stole my bag
on the way here, so no.
All right, I'm gonna
need you to sign in.
What? Is it MI5 here?
Jeez. They give you less hassle
in the police station.
- Are you Rose-Lynn?
- Aye.
Hello. I'm Mark.
I'm Bob's producer.
Oh, jeez, it's so good
to see you, boy.
You got here, then?
Aye, I did.
So the studio's through here,
and round here
is our control room.
And in the control room
is Bob Harris.
You must be Rose-Lynn.
I cannae believe it.
I can't believe it's you. Oh!
Honest to God,
I thought you'd be tiny wee.
Oh, God,
is that where they go,
Miranda Lambert and all that,
all they folk who come in here?
It is, yeah.
And we've got someone fabulous
playing later.
Would you like to have
a look around?
So this is very exciting,
meeting a homegrown
country star from Glasgow.
I mean, it's a great
music city, Glasgow.
All right, look, I'm trying
to get to Nashville, obviously,
but I mean, who's ever heard
of a country singer
from Glasgow?
That's ridiculous.
It cannae be.
Why not?
Well, uh, see, my life...
my life's like being one
of they transsexuals, you know?
When you're born a man
but you're meant
to come out a lassie.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, that is me.
I should've been born
in America.
I... I'm an American.
But here I am.
Do you write?
- Oh, no.
- Can you play?
No.
You know, honestly,
I don't think it matters
whether you're
from Glasgow, Scotland,
or Glasgow, Kentucky.
If you've got a voice
and you've got something
to say...
I watched your link,
and you really do have a voice.
So what do you need to say?
♪ Don't waste your life ♪
♪ Behind that guitar ♪
♪ You may get gone ♪
♪ But you won't get far ♪
♪ You're not the first ♪
♪ And won't be the last ♪
♪ And you can tell us
all about it ♪
♪ When you come crawling back ♪
♪ That road you're on ♪
♪ Just winds and winds ♪
♪ You're spinning
your wheels ♪
♪ And wasting your time ♪
♪ When the lights come up ♪
♪ And I hear the band ♪
♪ And where they said
I'd never be ♪
♪ Is exactly where I am ♪
♪ I hear the crowd ♪
♪ I look around, and I can't
find an empty chair ♪
♪ Not bad for a girl
goin' nowhere ♪
No keys?
Where's your bag
and your jacket?
Susannah just picked me up
from the station just now.
I left it on her back seat.
- Was it good?
- Aye.
What like was it, London?
- Ugh, it was heaving.
- Oh, that's what Mary said.
She's been down a couple
of times to see her nephew.
Said you can't move for people.
Honest to God, wherever
you go, people are like that.
Up your nose, in your mouth,
under your nails.
Och, I couldn't stand that.
What was he like? Bob?
I think he was...
well, he was saying I need
to write my own tunes.
But what
am I gonna write about?
"The bleach ran away
with the broom"?
You don't stick at things.
You know, that's your trouble.
But look at this house.
When you put
your mind to something,
you can do anything.
Do you want a cup of tea?
Och, no.
I'm away to my bed.
I'm up early tomorrow.
But you can ask me
for my dinner.
Lyle's after telling me
how he likes
your mince and tatties
and he doesn't like mine.
I don't have a mince.
My mince is your mince.
Night.
Did I wake you up?
No.
I wanted some water.
What's your book about?
About a girl and her dog.
That sounds
a bit babyish for you.
Key Stage 2.
Boo!
Why are you doing that?
I don't know.
Here, I'll take you
back to bed.
Those are nice.
Who are they for?
This one's for Isla,
and this one's for Shona.
Isla and Shona.
You've got half-term coming up.
Do you know that?
Got a whole week off school.
What'll we do, eh?
We could go away
for a few days.
- To the beach.
- I haven't went to the beach.
Yeah, you have.
You were too young to remember.
We went just before...
just before you moved in
with your granny.
You wanted to pick up
all the shells.
Remember that?
How come we were nae
allowed to see you?
'Cause your granny didn't
want you coming to the jail.
Who's gonna bring you
if she won't, eh?
'Cause of baddies?
Aye. Uh-huh.
You werenae a baddy, though.
You were outlaw.
Who told you that?
You did.
No, I wasn't an outlaw.
I was a fanny.
You said "fanny"!
How was it?
I tried calling you
so many times.
Oh, I know.
I lost my phone.
No.
- Yeah.
- What happened?
- I actually got pinched.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah, out of my bag.
- Oh.
- With my bag.
- Crap.
But it didn't matter.
- It was fucking "A."
- Was it?
Really?
I'm gonna get there.
I am going to fucking
get there.
Course you bloody are.
- Listen.
- Yeah?
I'm gonna be 50
in a minute,
and I was gonna have
this drinks party
for which I've got
really little enthusiasm for.
'Cause over the weekend,
I realized what I really need
is a party party.
A great big fuck-off
house party,
featuring, say, a set
by a young up-and-coming
country singer,
Rose-Lynn Harlan.
What, you want me to play
at your party?
Yeah.
Will you?
Well, aye, yeah,
course I will.
That is brilliant.
That's not the exciting bit.
The exciting bit is,
instead of bringing gifts,
people will contribute
to a... to a cause
that's very close to my heart:
you.
You perform a set.
If people like what they hear...
which they will...
then they invest in you,
in your career.
That's, like, 100 people
spending between £50 and £100.
Voilà.
By the magic of crowd funding,
you are there.
- Where?
- The Isle of Man.
Nashville!
What, you're gonna tax
your pals to come to your house
for an audience
with your daily woman?
- Yeah.
- You've lost the plot, hen.
Oh, do you have a band?
Aye, yeah.
Of course I do.
- When is it?
- Next Sunday.
You've already booked
the week off,
and you can use that time
to rehearse.
Oh, no.
No, I can't do that week.
But it's cool.
I don't need to rehearse.
I've been playing
with these guys since I was 14.
Rose-Lynn, you definitely
need to rehearse.
If you're asking people
for money,
if... if you want people
to buy into the idea
that you're gonna make it
out there,
then you need to put in
a really professional
performance.
Aye, yeah, cool.
Yeah.
Fucking "A."
Brilliant.
Whoo!
Well, I can't fault it.
Mum, uh, Susannah's
needing me in next week.
Well, she cannae have you.
Kids are on holiday.
She can do without you
for a week.
I know it, but...
You said you'd take them away.
Well, it's no, uh...
it's no cleaning.
Um, I'd be doing...
it's rehearsing.
What it is,
I'm doing this gig at her house
and she's invited
all these people,
and I'm gonna perform
with my band.
And then... then
they're gonna invest.
Invest?
Invest in what?
In me.
In my career.
In getting to Nashville.
Oh.
Don't remember her
investing in Mary
when she was in agony
with her hip.
18-month waiting list.
If she'd money to spare,
she could have
- forked out on that.
- She isn't forking it out.
She gave me a chance
to earn it.
But it's got to be good.
No pub band quality.
And we haven't got long
to put it together,
and I phoned the school
to see about holiday club,
but it's all full up.
And even if it wasn't,
I'd rather they were with you,
you know, 'cause I don't want
them thinking that I've just...
What? Thinking what?
You cast them off
when you get a better offer?
Or that all this is for nothing
'cause you've still got
one foot out the door?
I can't help you.
I havenae booked the time off.
You've been there 20 year.
- Special circumstances.
- I've used that enough.
Aye, when I was fucking up.
What's for you
will no go by you.
This is me trying to make
something of myself,
and surely to God
that's a good thing for them.
A good thing for them?
No letting them down
again and again and again,
that would be
a good thing for them.
And I thought
you'd turned a corner.
More fool me.
- Where are we going?
- We're going to the beach.
We're going to go
into the sea
and look at different
jellyfish.
Come on.
That's a good boy.
There we go.
- Oh, in youse come.
- I don't wanna go in there!
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Mary's gonna look after you
for a while this week, okay?
I didnae say a week,
Rose-Lynn.
I said today.
Oh, you're fine.
You're fine.
Come on, Mum'll be back
in a wee while.
♪ Well, I never did crawl ♪
♪ And I never did
toe the line ♪
I know... come on, this is...
it's way too slow.
♪ Well, I never did crawl
and I never did toe the line ♪
♪ No man is master of me ♪
♪ I ain't that kind ♪
♪ I just put on
my traveling shoes ♪
♪ If you wanna win,
you just can't lose the time ♪
Right.
- ♪ Or stay behind ♪
- Yep.
♪ Well, I was born to run ♪
- ♪ To get ahead of the rest ♪
- That's mine.
No, it's not.
You've lost yours.
- You gave it to me last night.
- No, I never.
- Liar.
- Lyle, you're lying.
Mum!
♪ And be someone ♪
♪ I was born to be fast,
I was born to run ♪
- Thanks, Amanda.
- Oh, nae bother, nae bother.
You know me from old,
don't you?
We could play a wee game.
Hotels.
You can be the waiter
and waitress
and I'll be the guest.
See youse later, okay?
I hate you!
♪ Sure, it makes you
feel nervous ♪
♪ But it makes you
feel all right ♪
- I hate you!
- Right, come on. In.
♪ Makes you feel all right ♪
♪ Well, I was born to run ♪
♪ To get ahead of the rest ♪
♪ And all I wanted
was to be the best ♪
♪ Just to feel free ♪
♪ And be someone ♪
♪ I was born to be fast,
I was born to run ♪
♪ I was born to run ♪
Mum, look.
♪ To get ahead of the rest ♪
♪ And all I wanted
was to be the best ♪
♪ Just to feel free ♪
She's amazing.
♪ And be someone ♪
♪ I was born to be fast,
I was born to run ♪
Yeah!
That was much better.
Wow, who else
has this lassie invested in?
Rod Stewart?
Right, now,
it's been a long time,
but I do love a call sheet.
So if you could all be here
from 4:00 tomorrow,
then we'll run
sound check from 4:30,
and after that, we'll go
to the lighting cues.
Big day tomorrow, gents.
This girl has cleaned
her last floor.
Please, leave it.
You don't have to do that.
Oh, no, that's all right.
I'll just...
I'll just pop them inside.
I nicked it from
the tech guys.
Fancy a smoke?
Oh, no, I've...
I've got to go.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Can you roll it?
When I first met Sam,
we lived in this...
shittiest little flat
on Clydeside.
There was nothing there.
Not like it is now.
We had rats
because of the river.
We were broken into
nearly once a week.
But we had these really,
really amazing parties.
Don't really want this.
You have someone?
No, I'm free as a bird.
Lucky you.
You're young.
You're incredibly talented.
You're at the height
of your powers.
There is nothing
you can't do.
This is your time.
Once you got kids,
it's a little bit different.
Yeah.
I'd better go.
Hello!
- Hmm.
- How are you, honey?
I'm fine, thank you.
- I'll drop you home.
- Oh, no, no, you're all...
Yeah, it's fine.
I'll just take the bus.
- No, no, come on.
- No.
- Sleep well.
- Aye, yeah.
See you in the morning.
You homesick, aye?
Mm.
What, is this the one
where you try
and stick it up
the daily woman?
No, no.
This is the one
where I tell you
that I'm onto you.
I know you did the jail.
And I know
what you were in for.
Susannah's bought into
whatever it is you're selling,
and I'm not about to take that
away from her now.
But I don't want you
anywhere near my kids,
so, see, the morrow,
sing your song,
get your money,
then you're gone.
Lyle.
Hurry up.
Haven't got all day.
Rosie.
Where you been, man?
Havenae seen
hide nor hair of you.
All right, wee man?
I'll be in in a minute.
- Do you want a drink?
- No.
- You all right, pal?
- Aye, you know, I'm brand-new.
Looking for something.
- Lyle!
- Mum!
His name's Lyle.
He's five.
He swung on a wardrobe
and then the wardrobe
fell on him.
I think it's just his arms
that he's hurt
but maybe his head as well.
Okay, Lyle, do you mind
if I have a wee look?
Ow!
- All right.
- It's okay.
She's gonna have a wee look,
okay?
- Any allergies?
- No, I don't... I don't...
- I don't think so, no.
- Fabric plasters.
Okay, um, we'll need
to X-ray him.
It's one of those nights
in here tonight,
so it might be a while
until a doctor sees youse.
- Okay?
- I want my granny.
Please, I want my granny.
- Please.
- It's okay. It's okay.
I want my granny.
My next pill?
Water?
Thanks.
- Are you Lyle's mum?
- Aye, yeah.
- Dr. Yousaf.
- Hi.
- I'm sorry about the wait.
- No.
The X-ray looks
fairly straightforward,
but he'll need a cast.
When can we go home?
We can't get the cast on
until the swelling's come down,
so we are looking
at a couple more hours.
I'm sorry it's been
such a long night.
Fucking hell.
- Where is he?
- He's still asleep.
Right, I'll take
this one home,
and you can stay here
with the wee fella.
No.
What's for you
will no go by you.
Maybe 20 year in the baker's
is enough for you,
but it's not enough for me.
Away and get me a wee cup
of tea, darling.
What's the matter with you?
I just... I just need you
to help... help me.
Help you?
Help you do what?
Leave him here
while you go to a party?
Is that the plan?
I don't know what this
awffy-toffee woman
thinks you are,
but she wouldn't give you
a brass farthing
if she knew the truth.
You haven't even told her,
have you?
She doesn't even have a clue
that you've got kids.
If you're no even prepared
to acknowledge their existence,
there's no hope for you.
And there's sure as hell
none for them.
Go.
Go to Nashville.
Do whatever it is
you want to do.
Come on, darling.
Let's go see your wee brother.
- Have you been to sleep?
- No.
- Not at all?
♪ Well, I only came
into this bar ♪
♪ To hear a sad song ♪
♪ But I'll probably be here
all night long ♪
♪ The way I'm feeling now ♪
♪ I couldn't get you
on the phone ♪
♪ So I let it ring ♪
♪ On and on ♪
♪ In a lonesome serenade ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ What am I gonna do
about my problems now? ♪
♪ Maybe I should try
to find a way ♪
♪ To kinda sorta maybe
work it out ♪
Rose-Lynn!
Where have you been?
Jesus Christ.
I thought you were a no-show.
The band have had
to talk me off a ledge.
You look tired.
You all right?
Aye, yeah, aye.
Yeah, I'm brand-new.
- I'm great.
- Oh, good, good, good.
Come on, let's go.
You gave me such a fright.
♪ And a double barrel
whiskey ♪
Okay, um, so...
not long ago,
a spark of light
flew in through my door
and reminded me
of why I fell in love with
Glasgow in the first place.
The girl, like the city,
is gallus...
She's funny,
and above all else,
she's completely fearless.
And with your help,
she's going to Nashville
to do what she was put
on this Earth to do.
I'm so proud to know her
and call her my friend.
Ladies and gentlemen,
put your hands together
for Rose-Lynn Harlan!
Okay, let's go.
So... s-sorry,
can you just give me...
give me... give me five?
Rose-Lynn.
Hey.
Hey!
Rose-Lynn.
Please, what's going on?
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
What's happened?
Oh, darling.
Come on.
I don't know what... what you
see when you look at me,
but it isnae me.
What are you talking about?
I'm not at the height
of my powers.
I'm not free,
and there's so, so much
I can't undo.
I can't undo
going to the jail.
I can't undo chucking in heroin
to all they lassies in there
already fucked for drugs.
And do you know what else
I cannae undo?
Having two kids.
Two beautiful children
before I was 18.
Wynonna, she's eight.
And Lyle, he's five.
And I...
I got 12 months in the jail
and I... I left behind two kids.
Yep.
That's the truth.
Not this.
That.
Them.
Everything I made you
think I am,
I'm not.
Sorry, I'm just...
Come on.
I see an island over there.
Island?
- Is that a clam?
- Do you think you can open it?
Miss Harlan?
What I'm gonna do, um,
and that... I mean,
I... I... I'll be happy
just mucking in.
I've got...
- Bye.
- Okay.
♪ Happy birthday
to you ♪
- Hooray!
- Yay!
Did you make a wish?
You can have mine.
Right, who's having
the first slice, eh?
- Me.
- Yeah?
Good.
It's only me.
Aye.
Aye?
Have you got a wee minute?
Aye, yeah.
You already gave me something.
What's this for?
Why are you giving me this?
I wanted you to take
responsibility.
But I never meant
to take away your hope.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Maybe there is more to life.
Maybe there... there isn't.
I don't know.
I've never been farther
than Dunoon.
But you need to away and see.
No.
I can't start
all that up again.
It's finished.
I always said
I'd go to college,
if I hadnae had to go
out to work at 15.
And I would have.
I wanted to be a pharmacist.
The thing is...
What was stopping me,
you know?
Even after I had you,
I could have gone.
But I think it was just easier
for me to...
to want things for you
than to go after them
for myself.
I hadn't the gumption.
That's the truth.
But you...
you do.
I'll look after the kids.
You go.
You see what's waiting for you.
Where'd you get
all this money from?
Amazing what you can do,
20 year in the baker's.
♪ Don't be afraid
to graze your knees ♪
♪ Jump over the fences,
climb up trees ♪
♪ Folk, they will say
♪ Don't fly too high ♪
♪ But put on those wings
and reach for the sky ♪
♪ And it's all right
to be all wrong ♪
♪ You've got to be weak
if you wanna be strong ♪
♪ So dance your own dance,
sing your own song ♪
♪ And live the life
you dreamed of ♪
♪ Till the dreamer is gone ♪
Right.
There you go.
Thanks very much.
Yep, all right.
Have a great stay.
Thank you.
How long you in town?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know, I just...
well, it depends what happens,
you know, so...
Well, I wish you what I wish
all y'all who come here:
may all your heartbreaks
be songs
- and all your songs be hits.
- Thanks.
Third door on the left.
Whoo!
♪ Roll it and tipped in
box upon box ♪
♪ Well, it's five o'clock
freedom ♪
♪ And the whistle would blow ♪
♪ Gates would burst open,
the river would flow ♪
♪ Lit up like matches
to the dance halls ♪
♪ It's high time ♪
- Sorry. Excuse me.
- ♪ Been missing my roots ♪
Ma'am.
♪ I'm getting rid
of the flash ♪
♪ Nobody needs
a thousand-dollar suit ♪
♪ Just to take out the trash ♪
♪ Ain't gotta be alone ♪
How do you get to sing?
You gotta go through
our booker.
There's a wait list.
It's all on the website.
But what if I'm only here
for a while?
I mean, there's people here
from all over.
From Australia,
New Zealand, Germany.
We're all trying
to do the same thing.
You know, it's Nashville.
It's a company town.
So eventually you're gonna meet
someone who knows somebody
who works someplace
who can help you out.
- Can I get you something?
- No, no, I'm fine. Fine.
♪ Fine time ♪
♪ To let it all go,
I've been too low ♪
♪ So it's high time ♪
Welcome to the Ryman,
the mother church
of country music.
This is the exact spot
where bluegrass was born
and where Johnny Cash
met June Carter.
Now, it was right here
that country music
found an audience
beyond its own back porch
and countless careers took off.
Now, when the Grand Ole Opry
put down roots here in 1943,
the live radio and TV show
brought the likes
of Elvis Presley,
Hank Williams,
Johnny Cash,
Marty Robbins,
Minnie Pearl,
Patsy Cline,
and Roy Acuff to the stage
and into living rooms
all around America.
Now...
♪ When I reach ♪
♪ The place I'm goin' ♪
♪ I will surely know my way ♪
♪ And I will turn ♪
♪ And look inside me ♪
♪ And bid farewell ♪
♪ To one more day ♪
♪ I will fly ♪
♪ Beyond this valley ♪
♪ I will open up ♪
♪ The gates ♪
♪ And when I reach ♪
♪ The place I'm goin' ♪
♪ I will surely ♪
♪ Know my way ♪
♪ I was born ♪
♪ Without a whisper ♪
♪ Beneath the rain ♪
♪ And when I reach ♪
♪ The place I'm going ♪
♪ I will surely ♪
♪ Know my way ♪
You would not believe
how many people do that.
On a tour,
give ole Wyatt the slip,
get up there and sing
a whole damn song.
Aye, I thought that
wee Disney prick
was gonna call the polis.
I have no idea
what you just said.
But, look, I'm getting drinks
a week from Saturday
with my buddy Laurel.
She's some kind of deal
out there at Curb Records.
So if you wanted to meet her,
you could come
by the restaurant.
No.
No, thanks, but... I'm away.
♪ And when I reach
the place I'm goin' ♪
♪ I will surely know my way ♪
- Quitting already?
- No.
No, I'm just kicking off.
To the airport, please.
♪ We have hands
to hold our sorrow ♪
♪ We have tears
to heal the pain ♪
♪ And though your eyes
ask many questions ♪
♪ On your lips,
I hear my name ♪
♪ I was born
without a whisper ♪
beneath the rain ♪
♪ But when I reach
the place I'm goin' ♪
♪ I will surely know my way ♪
♪ I will surely ♪
♪ Know my way ♪
Mum!
Oh.
Oh, God, look at you.
Eh?
Look at you.
- Mum, you're back!
- I'm back!
I'm back!
Did you miss me?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
How much?
10 million?
Yeah.
Have youse been looking
after your granny for me?
Uh, as you can hear,
I'm not from Nashville.
I'm from right here
in Glasgow!
Whoo!
Uh, well this is, uh,
a tune that I wrote.
Um...
You'll be lucky if you get
three chords out of me,
honest to God.
Anyway, I'll give it a go.
♪ I've worn out the stones ♪
♪ In front of your doorstep ♪
♪ Coming and going,
coming and going ♪
♪ You left the lights on ♪
♪ I always knew that ♪
♪ I should have
said thank you ♪
♪ A thousand miles ago ♪
♪ But I pushed you away ♪
♪ Put a pin in a map ♪
♪ Then I got lost
in the storm ♪
♪ Had to find my own way ♪
♪ Make my own mistakes ♪
♪ But you know
that I had to go ♪
♪ Ain't no yellow brick road ♪
♪ Running through Glasgow ♪
♪ But I found one
that's stronger than stone ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
♪ Ain't no place ♪
♪ Like home ♪
♪ Moon hanging low ♪
♪ Over my window ♪
♪ Shoebox of dreams ♪
♪ Hid under my bed ♪
♪ Follow the bright lights ♪
♪ City of gold ♪
♪ I had to leave to realize ♪
♪ All I needed was here ♪
♪ Mama, we both know
that there's nothing ♪
♪ That a little time
and Patsy Cline wouldn't fix ♪
♪ Had to find my own way ♪
♪ Make my own mistakes ♪
♪ But you know
that I had to go ♪
♪ Ain't no yellow brick road ♪
♪ Running through Glasgow ♪
♪ But I found one
that's stronger than stone ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
♪ Ain't no place ♪
♪ Like home ♪
♪ I'll just click my heels ♪
♪ Three more times ♪
♪ There it all is ♪
♪ What's always been mine ♪
♪ Ain't no yellow brick road ♪
♪ Running through Glasgow ♪
♪ But I found one
that's stronger than stone ♪
♪ Ain't no place ♪
♪ Like home ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
♪ Ain't no place ♪
♪ Like home ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
Whoo!
♪ He wore a Texas tuxedo ♪
♪ She wore Cadillac green ♪
♪ They went together like
a match and gasoline ♪
♪ Big Davey Cameron
from the abattoir ♪
♪ And Annie O'Malley
works the Laurieston Bar ♪
♪ 4,000 miles east
of Tennessee ♪
♪ Paisley Road West
is the place to be ♪
♪ He was the king
of the cowboys ♪
♪ Stealing the night ♪
♪ She was the queen
of Memphis ♪
♪ Robbing the bank of life ♪
♪ Whoa, robbing
the bank of life ♪
♪ Two shots of whisky
and an Irn-Bru ♪
♪ Hands up ♪
♪ No one move ♪
♪ King of the cowboys ♪
♪ Stealing the night ♪
♪ Queen of Memphis ♪
♪ Robbing the bank of life ♪
♪ King of the cowboys ♪
♪ Stealing the night ♪
♪ Queen of Memphis ♪
♪ Robbing the bank of life ♪
♪ Robbing the bank
of life ♪
♪ Mm-mm, mm ♪
♪ Wear this, don't wear that ♪
♪ Don't step out of place ♪
♪ Just smile,
don't say too much ♪
♪ Put that makeup
on your face ♪
♪ Just keep pretending
you're having a good time ♪
♪ 'Cause that's
the price of fame ♪
♪ And you're standing
in the line ♪
♪ That's the view from here ♪
♪ That's the view
from here ♪
♪ It's like
champagne and tears ♪
♪ When all you want's a beer ♪
♪ Keep your loved ones near ♪
♪ Oh, keep
your loved ones near ♪
♪ 'Cause famous folk
are weird ♪
♪ That's the view from here ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Mm-mm, mm ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ That's the view from here ♪
♪ Oh, that's the view
from here ♪
♪ It's like
champagne and tears ♪
♪ When all you want's a beer ♪
♪ Keep your loved ones near ♪
♪ Oh, keep
your loved ones near ♪
♪ 'Cause famous folk
are weird ♪
♪ That's the view ♪
♪ From here ♪