But we have to get rid of him.
I have never loved anyone
save for the child
that died inside me before it was born.
Since then, I know
that life is like a wave
on which you drift
always being careful not to drown,
only to die in the end after all.
And that my only protection is within me.
Every attempt
to find something on the outside,
or have expectations of someone
has ended in the pain of realization.
With the realization
that people love only their own reflections.
Blood red stains on towels,
oceans of clouds and light bulbs
surround me here.
I prefer to surrender
responsibility for my life
to Magdalena,
because she loves pain.
And the beauty of her face
is the beauty of pain.
For the last five years,
ever since I've been here,
I no longer have any memories.
My life has only begun again
since I came here.
You stand there and daydream;
you wear your children's clothes
that no longer fit,
and seek comfort
with animals that do not understand you.
Four years ago, when you came to us,
I told you
that you should burn everything
that reminds you of your past.
Take the dress off.
Help Christina wash her hair,
and do your chores like you do every day.
That is the reason you are here.
Ila, come back this instant!
I greet you, North Star.
I greet you, cry of distant jackal.
I greet you, loneliness of ours.
Oh, my companions,
preserve the purity of your hands
that deny lascivious temptation.
You possess the purity of those
who spill the blood of others.
The blood of the people we have killed
is our protection.
You will never be afraid again.
I am the force that led you here.
I am helping you.
I love you more than I love myself.
For you, I believe in the power of the police
who do not see what we do.
I close your eyes so you do not see
the mountains and ocean that surround you.
I close your ears.
You do not hear the howling of dogs,
or the song of birds.
We live here.
We will always live here.
I take away your fear and your hope.
I do not want you to know
where you are and what you are.
I want you to consider your actions.
I am the fulfillment.
I am the force through which we live.
She is the force through which we live.
I love you more than I love myself.
She loves us more than she loves herself.
I am the force through which we breathe.
She is the force through which we breathe.
The water!
Ila, could you please bring me my water
so I may wash my face?
I cannot use
the stagnant water from yesterday.
I'm sick of doing
what everyone asks of me!
You stand up there giving me orders,
but you're closer to the well than I am!
In other words,
get your water yourself!
You must fetch the water,
or I can't bear you between us any longer.
You must take care of me,
that is your duty.
You listen to your music all the time.
I have to clean and cook!
Concerns about your beauty
have nothing to do with me.
If I were to go,
you'd have no one to look after you.
Don't you forget that!
You'd be lost with Magdalena,
who you must also obey!
Fetch me the water!
I want my water!
I want the water up here in my room.
I heard you throw the bucket.
Now you must
fetch me the water I need again.
Please. This instant.
- No!
It was only an accident.
I'll be more careful.
I'll fetch water.
I'll go now. Please don't be cross.
What are you mumbling?
You should not speak.
You should fetch me the water that I need.
- Magdalena just arrived.
Christina, go to your room!
You should be ready by now!
Have you forgotten
what you also swore to me?
Go, and do not come down
until you are your usual self.
But I fetched water for the last time today.
Make breakfast right away, Ila.
Yes.
Where is my coffee?
I would also like coffee.
Come, Christina.
You can have some of mine.
I am going to tell you things now
that I have never told anyone before.
I have never loved anyone save for the child
that died inside me before it was born.
Since then I know
that life is like a wave
on which you drift,
always being careful not to drown,
only to die in the end after all.
I know that
my only protection is within me.
Every attempt
to find something on the outside,
or have expectations of someone,
has ended in the pain of realization.
With the pain of the realization
that people love
only their own reflections.
Blood red stains on towels,
oceans of clouds and light bulbs
surround me here.
I prefer to surrender
responsibility for my life
to Magdalena
because she loves pain.
And the beauty of her face
is the beauty of pain.
For the last five years,
since my parents died in the fire,
I no longer have any memories.
My life has only begun again
since I came here.
The radio is off.
Wouldn't you like to go to bed?
Ila, make some coffee for this stranger.
What stranger?
Coffee? What stranger?
Don't talk. Do as I say.
The starry heavens above me
and the moral law within me
are enough for me.
Throw the money away.
We live our own autonomous life.
We do not need the money.
Look at me.
You must follow me,
not reach out and grasp at nothing.
And when you are dead,
I will be the one to care for you,
to carry your bodies to their graves.
And the one who decided
what you do and do not have to fear.
Throw everything away
and remain yourselves, what you are.
What do you think
we're here for, anyway?
We must get rid of this young man.
He should stay here.
I love him!
I want him to stay here!
He should stay here!
I heard something outside.
Shouldn't we go see what it was?
Yes, of course.
Ila, come back this instant!
And when you are dead,
I will be the one to care for you,
to carry your bodies to their graves.
And the one who decided
what you do and do not have to fear.
Throw everything away
and remain yourselves, what you are.
But I just wanted... Forgive me!
But I just wanted to...
But I just wanted...
Magdalena, you're already awake?