Listen to this, Hank.
UGlobal Food Company triumphed
again in court last week
in its latest case
against a small farmer
accused of failing to pay
royalty on crops grown
using UGlobal's patented seeds.
Buck Thompson,
a local Hoxton farmer,
lost his lengthy legal
battle with UGlobal Foods
over his use of UGlobal's
patented soybean seeds.
Thompson was sued by the
giant agricultural company
for failure to pay royalties
on his crops grown
with the seeds.
UGlobal Food cannot
disprove Thompson's defense
that he had never bought any
of the agricultural
giant's seeds.
And the company had
no proof that he had.
But laboratory tests confirmed
that a portion of his crops
came from the seeds,
leaving the judge no choice
but to issue a directed verdict
against the long-time
Hoxton farmer.
And what's next?
I have to serve him
his eviction papers.
Easier from a friend, I hope.
When's it going to be?
A couple
of weeks, I guess.
Hell.
What's the world coming to?
I'll see ya.
Daddy bear?
Here's my Daddy bear.
I love you.
I love you
too, Maisie May.
Daddy bear,
there's a man
on the phone who wants
to talk to you.
Okay, sweetie, thank you.
That was Hank.
They're coming this afternoon
with the eviction
papers, at two.
But... Maisie's party
is this afternoon.
I know it is.
Look, I'll deal with it
and send them on their way.
She'll never know.
Hello.
Hello, sweetheart.
Hello, honey, happy birthday.
We brought
you a surprise.
Happy birthday.
- Louise.
- Thank you.
It's beautiful.
But you can't give
Maisie something so elegant.
She's just a little girl.
-Yes, she should.
-And I have, so there.
Gil bought it for me when
we found out we couldn't.
Yeah.
Anyway, it's yours.
Thank you.
- We love you.
- We love you too.
Go play.
Come on.
Look at that.
Itchy, can you give up that ball
long enough to have
some cake?
Hell, they're right on time.
Just take it easy. Don't
let 'em get you stirred up.
Maisie,
you have a haul.
Look at this.
He's got that fat
lawyer with him.
I... had it you wanted to send
one of the younger guys.
They ain't known you
your whole life like I have.
It didn't seem right.
I--God, Buck.
I hate that this
turned out like this.
I appreciate
your calling first.
Right in the middle of
a little girl's birthday.
'Cause of you?
You make me sick.
All of you make me sick.
Big company assholes.
It's hot.
Thompson, you had
a chance to settle.
And you didn't.
You no longer make
decisions about this land.
This now belongs to UGlobal.
We make the decisions now.
I make 'em.
You got two weeks
to be off this land.
I come back and
find a single trace.
He knows what the
court order says.
Get back in the vehicle.
Now, Mr. Gandy.
It's okay.
Happy birthday, little girl.
I bet this is one
you'll never forget.
Hey.
What did you say?
I said, "Happy--"
Somebody get a doctor.
Get off of me.
Kinsey to County.
Ambulance, Thompson place.
You listen to me, farmer boy.
Farmer boy!
Your suffering
hasn't even begun.
Hasn't even begun!
Inbound
with adult male.  Catastrophic injury to left eye,
occipital ridge, cheek bone.
Patient going into shock.
ETA 20 minutes.
Good afternoon,
and you're listening
to KDZZ AM Hoxton.
♪ Vámonos ♪
Hottie.
Oldie.
Okay, Maisie.
Yet one more reason we need
to get out of this town ASAFP.
♪ Save me from this prison ♪
♪ Lord help me get away ♪
♪ 'Cause only you
Can save me now ♪
♪ From this misery ♪
♪ I've been lost
In my own place ♪
♪ And I'm getting weary ♪
♪ How far is heaven ♪
♪ And I know that
I need to change ♪
♪ My ways of living ♪
♪ How far is heaven ♪
God, I cannot wait
to get to college.
No curfew, no rules.
No Mom and Dad
waiting up for me.
Sorry.
Maisie... you know you're
like a sister to me.
-I mean--
-Kat, slow down.
My parents are
like your parents.
Yes. Again, as always.
♪ I just keep on
Praying the Lord ♪
♪ And just keep on living ♪
♪ How far is heaven ♪
♪ Yeah, Lord, gotta tell me ♪
♪ 'Cause I just gotta
Know how far, yeah ♪
Maisie, does this not
qualify as self-torture?
We do this every Friday.
Every Friday.
I mean, my God.
I gotta stop doing this.
But I can't.
And I repeat.
One more reason to
get out of here ASAFP.
Let's go.
Hey, Daddy.
Kat, you got some
college stuff right there.
-Hi.
-Maisie.
How's my sweet Maisie?
So, what's the big plan tonight?
The usual.
Huge band downtown.
Then lots of hot new
guys who just moved here
with their rich parents
are going to be coming over
to stare at us and try to get us
to go driving around in
their new fancy foreign cars.
We may come home.
We may not.
Yeah. That is how we work.
So nothing.
No.
You know, I hate the
weekends when there's no game.
It makes for a long, long week.
There's nothing to
look forward to.
It's just--
I know.
So little hope.
- Yeah.
- So little reason to soldier on.
Have you ever
considered accepting
Jesus Christ as your
personal Lord and Savior?
You know,
I think I'd rather
create massive
uncountable wealth
by making really awesome
blue crystal meth,
killing all who get in my way,
and letting to money pile
so high that I can buy...
Well, whatever it is you buy
when you have a ton of money.
Who's with me?
You know who I am.
Say my name.
You're Heisenberg.
You're damn right.
I'm the cook.
Mom, how long is he going to
keep talking like Walter White?
Until Downton
Abbey picks up.
Then he'll become Mr. Carson.
That's a vehicle.
Yeah, that's a vehicle.
Damn.
Yes.
Yeah.
Let us pray.
Clint, I wish I hadn't
known you all my life.
What?
Then I'd let you
get at me a little
on the back of that monster.
Except it'd be like incest.
Well, a lot of people
who've known each other
-their whole lives--
-Nah, don't even go there.
You're like a brother to me.
It really creeps me out.
Man, what a truck.
Yeah.
-Friends.
-For life.
-In fun.
-And strife.
Six pals in Hoxton.
Livin' the life.
And...
♪ Hoxton how we're
Small and slow ♪
♪ So drink the beer while
The beer's still cold ♪
The important thing is, is
that a little while longer
and we are all
getting out of here.
-Yeah.
-Woo.
Amen.
Cheers.
Hello.
I'm staying.
What?
I'm not
going to college.
What?
I know I'm in automatically
'cause of my grades.
But I'm not going.
I'm staying right
here in Hoxton.
Maisie, that's
not going to happen.
You're leaving with
the rest of us.
Nobody stays here, nobody.
Maisie, come on, you of all
people know that you're just--
All right, listen, Jesse,
you are a quarter Mexican
and three quarters Neanderthal.
So going off and
doing the Marines,
that's going to be
perfect for you.
Itchy, you are 100%
full-blooded Neanderthal,
have been since we were kids.
So you're going to end up being
a big college football star
and then make a ton
of money in the pros.
Lawton, you're going
to go to Princeton
and do whatever
smart people stuff
it is that people
at Princeton do.
And Clint, you're set 'cause
you got all that money
your dad gets
from the government
for not growing anything.
And Kat, you're going
to college and become
this Theta Omega Googa and
marry the hottest guy on campus,
have three perfect kids, okay?
And then there's me, you know?
My mom is an alcoholic who
can barely dress herself.
My brother is a mute,
walks around
in a robot costume
made out of boxes.
And for the win,
my dad's in prison.
I've got it all going on.
Look, I know I don't
have much left here,
except for you five.
And y'all are leaving.
And I know I should
get on with it.
But... I can't stand
the thought of leaving.
Too many people
been too good to me.
Miss Katherine.
Pretty Maisie.
Clint, Jesse, Lawton, Itchy.
One of you fellas hand me
a cold beer, would you?
Yeah, we got
plenty, Mr. Denton.
Yeah, I can see you do.
Dang, that was good.
I was really
thirsty.
Well, I owe ya.
I suppose you'll
all be here again
tomorrow night, as always.
-Yes, sir.
-Yep.
Idle hands are the
devil's workshop,
and all that business.
No game tonight.
God, I hate it when
there's no game.
See y'all.
All right, now can
someone please explain to me
why I'm only three
quarters Neanderthal.
And what the hell makes
Itchy here a whole one?
All right, that's bullshit, man.
That's bullshit, I don't really
appreciate that, I don't.
All right, you
need to calm down.
- My God.
- What is wrong with you?
I still remember how
many flowers there were
at Mrs. Denton's funeral,
and how worried my Dad was
that his eulogy wasn't
going to be good enough.
I remember as we were leaving,
Mr. Denton reached over
and touched the edge of
her coffin so gently,
like he was touching her.
I was so sad.
I can't believe one of the
widows hasn't grabbed him yet.
It's been three months.
Mom says they usually
wait a week out of respect
and then they pour it on
with the casseroles
and chicken spaghetti.
He's got all that money too.
What difference does it make
if you've got any
money in this town?
I mean, what are you
going to spend it on?
You don't need much to
live like a king here.
You got to stop
talking like that.
You're going to screw
me up in the head.
I'll wind up marrying someone
who wants to go
camping or something.
Your brother?
Same as always,
in his own world.
Your mom?
You know how she is.
Why even ask?
You give them both my love.
I always do.
I haven't told Buckie
you're getting out in April.
He doesn't respond too much
in general these days.
And if he does, he doesn't
talk to me about it,
or anyone else as far as I know.
You keep an eye on
him for me, Maisie.
How are your friends?
Same.
Clint got a new truck.
Duh.
And Mr. Denton joined us
while we were drinking beer
on Main Street last night.
He seems real lonely.
I guess he is.
It hasn't been that long.
He's going to help
me when I get out.
What?
I got a letter from him
earlier this week.
What'd it say?
Classic Gil Denton.
"Buck, I want you to take over
my operation when you get out."
Dad, my God, my God.
Are you serious?
My God, this is
the best news ever.
I'm going to start
looking for a house.
I'm going to start looking.
And it's going to be
just like it was--
No, no, no, no, no, Maisie.
Nothing is ever going to
be like it was before.
Nothing is ever even going to
be like how we remember it.
You're going off to college
and getting a new start.
And you have to go.
I won't be able to
do much but work
and try to get some
money saved up.
I want to take care of your mom.
And we need to get
little Buckie some help.
Maybe it'll work out
and maybe it won't.
But I'll be an ex-con.
And you need to get a new start
in a fresh place... where
you're not my daughter.
Dad, you are Buck Thompson.
You hammered a
UGlobal Food lawyer.
You're like our King Carter.
Except you did it and he didn't.
But anyway, you
know what I mean.
The point is, you're
like a cult hero.
You know, you should
have your own website.
I bet if you were on
Facebook you'd get
like a jillion likes,
and you'd rule Instagram.
Hey, Maisie.
Buck, time's almost up.
You're my hero, Dad.
You're
my precious angel.
I love you, Daddy bear.
And I love you, Maisie May.
♪ Daddy, you're a lone ♪
♪ Ranger ♪
♪ Mama, there's a home ♪
♪ In my heart ♪
♪ Daddy, you're a lone ♪
♪ Ranger ♪
♪ Mama, there's a home ♪
♪ In my heart ♪
♪ I tried to be tough ♪
♪ Without revealing ♪
♪ But I've cried just enough ♪
♪ To know the feeling ♪
♪ Daddy, I'm a lone... ♪
Maisie, come over here.
I want you to see this.
I'm sitting in my
yard swaying out here
in the tiny town of
Hoxton, and I'm reading
this morning's edition of the  New York Timeson this device
that I have no idea how
in the world it works.
And then I'm going to
read a British newspaper
and it's going to hone my
worldly and polished ways.
And then I'll go to sports.
And after that, I'm going
to follow the weather
all across this
great land of ours.
All on this little device.
How can that be possible,
this little gizmo holding
all that information?
Of course, I don't even
understand how a radio works.
And air conditioning puzzles me
if I kind of let my mind
wander a little bit.
Television, I got
no idea about that.
Magnets.
The list goes on,
and on, and on.
And then this thing.
You have no idea what this world
was like when I was your age.
We used to talk to each
other face to face.
We'd write letters on
paper with ink pens.
We did our own cooking.
We would...
We only had two kinds of gasoline.
We had regular and
ethyl, that was it.
And then in the evening
we would sit on the porch
and visit with our neighbors.
Did you have to hit Mrs.
Denton over the head with a club
and drag her into the house too?
On occasion.
Have you seen your
mama this week?
Yes, sir.
How's your
daddy doing today?
Finally, thank God.
He's good.
He told me what you're going
to do for him when he gets out.
You can't believe anything
that they say in prison.
You know those criminals are
always just after attention.
Mr. Denton, I--
You don't know what this means.
You don't-- It means
he's going to be okay.
It means I'm going to be okay.
It means we're going to
be all right, and I--
Ssh, ssh, ssh, ssh, ssh, ssh.
Okay.
You know--
Your daddy... destroyed
a UGlobal lawyer with one blow.
He hit him and he took him out.
Now, with what these
big corporations
are trying to do to us
now, to have one man
have the courage to stand
up to the representative
of one of those things
and take him out...
I mean, that restores
my faith in human nature.
It strengthened my faith in God.
And I cannot imagine
a person that I'd rather
have running my
operation than your dad.
That's the truth.
We'll be on Main Street tonight.
There'll be lots of cold beer.
I hope I see you there.
I'll be there.
And cookies, I
brought you cookies.
Well, I wouldn't ignore them.
That'd be my supper.
Mr. Denton...
All the guys want
to grow up to be just like you.
Well I can't think of a better
aspiration for a young fella.
I hope he can hold it together
to become a tired old man.
I don't blame 'em,
I really don't.
Hey, Lawton, what's up?
Hey. Is Kat up yet?
Please.
Kat, get up, Lawton's here!
Mom wants to interview
us for the paper.
She wants to talk
about how the six of us
have been best friends
since we were kids
and some of the cool
things we've done so far.
Like Mr. Hoxton High,
National Merit Scholar,
Division One
football scholarship,
and you know, Marine.
As well as the two
head cheerleaders
that are class president
and class favorite.
So it's like, mainly
about me and Maisie, right?
It's mainly about
the six of us.
Whatever.
She wants to talk
about how you've dealt
with your dad being in prison,
if that's okay to talk about.
What?
You want to let everybody
know my dad's in prison?
Wait till this gets out.
I'll be ruined.
She, look, she can leave
it out if you want her to.
She just wanted me to ask.
You know, she thought
she ought to talk about
how you've been
able to do so much
despite that, and all that.
It's okay, I know.
Did anyone ever tell you
you're like, super serious?
Ninth grade's when I guess
I got pretty good at football.
But I just figured I was
quicker and that's all.
Then my sophomore year
when all the scouts
started watching me
my parents said that,
you know, maybe
they knew something.
And now that I'm going
off to college to play,
I guess I'll find out
if I'm the stud horse
they keep telling me I am.
Wouldn't
that be something
if one day you play
professional football?
I hope I do.
I'd like to be the
first guy from Hoxton
to make it in the pros.
- I
- bet a lot of people
would come to the
Mexican restaurant
and the bowling alley just
to say they'd been there.
I bet every family in
the area would want
to be buried by your
family's funeral home.
Well, I'd like to
think that we wouldn't
have to keep all three of those.
I'd like to be able
to help my parents
so they wouldn't
have to work so much.
I hope you
don't close the restaurant.
I love that guacamole.
And better not
close that bowling alley.
I ain't driving
to Maston to bowl.
I guess the main
thing is I'll always be
a Hoxton boy in my heart,
even if I live somewhere else.
You'd have
to live someplace else
if you play
professional football.
Yeah, I know that.
I might even wind
up having to stay
somewhere afterwards for a
while, like lots of guys do.
But I guess if I had
my dreams come true
I'd do well in college, get
drafted, play in the pros,
then come back here
and coach our team.
That'd be cool.
And Coach would
probably be about
ready to retire by that time.
It'd sure be
nice to have somebody
over there coaching
that would listen to me.
Tommy, we're
up here on the porch.
Montecristo No. 4s,
from the motherland.
Look at this.
Tobacco contraband.
I hope we don't all wind
up in the penitentiary.
Oo-ee.
Tommy... Gil has cancer.
It's a rare form of bone
cancer, but it's serious.
Doctors in Houston diagnosed it,
and... I'm going to do
what I can for the pain.
But if we don't catch a
break, he's got about a year.
You're the only other person
that knows about this, okay?
Okay.
Tommy, I invited Kline
here to explain this to you
because he's my doctor, and
you, you're my brother in law.
At least, you were my brother
in law until Louise, well.
Well...
That meant I still think of
you as my brother in law.
Right, yeah.
Now, I want you to be
the executor of my estate,
make sure all the
transition goes smoothly
when Buck gets out of
prison and it's time for him
to take over if I'm
already, you know.
But any questions that you
might have of a medical nature,
or anything else, just feel
free to ask either one of us.
Can I have your golf clubs?
Golf clubs.
Damn, Tommy.
Yes, Mom.
I remember what all I'm
supposed to talk about.
I never thought I'd get
into Princeton, not really.
I applied because I
thought it'd be cool
to go to an Ivy League school.
They told me that they've
never ever had anyone
from Hoxton before,
so I'm proud of that.
You're proud of that?
Your dad and I are so
proud of you, sweetie.
I always knew you could do
anything you wanted to do.
Okay, Mom, thanks.
Please.
I think I got a good
education here in Hoxton.
I was taught good values,
hard work, honesty.
I think Princeton liked that.
And my test scores.
Dad said too that he
wishes he had gone
somewhere else for college,
so I also did it for him.
Maybe we could practice
law together one day,
if I go to law school.
My God, Lawton,
that would just be perfect.
We would both be tickled pink.
But I don't know if I
want to come back here, Mom.
And I don't want
to be pressured.
I hate it when you
pressure me like that.
Anyway...
I think being from
Hoxton made me stand out.
'Cause I was probably
a little more normal
than some of the other kids
who want to go up there.
And I'll come out normal too.
I won't be some
radical East Coast kid.
I-- I won't come out with
a lot of weird ideas.
And I won't be one of
those people who only cares
about the money and acting
like a big shot, and all that.
I'll still be one of us.
Lord.
Kline, I can barely
stand up on my own now.
The pain pills are all
right, but I don't know.
A man's no good alone, Kline.
You know that.
The only person I
want to be with now
is Louise, and she's not here.
So I'm ready to follow
God's timetable.
And it's--
It's time.
Without the chemo
you may last a year,
but the end is going
to be miserable.
Just-- Just do the damn chemo
and let's see what happens.
Do it for me and Tommy.
Do it for Buck.
Do it for Maisie.
Damn it, Kline,
that's not fair.
You know I'd cut off my
right arm for that girl.
All right.
I'm going to
pick you up at nine.
We'll go to the medical center.
I'll have you back by
supper time, you hear me?
Okay, I'll do it.
But I want that to
be powerful stuff.
- I want it to pack a wallop.
- Okay.
If I take a piss
outdoors I want it
to kill every flea on every dog
between here and
Denbury, you hear me?
See, I'm not a big one
on paying for something
to make me puke my
guts out every morning
and have it not do any good.
That's just me though.
Now hear me out.
There are things you can
do now to ease that issue,
like anti-nausea
medication's pretty good.
And there's some
non-traditional alternatives.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now I ain't
going to take yoga.
I'm not referring to yoga.
I'm talking about marijuana.
I'm not
some damn musician.
And I don't relish
the idea of spending
my last days in
the penitentiary.
What in the hell is the
matter with you, Kline?
Nothing.
It helped me when I was
getting over that foot surgery.
My best friend,
a damn dope fiend.
What-- What's it like?
You'll like it.
I guarantee it, okay?
Well, it ain't
going to turn me
into Charles Manson, is it?
He was a family man.
Yeah.
♪ My days are moving fast ♪
♪ I've got to find a plan ♪
♪ That will last ♪
♪ Car's a running, I've got no ♪
♪ Doesn't suit me anyhow ♪
♪ I've got to push on
Past the cars you know ♪
♪ I'm good, yes you know ♪
♪ I am good ♪
♪ Even though I want
To be back ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ I could never ever ♪
♪ Be like that ♪
Well, it's
a beautiful September night
in Hoxton.
But with no game there's
really nothing to do
but listen to your old
Uncle Bud on the radio.
The weather is what is
always is this time of year.
And whatever happened
in Washington, well,
it'll just make you sick.
So let's just skip it.
So, just light it
like regular tobacco.
Take a little in your lungs,
and hold it before you exhale.
If I start thrashing around
or pulling my clothes off,
you all gotta
promise to stop me.
It he's naked and
starts thrashing around,
I'm gonna have to
let you take over.
Good practice today.
Yep.
Hey man, sorry about
that hit on the last sweep.
I just--
I'm still just so pissed
about Ashley
breaking up with me.
And apparently
she's been going out
with this new guy from
Maston all places.
And I was just dwelling on
it and it made me go psycho.
No wait, that last play?
Where I ran it all
the way, you hit me?
Yeah, I did.
Douche.
Hey man.
You know, that guy's
got a lot of nerve.
A guy from Maston going
after one of our women.
Right.
-Yeah.
-Wait, who is he?
Wilkins, their
pussy quarterback.
Apparently he's real smart,
he's got a whole lot of money.
He's this big jock,
so they all decided
to make him president of
their sorry senior class.
Captain of their
bullshit football team.
chickenshit basketball team.
And all-star pitcher of their
half-assed baseball team.
Wait, is this the same teams
that beat our asses last year?
-Well.
-Yeah.
Well-- I'm just saying, I am our
goddamn middle linebacker.
- Damn right.
- I'm one of the most
dependable basketball players.
Yep, yep, yep.
And I am the
best-hitting catcher
that our team has ever had.
I mean, seriously, what does
this guy have that I don't?
Ashley.
- We're sorry.
- Come on.
You know we're messing.
-Come on.
♪ Never be like that ♪
Well...
my family's been
farming here for over 100 years.
So I like to think
that's pretty cool.
But
they don't farm anymore.
Well it's more profitable
to not farm sometimes,
take the deal from
the government.
But I really don't know
anything about this.
I mean, it doesn't
make much sense to me.
But anyways, I'll
either stay here,
learn the family business,
or I'm off to college.
What?
You might stay here?
Lawton never told me that.
Well, I doubt it.
See, this is how I live my life.
Every day that goes by
that I'm not learning
about my dad's business is a
day that I'll never get back.
And, you know, I don't like
to let things slip away.
So, that's why I'll be happy
to be voted Mr. Hoxton High.
So, so you're proud
of being Mr. Hoxton High?
Yes, ma'am.
I hope to always uphold the
things the honor stands for.
I think my mom would
be proud of me.
Clint, she's up there
smiling down on you right now.
Yeah, I like to think so.
I know so.
And she always will
be, you know that.
So, what are
those things, Clint,
the ones that mean
the most to you?
Well--
I don't think
I know what they are.
Maybe they forgot to tell me.
I just--
I just know I believe
in 'em and I always will.
Robert Buckner Thompson,
you have served
almost all of your
ten-year sentence.
You're scheduled for release
April 30th of next year.
Yes, sir.
Your actions had such
terrible consequences.
Although your victim sustained
his most serious injuries
when he fell, it was your attack
that set events in motion.
Had it not been for the
quick actions of the sheriff,
sheriff... Sheriff Kinsey,
you'd most likely be serving
a term for murder instead
of attempted murder.
Now we have reviewed
your case and reports
from the officials
of this prison.
Early release is denied.
You'll serve out
your full sentence
until April 30th of next year.
Yes, sir.
Ten years.
Ten years, my God.
I'm eight when he goes away.
He misses seeing everything.
Even though he was
locked up in that joint
he was still there for you...
talking to you... listening.
He was a good dad to you.
I get so mad at him
sometimes, doing what he did.
For being locked
up, for being away
from all of us for so long.
A man can only take
so much before he snaps.
Your dad worked that land
for ten years by himself...
improving it, making it
better than what he inherited.
And all of a sudden he's sued...
for raising a crop
that he didn't plant.
And unlike all
these other people,
he... he refused
to cave in to the...
piss poor settlement offer
that UGlobal made...
and decided to fight 'em.
He couldn't win.
This country's being
run by big corporations,
big politicians, big business.
All this about the
little man, small farmer...
It's just so much
finely sifted... horseshit.
Your dad, me...
a few others like us...
we're the old way,
on our way out.
Some day the teachers in
school will be talking
about how the small
farmer raised his family...
fed 'em on crops from his own
farm, and sold the surplus.
And it will seem as
amusing to those kids
as when I talk to you about
black and white television.
Thanks for helping me
get through all this.
I know it was you who
helped out me and Buckie.
tried to help my mom.
My dad told me.
I told
you not to listen
to what you hear in prison.
Your dad's a violent
criminal, not to be trusted.
I know.
I brought you some more of
those oatmeal raisin cookies.
I'm a leave them in
the kitchen, all right?
I'll eat 'em all in
one sitting tonight.
♪ Find your place and stay ♪
♪ Face turned away ♪
♪ From everything
That's passed ♪
♪ And not yet come ♪
♪ Close your eyes and see ♪
♪ Things might not be ♪
♪ The way you always thought ♪
♪ But hey, it's not your fault ♪
♪ There are days
When you're running free ♪
♪ There are weeks
When you're quickly fading ♪
♪ There are hours when
You've nothing left to say ♪
It's
a cool 55 degrees,
but it's a miserable
night here in Hoxton.
The Warriors, they
lost a tough battle
to bitter rival, Maston.
And they lost on just a
terrible call by the refs
who basically gave
the game to Maston,
stealing a game from Hoxton
and ruining the senior year
of a bunch of great
kids who don't deserve
to have their life's dreams
crushed by a group of zebras
clearly, clearly
bought and paid for
by someone who doesn't give a damn about good sportsmanship.
No other news is
worth talking about.
I can't believe I just played
my last game of
football for Hoxton.
I can't stand that
we lost our last game.
Man, that was
the dirtiest team
I have ever played against.
Last game at Hoxton,
my best friends...
drinking beer on Main Street.
I can start crying
pretty easily,
or write a country
and western song.
I don't know what
that other team
did to y'all on
that field tonight.
Well, at least they
didn't waterboard ya.
Yeah, well that's the only
thing they didn't do to us.
No, I'm good.
You ought to be happy
they don't eat the dead.
Well, I guess there's
more important things
than caring about what
your football team does.
But not here in Hoxton,
not any other small town.
Somewhere, I reckon.
You all... cherish
these moments...
'cause one day down the road...
you're going to wish you had
thousands of other Fridays
that you could sit and have
a beer with your friends,
shoot the breeze and...
Good night, y'all.
Mr. Denton's dying.
Wait, what?
Where'd you hear that?
No, no, that can't be right.
He was just at the game.
He looked fine.
Look, I saw his chemo schedule
on his refrigerator door.
Don't say shit like that.
That must be why
he's hiring my dad.
He spends a lot of time
out on the porch now.
I can see him from the highway
every time I drive by,
no matter what time.
He's just out there
smoking his pipe.
Shit.
That must be it.
My mom said every lady in
town's been trying to get him
to come over for dinner,
but he turns them all down.
Look, I'm not
supposed to know.
If he wants to tell
anyone, he can.
But we can't, okay?
My granddad was a Marine
and my dad was a Marine.
And, of course, he's a sheriff.
And I'm going to be a Marine.
And I'll tell you,
that's not because
that's what's expected of me.
No.
That's because
that's what I want.
So if you look at
the news you'll see
they're always listing the names
of the different guys that
were killed in action.
It's usually small town guys.
I think that small town
guys love this country more.
And I think they love it
because of their hometowns.
I think that's the
reason they sign up.
And I think if they
were, you know,
all from some big
city, I don't know
if they'd love their
country as much as they do.
That's
so sweet, Jesse.
My goodness.
Thank you, thank you.
Are you okay?
I'm real sorry about
your, you know, cancer.
It's okay.
Don't you worry about that.
I'm fighting it.
Yeah, well.
It sure seems to
be going around.
Man, I love my country so much.
I love it so much, I really do.
I think I made that
pretty obvious.
So, you know, if I'm--
If I'm stuck up
in some lousy place, right?
And I'm getting shot at,
I'm going to be doing it
because I love my country.
And even more than that,
I'm going to be doing that
because I love
Hoxton, and because
I love my friends
and my family here.
And because they are something
that's really
worth fighting for.
Plus, you know, us Mexicans
are real ass kickers too.
Yeah, excuse my language.
But you're just
one quarter Mexican, Jesse.
Hey okay, even
a quarter Mexican
is still enough to kick
most people's asses.
Look, we made tequila
out of a cactus.
You don't jack with somebody
that does something like
that, I'm just saying.
Happy,
happy New Year
to everyone on this
cold and frosty night.
Now you need to drive carefully
because drinking and
driving doesn't end well.
Well, unless you
have a good lawyer
or you're related to the
cop that pulls you over.
Slow down.
My God, not so fast please.
Wow.
You promised me you'd
look in on her every week.
What's the point, Dad?
Seriously, what's the point?
She's never once been awake
when I've come by there.
Don't go by so early.
Dad, she is a drunk, okay?
She's a drunk.
She doesn't wake
up for anything.
Maisie, please don't talk
that way about your mother.
Dad, you're the one that's
been there for me, not her.
Honey, it is not her fault.
It's my fault she's like this.
I could have given up.
I could have.
It would have been
real easy for me
to just leave, or
give up, or whatever.
But I didn't, and
I stayed around.
I took care of Buckie
when she started drinking.
And I have been here
every visitors day
for the last ten years.
I don't expect
you to understand
everything at your young age.
I sure didn't.
I'm pretty grown up, Dad.
You're smarter than I was.
All of ya are.
But that doesn't
make you any wiser.
I go to bed every
night knowing my family
is split up and suffering.
I could blame that lawsuit
and be bitter the
rest of my life.
I could blame my hot temper
and never forgive myself
for going after Gandy.
Or I could take it like
a piece of bad luck...
and work through it
and let it go.
Which is what I aim to do.
I was never a threat to anyone.
I was a farmer.
I was just a farmer.
How was your Dad?
Still the best guy I know.
Yeah.
Was he hung-over?
He's in prison.
They don't party much, so
he never has a hangover.
Well, he's got
that going for him.
Which is nice.
Here, drink it.
You gotta take it.
Come on.
You watch it.
♪ Days grow shorter
As the months go by ♪
♪ Summer and the autumn skies ♪
Talked to that
doctor in Houston.
What?
Told him to hit me
with everything he had.
He said it might kill me.
I said, so be it.
Buck's going to be taking
over this place pretty soon.
There's a lot of things
that I want to get done.
This cancer may kill me,
but it's going to take
a hell of a licking doing it.
I'm going to fight it.
Maisie's taking too
good a care of me...
for me to say goodbye
to her now.
I'm worried
about you getting weak...
all this nausea.
- How much weed is that?
- All of it.
Kat.
It's an
interview for the newspaper.
It's not a video.
I know.
I knew that. I mean, duh.
So, what does it mean
to be from Hoxton?
What does it mean to
be head cheerleader
at Hoxton High School,
home of the Warriors?
I have thought about it.
And I'll tell you what it means.
It means...
It means a lot.
And I mean that.
That's four words.
Can you
think of more things to say
about what it means
to be from Hoxton
and to be head cheerleader,
and all of that?
So far all you've said
is those four words.
I've never known
you to only say four words.
More?
Yes, more.
In case it goes into a time
capsule, or gets discovered
by archeologists thousands
of years from now.
Okay, wow, I hadn't
thought about that.
Um--
Okay.
Well...
It means
I got to grow up
with some of the best
people in the world.
It means I got to grow up with
the best guys I'll ever know.
And I got to grow
up with Maisie,
who's... the best friend
anyone could ever ask for.
And I know that... no matter
what happens to me,
or... where I end up,
or who I wind up with...
if there's anything in me
that will make people like me
or want to get to know me...
it'll be because
I'm from Hoxton.
And no one else could
ever understand that
because... no one else's
hometown is as great as ours is.
They may think it
is, but it's not.
Hey, Buckie.
Are you hungry?
My gosh, this looks so good.
Excuse me, sweetie.
How's your day?
Maisie.
Yeah?
You wanna talk?
Sure.
Look...
You've had more
bad luck in 18 years
than anyone should
have in a lifetime.
Is that supposed to
help me sleep tonight?
You deserve a break.
And you can have that if
you can get out of here
and leave this all behind you.
Leaving doesn't
make it go away, Kat.
It just means I go away
and it all goes with me.
My memories go with me.
I'll never be able to forget
my dad getting hauled off
on my birthday, or my mama
crawling into the bottle,
or my little brother
drifting away.
Leaving just means
I'll... be leaving behind
all the other people
that have taken care
of me all these years. And...
I won't be leaving behind
any of the bad stuff.
I'll just be moving it
with me somewhere else.
It's not that I'm
not ready to go.
I can't.
My brother needs me.
My mom needs me.
My dad's about to
get out of prison
and I'm going to hug him
for the first time in ten years.
I'll stay if you want me to.
In Hoxton.
Look, you--
You've always been like the
glue that holds us all together.
But you don't always have to
take care of everybody else.
You need to like... go off and
start the rest of your life.
But I'll stick around
till you're ready.
That's the craziest
thing you've ever said.
I need you to go... you know?
I need you to be my friend
that I can visit on weekends.
that tells all the hot guys
in college about her cute
friend at home, okay?
So you gotta go.
All right.
And you can tell them
that gotta know me
because I'm the luckiest
girl in the world...
because I live in a
safe place with people
watching over me
and taking care of me...
like the Queen of England
in Buckingham Palace
or that castle.
You know... Windsor.
Okay.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Hi-de-hi,
and howdy doody
from your old pal, Uncle Bud.
As all farmers say, when  there's no rain in the forecast
it's going to be another  dadgum beautiful day in Hoxton.
The high, well, it's going to be
in the 90s, a little
warm for April.
And tonight it'll
dip down in the 60s.
Now that's all the
details you need, really,
so let's talk about sports.
The Hoxton Warriors
split a double header
with Maston yesterday.
They won the first game
and they ran out of
gas in the second.
And on the national
scene, well, trust me,
you don't want to
hear about anything
that happened out in Washington.
I could easily
have a bad attitude
about everything
that's happened.
What with my dad being
in prison and all.
But I don't.
Because everybody just sort of
wrapped their arms around
us and took care of us.
Me and my little brother Buckie
have lived with Kat and
her family for ten years.
And Harry made me call
him Harry from day one.
He said he didn't
deserve to be called Dad
because I already had a
dad and I always would.
Carolyn, I've always
called "other mother".
Because my mom sort of... um...
Anyway, I'm sorry.
I'm going on and on.
I just...
You know, to be honest,
I'm not entirely sure
why I was elected
class president
or why I got to be head
cheerleader with Kat,
'cause I'm really
not that flexible.
Um... But, you know, I guess
I get good grades.
But I just do that
to make my dad proud.
It's nothing crazy.
I guess they voted for me
'cause I'm sort of an underdog.
Maybe I represent
what's happening
to all the little
farmers in this country.
Losing our farm the way we
did, that shouldn't happen.
Not here.
Not in the USA.
It used to be something
like that wasn't allowed.
So yeah, I guess I
represent the little guys
and my friends at Hoxton High
wanted everybody to know.
Anyway... it means to world
to me to be from here.
And it means the world to me
that they voted me
class president.
Because being from Hoxton means
I got two sets of parents,
and a little brother,
and Mr. Denton,
who's like a granddad to me.
And... Itchy, and Lawton...
Jesse, Clint, and Kat.
That's why I'll always want to
live here, why I always will.
Any plans
for when your daddy gets out.
Well, he gets out April 30th.
I'm really just hoping everybody
will help me give him
a big welcome home.
He's had Hoxton in his heart
every day he's been gone.
♪ I've just woken up ♪
♪ Burnt dreams through my head ♪
♪ Staring in my coffee cup ♪
♪ My heart is as heavy as lead ♪
♪ Here ♪
♪ I am again ♪
♪ Crying before ten ♪
Mom.
Good morning.
Now you might think it's  Saturday morning, but it's not.
It's Senior Salute day.
Be sure you and your
whole family are downtown
on Main Street today when the senior class of Hoxton High
will be saluted on,
yes, a job well done.
The parade starts at noon.
And if I were you,
I'd be there early
or you might have
to sit in the sun.
What?
Excuse me.
Pardon, excuse me.
No, they are not there.
The rest of the class is,
but they're-- Hello?
Hank, did I-- Hank
can you hear me?
Can you hear me now?
Okay, look.
There is no sign, not one,
of my sweet Kat or Maisie.
Or Lawton, or Itchy,
or Clint, or Jesse.
And we cannot take the
class picture without them.
And Kat is not
answering her phone.
Nothing new there.
But Maisie is not
answering hers either.
Now I am a calm and
reasonable woman.
Are you listening to me, Hank?
Calm and reasonable.
But at some point, when
all sense of order is gone
and the rules of law have
just flown out the window,
it is not unheard
of for a person
to become just a
little agitated.
Now my babies are graduating
from high school one time.
One time, Hank.
This is a magical
milestone moment for them.
Are you listening to me?
Three of our banners,
three of our banners
have been cut down
and stolen, Hank.
Vandals, vandals, in our town.
Roving gangs of vandals are
desecrating Senior Salute day.
Roving gangs!
Now I am not going to
lose my self-control.
Nor will I insult
your intelligence
by lining out for you exactly
where this is all headed.
But you are supposed
to keep us safe, Hank.
Not allow hordes of
devil-worshiping psychopaths
to kill us in our beds
while we're sleeping,
and this is obviously
where this is all headed.
There is only you
between them and us.
Thank you.
I know you will.
I'll see you in church, okay.
Paperwork's almost complete.
You're looking
at about one hour.
Thank you.
Back then was so different.
You wouldn't get on an airplane
without a necktie
and a suit coat.
No shorts, no flip flops,
no tank tops...
no pajama pants, and no tattoos.
Well, bikers had tattoos.
I guess bikers
always had tattoos.
I guess they always will.
I don't know why.
Anyway, people were
better looking then.
They were just more polite.
You didn't have to lock
your doors all time.
And if you did lock your doors
they figured something
was going on back there.
You know, a fella
could call a girl
two, three, four times
and never reach her.
And when you finally did reach her, she'd already agreed
to be some other fella's
date to the big party.
So... a boy could go from...
being in love
to being broken-hearted
and never even
talked to the girl.
The good guys were good guys.
A lot of cop shows on TV.
Westerns were big, too.
Movies and TV taught
you good lessons.
People went to
church every Sunday.
Nobody had a bolt
through the earlobe.
Movie stars didn't run round
without their underwear on.
People took care of each other.
♪ It's taken time
To get moving along ♪
♪ And now it's finally begun ♪
♪ And the scenery
Goes by so fast ♪
♪ On this road that I'm on ♪
♪ But the heartaches
And the old pains ♪
♪ Seen in rear view
Mirrors shrinking ♪
♪ Aren't really any
Smaller in your heart ♪
♪ And the friends
You leave behind you ♪
♪ Are the only who remind you ♪
♪ Of the things that really
Mattered in the start ♪
♪ Now I've given up
On seeing you face ♪
♪ And I know loneliness well ♪
♪ And I've carved out
Such a cold hollow space ♪
♪ Where the warmest light fell ♪
♪ But the heartaches
And the old pains ♪
♪ Seen in rear view
Mirrors shrinking ♪
♪ Aren't really any
Smaller in your heart ♪
♪ And the friends
You leave behind you ♪
♪ Are the only who remind you ♪
♪ Of the things that really
Mattered in the start ♪
♪ Maybe I needed
Time on this road ♪
♪ Time to wander and roam ♪
♪ To remember
My own flesh and blood ♪
♪ And to want to come home ♪
♪ But the heartaches
And the old pains ♪
♪ Seen through rear
View mirrors shrinking ♪
♪ Aren't really any
Smaller in your heart ♪
♪ And the friends
You leave behind you ♪
♪ Are the only who remind you ♪
♪ Of the things that really
Mattered in the start ♪
♪ The heartaches
And the old pains ♪
♪ Seen in rear view
Mirrors shrinking ♪
♪ Aren't really any
Smaller in your heart ♪
♪ And the friends
You leave behind you ♪
♪ Are the only who remind you ♪
♪ Of the things that really
Mattered in the start ♪
♪ Yeah, the friends
You leave behind you ♪
♪ Are the only who remind you ♪
♪ Of the things that really
Mattered in the start ♪