CHINA FILM ADMINISTRATION
SPRING ERA
MIRAGE
SCITECH FILMS
STEAM
QITAI CULTURE & MEDIA Co.
Mount Everest the highest mountain in the world 8.848m above sea level
peak condition is extremely volatile, with wind speeds above 117M / h and temperatures reaching 117ᵒF
285 people have died while climbing Mount Everest. 120 corpses still lagging near the top, in the area known as the "Death Zone".
Earn hand.
Team Wings, check your situation at this time, replace.
Here Tim Wings. Already we have found the location of the target.
West valley, height
6000 meters, over.
Be accepted.
Come on!
Here Xiaodaizi, asking for a helicopter to get closer!
Come on. / Well, boss!
Beware, avalanche of ice!
Hey, watch out! / Calm...
You made it.
Pull us!
Who's the new woman? Wonder Woman?
It works fast, is not it?
She's just temporary freelancers.
Yes I know, understand ... he could not join Team Wings.
Because the head does not employ a woman ...
but he should know, some members of the team is still single.
You ask a lot of talk but no contents, man.
Almost there, Tashi, be prepared ...
Ready. / Come attraction.
1... 2... 3...
Sign up here ...
...
All fasten your seatbelts.
Depart! / Understood!
Understood!
Do not talk, rest and breathe ...
Below...
my daughter.
He said, "Under"!
What do you want?
Back!
There might still be people down there. / Are you crazy huh?
This is an order!
Back...
or you're fired!
Kapten Jiang ...
Nothing strange happened near the peak.
You have to dodge soon!
Wings team, you hear?
Immediately away ...
Now!
Wind speed reached 40 knots. We distress persist here.
Lower us.
I said, lower!
Understandably.
Damn that woman crazy!
Is someone there?
I am here.
Hold on ... I'll be there.
Catch this rope!
Amitabha, bless ...
God bless ...
ong ma ni bei mei hong ...
Come on, handle.
Avalanche!
Run!
Leave the rucksack!
Come on, give me your hand!
Approaching!
Quick!
Hey, close ...
... give me your hand ...!
Ride! / Boss!
Damn!
WINGS ON TOP OF EVEREST
3 DAYS LATER
NEPAL
translation broth3r max
Dangerous avalanche that occurred 3 days ago
south slope near the summit of Mount Everest ...
Most climbers injured in avalanche
has returned to Kathmandu ...
Avalanches are rare hit of the Nepal side of Mount Everest ...
Rescuers managed to carry the climber to Kathmandu after a landslide ...
Rescuers Wings, led by the famous climber Jiang Yuesheng,
Jiang himself was also down to the avalanche ...
New Year's fireworks show will be held at the Durbar Square 21:30 hours this evening.
Traditional New Year's Eve Nepal will arrive on April 13.
Excuse me, where Bar WINGS?
Directions here. / Thank you.
You're welcome.
♪ I sat in the dark side ♪
♪ Under dusty and cold day ♪
♪ Telaga morning ♪
♪ Drinking sky ♪
♪ Kathmandu ♪
♪ Soon I met ♪
♪ And the day that weird confusing ♪
♪ It would keep me ... ♪
What happen?
Hey, what are you?
Come on!
Since when we burn incense for people who have died?
The captain could barely escaped yesterday.
We have to ward off evil spirits for her.
You almost make me a heart attack!
What the captain was upset at the new guy?
Immediately hit fired, although badge has not been taken.
Well, back to the board for hiring.
I'm getting bored with this old tradition.
What ever kepikiran captain eliminate the stupid bird exam?
Who would be the new member of Team Wings?
You almost scored high, my friend ...
The big winners, the big winner, eat chicken!
This is her friend, and do not return.
Well, it's time for the next round!
To place a bet for the next round.
Hey now the young lady! Want to play the big league?
Hajar their hips!
And he that I marked.
You're My luck goddess.
Cheers ...
You ... Goddess ... My luck.
Wow Chairman come!
Hey Bos.
Hey, housewarming party of friends, long time no see.
Hey, how are you?
Hey bro, next time do not make me a heart attack, you understand?
Welcome back.
Listen bro,
This issue is a matter of management salaries
but the rest of the money we do not exist anymore.
Those people have to be paid. Suppose the debt, I'll find a way out.
You're nice talking, this place is falling.
See, the ceiling leaked.
So what, we can see the stars, right?
And discordant voice gramophone.
That's from my youth.
Hey, come here please!
Hey James, you're late again ... / Late what?
Are you ready?
Because I'm going to introduce someone who is certainly rich.
Moneyed? / Yes.
1, 2, 3.
Cheese! / Cheese!
Let me introduce.
This is our new client, Mr. Victor Hawk.
And this is a fellow brother, Marcus Hawk.
Both men worked in the Research and Analysis Slope India ...
Are we again make a Hollywood movie ...
Where you can wear all white people?
Our grandfather, the English,
sent to India before World War II.
After the independence of our family stayed in India.
Start working on the Indian government.
So you could say I have a ...
Great white crossbreed in India
rather be Chinese.
Whoops!
So,
why did you come to us?
A few days ago, some very important files stolen from military intelligence.
According to our tracking,
file transport aircraft fell
when crossing the Nepal side of Mount Everest.
It occurred at 10:13 am, three days ago.
It was the same time when we hit avalanches ...
In other words, the Indian government did not want anyone to know ...
their secret files are now in neighboring countries.
That's why they have not contacted officials in Nepal.
In fact, they turned to a private rescue team to clinch their duties.
If you watch the news, you'll know ...
for the purpose of improving relations strained,
government in the Himalayan region
currently planning to meet in Kathmandu.
The meeting will be scheduled 65 hours from now.
The political situation is very difficult,
if not treated immediately.
The documents are missing,
very very important.
Because it involves direct multilateral relations.
Wherein the crash?
Death Zone ...
Last Transmission air through the tool ELT
are in the Zone of Death,
approximately 8700 meters above sea level,
near the summit. / You realize even in good weather,
rescue helicopter could not reach an altitude of 6000 meters above sea level.
72 hours, in the Death Zone,
zero chance of survival.
That's right. / Well this is why we come to you.
You guys are experts in their field.
Suppose we could,
why we want to take? You're going to slow us down.
My sister is not here to answer your question,
but tell to settle this!
Boss, when we will put an end to this meeting?
We do not have to take this job, something feels awkward.
Yeah, you know what? I'm having a pretty fun day.
I just try your luck on the gaming tables.
Anyway thank you friends. / I'm sorry, this will not work.
We wish you luck.
Happy New Year! Happy New Year!
1 dollar ... one dollar!
1 dollar.
If you take us there,
we will pay half a million dollars.
Listen bro, this is really a good chance.
Although you do not like the idea, at least listen to the opinions of others.
Now I feel a little challenge there would be no harm.
Chairman, you are decided, I adherents alone.
The business we are saving lives. We are not equipped with political affairs.
Yeah, but even though we are well known, we are again heavily indebted.
If we go on like this, soon the team will disband.
Political tensions are short tonight ...
with increased military presence on both sides of the border.
Many feared this action could trigger a war area.
Peace meeting scheduled with 3 days,
the officials agreed to meet at the Conference,
hoping to prevent a wider impact.
Tashi injured. We are understaffed.
What about the young girl?
Suya shown on recordings of the mission,
he was quite remarkable. / Never mind that.
He was not a member of Team Wings.
You will not find a qualified person
and familiar with the Death Zone like the girl?
Well, this file. Perhaps you change your mind.
"May 18, 2014, the last survivor"
Hey, Kapten Jiang ...
finally there are people who can reach the bird.
She'd break his record of your daughter.
Who? / I do not know,
I've never seen him before.
Da says go towards Everest.
BANDARA TRIBHUVAN
How did you find me, Chief?
Just a coincidence. I'm just passing through.
Not good at lying.
What?
I want to go back to Tim Wings, without pay.
I've read the incident report, 2014.
You think I do not know the real motives
to join the rescue team?
Maybe before no one was willing,
but there must be people who say honest with you.
If you're looking for someone,
already 5 years!
No one knows where ...
The wind threw her body.
Even if you find him, it's just simply ...
mere corpse!
I understand that you think
I have gone mad ...
I is not logical.
If I could think clearly,
I could have packed up and left,
leaving all the ice and snow,
back to China and find a decent job, marries a normal man,
have children,
take care of housework,
and live in peace
like everyone else.
However ...
not so easy to forget about the people close to you
and forget everything as if nothing ever happened.
I do not care what others,
I will not leave him alone there.
You know the first thing about leaving the people close to you up there!
If you assume I did not follow the protocol properly,
I promise to stick to start now!
If you still perceive me less worthy,
I will keep trying until you ... / Enough.
North star cluster, Cygnus, visible tonight,
means there are persistent fight.
Turns out I was right.
Go back to sleep.
We're leaving tomorrow morning at 6 o'clock.
And do not forget this ...
Chairman, you will not regret it!
You do not heal you? Shouts nights like this!
Get lost you! / Sorry.
"PEMULA (NOOB)"
broth3rmax
Get rid of all unnecessary James, including the crane machine.
Are you sure, Chief?
The more light the higher flying.
BANDARA HELI KATHMANDU
Han, activate the procedure, be prepared to take off.
Understandably.
Sorry...
Why late? Team Wings ...
no special treatment just because you're a woman.
I warn you, do not cry over to someday start no trouble!
Ready, Chief!
Hey, noob!
James would say something.
You're talking what, stupid clown? / He's been practicing all night.
Aah, okay okay ... that ...
You're really beautiful...
thanks. / But once ...
construction!
Hello, Victor.
Xiaodaizi.
Team Wings, take off.
Caution in the air. / Be Careful...
Biking to Camp III cut off by avalanches,
we have to make the rope bridge itself.
This is it.
Why he could sleep when this be?
You know, he used to be called the chairman of the "devil Himalaya"
Bos, the air begins to thin.
Only so far helicopter arriving.
Lower us here.
Lower helicopters in Lobuche, and wait there Be there!
Understandably.
Wings team, there is an increase in the peak of the storm, be careful up there.
I do not need to be careful, I ''m not climbing.
Han, do nyombong!
Above Base Camp 5700 meters
We have two satellite phones, I take one,
only brought Victor.
Understandably, Captain. / I'll call again when up to Camp III, so.
Now remember, you all carry GPS devices,
The tool shows the fall of the signal plane.
We must find the missing plane before the battery runs out.
We have less than 48 hours.
Good, let's go!
Come on!
Be Careful!
Come on, come on, pull!
You do not what?
Not at all.
Hey, you're next.
Noob, notice your breathing pattern
and the rhythm of climbing.
Your ways too wide and too quick breath.
It makes you more easily tired.
Climbing it like yoga,
increasingly sluggish movement, much more can be achieved.
Try one after another if you can.
This is not a race, Noob.
Kamp III, 7158 meter
Captain, I've check the cigarette Trinidad you ask.
It's expensive brands with exclusive supply,
average, rather than the brand choice of government officials.
But it's the same kuselidiki colleagues Indiaku military contacts.
They sure are
sent two agents named Victor and Marcus.
All right, let me know if any other info.
Keep in touch. / Well.
Lobuche, 4930 meter
Whose is this?
Code Morse?
Noob!
Aw, I think he's already sold!
I am back.
What will we prepare the rope bridge now?
You do not need to go. James and I could take care of his rope.
Are you sure?
Without your mess,
we can move faster.
2030?
How do you know? / Morse Code is part of mandatory training for rescuers, remember?
It's a game that often we play.
Her name Summer.
We formed a perfect climbing team.
2 people, complementary
as if we mirrored each other.
Everest was the final challenge in the 14 thousands of our adventure.
One day we climb past 5 years,
a few hundred meters from the summit, in the Death Zone,
unexpected weather change ...
Rescuers said she was too far a hike
they left it on the mountain that day
That's the last day all saw him.
His last words to me via morse code ...
2030...
Just figure it is what he said to me.
What would he say?
I searched all associated with that number.
But there was no result.
I did not give up looking for him.
Do not you lose everything.
Sometimes time will erase all the memories.
He is only one part of you,
but...
forget not the same as giving up.
Hey Chief, are you ready to go?
Maybe...
not only that she wanted to say.
What is this?
Of course, a secret.
And the secret will be revealed later during the end of the course.
Xiaodaizi. Sorry, I'm not pro ... mak ... sud ...
Did not mean it.
Yes, I did not mean it. / Well, forgive.
Zou Lei?
"Zou La"! / Ya.
Zou La! (Ayo!)
♪ This is a sad song ♪
As a gift to new members Wings team, we are a new ringtone!
♪ Xiaodaizi want the age of 30 many years ♪
♪ Every time he met a friend ♪
Cowboy shit!
♪ They continue to ask the same question ♪
♪ When did you get married? ♪
♪ But the marriage issue ♪
♪ can not be decided alone ♪
♪ He asked his father ... ♪
Halo?
What is Tashi?
I got a phone call from a military friend, he said ...
Victor and Marcus who come to us ... they were ...
What? Who is a liar?
Hey, your cigarettes behind.
This is it.
Marcus!
Hey, your brother called.
He did not know his name.
Mr. Rum Head. (stupid)
Victor and Marcus are genuine, their bodies ...
met in Kathmandu recently!
Time of death was estimated to be 2 days ago ...
I give them a physical description of two men with us ...
Fellow my contacts send their photos ...
and they could find two people that is almost similar.
Victor and Marcus we were ...
they are cheaters who work ...
the biggest arms dealer in the Himalayan region.
They membayakan his life to have a confidential document ...
do not stop the war, they want to spark a war ...
Halo?
Tashi ...
Very humiliating.
I was so expect a lot of you.
Sana take-ice ax, ropes and GPS girls,
we must not waste it all.
This is me.
Already I convinced my team to bring disposable helicopter ride,
killing them is not part of the deal!
We get caught by them, this is indeed necessary.
You do not understand?
Team captain Jiang was like family.
They were siblings.
I have long heard when Suya are those who traffic children organ.
What is not the case?
Okay,
my price just went up.
Noob!
Xiaodaizi!
Daizi!
I am here...
Noob!
Xiaodaizi!
Daizi!
Noob!
Nemu something? / No, are you?
Chairman?
Captain,
I understand if a lost your team while on duty.
I know it's almost morning.
But finding him is not our priority. How? At least 30 hours ahead.
You're nice talking, huh? Not anggotamu that are out there!
Remove your hands! / You're kind of yes?
James! Stop!
Now listen to me!
He was a professional climber, really so?
Now what if he's not impossible to climb out of here ...
and trying to find her missing boyfriend?
We continue the journey. / Chairman!
I left my cell phone here.
When he gets back, can catch up with us as soon as possible.
Understandably.
If anything happens, you know what to do.
We'll meet again, understand?
♪ boyfriend cheating not just have one girl ♪
♪ Shit shit shit ... ♪
What happened?
Unable to contact anyone?
Wow, son! Where have you been? Geez, we were looking for you!
Behind ... you ... / You want to say something?
Behind you! / Just talk!
Marcus!
What? Slow down, son, do you want to say something?
Xiaodaizi ...
Run!
Zou ... La ...
Halo?
Hello? It Daizi ... Hello?
Halo.
Hello ... / Hello, this Han ...
Can you hear me? / Hello ...
There was no one there.
Do not shut down ... / Hello ...
Code Morse?
Hello ... wait a minute.
Daizi,
Xiaodaizi! / This is me...
This is me...
Xiaodaizi, could meet me at camp II?
I've found Xiaodaizi, it seems he was injured.
Now I'm going to camp II to meet him.
Well, cowboy, will immediately tell you to meet the rescue team in camp II.
Be careful there, and take care of Xiaodaizi when you met him, yes?
Change.
Understandably, we will wait for the rescue team there.
Thank you friend. Years.
instagram @broth3rmax
We must come to Camp IV at dusk.
Fast-forward, our time is less than 24 hours.
Stay a little longer.
Match II, 6474 meters
I am here!
Caution!
Do not come close!
Hey!
There was a problem at the signal, we kept going.
If we can not contact them, we have to go down.
Your mission to be postponed.
Ah ... good.
Well.
Yes, all right.
Let me know immediately if there is news.
Well.
How?
Bad weather interfere with GPS signals.
But Suya said he could put a call through them.
That's great news.
Yeah, her.
If we are not to kill women cowboy!
Hey, Rum Head.
I do not see you 2 days, and you ...
Operating its own face.
You bitch!
Anything else that you store in your clothes?
Needless to say thanks, I'm here just want to see the sunrise.
I find useful objects in the wreckage of the helicopter.
Dont worry...
I contacted Suya had before I went.
He will send a rescue team as soon as possible,
to find us.
However ...
not Suya which introduced Marcus and Victor on us?
You suspect Suya?
It is impossible. We've long known him.
Before you hit the lungs coughs,
must kuobati you as best I could ...
Match IV, 7906 meters
It's just a fire.
Pain will always be with you.
Your scar?
Our nation was born in the Himalayas Caucasians.
We are not English or local residents.
Just ...
mulatto, struggling to survive.
My sister and I learned early in life ... is to kill or be killed.
But the strong always prey on the weak.
From what I know, at one point you were not much different.
Huh? What do you mean?
From what I heard, once you people are often "end justifies the means'.
Nobody can mess with ...
what do they call you, the devil Himalaya?
The devil was dead.
Because your daughter?
Are you talking about?
From what I hear, Xiaodaizi not your first pupil ...
before him, you have to train your daughter, right?
It was a mistake.
Why? I heard she received many awards as a climber ...
Diam!
I do not want to discuss it!
Take a break.
Do not believe the boss who gives it to you.
Spare astrolabe was ...
daughter thinks it's like a precious treasure.
He had the talent.
But the boss was never satisfied.
She hoped her daughter could be his successor
and surpasses him.
Until one day, his daughter go hiking alone
in a challenge to the top
but he failed to return.
But, this is for what?
I just knew that...
This kind of tool
if you're pointing direction of the coordinates in the sky,
This tool will show some kind of constellations.
Try.
2030...
What exactly do you want to say?
Because the first large-ambassador has arrived,
Kathmandu streets so lively.
Because many are hoping this conference will bring improvements forever ...
in the multilateral relations between the regions of the Himalayas.
However, there are also pessimistic about the success short of expectations
given the long history of conflict and complicated this region.
Only in 6 hours, the talks will start in tension.
The world will be watching.
Be Careful!
Here it is, all our friends are here.
More than just family.
Perhaps you change your mind, you can contact us by Suya anytime.
If Suya did help them ...
then nobody came to save us.
You should have gone yesterday.
I'll make you something to eat.
I've been there.
Noob, you stupid or what?
God knows what happened to the Boss,
and I was injured.
Between the two of us,
only one person who might be able to ...
managed to get off safely.
Look, you're supposed to have said,
"Wait for me, I will go down looking for help."
Then I would say,
"baiklah."
"Bagus."
But we both know
this is what happens.
No one is hurt.
Listen to me...
you have to leave me here.
There is no other way!
Maybe ... there are other ways.
You're good at wearing the equipment, right?
What are you doing? / The blizzard will still come.
Bring your equipment, we will begin to descend the mountain.
Our distance with the death zone just hours.
If we go back, we will lose the chance of finding that plane!
As I said yesterday,
if the weather gets worse
and we still can not contact my team,
we will go down and start the rescue.
This is more important than your document.
It works. / Good.
Oh, my God,
you're a student engineer kayak worst ever.
That's why I became a mountaineer.
The location of the crash is still sending the signal.
Possibilities can be reached within half a day.
If we're lucky,
radio equipment on the plane that crashed was still functioning.
We can call the rescue team.
I hire you to take us to that plane!
Own brother also lost!
Will not let anyone deter goals, although it was my own brother.
Captain!
Why is this to you?
You were a top climber, I thought was great, I admire you.
Now look at you, you're just a man ... full of doubts.
What is your daughter's accident ... this makes you weak?
If we go down now, what about the reputation of business?
What an asshole!
You do not understand too huh?
Business can walk alone.
But the matter of saving people is not so.
Many lives are at stake.
Do you think only state security,
but what does it mean if you do not save people close to you?
Oxygen! Go after!
Thank you friends, I owe you my life.
You said the girl was missing.
You are lying!
You want to kill me? Well, kill me.
But then you'll never see your beloved disciples again.
First you have to kill your daughter, now you kill your pupils.
Enjoy the guilt.
Where is he? / If you drive to the crash site, I'll tell you where he is.
Is this not a fair bargain?
That Morse code?
Why are you doing this?
You would not understand.
Since we were little, we were treated like a bum.
The only way to be respected is money, then we are looking for an advantage in the war.
Now the monsters, they have destroyed us, and now want peace?
Peace Fuck them!
How do I know if my team is still alive?
You do not know.
But there is one chance.
You know the captain, life is like a game of Russian roulette.
Let's play, how?
Only this is our chance.
Within a few days ago,
we lost a lot of people.
From this moment,
I will never forsake or Chairman.
I will not leave anyone again.
You're crazy.
This is really crazy!
Hey skipper, make sure the rope tightly bound.
I do not like it when missed.
Noob...
What you say I have
"Goddess of Luck" mu?
Wait for me back.
We've been road for hours.
I think we walk in circles!
In this bad weather did not know where the left-right.
Do not mess with, Captain!
Why do we take a shortcut instead?
Ah, a shortcut.
But only a few people in this world that can be managed via that route.
You want to try it?
It is enough! I'm tired of you!
You think I do not know what you want?
From here, I can get to the plane itself without you.
Frozen Morning?
You can not catch her ...
Nothing can!
Chairman!
Noob...
breath and keep your step.
Climb it like yoga ...
increasingly slow you move, the more far can you accomplish.
Death Zone
Victor and Marcus we have ...
working for the biggest arms dealer in the Himalayan region.
They endanger his life for the sake of getting confidential documents ...
not to menghantikan war, they want to spark a war ...
Peak, 8848 meters
Ya ya ya ...
is not this a surprise!
All your team members are dead, you lose everything.
But you survive here, still trying to stop me?
Are you going crazy?
Not .. do not ... do!
Okay...
Enough, enough!
Let us stop, okay?
Everything in life has a price.
... Let's make a deal, how?
Submit the document in your hands ... / I do not like you.
All that you do for yourself.
But people in my life have taught ...
we can be more than that.
You want ... just money.
Ambition, confession ...
everything is in here!
Do not! You're a crazy bitch!
Chairman!
Chairman...
You should ...
reduce weight ...
Hurry up!
Chairman, what are you doing?
Holdfast, Chief!
Holdfast!
Chairman, holdfast!
Meaning of Cygnus is ...
each end ...
there is a new beginning.
No...
Chairman...
It's over ... I have this time
I guess I'll never see another sunrise ...
OXYGEN: 0
No...
Nepal Police, what is your emergency?
It's the police, give it up!
KATHMANDU HOSPITAL
thanks.
I contacted the rescue services and the police.
They said there was an unknown person called and told them about me.
I told them that definitely Xiaodaizi,
but they did not find him up there ...
and he disappeared from the records of departure Wings Team.
As if he had never existed.
Himalaya conference has been conducted successfully.
Signatory to this historic peace agreement ushered in a new era of multi-national ...
Peace ... peace ...
Hey, cowboy!
What are you doing here want to see another sunrise?