Hello? Mother?
I can hear you How are you?
I'll call you back.
Hang up!
Yes, I'll call you back.
Hello? Mother?
How are you ?
I'm fine and you?
Did you get the money I sent you?
It's for the jewellery
and the plane ticket.
Yes, it's so cold
that the sea has frozen.
Yes, I'm just fine.
WINTERLAND
Mother, how is she?
Yes, I got the video cassette
I like it
She's beautiful like an angel.
It's me.
Look at the picture. It's of me.
It's a picture of me
-But it's just a picture.
-Yes
When and where did
the wedding take place?
In Kurdistan in Iraq
About three months ago, I think
-Why weren't you there?
-Because of the war in Iraq.
Well, there's nothing in
our guidelines about this.
A marriage without a groom
How long have you known each other?
-About a year
-But you've never met her?
Oh,yes!
Because I call her, and she calls me.
And because
I write letters to her about love.
And she writes
letters to me about love.
Well, I'll write
that the picture is of you.
-That you're the groom.
-Thank you.
-Hello, Mirza !
-Selamu aleikum, how are you?
-Fine. And you?
-Where are you heading?
To work.
Why are you out in the cold?
I don't know.
Do you think they'll
put us to any use some day?
-l have e no idea .
-Neither do I!
I hope to see
you and your wife at the wedding.
-Sure, we look forward to it
-Why walk? I'll give you a lift.
Thanks but l prefer to walk,
like everyone else .
-Well, goodbye
-Go with God
I've got great news!
Fermes has
been granted a residence permit.
Yes, she'll be here soon.
Sherko, you promised me a satellite
dish three months ago!
Just bring me
the biggest dish you've got.
Careful! Don't drop it!
Your wife will be happy
to get all those Kurdish channels
- as she doesn't speak Norwegian.
I've waited a year for this day .
This ls really great
This is the best dish in town.
Congratulations!
I've said it a hundred times.
You've got a gorgeous wife!
Words can't describe
the beauty of this princess.
-You should get a girl from home too
-I'll never marry a Kurdish girl
-Where do I get a kilo of gold?
-It's just a formality
You don't really need to buy it.
Forget it.
There are lots of women here.
They give me everything.
Money, booze.
And women here are experienced
Unlike the ladies back home
They leave you in the end .
So you're getting married
to avoid ending up alone?
Sherko,
it's a different word altogether
I'm entering a new phase in life
Fermes and I will have a son .
He'll carry my name.
I'm not getting married
Please, Mirza take the front seat
-Well has she landed?
-No, I can't see her.
-Isn't that her?
-No, don' even look at that woman.
It's her, but she's...
Renas?
It's her!
Give her the flowers, Renas.
-These are from Renas. Welcome.
-Thank you.
Welcome!
It's cold and snowy here,
but the houses are warm.
Follow me, please.
Please enter, Fermesk
Welcome!
This is the kitchen.
There's the living room.
And the bedroom ls p there.
These shoes are from your family .
-Mom has made this pajamas for you
-Thank you very much
I've only invited people I know.
FERMESK & RENAS
Hello?
Who is this?
Father-in-law, is that you?
Everything's fine with us
With Fermesk as well
What's the problem?
What?
Five thousand dollars?
I can't keep supporting you forever.
-She threw you out already?
-She had such a lovely voice on the phone.
-And I fell in love with her photos
-A photo never tells the truth.
I gazed at it for months I fell
in love with the girl in the picture.
-She's the same girl, only fatter
-Did you say ''fat''?
I saw how fat she was at the airport.
But I told myself:
''It's the princess, only in XXL''
I don't mean any harm
I can see you're a bit tense.
Go home to your wife
You know, having one woman in bed -
- beats dreaming about nine
Go home, brother.
Sherko? Where's the towel?
-I'm coming
-Who's that woman?
Just anther girlfriend.
Now head back home.
-You're the man
-Bye
Take care. Bye.
(Norwegian course)
Chapter four, page thirteen
Pronouns
I, you, him
Isn't it hard to fall in love with
a woman you've never met before?
No. Maybe in the beginning.
But wasn't 't sIe shocked
by the cold and the dark weather?
Why do you ask?
Of course it's a shock to her.
What if you
found your self in a desert?
No, I'm from a big city,
not from Sahara.
-Johan can get reindeer cheap.
-It's not about money
I'll do my duty as a man,
and get this wedding right.
-Listen, I've never done this before.
-It's just like slaughtering chicken.
-We must stop. It can't breathe.
-We'll be there soon
-Well, I hope so
-Very soon
Hello, Johan!
Hi, Johan.
-Let's get started.
-Does he have a knife?
-Johan, do you have a sharp knife?
-Sure.
-Good
-Are you going to do the job?
No he is. Sherk.
-Get it! Hurry!
-Shit!
Grab it!
-You must slaughter it towards Mecca
-Where is Mecca?
Where the sun rises.
-I can't You do it
-You promised!
I don't know where Mecca is!
If we don't do it towards Mecca,
it won't be Hal-Al
-Well, ask him
-Johan? Come here.
Where does the sun rise?
Excuse me? You know about sun?
What's going on?
They want to know where Mecca is .
Where the sun rises.
Just point somewhere,
and we'll get this over with.
Just point!
-Right. In that direction.
-Lay it down on the ground.
This knife is dull.
Oh, shit
-I'll be damned.
-No prayer?
-Sure, I said ''Bismillah''
-I didn't hear it.
I just didn't say it out loud.
Here, take the knife.
(Norwegian course)
-Welcome home.
-Thanks .
What have you done with the house?
-I thought it would be nice.
-Wasn't it fine as it was?
What do you mean if
I've become a man or not.
Hello? Father?
What's mother trying to say?
Asking if we've done it or not?
I realize you want
to know when it's happened.
We need time
We'll wait until after the wedding.
She's just arrived.
I realize you want to know.
Yes, the wedding night.
Goodbye.
Fermes, are you a sleep?
Renas, we have to wait.
We're not yet married.
We're man and wife.
We're only married on paper.
Can't I wear a wedding dress first?
-Hi.
Sorry if it seems a bit dreary
It's the middle of winter, after all
-But I've put a heater in your room.
-Thank you.
He welcomes on behalf
of himself and the entire staff.
It's a great honor -
- to have us as guests
He'll personally look after us
Well, thank you.
Right, welcome.
Please follow me.
Fermes?
What's wrong, Fermes?
-Aren't you going to undress?
-I'm cold.
We're man and wife now
Don't be afraid.
I don't know how to tell you this
I'm not the girl you think I am.
-What?
-I'm sorry, I just.
I lost my virginity in Kurdistan.
Oh, Renas.
Renass! Renass!
-Will you send me back?
-Come on The ice is thick!
Don't be afraid
You won't go through the ice
It's safe Look!
Come on, let's go
I don't want to go back, Renas
But I couldn't lie to you
You'v already lied to me for a year.
To hide something is a sin.
-He died . l never saw him again.
-Who else have you been seeing?
Nobody.
I'm no like you think.
We'll live together for a year.
You'll sleep in your room, I in mine
Then we'll get a divorce.
l won't touch you .
After a year, you'll return home.
Yes.
The wedding was very nice , yes.
Of course we did it!
Right,' goodbye.
Yes, mother?
What is it now? What?
Yes, Fermesk is my wife.
Norwegian class ?
Yes, she can start tomorrow.
''Ø''!
''Å''!
It's essential to learn the letters
-May I help you?
-Excuse me.
Fermes, my wife, forgot her lunch.
-Well, I go ahead.
-Thanks .
You forgot this, dear. Thank you
-Make up your mind. Which direction?
-To the right
-No, to the left.
-What about now ?
-That's perfect!
-A nd now ?
There's no picture .
Tell me when you find
the Kurdish channels.
-Nothing
-Just shout if you find anything
There it is!
I can see a music video on TV!
We lost the picture.
This is driving me crazy.
What happened
to the yapragh, Renas ?
I threw it away.
Did you throw away our dinner?
It was starting to smell
I threw it away.
I hate taking the bus here.
Nobody speaks to anyone.
They just stare into the space .
Nobody offers you a hand.
People up here are friendly, but
it takes time to get to know them.
You just have to reach out to them.
Norwegians friendly .
Look, I'll talk to that guy .
-Leave him alone.
-Watch this.
-Hei
-Hei.
-Cold today
-Yeah
-It wasn't this cold yesterday.
-No, it wasn't.
Maybe it'll snow?
Have a nice day .
l told you they 're friendly .
This ls how you eat it.
Have some globaaroshaa. It's kurdish.
Globarosha
-Doesn't your wife eat pork either?
-No.
-Why doesn't she eat pork?
-Because it makes you impotent.
-You know?
-Yeah
You eat them like this .
Look at me.
-What are you eating, Atle?
-Boiled ham.
Any luck with the ladies lately?
-Why the kisss ?
-To show them we're married.
No kisses from now on.
Why are you laughing?
Who was that man?
-Who?
-Stop acting like a fool.
He's just another student.
You told me he was rich.
But he's got nothing!
Just a large, empty house
All right, mother.
We'll talk later.
All right, goodbye.
-Hello Mirza.
-Hello. How are you doing?
-Fine, thanks will you come inside?
-Is Renas home?
-He'll be here soon. Come inside.
-I'll wait here.
-I need him to read a letter for me
-You can wait inside.
Thank you , but I'll wait here.
Renas seems happy.
He's found a good wife.
Thank you.
Goodbye for now.
Hello, Mirza.
Welcome.
-How are you ?
-Fine, thanks.
The letter
from immigration has arrived.
I hope it's good news
What does it say?
''Application
for residence permit denied''
Is it good news?
Say something.
The suspense is killing me.
The immigration office has
granted you a residence permit.
Praise the Lord!
Is it temporary or permanent?
I couldn't tell Mirza the truth
It would have broken his heart.
Have you been at our house?
-Why didn't you tell me?
-I thought we were divorced.
Sherko was here
I've got the right to know.
He just took a quick look
at the satellite dish.
Get out of here!
Fermes is gone.
Have you seen her?
No, she's not a home.
She took all her things and left.
She doesn't know anyone here!
I don't know where she might be.
I've said things to her.
Fermes
Your residence
application was denied.
How do you know?
You don't speak much Norwegian.
It says ''denied''.
''Denied'' was the first word
I learned in this country.
I've waited so long
Maybe it's better this way.
What do you mean, Mirza?
I don't belong here.
I'm an old man.
I have lived my life somewhere else.
But you are young.
You should stay.
You love that poor man,
like he loves you.
If you must lie to get along,
your happiness won't last
Go home, my dear
Renas needs you.
Go home to your husband
It's the best thing you can do
Without you, he is nothing.
Go home, God bless you
Where have you been?
I came back to talk with you
Then go ahead and talk.
Come on, come inside.
-No, not as long as you're angry.
-What are you talking about?
I don't want to live like this!
I'd rather be divorced!
I could have
sent you back the first night
-Come home
-Don't touch me!
Come back! Don't go.
Fermesl
Fermes, stopp running!
Stop!
-Get up.
-Go away.
Fermes, come on. Let's go.
Give me your hand.
-Let's go.
-No.
You don't want to talk
You lied to me, to the whole family.
You lied as well, have you forgotten?
Renas
We didn't send these pictures.
It's not our fault.
Fermes, our families are far away .
It's you and me now .
Give me your hand and let's go
I won't send you back
Come on, darling.
Let's go home.
Hello?
Father-in-law, is that you?
Why says l've mentioned
the money to anyone?
What?
Don't you believe me?
Stop calling us
We've had enough!
Hello?
-What's the matter, Renas?
-It's your father
It's either mother,
father or uncle
The whole lot!
Thanks.