Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Come on, you witch. Come on!
- Gonna burn you!
- Get a move on!
- You've been betrayed!
- Stop flirting!
Death forwards!
Now!
You dirty witch!
Mercy!
You sure this is the place?
Tom was doing some work here.
He said he saw three
women living along.
Said there's a safe in there.
Rumor in town is they
got a lot of money.
All right, I'm in.
Okay, we go in quiet.
We try not to wake anyone.
Be a lot easier.
Ready?
Oh, I'm ready.
Let's get rich.
Let's do it.
Quiet.
Check upstairs.
What are you doing?
Where the hell
did you come from?
This is my house.
Please.
Shh.
Shut up.
Now tell me, where is the safe?
We don't have a safe.
Please, just leave us alone
or we'll be forced to act.
And I don't want to hurt you.
You brought this on yourself.
Where is the safe?!
We don't have a safe!
What the fuck?
Don't touch that.
Where's the money?
Money?
In the safe, the money!
Now, that wasn't
very nice, was it?
What are we going
to do with him?
I say, let him go.
We wipe his memory
and we change his ways
with the power of suggestion.
Well, that went rather nicely.
Can I keep him?
We could use the Butler.
What?
Jesus.
It felt good to use my
powers like that again.
Well, you know we can't, Sam.
We've gotta stay to ourselves.
Besides, you know humans.
They'll never accept witches.
We'll either end up
hung by a gallow pole
or burned at the stake.
So why do we keep watching
Dominique and her coven
if we're not gonna intervene?
I think Lucy's right.
We can't bring
attention to ourselves.
We have a responsibility.
We just need to
keep our eyes open,
and hopefully we don't
have to use our powers.
All I know is there's nothing
like a good chardonnay.
Cheers, girls.
Come on, drag her this way.
Be quick, the poison
will wear off soon.
My arms are weakening!
Come on, stop your
screaming, witch!
You all
right back there?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
Just a nightmare.
So what are you doing
at the Academy, anyway,
if you don't mind me asking?
I am here for induction.
I was offered a place.
Do you know much about it?
It has a good reputation.
No, I've
not heard anything.
Why are we pulling...
Are we here?
Yeah, there's just
like potholes and stuff.
Really don't want
to ruin my tires.
So yeah, this is it.
So how do I get in?
Just, you know,
head into the forest.
Five minutes and the
Academy's on your left.
Can't miss it.
Hello?
Oh, hey.
- I'm-
- Jessica.
- Yeah.
- I'm Katherine.
I'll show you around.
Were you surprised
to get your invite
to the Amityville Academy?
Yeah, because I
never actually applied.
Well, Ms. Marcom
always seeks the best.
What will you study here?
Drama and the arts.
Cool.
Me too.
I'll give you some advice now.
Never questioned Ms.
Marcom's methods.
This is Ms. Marcom's office.
Knock, and then
enter on her command.
After your induction, I'll
take you to your room.
We've been watching
you some time.
Sit.
We almost exclusively
offer places
to students of your background.
My background?
This building is beautiful.
The location is perfect.
It allows seclusion, privacy,
and minimal distractions.
You've come late to semester.
You have a lot to learn in
a very short space of time.
This is the contract.
Once you've signed
this, you'll be ours
for the foreseeable future.
Until graduation, you mean.
As you wish.
I'm not sure I know
enough about the school.
I told you, there
is not much time.
You must be willing to
learn, and learn quickly.
We will teach you here,
but you must open yourself.
Besides, what else
have you to do?
You lead a rather sad existence.
Friendless, alone.
Have you not always
wondered why?
There is no choice to make.
Sign and belong to something.
Something that will promise
greatness in this life.
Excellent.
Perhaps a toast?
Wait.
It's getting kind of late.
I should probably go to my room.
Very well.
Thank you, Ms. Marcom.
Welcome to the Academy.
What did you
think of Ms. Marcom?
She's a brilliant woman.
I'm sure she is.
Did she tell you much?
She was quite vague.
I'm sure you'll find
out more tomorrow.
Good night.
Yeah.
She's new as well.
I'll leave you two
to get acquainted.
Hi!
Sorry, I'm not sure if
this is my room or not.
She didn't...
Oh, don't worry.
Come hang out till you find out.
- Hi, I'm Sally.
- Jessica.
I didn't even
apply to join here.
I just got offered a place.
Yeah, same.
You didn't know much
about here, why come?
I guess I was just
trying to work out
what to do next, you know?
Maybe this is my calling.
I got thrown out
of my last college.
No one else would take
me, and then Ms. Marcom
offered me a place.
Hey, are you okay.
Yeah, I'm fine, it was
that wine Ms. Marcom gave me.
It's quite strong.
Oh, okay, sit down.
- So sorry.
- No, don't be silly.
Totally okay.
Here, have some of this.
Thanks.
No, it's totally okay.
I'm so sorry, I just...
No no, it happens
to the best of us.
Well, is it confirmed?
She bears the mark.
- Where was it placed?
- Her back.
The mark had three
horns instead of two.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
What does it mean?
Be gone.
Prepare the hall and the coven,
and bring the new girls to me.
As you wish, Madame.
What is going on?
Stop it!
So, we have a
volunteer to go first.
You will be next.
The chalice.
When the sacred blood is
spilt, the gates will open.
He will rise.
And those
who burnt us alive
will meet their demise.
He will rise.
And those who burnt us alive
will meet their demise.
Oh great Bortis, demon of
dark, accept this sacrifice
in return for your
promise to bring forth
your legion for my command.
Take this soul.
And allow me the blood!
Now for you, Jessica.
You bear the mark of the
the three-horned beast.
The power that lies
within, you have no idea!
Get her!
Boo.
Get to the car, go.
Hurry!
Push!
Come on, get in.
We failed you.
I'm sorry, Ms. Marcom.
Apologies are for
the weak, Katherine.
I'm sorry!
Please!
Fail me again, and I
will pull your heart out
and feed it to the maggots.
How is she?
She's okay.
I gave her a sleeping spell.
She needs to relax.
So just what are we
gonna tell this girl?
I don't know.
The truth?
It's only fair she
understands the power she has.
What about Dominique?
We can't interfere too much.
Not until we know what.
We took a big risk
helping this girl.
I'll study the ancient texts.
Maybe that'll shed some light
onto what Dominique's plan is.
But she's building up to
something, I can feel it.
It's her!
Where am I?
- Who are you?
- It's okay.
What's your name?
Jessica.
Jessica, we're
here to help you.
Don't worry.
Is it Ms. Marcom?
Yes, but we're protected
here by boundaries.
Protected by what?
She's trying to kill me!
Relax.
Sleep.
Sleep, Jessica.
She's getting stronger.
We have to intensify
our protection spell
to keep her off the property.
I agree.
Yeah, no shit.
We do need to decide
what to do with Jessica.
She's our responsibility now.
I know.
We have to tell
Jessica the truth.
But if we tell her the truth,
it's our duty to
teach her our ways.
We're gonna have
to prepare Jessica
for whatever might arise.
Yes, we can all feel it.
Dominique's coven is
gaining power every day.
And we have to
tell her the truth.
Tell me what?
Who are you?
We are all members of
a white witch bloodline.
I'm a Lucy Belle, and these
are my sisters, Sam and Elena.
Witches?
We study for enlightenment
and healing and good.
Not like Dominique.
She's a mistress
of the dark arts.
But why did she
want to kill me?
You're part of our bloodline.
Within our lineage,
somewhere in our DNA,
there lurks a power that
she wants to sacrifice
to increase her own.
Botis?
She told you this?
It was the name of the demon
that she was chanting for
when she killed a
pupil at the Academy.
She said I had the
three-horned mark?
What does this mean?
Dominique wants Jessica.
Her potential, her
power, her life force.
It could be greater than
all three of ours combined.
My power.
You're a witch!
You've never felt your power?
Felt different?
Sometimes I have
these strange nightmares
of being burned at a stake.
Those aren't nightmares.
Those are residual
memories of a past life.
What happens now?
What can I do?
We'll train you, Jessica.
You need to learn our ways.
And how to harness
your natural gifts.
We'll protect you.
We've got your back.
What are you guys doing?
Come in.
Do you trust us?
Yeah?
Because for what
we're about to do,
you need to open your
heart and let us in.
A sisterhood of power
is based on trust.
Love.
And light.
Is your heart open?
Sure, yeah.
Okay.
Blessed goddess
of love and light,
guide us on this moonlit night.
Fill our hearts
with energy bright
and give her righteous
strength to fight.
Earth, fire, life, and death.
Blessed goddess
of love and light.
guide us on this moonlit night.
Fill our hearts
with energy bright
and give her a righteous
strength to fight.
Earth, fire, life, and death.
Blessed goddess
of love and light,
guide us on this moonlit night.
Guide us on this
move at night.
Blessed goddess
of love and light,
guide us on this moonlit night.
What do
you have to give?
Speak.
From your heart.
Clear your mind.
This is crazy.
Look inside and
see what you want to give.
Okay.
Don't be afraid.
You're safe.
Clear your mind.
Stay calm.
You let go of your fear
and found your power.
Jessica, you have the gift.
No freaking way.
Ms. Marcom?
Ms. Chloe Argento is here.
Should I get her?
No!
No one go near her.
You may return to
your domiciles.
I will welcome her myself.
Hello?
let me go.
No, please, no!
No, no, please, no!
These spell and
potion recipes?
They're all for healing
and enlightenment.
Our magic is always for good.
Or for defense.
I think you're gonna
really like some of these.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Which one's your favorite?
I think I like this one.
How come?
It's for enhancing energy.
Yeah.
What is it, Elena?
She's taken another one.
Give me power, Botis.
This is my offering to you.
Give me more.
More!
We are close to releasing Botis.
I can feel him.
Ready yourselves and the others.
We will retrieve
Jessica tomorrow.
If I give her to Botis,
he will obey my commands
in this realm.
What's going on?
It's Dominique.
She's trying to
break the barrier.
Keep strong.
Hold on tight
Focus.
I don't know how
long I can hold this.
I don't know how much longer.
I felt that power again.
I'm not sure where it came
from and I had no control,
but it felt like...
Instinct?
Mm-hmm.
The more you train, the
more power you'll gain.
But I have a feeling
we're running out of time.
And we don't know what
she's doing with Botis.
We've never read
the demonic texts.
The words within,
written in blood?
And have the power to
compel those who read them.
And you know, someone
with your potential
would have been a great
ally for Dominique.
So why does she
want to kill me?
The elder will
know what to do.
But we don't know how
much sanity she has left.
She won't see us.
Well, she might see Jessica.
Hey, who is the elder?
She's our old teacher,
Tilda Von Erich.
Nobody really knows
how old she is.
But she's read all
the demonic texts.
But she's remained immune
to the dark powers.
She'll know what
Dominique is up to.
But it won't be easy.
She still retains power,
but Dominique banished her
outside of Amityville and
warned her not to intervene.
If you're willing, we will try.
Sounds good.
I'll watch the Academy
and just make sure
nobody tracks you.
Okay.
Tilda?
Jessica.
Go to the cauldron.
What is she doing?
She's in a trance.
Drink.
It's good for you.
Don't drink that.
The taste
is wretched, yes?
It helps you focus.
Bring me some.
Tilda?
Continue by yourself.
You're on your own.
Lenora.
- Tilda.
- Silence.
I want to speak with the girl.
The book.
The book?
- This one?
- Mm-hmm.
It is like a family
tree, I guess.
The entries are chronological.
You'll find Leonore Belle.
1568 to 1599.
You died on New Year's
Eve during a blood moon.
They burned and hung women
without prejudice or due process.
That's horrible.
Oh.
She looks just like me.
You are one and the same.
Will I ever
remember everything?
It is not likely.
Besides, life is best
lived looking ahead.
You have great power.
Greater even than in
your previous life.
The Belles all bear the mark
of two horns on a beast.
It was a Wiccan symbol, a
creature of peace and power.
Oh, but occasionally,
someone special is born
with a third horn.
I'm not special.
Oh, you'll see.
When the time comes.
You want to know
more about Dominique?
Yes.
And what of Botis?
A demon who has fascinated
Dominique for many years.
Her extracurricular
activities worried me greatly
when she was my student.
Like all demons,
he has his domain.
He is cut off from this realm.
But when the stars are
right, the door to open it,
it becomes easier.
She
means to release him?
Yes.
Why are you
watching my school?
Go to hell.
How about I bring hell to you!
Why are you alone?
Where are they?
Where are your sisters?
I can see your thoughts.
Tilda.
You won't get far.
Dominique has been
appeasing his lust
for essence and
soul with sacrifice.
And with each one, she
herself becomes more powerful.
It takes a great deal of
power to release Bortis, but
it takes even more
to control him.
That is why she is
so taken with you.
Your sacrifice means the
Botis will become her slave,
and the world as we
know it will end.
We will get Dominique.
We'll fight this.
Then you must go.
You must prepare.
May we visit you after?
In the next life, maybe.
You will send my love to Elena.
We will.
Thank you.
- Good luck.
- Goodbye.
Thank you.
Oh my god, Elena!
Sam, Lucy, help!
What happened to her?
It's an Agravarian slug.
No.
How do we stop it?
I have an antidote for it.
Keep her warm, don't
let her convulse.
I'll be right back.
Elena, stay with us.
Stay strong, I need you.
We all need you.
Remember, two drops,
no more, no less.
Okay.
Hold her mouth open.
Come on.
Okay.
Okay, come on.
Come on.
Get it out.
Good, good girl.
What are you working on?
I'm working on breaking
a protection spell.
And I'm almost done.
How's Elena doing?
She's okay.
She's out in the back with Jess.
Great.
I brought you this.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, these are beautiful.
Remember what I taught you.
Breathe in.
Focus.
You can do this
I did it!
You did!
I can't believe it!
It went so fast,
did you see that?
Yes, it was awesome.
- Wanna do it again?
- Yeah I do!
So fun.
You old crow.
I told you not to interfere!
Yet you defied me.
What did you tell them?
It matters not, now.
Once I have the girl, I will
release and enslave Botis.
There must be something
inside of you, Dominique,
something of that girl who
first came to my Academy.
My Academy!
How could
you release Botis?
There will be nothing left!
What's left is mine.
When sacred blood is
spilled, the gates will open.
He will rise, and those
who burned us alive
will meet their demise.
I will allow you to
live to see hell.
Elena, wake up.
Wake up!
Come on, Elena.
Where's Jessica.
Sam!
Are we too late?
We have until
midnight tonight.
That's when the blood
moon is at its fullest
and the planets are
all in alignment.
Our focus needs to
be on rescuing Jessica
first and foremost.
Without her, Dominique
cannot control the demon.
Can she release
him without her?
If they do unleash him, we've
got a short window of time
to put him back before his
power fully forms in this realm.
Would she do that?
We will prepare for the fight,
The power of three.
The hour is almost upon us.
It's a shame you won't be
around to witness the new dawn.
I shall return soon.
I think we have visitors
I should prepare for.
Unleash me!
I will sacrifice the
final offering soon.
Release me!
You pledge your power
to my every command?
If the offering
satisfies, yes.
It will.
Stop right there.
Don't even think about it.
I warned you.
Come on, we better go.
This is it.
Jessica?
Water, earth, fire, air,
feel the pain, feel my stare.
Lucy, are you all right?
Lucy!
Dominique has a voodoo doll!
I can break the spell,
give me your hand.
It's okay.
Stay with me.
Hold my hand, stay with me.
Lucy.
You're okay.
You okay?
Are you okay?
She's okay, she's okay.
We have to get to
the great hall.
That's where she'll
perform the sacrifice.
Okay.
She's weakening!
No!
Are you all right?
You all right?
I await my sacrifice.
I cannot give her to you!
You must give me more
blood of power to release me!
You'll get your sacrifice.
In exchange for a promise.
Of what to you?
Destruction.
Turmoil.
Blackness, death of everyone
in the Belle bloodline.
So be it.
Oh great Botis, demon of dark.
Accept my final offering...
And fulfill my last wish.
No!
Run!
Quickly.
Where is he?
We have to banish him, so
his power doesn't go stronger.
Don't break the circle.
Where is he?
What is happening?
Don't, Jessica.
I'll take what
was promised to me!
Demon dead.
We did it.
Dead demon!
Is Jessica still sleeping?
Yeah, she's been restless
the last few nights.
What did we decide?
About the Academy girls?
Well, I say they're
eager to learn from us.
We teach them, and we set
them on the right path.
But I don't think we should
teach them at the Academy.
Those walls are cursed.
Hmm.
But we could teach them here.
Agreed.
Sam?
Lucy, Elena!
Jess, what's the matter?
Something's coming.
We need to go to Salem.
You gotta be kidding me.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org