OOKAMI SHOUJO Film Partners
presents
Those days when it was called
The Era of Showa...
There is no 100% in this world.
Uh, yeah...
We can indeed go to the moon now.
The scientists go digging
mysteries of underworld.
Uh, yeah...
Aren't you listening?
Tell you what,
everything is not what we see!
...I know, Akira-kun.
You don't believe this!
I do, I do!
This isn't the place but,
The ditch is connecting to
bigger pipe, and
That connects to even
bigger ones.
That's where
underworld people would live.
...Say, how about playing
at your house?
Ko-chan, let me do it.
He is messing your kite,
Ko-chan.
It is mine!
That is mine!!
Ah, yes, that is yours indeed,
Ko-chan.
You cannot call me Ko-chan!
Sorry, Koichi-kun.
He is tearing up your kite,
Ko-chan.
I kick ass!
Ohta, Don't go away!
Stop, Ohta!
Ohta, wait!!
Ohta, wait!
Ohta!
Shunji, not that way. This way!
Yah!
Welcome, welcome,
yes, yes, please this way!
Well well, ladies and gentlemen,
Have mercy and pity this girl.
Saved by a wolf,
No more misery if eaten up then.
But she was alive and brought up
by the wolf. At age 10,
She grows hair all around her body!
Well worth watching,
worth watching!
80 for kids, 40 for half blind,
50% more for pregnant,
Show tent will start tomorrow!
Wolf Girl, Human Pomp,
Lady Octopus and Girl Torch!
Stretchy Neck Girl.
They are all genuine.
Well well well,
Show Tent will start tomorrow!
"Wolf Girl"
WHEN THE SHOW TENT
CAME TO MY TOWN
Thank you.
Guess she is still in
elementary school.
That's impressive.
OK, I will go.
Have safe commuting.
"Monster Encyclopedia",
"UFOs", "Dracula"
"Elementary school, School Yard"
You've got to pay the damage!
It's 10000 yen worth, that kite!
Have it by tomorrow.
I didn't break it.
It just fell on to me.
Shut up! Just pay me!
It's a rip-off!
A kite cannot cost 10000 yen.
You are ripping him off.
Police will come and get you.
...What's it to you?
Hurry, you guys will be late.
What's a Rip-off?
Don't know!
Who is she?
We have somebody new today.
Be nice to her.
I am Rumiko Tezuka.
Nice to meet you.
"Rumiko Tezuka"
Where are you from,
Tezuka-san?
Tokyo?
I've been there...
As I thought! You are different...
Where did you buy your skirt?
She is wearing a wristwatch!
Looks nice, Tezuka-san!
She is late again.
Yeah, she's weird.
Hey, let's show her around.
Let's
I want to go too.
How about music room first?
Can I call you Rumiko-chan?
Yeah.
Let'me call you that way.
Me too.
Your brother's cold,
is it still bad?
Be careful,
you won't catch it, Komuro-san.
You want Class-List?
Yes, I want to remember
everybody's name quick.
Wait a moment.
Network list will be better?
Hoping you make
many friends soon.
Yes...
Teacher, that girl?
You mean, Komuro-san?
Doesn't she have a school bag?
No... Taking care of
her little brothers and...
Be nice to her, will you?
Yes!
That new girl, she got nerves!
Does she...?
But she is kind of cute, isn't she?
...is she?
Look, look, this magic card!
Well, fellows, gather around!
What I have here is MAGIC CARD.
Doesn't this look cool? Magic it is.
Don't blink. Look just closer.
I do it once and only once.
Well, I put this on the card...
And do this...
Invented at Dr. Takayanagi's Lab,
up in deep Northern Hokkaido,
What is underneath this card?
1 Yen!
That's right. You saw it.
And what happens to 1 Yen...
As you see!
With this ca rd, anyone can change
1 Yen to 100 Yen Coin!
No need to beg your parents,
have all the money you want!
Well,
who wants to have this card?
Me, me, me!!
He was cheating.
There aren't no Magic Card.
Just a Trick.
A card covers 1 yen.
Then, a different coin in another card
comes out when opened again.
You got that?
Don't you see, you almost got hooked,
Akira Ohta-kun.
What? I looked at it up closest.
Ohta-kun, you are funny.
Ohta-kun, you cannot tarry on.
Never bring this stuff here!
Will never let you in again.
Please... Koichi-kun.
I'm not swinging by.
It's a short cut.
Aren't you scared?
What?
Place like this,
you see some ghosts.
I am not afraid!
Hey, there is
a long-nosed goblin in shrine.
I know that. It comes kidnapping.
You know it well.
Common sense,
but I am not scared at all.
How come adults tell a lie like that?
There is no long-nose goblin at all.
There is!
It must be here even now.
We just cannot see it.
You are funny.
From their view,
people are all funny!
Well, well, well,
everybody, everybody!
Split-mouthed Woman,
Lady Octopus, Spellbinding!
Brand new to this area,
Wolf-Girl Hana-chan is must to see!
Cursed badly or sent by God,
pity girl, poor girl.
She was born in
deep Northern riverside of Hokkaido,
Her father dumped her in deep mountain
foot of Big Snow Mountain.
As in ill luck,
saved by a big wolf.
No big deal if eaten up then.
Misery starts as the wolf raised her.
She is just age 10!
Here, you nice-looking little gent!
Just like your age!
What ill fate, raised by wolves,
Thick body hair and
speaks no words.
Rats, Chicken, snake, frog,
she eats all of them alive.
Shocking live show
will wait for you!
Well, everybody, come in and see.
Come in and See.
Little Fellow!
Do you have money?
Welcome, welcome.
Ouch!
"Hideko Komuro"
Teacher!
I saw Ohta-kun yesterday
running away from the Shrine,
still with his school bag on.
The school note said
"No Swing-by after school".
Is it true, Ohta-kun?
Ohta-kun?
Lost your tongue?
It's true... My tongue is okay.
Quiet, everyone!
Remember what I said last week?
Yes, I do.
To the corridor, then.
Stupid!
You nerd!
Teacher?
I was there, too.
Tezuka-san?
The corridor, for me, too.
Good morning, Komuro-san.
...Good morning.
She spoke!
Hadn't heard her voice in a while.
But you two are
in the same class!
Hey! You are being punished,
so be quiet!
No way. Going to
the show tent is out of question.
I am not asking you to come along.
It is all fake I think.
You've seen it?
No, I haven't.
Then how would you know?
I saw a Lady
whose mouth was split up to here.
Can't be true.
But it was, I saw it.
And the Wolf Girl, too.
What's a Wolf Girl?
It is written here,
take a good look.
"Wolf Girl"
She is really human,
but was brought up by a wolf.
She walks on all four limbs
and can't talk.
That reminds me of something
I heard from Grandma.
Speak up!
A cat brought up by a dog.
Please. Dogs and cats are
a totally different matter.
It is?
Thank you very much.
You are very good.
Not worth showing around, is it?
"Wolf Girl"
I met the owner of
Canary Craft Shop today.
He gave me a generous discount.
Nice colors, aren't they?
I will knit your muffler with this.
Going to keep you warm.
Akira,
I was asked to teach knitting.
Two days a week.
What do you think?
Imagine, me teaching at
a knitting class! Isn't it great?
Yeah...
"Yesterday was Father and Mother's
Wedding Anniversary..."
"I helped out and
we baked a large anniversary cake."
"The three of us blew out
the candles in the dark."
"I could hear
Father and Mother laugh."
"I want to get married soon and
bake cakes for someone, too."
Very good.
You are next, Ohta-kun.
"My mother likes the winter season."
"It is because
she will have a lot of things to knit."
"She is going to knit my father
a necktie next,"
"but my father said Please, No!"
"Still my mother knits
with a smile on her face..."
Right, well done.
How about a hand for Tezuka-san?
We will be eating the curry
you are making now for lunch.
So better make it delicious.
Tezuka-san, you are good.
You do it at home as well?
Komuro-san does better than I do.
Don't go near her.
She is muggle.
No one is gonna eat anything
she makes.
Dis--gusting.
Don't come near me, Komuro-san.
This would be fun,
everyone, get Komuro!
Coming infield!
Fool! You got hit by a girl!
Ko-chan, not hurt?
Are you all right?
Ouch...
Komuro,
do you clean up properly!
Having a newspaper route is
no excuse for loafing.
That's so, Wolf Girl!
Komuro is a Wolf Girl.
Don't bring a cookie can to school!
Wolf Girl! Wolf Girl!
Stop it!
I am not letting you
pick on Komuro-san!
Komuro-san!
Don't you stop picking on her!
"Hideko Komuro"
"Totally naked,
running four-legged,"
"speaks no words,
just howling like a wolf."
Right... but...
And here.
"The girl had thick body hair and
sharp teeth, eating birds alive."
See, this Wolf Girl must be
the real thing...
But that was so long ago,
it must be dead by now.
Can I go to your house today?
Your Mom's gonna be late again?
Akira-kun?
Hey, Akira-kun!
Akira-kun!
Huh, what? Akira-kun...
What? What is it?
What happened?
Akira-kun, tell me!
Believe me. I didn't go!
You saw Komuro
of the Show Tent, right?
You said so.
You saw Komura doing
the Wolf Girl act, didn't you?
No, I didn't say so. I wasn't...
Make up your mind.
Or you're gonna get smacked
by Ko-chan.
I saw it, but
I didn't go to the Show Tent!
You really didn't go?
I absolutely did not go!
He lies too much, no fun.
You are not allowed into
our secret base from new on.
...Wait!
Koichi-kun! Promise me
you won't tell the teacher?
4 days a week.
Oh, 4 days a week I have to...
Please...
That is my son.
Please consider my request...
Yes, I will be considering it.
Thank you.
I am home.
Welcome back.
What is it?
You don't seem that pleased.
The front door was locked!
Right. I am sorry.
I guess should give you keys
from now on.
And now the show is about to begin.
The hottest topic in town!
The WOLF GIRL!
Her strange but fascinating story,
and real-life performance.
You got money?
I say you got money?
Help, Help me!
I was waiting for you, kid.
You... Saw... Me!
Going different ways.
You mean divorce?
All in all, not much understanding
for a job like ours.
The child..., which will...
The mother should, right?
At this point, why the father?
...What's that?
I hate the way you say it.
The child gets hurt the most.
Maybe he woke up.
What, is he sleeping there?
Akira, you gonna catch a cold
dozing off like this.
Ohta-kun, you all right?
Yes.
You want to take a rest
at the sidelines? Can you sit up?
Sit down.
Are you OK?
Airball...!
"Teacher's Office"
I think you should start wearing them.
Having trouble exercising?
Let's speak with your Mother.
Tomorrow, I can accompany you.
No, it's OK.
Can you tell her by yourself?
Don't have to buy a new one.
You can borrow some
from your mother.
Is it OK?
What's wrong?
With the lights out.
Nothing... welcome back.
Where is Mom?
Canary Fancy Shop.
Really...
Wanna go out for a bite?
No.
Aren't you hung FY?
Not hungry.
I will wait till my Mom is back.
Hey, Akira. Sit down here.
You wanna come to
Dad's office tomorrow?
Well, tomorrow's Saturday.
How about lunch together?
Yeah...
You don't like being together
with me?
No, that's not it.
You know, Mom's got
knitting classes tomorrow, too.
At the bus stop
in front of my office, 1 o'clock.
Here, this is your bus fare.
So don't lose it.
"500 yen"
Hideko-chan!
I can't go to school today.
I wanted to give you this.
What is it?
I got it from my sister.
No use for me.
Bye Bye.
"500 Yen"
Isn't the show tent open?
Don't know... well,
the street stands are all gone.
What? You mean
the show tent is not here to stay?
Don't know...
but no sense being here all the time.
Guess they move on.
Wish the show tent would stay.
Akira-kun!
Tezuka-san?
I'll get off here.
Your father?
Yeah.
Why did you skip school?
Well... I went to Tokyo,
but there was a change in plans.
Had I known,
I would have gone to school.
Where are you going,
Akira-kun?
Nowhere... wait!
My father's office!
What does your father do?
A newspaper reporter.
Wow, sounds interesting!
Not really.
I think its cool.
Can I go with you?
I hear something.
Hideko-chan!
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Can you stand up?
Give me a hand!
It was them, wasn't it?
They did this to you?
This is outrageous! Boys picking on
girls is despicable. Am I right?
Ahm... yes.
You should get angry, too!
I am.
No, you are not!
Yes, I am.
You got angry first,
so I might not look like I am angry,
But I am definitely angry.
Carry heron your back.
You are a boy, aren't you?
Yeah,I am...
I am all right now... I can walk...
You are still OK, Akira-kun?
Hideko-chan,
you can't let them get away with this.
Yeah...
You just can't.
You will lend a hand, Akira-kun?
Yeah.
Hideko!
What are you doing!
Late for paper route!
Where did you goof off?
I am sorry.
You are covered with mud.
I fell down.
Tezuka-san and Ohta-kun helped me.
You are so clumsy.
Thank you.
Hope you will be friends with her.
Yes, we will.
Oh, yes.
You missed meeting your father.
That's okay.
It's my fault.
No, it's not...
I didn't want to go, really.
You are kind.
I meant it.
Why don't we go somewhere now?
What do you mean somewhere?
I only have 500 yen.
Want to go to movies tomorrow?
What? The two of us?
Three, with Hideko-chan.
Oh, okay.
Hey, from now on
we are going to stand up for her.
But... I...
It's a promise.
"Rock-Pa per-Scissors"
Ch...o...co...la...te!
Rock-Paper-Scissors!
P...i...ne...app...le!
G...li...co!
Rock-Pa per-Scissors!
P...i...ne...app...le!
See you at school tomorrow.
Akira-kun, bye-bye!
That's her house?
It's gorgeous.
Ohta is on a date with Komuro!
You two are a good match... Yuk!
We got you, we got you!
Are you two dating?
A Wolf Girl and a Wolf boy!
Who are we going to tell?
Hideko?
Better get sleep or
you'll be late again tomorrow.
Yes.
Father will be back from work
in spring.
Then it will all be better.
Good night...
Good night.
"Akira and Hideko is in love."
Rumiko-chan,
tomorrow's Satomi-chan's birthday.
Well, Happy Birthday!
We are having a party.
I want you to come.
Oh, I can't.
I will skip school, too.
What? Why?
I am really sorry...
I bet she takes singing lessons.
But it's no reason to skip school.
"Wolf Girl"
Lovely couple!
Hey, Ohta.
You'll be a Wolf Boy, too.
Komuro, have 0hta's baby!
What?
Ouch! What is that for?
What!
Nothing.
Don't mind it.
Uh... here.
I thought it was amazing.
I've never used up pencils
that short.
Your Mom wrote your name?
Very nice mother.
I said something wrong, didn't I?
Well, where are we going?
Sort of heavy, this is.
This way.
What are we going to dig up?
Here.
Something buried here?
Show you the proper way
to use a scoop?
Bye bye.
Your mother has
started teaching knitting?
That's awesome.
My mother told me.
Let's do homework at my house.
I've got to be back home
early today.
Your mother is going to be late.
My mother says
you can have dinner with us.
Sorry, I am busy.
Divided by 3,
that's 17 remainder 1, right?
So 26 x 2/3 is 17 remainder 1.
Ah, right. You are right.
You should finish your homework
at school.
Talk of the impossible.
How deep are you going to dig?
All the way
to the core of the earth.
What if we find
the underworld people?
If we do,
Akira-kun would become a celebrity.
I don't want to be famous.
But that would show
those people that made fun of me.
Then it would be really great.
What!
You are...
The newspaper girl?
To our housing project.
Thank you for delivering.
You must be cold. Take this.
No, that is okay.
I want you to have it.
I teach knitting.
These are samples.
There are many more.
Don't be shy.
There are generous people.
Take good care of it.
No!! Don't scribble on it.
It is not yours! No scribbling!
I don't know!
But it looks the same to me.
It's not!
You are right... Pair mufflers
with Komuro, that is awful.
Yeah...
Akira-kun, wait for me!
Definitely the same mufflers.
Maybe the rumor is really true.
Right. Koichi-kun and the lot has
seen them together so many times.
Disgusting!
The two of them sucks!
Rumiko-chan, did you hear
about Ohta-kun and Komuro-san?
Yeah.
Stop it, Nobuko-chan.
She likes Ohta-kun.
Is that true?
I've been watching her,
so I know.
I like both Akira-kun
and Hideko-chan.
More than I like you girls.
Tezuka-san, digging today too?
I have a gift for you.
Wow, marvelous...
Is this for me?
Yes.
How about doing homework
at my house?
You are in love
with Komuro.
No way, right?
I will do my homework
with Masashi-kun today.
Thank you.
Your voice is loud.
Still here?
You dig this far alone?
Why are you here?
Enough for today.
It's getting dark.
I can dig by myself.
You can go home.
Let's go home together.
Sorry, I smudged it.
Don't mind it.
I'll pay for it.
I say don't mind it.
What are you doing?
You know what?
I hate it. It pricks me.
Let's go home...
An unexploded bomb, really?
I found it by chance.
Like you read in the papers.
What if it really explodes?
It will not.
I wanted to show you before
telling the police.
You seem to understand us, huh?
You can be in our group.
Over there.
Wait, Ko-chan.
Ko-chan, Ko-chan,
please come out.
Don't leave me alone.
What is going on, Ko-chan?
What are you doing, Ko-chan?
You, stop!
You can do it too.
But I...
Eye for an eye.
Stop!
We are being buried alive!
You do it too!
Stop! Please stop!
You won't call her
a Wolf Girl anymore?
None of my business!
Apologize to her!
I am sorry, I am sorry!
Not much injury to the children.
Their parents say
it was just a usual kid brawl.
I am really sorry, miss.
Ohta-kun.
You understand what I mean?
Your mother is not here?
Bringing my brothers,
so will be a little late.
Okay...
tell me when she is here.
Excuse us.
Mrs. Ohta, I am sorry!
You are...
I am truly sorry!
No, don't mind... It's also him.
Keep up your newspaper route.
Why did you hurt your friends?
He was standing up for
Komuro-san.
Why, Akira?
Whatever the reason,
you must never hurt others.
He didn't mean to hurt...
You stay out of this!
Answer me.
Did Tezuka-san, the new girl,
put you up to this?
That is not so, Akira?
You lost your tongue?
Hey...
Don't hit him!
What kind of a girl is she?
You shut up when it suits you.
When have you become
such a coward?
You didn't watch him good!
I left him in your charge!
He is not a baby anymore.
Do you expect me
to watch over every minutes?
Yes, that's what mothers are for!
Well,
what about the fathers, then?
I have my work!
Always work,
you never take the time for him.
How about you?
Not home and a bad mother!
I just teach a knitting class!
Akira and knitting,
which is more important?
Akira, of course!
Then quit knitting!
I have things I want to do!
You know much about Tezuka girl?
You don't know who's his friend!
Shut up!
I am sick and tired of all!
It's nothing to do with Mom
or Tezuka-san!
Akira !?
This is all?
No, Stop, please!
These are not things
you get from other people.
I am so heartbroken.
Sorry.
I am sorry.
I am sorry...
Sorry for calling late.
He is not at Masashi's
He'll be fine.
He doesn't have his jacket on.
Like father, like son...
Born to this earth,
this fabulous beauty,
I would like to hand her over
to you tonight.
Still a twenty something cute girl.
The thing is that she's got six legs.
Please doggy-bag our sushi.
Just octopus legs.
Hundred sushi from her legs alone.
Next up, a shocking act,
more so than the oil shock.
Please be aware,
it is a dangerous act.
Get ready for the next act please!
This one here, when not performing,
has other jobs.
You have seen him elsewhere.
Can't give you details,
the smaller monsters in movies...
He is in most of them.
Now,
we are ready for the show.
Just as advertised in the billboard,
Beast or human,
here is the Wolf Girl!
Oh, oh.
A sinister cage before you!
Don't worry,
it won't bite, so come closer.
But quietly, quietly,
it does react to noise.
So we open it slowly...
See it? Please, no sound.
See? Do you see? No? Not yet?
You don't see? Well then!
Especially for you tonight,
we will open the cage!
Normally she lives in this cage.
She still bites sometimes,
but tonight will be OK.
She feels easy
with this keeper lady.
OK, come out, come out!
This young girl eats
no rice or bread.
Still remembers
being raised by the wolves.
Her food is mostly
snakes and frogs alive.
We'll let you see her
eat in action.
My, so many audiences have her
little blood running.
She's been with us
for half a year now.
Yet I still misunderstand
her feelings?
Oh, no! Don't you bite me!
Let me go!
Let go, will you!
Akira-kun!
What's up?
We got a phone call from your mother.
Akira-kun, what is wrong?
I came to look for you.
You are a little strange
these days.
You don't play with me much,
but only with the girls.
I told your mother. You've been
strange since Tezuka-san came.
But I didn't mention you being
made to stand or about Komuro.
It was Tezuka-san.
The Wolf Girl... I saw her...
What are you saying?
Don't come near me!
Akira-kun!
Damn it!
Why?
Can't be!
Damn it!
Thought we'll be here
for the winter.
What is this suddenly?
You were upset about
not going to the bigger shrine.
I don't want to go anywhere.
If we stay here longer,
we'll starve.
I don't care...
I want to go to school.
There are schools where we go.
I don't want a new school.
I like it here. I want to STAY!
You can leave me here.
No one will take you in.
I can live on my own.
Stop it!
You are ten now. But still...
you are just ten, Hana-chan.
Akira!
Akira...
Got to rescue... the Wolf Girl...
Got to rescue her...
You were sleep for so long.
Be good and rest.
That is...
Untwining Father's one.
It's for you.
Why?
His was getting all worn out.
I am going to use
the unworn parts.
I don't want it.
Your favorite color.
I'll knit Father a new one
next year.
Dad's still
going to be here then?
Why, of course.
Not getting divorced?
Why would you think so?
But you were talking about it.
Oh, that was about
Father's colleague.
He was our matchmaker.
I will quit teaching
at Canary Fancy Store.
Why?
Rather knit and
wait for you at home.
Rumiko?
No granddaughter by that name.
This isn't the Tezuka residence?
We are the Tachibanas.
What are you doing?
I say, what are you doing?
None of your business!
Hey, wait...
...Want to know something juicy?
"Departure"
Which is next?
There.
Next?
Hideko-chan,
let me help you out.
Where is your house?
What?
I couldn't find it on the hills.
I am staying at a hotel now.
A hotel?
Top floor of a big hotel,
the view is great.
...you can come visit me.
You're my friend.
Stop it!
...you are just rich...
you pity me.
So you've been kind to me.
That is not it.
No more gifts!
Wait!
Hate you...
I hate you the most!
Morning.
Good morning.
...how's your bruises?
Ohta-kun still may not be
able to make it today.
Komuro-san will be late.
I know.
I thought you could
still stay here longer.
When will we tell?
Good morning.
We'll have a stay-over tonight.
Do you want to come?
...Got to go somewhere today.
Be on TV in Tokyo, maybe?
...Right.
You are a consummate liar,
aren't you?
You are the spectacle
at freak show.
You are the real Wolf Girl.
Awful.
Fooling them to earn money.
Masashi-kun told me.
Ohta-kun saw you there.
That's why you are nice to her.
Poor Komuro-san!
No, it's not!
No... It's not that.
Don't come near me! Disgusting!
It is not true!
Stop it, Wolf Girl!
It's all wrong!
Stop it!
She is bullying Mizuguchi-san!
You've got it wrong!
Yes.
Hello. How is Akira-kun?
...you are... Tezuka-san?
Yes, I am.
Come in. Its cold out there.
Just a second.
Akira... are you asleep?
I am sorry. He is still not well.
These are from school.
Thank you.
I knit this. If you like...
...I am not cold. Good bye.
Is this OK?
Don't you use the same books?
"Wolf Girl"
See Hanako the Wolf Girl.
This is her last performance!
By cruel fate or God's bidding?
Born deep inside
the wilderness of Hokkaido.
Left to die by her poor father.
The cute child was
brought up by wolves.
Better to have been
eaten up instead,
At age 10, and devours chickens,
snakes, frogs all alive...
I am off now.
"To Hideko-chan"
"So sorry you got scolded
by your Mom because of me..."
"I am sorry that I lied to you."
"I am not rich at all.
I don't have a father nor a mother."
"I never thought that I was lonely."
"But when I met your mother,
I felt envy for the first time..."
"If I had a mother
like yours or Akira-kun's,"
"how happy life would be..."
"I'm going now
to somewhere far away."
"Wanted to talk so much more
with you."
"I don't need the school bag,
so I want you to have it."
"I never pitied you, you know."
"I like you so much.
Thank you so much. Good bye."
What is it?
Katoh-san
Komuro-san
Naomi Takahashi-san
Mizuki Takahashi-san
Tukada-san
Tezuka-san
Nakagawa-san
Numata-san
Nogami-san
Handa-san
Fujishiro-san
Mamiya-san
Morishita-san
Yoshida-san
Teacher!
Yes, Naitoh-kun?
You said that we couldn't go to
the Show Tent, that still true?
It is not for school kids.
Then is it OK to be in the Show?
What do you want to say?
The Wolf Girl Show,
Hide-kc Komuro is in it.
Wolf Girl...?
See, the Wolf Girl!
Wolf Girl! Wolf Girl!
Stop it!
Who is saying this?
I hate these kind of lies!
It is not a lie. Toru saw it.
Come to the Teacher's Office later.
I heard Tezuka -san
was the Wolf Girl.
Akira-kun, I am sorry!
I too think that
Tezuka-san is the One.
Ridiculous!
Komuro is the Wolf Girl. Right, Toru?
Yeah!
Teacher!
I cannot be in the same class with her!
Me too!
Quiet! No howling!
Teacher!
No, Ohta-kun, you don't.
All wrong!
She isn't the Wolf Girl!
I went to see-t it! I just had to!
But Tezuka -san
isn't the Wolf Girl!
That's right! We saw wrong!
So Komuro is the Wolf Girl.
Definitely not Tezuka!
Quiet!
It isn't Komuro-san...
I went to see though
I was told not to.
But it wasn't Tezuka-san.
Not Komuro-san, too.
No one in our class.
Sit down.
Sit.
You two, too.
I thought
I would wait till the end.
But I will tell you now.
Tezuka-san is
transferring to another school.
Leaving this afternoon.
She said she had a short
but a wonderful time with you all.
And you are still calling her
a Wolf Girl?
Ohta-kun!
Let's go! To see Rumiko-chan!
Here.
Said good-bye to your friends?
I have no friends.
I want to leave now!
You begged not to go.
What is this change?
I said horrible things to Tezuka-san.
...Me too.
Thank you for everything.
Good-bye.
You okay, there?
She was so nice to me...
Hey!
I am sorry!
I didn't think well enough!
Ohta! Take it!
Tezuka's school bag!
Akira-kun, sorry I messed up!
Wait!
Tezuka!
Naitoh-kun...
Rumiko-chan!
Hideko-chan...!
Rumiko-chan, forgive me!
Stop the car!
Hideko-chan...
Rumiko-chan, forgive me!
Rumiko-chan, I am really sorry!
Thank you, Hideko-chan...
thank you.
Thank you...
Tezuka-san! Tezuka-san!
Tezuka-san!
Akira-kun! Akira-kun!
"Friends Forever" "Good Luck!"
Thank you... Thank you...