It's over.
I will always speak to you...
...and I don't mind if
you don't say anything.
Just because you went away, it doesn't
mean you're not here anymore.
Perhaps all I ever needed
was this gift.
The one you gave to me at the end.
WOMB
- Shall I read to you?
- No, thanks.
Good night, Grandpa.
Hi! I'm Tommy.
And you?
Rebecca.
Have you moved here?
No, my grandpa lives here,
I'm staying with him.
Rebecca, your grandfather's on the phone.
She's fallen asleep.
Shall I wake her up?
No. Not at all.
That's fine.
She's welcome to stay tonight.
Good night!
Tell me where we're going.
Up till now, he's only seen
blades of grass before.
It must seem like a
different planet to him.
Tomorrow we'll take him on the beach
and show him the sea.
I won't be here tomorrow.
I'm going away.
Are you going home?
- No.
- Where then?
- To Tokyo.
- Japan?
- What for?.
Mom's got a job there.
- We'll be living on the 72nd floor.
- 72nd?
That's high.
I have to go.
- Hi?
- Rebecca?
Where are you?
On the beach, I came out to look to the storm.
- When are you going tomorrow?
- I'm leaving at six, on the ferry.
I'll see you off, I've got a good idea.
- Rebecca?
- Yes, I'm here.
Tommy, hello?
Tommy?
It's time, Rebecca.
- Excuse me.
- What can I do for you?
- I've come to see Tommy.
- Oh, he hasn't lived here for a long time.
You look very familiar.
Have I metyou somewhere before?
I'm Rebecca.
Rebecca... The little girI,
thatwent to Japan?
For a while, Tommy nagged us
about going to Tokyo.
But then he forgot about it, luckily.
Where does he live now?
Do you know the little harbor
down by the embankment?
You'll find him there.
Hello?
Who are you?
What are you doing?
- I'm looking for Thomas.
- I'm Thomas.
Who are you?
Hi, Tom.
Hi.
Who is she?
How was Japan?
- Fine.
- 72 th floor.
So, let's try like normaI people.
I'm Rose, this is Tommy. And your name?
- Are you going back?
- No, I finished my degree.
- What did you study?
- Maths.
And now?
What do you do now?
I design software for sonar devices.
Sonar devices that detects tiny cracks
in underground storage tanks.
Like the kind used in petroI stations,
you know they sometimes crack.
CooI.
So Bingo letyou come in just like that?
I've never seen him do that,
he hates strangers usually.
Once he bit a girI's thigh,
though she menstruated.
- Maybe he liked your scent.
- Maybe.
Maybe you twojust start
sniffing each other?.
How many years is it?
- Twelve.
Maybe I should go.
Does Rose know thatyou're here?
I don't know.
She is your girlfriend, isn't she?
Girlfriend?
I met her yesterday for
the first time in my life.
How long is it since your
grandfather passed away?
Long time ago.
It's odd.
Seemed bigger in my mind.
Do you remember that night, when
you had an idea...
...and you didn't turn up?
Whatwas your idea, do you remember?.
I thoughtyou'd never ask.
I wanted to give him to you that morning.
Tokyo would have been
a great adventure for him.
I fed him, for about a year actually,
after you left.
He managed to eat and shit
at the same time.
Which is impressive.
He looked too good.
And one day, he didn't
appear anymore.
He was dead.
Why didn'tyou come?
I overslept.
But now I'm awake.
You're cold.
Weird.
I know.
Yeah.
- What are you doing this weekend?
- Same as you.
I can't do it.
- I have to go away.
- I'll come with you.
I have to go alone.
It'll only be two days.
Where were yo go, I go.
This is somewhere you can't go.
Then you shouldn't go either.
They simply drained the marsh...
...and caught it thousands of tons of
reinforced concrete over there.
They built in six months, which is a record.
On paper, it's a wellness center.
They've called it Sparkling Park.
Profitwill mainly come from
cyber-prostitution, you know...
...cyber-bitches, the plastic surgery,
cloning of domestic animals.
They opened lastweek.
This will be their firstweekend,
or rather our weekend...
...because our group will
be there too.
Group?
Pollungroup. A militant environmentaI
activist group.
Itwill be a planned action,
with 23 participants.
We go inside, we cause
mass hysteria Rebecca...
...I'm telling you, mass hysteria,
thus diverting the security guards.
Now, meanwhile outside, the other guys
were blocked the enterance and...
...exit to the carpark with a quick
setting cement pooI.
You know quick-cement?
No? Fine, don'tworry about it.
- Anyway, then the media will turn up...
- How do you do that, mass hysteria?
Ready?
You see those rucksacks? We're going to release
the cockroaches from those in the shops.
Around the pools and the restaurants, just
depending on the where the largest crowd are, really.
"Sparkling Park"
I've got six ruckssacks.
- Where are you going? - Away.
- What's all of this you're carrying?
Backpacks.
- Do you want to come in for a coffee?
- No, no, not now.
Well, do I even get a kiss?
- What?
- I love your plan. Did you think it up all by yourself?
A- ha, yeah, of course.
What?
I am but a simple cockroach breeder Rebecca.
I hope that makes me good enough for you.
I've always dreamt of meeting
a cockroach breeder.
I need to pee.
- How badly?
- Badly.
"I will wait for you,
for as long as it takes. "
- I can not eat Rebecca, I'm sorry.
- - At least sit down.
At least sit down.
I can't sit, either.
Would you tell us please
why you invited us here?
Of course.
He could be here with us again.
Again? Who, Thomas?
Who would give birth to him?
Ralph.
We are atheists...
...and we brought up Thomas
as an atheist.
But that does not mean we could rummage
in our deceased's grave and clone them.
We are not farm animals.
We acceptwhat life gives us...
...and also what it takes away.
But...
Butwhat?
But life has also given us
this opportunity.
This gift.
Don'tyou see?
If I were you Rebecca,
I would repaint this room white.
Ralph?
Thank you.
Would you like us to move away?
No, stay.
He loved the sea,
he'll love it again.
As for us, there is no way we can stay here.
We're moving next week.
Okay.
Thank you, Ralph.
Rebecca...
...have a good think about it.
You can still change your mind.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- How old is your baby?
- Three months.
Do you want some pie?
Baked it myself.
Thanks, but not now.
I have to go to home.
- Okay.
- Bye. - Bye.
It's alright, baby.
Eat, sweetheart.
It'sjust us two.
Tommy?
Come out for a bit, I want to tell you something.
- What?
- Come out darling.
I know. I know I'll be going to
primary schooI and I go on Monday.
Yes, on Monday, you'll go to
primary schooI. But now come out.
I can see you okay from in here.
I have to speak to you
aboutyour daddy.
Your daddy died in a car
accident before you were born.
- Really?
- Yes.
- I thought he went back to his home planet.
- His home planet?
- Yes.
- Your father was from this planet.
That's a shame.
Listen Thomas.
Your father was reaI,
he was a student in biology.
And he was hit by a car.
Do you understand?
A man of words and not of deeds
is like a garden full of weeds.
And when the weeds begin to grow,
It's like a garden full of snow.
And when the snow begins to fall,
it's like a bird upon the wall.
And when the bird away does fly,
it's like an eagle in the sky.
And when the sky begins to roar,
it's like a lion at the door.
And when the door begins to crack,
it's like a stick across your back.
And when your back begins to smart,
it's like a penknife in your heart.
And when your heart begins to bleed,
you're dead, and dead, and dead indeed...
I keep dying.
Try again.
Mom?
Eric's staying over tonight.
Hi.
Can I getyou anything?
Hi, Mom.
Look at that little rabbit.
It's lovely.
What's your name?
I Dima, and that breast.
- - Snow Lump orjust Lump?
- - Just Lump.
Well, we're off.
Bye, Tommy, see you.
Wouldn'tyou like to come and
play at our house Dima?
No, thank you.
- I can smell it. What aboutyou?
- I could.
What did you smell?
- The copy smell.
- What?
Copy smell. Copies have a
weird smell.
- Where did you hear that?
- Oh mom, everyone knows that.
They smell like window cleaner.
It comes from their skin.
So?
Eric says thatyou invited
little Dima into your home.
Yes.
Why?
Look Rebecca, we don't have any
problem with human repliaction...
...we think that some clones
are decent people
they have their own lives and rights...
The thing is, it's too complicated
for our kids.
Now we hear about these things in the news
all the time, but quite frankly...
we do notwant our children coming up
against these things first hand.
Neither do you, I suppose.
Dima is the victim of
artificiaI incest.
Her mother gave birth to her own mother.
Did you know that?
So, if you'd known, you obviously wouldn't
have invited her into your home, would you?
No, of course not.
I'm gonna go now.
Come on Eric.
Come and give me a hand Tommy.
It's your party after all.
Hi.
Molly, it's Rebecca. I justwanted to
make sure you got the invitation?
But he...
I see.
Happy birthday, Tommy.
- But the others aren't...
- There'll just be the two of us, my love.
Two?
Butwhy?
- The others aren't coming.
- Why aren't they coming?
Because of the copy?
Butwe didn't invite the copy,
we didn't invite her on purpose.
Why aren't they coming mom?
Please?
- Mom!
- Because the mothers...
Their mothers were not allowed.
Why not?
- Because they are stupid.
- Stupid?
Where we going, Mom?
This is exactly how I imagined it.
- Do you like it?
- Yes.
CooI, it's like the end of the world.
Mom?
Come quickly.
I thought they were extinct long ago.
Can I take one home?
Home?
That's where we are, Tommy.
Tommy?
I'm back.
You can look.
- CooI!
- What are you gonna call him?
I don't know.
Bingo?
No.
Booboo.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Thanks, Mom.
Hi, I'm Mark.
We are neighbors.
- Can I see in your binoculars?
- Sure.
Come on.
And you there when Father died?
Yes.
- How did it happen?
- What made you think of it now?
I do not know.
You know, itwas an accident.
What sort of accident?
We were on the road, we stopped,
he got out of the car...
- ... and another car hit him.
- What sort of car?.
Van, Tommy, coming very fast.
- What sort of van?
- I do not know.
Why did you stop?
- Why did you stop?
- I had to pee.
Now I can do whatever I wantwith you.
Go ahead.
Tommy?
Good night, Mom.
Good night, Tommy!
Everything will be alright my love.
Good morning!
Mom...
Weird. I was in university...
...I was a rusty tin...
...or not even a tin,
but some kind of container.
I moved to creak, as the old job.
When I lent down, this rusty sort of
liquid flow through my mouth.
Itwas cooI.
Good morning!
Mom, this is Monica.
Monica, mom.
- Hi.
What did you dream about?
Nothing.
Enjoy.
Did we wake you when
we came in last night?
- I wasn't asleep.
- But itwas dawn.
Did you ever sleep, Mom?
Sometimes.
Monica went out for couple of things,
she'll be back soon.
She'll be living here for a while, I mean
of course only if you don't mind.
Mom?
She is a nice girI.
Pleased to have her here.
...after thought?
I love thinking about this.
Imagine great snow storms over the oceans,
in the mountains, deep in the clouds...
for millions of years on this planet,
...billions of tiny snow crystals have
been whirling about...
...and no two of the are same.
Just like us in fact.
- As people?
- Yeah, as two.
I was thinking of all living things,
notjust our faces and our fingerprints.
villus in our lungs, our irises,
the structure of our brains...
...and nails, you know,
everything about us.
I mean, think about, how long are birds here?
They came not long after dinosours.
Basicly, way before us. Can you imagine,
how many billions of feathers they produce...
From ostrich to terns, to hummingbirds,
from penguins
Everywhere in the world.
It must be an orbitaI thing.
A billion times of billion times of billion,
you know...
There are no two alike.
This is a duck's feather.
It's almost incomprehensible, billions
of amazingly complex patterns...
...permanently whirling around us
and never repeat themselves.
What's the matter?.
I don't know Tommy...
This is so...
...so immature.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
So?
- So what?
- Do you like kids?
Come in.
Hi Mom.
Smells great, doesn't it?
Monica baked it, I was the kitchen boy.
- He is a very good kitchen boy.
- Thank you very much.
Thanks.
- I'm not hungry now, I'll have it later.
- Okay.
Mom.
Good night!
I don't think she's been up for the day.
- I think you should talk to her.
- And what shall I say it?
Mom?
It's you.
Wait.
- Hang on.
- Why?
I have to take a shower.
Let's take one together.
Tommy, don't.
No, no!
No.
Stop it.
- Wait.
- What? What's wrong?
I think she woke up.
Aren'tyou going to say anything?
Hello.
Can I help you?
Go inside now Tommy.
Who are you?
Who is that, Mom?
Mom.
Who was thatwoman, Mom?
Tommy?
I know her.
Let me in, please.
You've been in there for hours.
Please, open the door.
I'm leaving.
Mom?
I have to tell you something.
I was nine,
I was on the beach...
Itwas so cold.
- Then I met this boy?
- What, what, what boy?
What beach? Who cares?
Who is this woman, Mother?.
No! No!
No!
I'm scared.
I do not know who you are.
Or who I am either.
Who are you, Mom?
Who are you?
Why did you do it?
Why did you do this thing?
- Look atyourself, Tommy, you're here.
- So? So? So?
What am I supposed to do now?
What am I supposed to do with this fucking life?
Don'tyou see I have no idea who I am!
Can'tyou understand?
- What more could you want?
- More than what?
You're here, Tommy.
You're alive
Take your hands off me.
Who are you?
Thank you...
...Rebecca.