NETFLIX PRESENTS
[man in French] It's funny
you mention your kid.
-I had a dream last night.
-[driver] Yeah?
What was it about?
I'll tell you, but you can't tell anyone.
-[driver] You know I wouldn't.
-That's why I'll tell you. I trust you.
I dreamed that…
I saw my biological mother
and biological father in my sleep.
-[driver] Did they have faces?
-I can't remember if they did.
[driver] Did you remember
when you woke up?
The dream, yes, but not the faces.
I've actually been thinking that I…
It's been on my mind for a while…
-[driver] To know who it is?
-Yeah.
With every interview, I wonder…
Every time that…
Can you imagine?
Do you think my mom sees them?
When I do all these things on TV,
do you think she can see
that it's her son?
Can you sense something like that?
I'm 30.
Let's say my life expectancy
is between 80 and 90 years,
100 if things go really well.
That means I'll spend the next 60 years…
never knowing where I'm from.
[applause]
[crowd cheering]
IN 2011, AGED 24,
OLIVIER ROUSTEING BECAME
CREATIVE DIRECTOR OF BALMAIN.
HE IS THE YOUNGEST CREATIVE DIRECTOR
SINCE YVES SAINT-LAURENT.
BALMAIN SAW A SIXFOLD TURNOVER INCREASE
BETWEEN 2011 AND 2018 THANKS TO HIM.
[indistinct chatter]
[applause]
[crowd chatter]
IN 1985, OLIVIER WAS BORN
TO AN UNIDENTIFIED MOTHER IN FRANCE…
MOM
[phone rings]
-[Mom] Hello?
-Hi, Mom. It's Olivier.
-Hi, sweetheart.
-How are you?
-Fine, and you?
-Yes, I'm fine.
Is your desire
stronger than your reason?
-That's something else, you see?
-Yes.
So, you can create an image yourself.
If you liked the image,
perhaps you imagined faces
for these people.
-Yeah.
-What was your mother like?
Mixed-race? Dark skin? Light skin?
She had very dark skin.
Very dark. And your father?
Very white.
Yes, that's something we were told…
That's what I can't understand.
Do you have any information
I'm not aware of?
No, that's the only… You can ask Dad.
It's the only thing I know.
I only mention this man
because you're talking about your dream.
You're sure that…
What I mean is that I'd like--
Olivier, if there was anything…
I swear,
if I knew something,
I would tell you.
[Olivier] I'd like to start
looking into it after the show.
[Mom] That'll be… Okay.
I feel like, with everything I've managed
to achieve in the last few years,
it's the right time.
The more I know where I'm going,
the more I need to know where I'm from.
[Olivier] I love the waistline it creates.
[in English] No? You like?
-[woman grunts and chuckles]
-[Olivier] Mm-hm.
[in French] Incredible.
[phone rings]
But do you have both feet?
Even if there's only one…
Okay, sure.
Try to check with him.
Some pairs must be ready.
-No, the pairs arrive tomorrow.
-[woman 2] Okay.
-[in English] Have a nice weekend,
-[woman 2] Tomorrow?
[in French] Ah! Are you working tomorrow?
-This is new!
-It's not certain.
[In English] See you tomorrow?
-For once, I won't be alone in the office!
-[In French] Would 14:30 work for you?
-Perfect.
-To relaunch some pieces?
But we'll reschedule lunch.
[Olivier in English] Thank God
someone is working on a Saturday!
[outbound text whooshes]
["Running Up that Hill"
by Kate Bush playing on stereo]
[indistinct chatter]
[French music playing in headphones]
[in French] Well, she's nice, isn't she?
[radio presenter in English] …2018.
This program includes a long conversation…
["Running Up that Hill"
by Kate Bush continues playing on stereo]
[French music playing in headphones]
[upbeat music playing in headphones]
[female podcast host in French] She said,
"I thought as we grew up, we became white,
and therefore pretty."
["Running Up that Hill"
by Kate Bush continues playing on stereo]
[Olivier in English] Do this.
[in French] No, you--
[in English] No, no, it's fine.
[in French] I love it!
SPRING-SUMMER 18
[in English] Picture.
[in Italian] Life is great!
I'm finally doing Balmain!
[in French] Stop! No!
[ in English] No, stop!
[laughter]
[in French] It's great.
[giggling]
[cheering]
My parents will be so emotional.
[Olivier] They made me cry
before the show.
It's family pride.
-[driver] They're happy for you.
-Yeah.
[Olivier] It's not a question of pride.
It's that they…
They get too emotional.
[driver] And then you do too.
I don't cry with my parents,
but if I see my grandfather crying…
That makes me cry.
Or my grandmother.
[indistinct chatter]
She doesn't want to lose me.
-That doesn't work.
-[driver] Yes, it does.
I have to prepare my finale.
Leave me in peace.
[upbeat music plays]
It puts me in a good mood, this song.
[woman] We're cutting through
the demonstration.
Okay? We're cutting through.
[indistinct speech]
The windows are tinted, right?
-[driver] No one can see you.
-Okay.
[driver] You can let yourself go.
Look!
[man in English] Okay, everyone step back.
[in French] You okay?
What's happening?
It's fine. Go for it. No belt!
Hands in your pockets.
Let me do it.
Shit! The belt's on the outside.
[woman in English] Nearer up!
She's next, she's next!
[in French] Shit!
[man] She has to get out there.
-Go!
-Shit! Go on.
If one's not ready, move on to the next.
[Olivier] No, not Natalia!
-[Olivier in English] Okay?
-[man] Go!
[in French] It's never been like this
backstage before.
-It's your most beautiful collection.
-You think?
[in English] Oh, Olivier!
-Hi! How are you?
-Good, you?
[indistinct chatter]
-Sorry I'm so sweaty.
-I know.
-That was amazing.
-You liked it?
-You're a genius.
-Thank you.
[indistinct chatter]
-[in French] Did you like it?
-Beautiful!
Very beautiful. The colors…
[in English] Twenty years ago, I was
ten years old and I came with my parents,
and I've been impressed and amazed
by the beauty of Paris,
the beauty of, of the Opéra,
so, I wanted, today, to celebrate…
[in French] I've searched
through all the files at home…
But… Yeah.
I-- I mean…
That's why I feel sad,
because I know he's looking
and I have nothing to give him.
You know?
I can't give him information
I don't have and never will have.
-And I won't make up a nice story.
-You're helping him nevertheless.
So, it's a little…
You did what had to be done.
Now we wait for the file.
[in English] No, he's that way.
[in French] Tell him
I went to the children's home
I adopted him from.
There's no one left from when…
And the people who work there now…
They don't even know
the staff from before.
When I got there, I was in tears.
Going through those gates again…
It was hard.
-It was good.
-We did it.
-Not bad.
-It's a bit too much…
-Yes, it's noisy.
[in English] Open tour!
[crowd chatters]
[inaudible speech]
[man on phone in French] I'm listening.
[Olivier] I just wanted to say…
The dinner was good, right?
[man on phone] Oh, yes. It was good.
-[Olivier] But…
-[man on phone] It was very good.
-[Olivier] Were Grandpa and Grandma happy?
-[man on phone] Yes, they were very happy.
[Olivier] Don't you think
Mom's acting weird?
[man on phone] I know why.
I'll tell you. It's because…
we talked about your adoption
this evening.
The strangest thing about her
is the way she's reacting
to my adoption now.
I don't understand the mixed messages
that I'm getting from you guys.
You said you were sure
there was something, and Mom--
[man on phone] Yes,
I'm sure there's a letter.
But it might not be important,
what's in it, I mean.
They told us there were things
that concerned Olivier,
but not us.
That's important,
because Mom never said that.
That's what I'm saying.
At some point,
she went to see
a hypnotist and a psychic…
-But that's just--
-Yeah, but that's not based on anything.
And this woman,
she's the one who told us,
with her pendulum,
what we wanted to know.
[in English] Whatever.
[in French] The Health and Welfare Office
called me.
They found my file,
and there's something in it.
So…
Great! I'm very happy for you!
What did they tell you to do?
They called me to tell me they found it.
The woman was quite strange.
I asked if there was anything in the file,
and she said yes.
"It might not answer all your questions,
but you'll definitely find some answers."
-[in English] Are you ready for it?
-[in French] I don't know.
I can't…
Seeing pictures in the file
would get to me the most.
[woman on phone] …a satisfaction survey
that you can accept or decline.
The Department of Gironde
thanks you for your participation.
I'm looking for my biological parents.
Someone contacted me to let me know
that my file should be arriving,
and I wanted to know
if you had an idea of when that would be.
[man on phone] Well,
this is the main office for Gironde.
-Your name, please?
-Rousteing, Olivier.
-[woman on phone] Hello?
-Yes, hello.
My name is Olivier Rousteing.
I'm calling, because someone
from your office called me
to let me know that you'd found my file,
and I'd like to know when it will arrive.
-Has it been found or not?
-It seems it has, yes.
Someone called me
to let me know it had been found,
and so I'm calling to find out
when it will be sent… to your office.
-Who called you?
-A woman.
No… A woman, okay.
-You don't have a name?
-No. No name.
A first name?
No first name or last name.
She called and told me
they'd found my file,
and that I had to call back
on the same number
to find out when it would arrive.
So I wanted to know if it had arrived,
and if you had any information.
Okay, I'll look,
but I don't know who called, so…
Can I take your details?
We have it here,
but I'm not sure who's handling it.
You received my file?
I can see that it's been logged,
but I haven't seen it myself.
I don't know who it's been assigned
to read it through with you.
-I'll call you back.
-Okay.
[Olivier] Hello?
-[woman on phone] Mr. Rousteing?
-Yes?
I'm calling you back as we discussed.
Listen… After checking, it turns out
I was wrong. It hasn't arrived.
-It's been requested from the archives.
-Okay.
So, we're waiting
to hear back from the archives.
Okay.
As soon as we have the file,
we'll send you a letter
indicating the staff members available
to read through the file with you.
Okay.
We'll have to wait.
Do you know when it might arrive?
We don't know that.
We can't control the delay, sir.
[chattering voices]
-[in English] Balmain VS. Yeah!
-Yeah!
Okay, do it, do it.
But do it seriously!
Yeah. Do it, do it!
Hi, guys. Today's the VS and Balmain show
all together.
…like a dream. And
I kind of feel emotional about it,
but it's gonna be amazing.
-Okay!
-Thank you, Cosmo. Love you guys!
Thank you very much.
[upbeat music playing]
[man] What do you wanna see?
-[man] Like something with culture--
-[Olivier] Something really chill.
We can just, like, relax
and something like… You know?
What about this? Like, one thing…
-Like, this is an antique market.
-This is nice.
Like something more modern.
Where young people hang out.
It's so cold.
-It's freezing.
-Hm?
It's freezing.
[Olivier] Are we still, in 2017,
telling me
that my casting is really diverse?
Of course it's diverse,
but it's actually normal.
You know?
And that's what I think is sad, is that
my casting is much more different
than the others.
I think what should be the question
is to the others
and say,
"Why your casting is not diverse?"
You know what I mean?
I think we should switch the question.
Because my casting is normal.
My casting is just a reflection
of what's in the world today.
Maybe the casting
of some other fashion shows are wrong.
[Olivier in French] I'm afraid to leave,
because I'm more afraid of going home.
I've realized that, whenever I travel,
a sense of solitude starts to grow in me
and intensifies when I get home.
The people in the lobby say,
"I'm going to see my boyfriend,
my family, my children."
And I ask myself what I'm going to do.
I'm going to lock myself in my office
to continue my collections.
It's interesting when you think about it.
All that people see of me
is what I've created myself,
and I think I got a bit lost
in…
In this deep solitude, really.
What I'm most scared of
is that I'm not that old
and now, when I'm supposed to have fun,
I'm not enjoying myself.
I'm constantly in control.
I'd like to say,
"I'm going home this weekend."
"I'm going home Thursday morning at six
and someone will be waiting."
When, in fact…
Mohammed is waiting for me.
Who am I doing it for?
When your parents don't want you,
you wonder what you're doing here.
I realize I'm actually scared
about this film ending.
What will the last scene be?
Will my life just go on like before?
[Olivier in English] Now, girls,
start moving.
Yeah, okay. Now start to just…
[laughter]
[In French] It's going too fast.
At least, I…
At least I had airbags in the back.
Yes, hello?
[Woman on phone] We've received your file.
-Are you able to come to Bordeaux?
-Absolutely.
Let me know a time, and I'll come.
I don't know…
We have to decide together.
-I don't want to impose a date.
-No, but…
What I mean is
I want to see my file as soon as possible.
Will you be coming
for the Christmas holidays?
Absolutely.
-When will you arrive?
-I actually arrive on the 24th.
I'm arriving very late.
So, you arrive on the 24th…
And how long are you staying?
Until the 26th.
I'm very scared my file will be empty.
In your file, you have
your data.
The document completed
when your birth mother handed you over.
So there's nothing.
What would you call nothing?
I won't find out the identity
of my biological mother.
Yes, you will. In the document…
Well, you'll see.
But, yes,
there is information on your mother.
It might not end up
being everything you'd hoped,
but we can't call it nothing.
Okay. Is there any information
on my biological father?
There's no identity,
but there is some information.
Okay.
-You'll see for yourself.
-Of course.
It's hard to say in advance
where it will lead you. We don't know.
Okay. Thank you very much.
-Thank you. See you Friday.
-Yes, see you on the 22nd.
-[Olivier] Hello.
-[woman] Hello.
-I'm Mrs. Lamothe.
-[Olivier] Pleased to meet you.
[Mrs. Lamothe] Take a seat… here.
Okay…
-You've come a long way.
-Yes.
-Not too tiring?
-No, I'm okay.
You're okay? Do you feel ready?
I don't know.
Do you ever actually feel ready?
Okay. We'll take it slow.
So, here we go.
You'll be able… to read through your file.
This is a process you began
several years ago.
Yes, I came when I was young.
I was 16, I think.
-In 2001, I think?
-Yeah.
And… when I saw that the last name
I used wasn't my birth name,
my family name,
I couldn't get over it.
I just couldn't imagine that
there was another Olivier
before Olivier Rousteing.
-So, yeah.
-Okay.
After you sent this letter to our office,
you didn't then have a meeting
-with anyone… to discuss it?
-No.
So this is your first time
going through this process.
-Okay.
-But, I mean, it's…
I wanted to do it before,
but I didn't feel ready.
I'm not sure you can ever be ready.
But I really want to find out, so…
Do you have any particular expectations?
My first hope is to see…
what my parents look like.
But that won't happen today.
To understand where I'm from. My origins.
Because I grew up without really…
Without really knowing
why my skin is this color.
Um, I also want to know why…
I was given up for adoption.
So I hope…
[Mrs. Lamothe] We don't know
if it was your mother who named you
or if the maternity staff
gave you your name.
You were born at Pellegrin Hospital.
No paternity was acknowledged.
The baby was a natural child.
That means you were born out of wedlock,
outside of a legitimate union.
So…
the different handwriting might mean
that your mother filled some of it in.
Okay?
We can try to find out who filled in--
There are spelling mistakes.
[Mrs. Lamothe] There are
spelling mistakes, but, well…
-She must have been young.
-[Mrs. Lamothe] Indeed.
So… perhaps she filled in part of this.
-So--
-That's a child's handwriting.
[Mrs. Lamothe] She was Catholic,
and she wrote like a young child, yes.
"Was he baptized? No."
"Place of birth: Pellegrin Hospital."
"State of health of the infant: Good."
It wasn't necessarily your mother
who filled this in.
-It must have been done later.
-Mm-hm.
You were born a little prematurely.
-[sniffs] Ah! Cool.
-Yes.
You were fed with a bottle.
Again, she didn't fill that in.
Next… So…
As for information on your birth mother…
Here, I've covered up
the day and month of birth.
Those are identifying elements
that we can't…
At your current stage,
we can't share that information with you.
Oh, really?
[Mrs. Lamothe] However,
she was born in 1970--
-Hold on. In 1970, so--
-[Mrs. Lamothe] In Djibouti.
-You were--
-She was 15?
[Mrs. Lamothe] She was 15.
[he exhales]
[Mrs. Lamothe] Yes, she was 15.
[he sniffs]
That's awful!
[he gasps]
[Mrs. Lamothe] You didn't think
she was so young?
[he sobs]
That's terrible!
What seems terrible to you?
Fifteen, I mean…
-She was so young!
-[Mrs. Lamothe] Yes.
Yes, but you know, at 15…
It is very young. That's true.
How old did you think she was?
-You knew she was very young.
-Yes, but…
[Mrs. Lamothe] You weren't imagining
a teenager.
[he sniffs]
No.
[Mrs. Lamothe] So the biological father
was 25.
Your mother, 15 and a half years old.
Big age gap.
[Mrs. Lamothe] Yes.
She got pregnant before she was 15.
But we don't know--
It's not indicated,
but, if she had agreed to disclose it,
she could have indicated
whether it was a romantic
or non-consensual relationship.
-But… it doesn't say.
-[he sniffs]
-Okay.
-He was a young Ethiopian man.
That tells you something else
about your roots.
-He was unemployed.
-Mm-hm.
[Mrs. Lamothe] That's all there is.
"Has she been made aware
that registration as a ward of the state
is only definitive after three months,
and that she can request the child
be returned to her before then? Yes."
"Does the mother seem attached
to the child,
and are there grounds to believe
she may request they be reunited?"
There's no information provided here.
As you'll see below,
she didn't ask…
She didn't try…
to establish a relationship.
"Does the mother wish to remain anonymous
for the child's entire life? Yes."
So, this here is really what allows us…
to consider this file
a request for anonymity on her part.
That's why I covered up
certain pieces of information.
Because she specifies
"for the child's entire life."
That said, in light of the current law,
we might be able to see
if she'll reconsider this decision,
and ask her if, now,
she is in a position
to review this decision,
and if she wishes…
And if you do too, of course.
If you both wish to take this step.
You have to make the request.
"She arrived in France in July
with her sisters and brother,
all younger than her…"
So she was the eldest.
"…and her mother, to settle in Bordeaux,
where her uncle lives."
"Her parents are separated."
"The mother and uncle know…"
About the pregnancy, that is.
"…but not her siblings,
and she does not want them to."
She hid her pregnancy
from her brothers and sisters.
"She does not wish to discuss the father,
whom she barely knew, it seems."
"She was in seventh grade in Djibouti."
"She is going to a private
vocational college to study IT."
"She had a C-section
since her pelvis was too narrow."
"She did not see the child."
So the birth was…
-Not easy.
-[Mrs. Lamothe] Not easy.
A C-section, because she was young,
and her build was probably
very slim, a little bit like you. So…
Here's what she was able to write
about her reasons.
"I'd like to continue my studies
without looking after
or thinking about a child."
She must have written that.
There's a mistake here too.
"Mother of Somalian origin."
So…
you are of Somalian and Ethiopian origin.
-Okay. Wow.
-There you go.
When you're adopted, well, given up…
Like many people, you make up stories,
especially being a person of color
in a white family.
I imagined many things.
But…
some are dreams and some are nightmares.
What I learned today is more…
It's a pretty sad story.
Well, it could have been
a real love story.
We just don't know.
If it was a love story,
she'd have spoken about it.
Not necessarily.
[gentle piano music plays]
[indistinct conversation]
My grandson.
Isn't he beautiful!
Look at him later on, older.
Was your dad there?
No, no one knows.
-Your mom doesn't know?
-No. No one.
Not even your mom! Goodness.
-So, you--
-It has to be hush-hush.
-Yes, hush-hush.
-Hush-hush!
[laughter]
I don't want them to know, because then,
I would've had to go see them,
and I don't have time.
-Oh, okay then.
-I'm going back to Paris.
I'm not sharing you.
-I can have you to myself.
-All for him!
From Sunday, you're going to have
45,000 people here, no?
No!
Eighteen or 20.
Yeah, it's not…
-You know a lot of them.
-And a lot I don't know!
Not many!
I don't know who he is! A singer…
-[Olivier] Yeah!
-It's…
-[Olivier] Maître Gims.
-Maître Gims, that's it!
I was trying to get it.
[Grandmother] We can't sit together
on the armchair.
No.
He fell asleep!
Scooch over!
Sit down next to me.
"Grandma, I'm coming
to the supermarket with you!"
He was this big.
His mother would get up
and she'd say, "He's gone!"
Oh man…
[he sighs]
Yeah…
-I have a headache.
-You do?
-I just take one?
-Yes.
-If you can.
-What did you give me?
-Paracetamol.
-Is that okay?
Yes! It's…
[she chuckles]
I'm not trying to poison you!
Enjoy the cake,
and find a good spot for the photo.
Take it with you. It's not for you?
No, it's for you!
Grandpa will eat it
in the morning or tonight.
[Olivier] It's crazy,
because I've always dreamed…
of having this in front of me…
but I never knew…
I always thought I'd be
so strong that I'd control my emotions,
that I'd be able to anticipate,
whatever the answers were,
and now, I feel like I'm…
I don't feel free…
Yet.
I have to look in the mirror,
and say I'm from this continent,
these countries…
But there are no pictures.
One thing touched me today
that felt really… nice.
It's really dumb.
She said my mother was very slim
and that, ultimately,
unfortunately for her,
her youth and her size
prevented her from…
actually giving birth to me.
But it's the first time
I've ever been told I look like someone.
Actually… when I opened it, I just wanted
to take her in my arms and say,
"I understand you. It'll be over soon."
"It's just a fucking dream."
"You'll wake up, and it'll be over."
Then I said to myself…
maybe one day she'll see this film.
-Suzanne?
-[woman] Can you come help us? Yes?
[man] Is it okay?
Yes, but they'll put that…
-Yes, you're right.
-It should…
[woman] It's going to be like that
afterwards.
There's also a button to fasten it.
[she laughs]
-I was like, "Okay, perfect!"
-[woman] I'm going to take it.
-[man] Where do I put the embroidery?
-We're shooting upstairs.
[indistinct chatter]
No.
[Olivier] I'm calling because I received
a call from Mrs. Lamothe.
It's Olivier Rousteing.
I was wondering… if I could talk to her.
[man on phone] Of course.
I'll put you through.
Children's Services?
-Yes, please.
-Okay. I'll connect you.
[recorded female voice] …the full program
at archives.gironde.fr.
-[Olivier] Hello. Happy New Year!
-[Mrs. Lamothe] To you too!
Yes, it was quite
an unusual end to the year.
I wanted to thank you again
for the support that
you gave me.
It meant a lot.
I thought long and hard
after our conversation,
and I'm ready to take
the next step towards finding her.
Okay.
I'll try…
This weekend,
I'll fill in the form you gave me.
Do I send it to you?
Who should I send it to?
Send it directly to the National Council
for Accessing Personal Origins in Paris.
-Yes.
-And to save time,
I'll send… an email
to Mrs. Anat, the…
She runs the department
that deals with the files.
We work with her a lot.
I'll let her know in advance,
and send her the documents right away.
We'll save time that way.
If I send it to her directly…
Okay.
…then they can start the investigation.
It can take some time.
Yes, I imagine.
But if your birth mother
is still in France,
she might still be in Gironde,
or in another region.
Or she could no longer be with us.
Yes, sure, but…
that can be verified very quickly.
I'll take care of things on my end,
and keep you updated if there's any news.
No problem. I'm available anytime.
Thanks again, Mrs. Lamothe.
-Bye. Have a good day.
-You're welcome. Bye.
All good?
[indistinct chatter]
[man] That's the boy
who had the missing look.
I mean, I know it was bad,
and he was extremely nervous, but…
You know? We were lucky, we could say.
Have you spoken to your mom
since her birthday?
On the phone?
No…
Well, we spoke for two or three seconds.
[man] She just sent a text.
She says to have a good show
and enjoy blowing off steam tonight.
I think she misses you.
[dramatic music plays]
[applause]
-[in English] You liked it?
-I loved it. It felt like…
-Blade Runner, future and bold.
-That was it. Mad Max.
-[Orlando] Mad Max, all of it. I loved it.
-[Olivier] Cool!
[in French] Hi! Happy New Year!
-To you too.
-Thank you.
-Welcome.
-[man] This is my first Balmain show.
-Really?
-[man] These boys are quite extravagant.
Yes, they're very extravagant. It's…
We love adding masculinity
to our womens wear.
Women wearing men's jackets.
But you never hear
about men also wearing clothes
translated by the codes of femininity.
That's what interested me.
[man in English] I mean…
[Olivier In French] "Father married
or unmarried to mother. Unmarried."
"Date and place of birth, nationality:
25 years old, Ethiopian."
"Profession: Unemployed."
"Current residence." Nothing.
"Health." Nothing.
"Other information." Nothing.
[man] It's also possible
she just didn't want
to provide the information.
"She does not wish to discuss the father,
whom she barely knew, it seems."
The only thing…
The only important thing to know
is if she was with him willingly.
That's what you want to know.
[in English] Anyway, this is the letter.
And we just need to send.
[man] Okay.
[Olivier] I will give you the address.
[Olivier in French] I discovered
that my biological mother was 14
and my biological father was 25.
That she was from Somalia
and he was from Ethiopia.
Why should I feel better?
Because I've pinned down the origins
of my facial features?
Absolutely not.
I want to meet her to understand why
she brought me into the world
and rejected me.
Then I'd have a new answer.
Will it be enough for me?
I'm so furious, and…
I mean, really furious.
And yet, I'm thankful,
since I wouldn't be here otherwise.
But when you've been abandoned,
it gives you this uncontrollable,
raging zeal for life.
And the problem, when you have this zeal,
and you are so hard on yourself,
is that
it gradually becomes a prison of anger.
If I have to be honest,
I hate her for who I am,
because I am always unsatisfied.
Finally, what I dreamed of as a kid,
to know where I come from,
is no longer enough today,
now that I'm in my thirties.
Because I want to know
why, and when I've understood why,
I'll want to know my biological father,
who might explain, if I get to meet him.
Then, finally, it won't be enough,
because, when he's told me why,
I won't be happy.
I'll say, "Why did you make this choice?
Why did you do that?
Why did you do that to her?"
Now, I think I'm…
unable to receive a good answer.
I'm not able to appreciate the answers.
As long as I don't know who I am,
I can't love myself.
[trainer] Knee.
One, two.
One.
-You're exhausting me.
-Skipping rope next.
[trainer] Twenty seconds.
I'm dead.
[trainer] It's just the start.
-[Olivier] Go easy.
-As usual.
[Olivier] No, I'm telling you go easy,
because I don't want to be…
Don't forget I have a show, my dear.
Don't push me, or I'll destroy you.
[trainer] One more minute.
Four, three, two, one, and rest.
I hate that.
I really hate that.
[Olivier] Our skirts are 38 cm.
It would be nice to have them
10 cm. higher at the waist
and 10 cm. longer.
Put that in the side seam here,
and in the yoke, here.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
It's real yellow.
It doesn't exist in white.
-So we wanted to check if you liked it.
-Yeah, it's fine.
This, no.
That could look good.
All in nude draped tulle?
No, all in my black draped tulle
on a base of nude tulle.
It's between bougainvillea and bubblegum.
Let's get rid of it.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
[sewing machine clacks]
[Olivier] Maybe it needs to be shorter?
It's a bit short, no?
Okay.
["The Sun Always Shines on TV" by A-ha
playing on stereo]
["You Keep Me Hangin' On" by Kim Wilde
Claire,
it's great having long dresses this year.
-She just has to avoid stepping on…
-On the train.
[Olivier] They're so long!
You know what happened this morning?
-[driver] What?
-I went… I was coming out of
the gym, the boxing gym, and
there was a guy in the changing room…
who I like, and he said hello to me.
[driver] Mm-hm.
You don't give a shit,
but I'm telling you anyway.
[driver] Do you see him
every day at the gym?
No, but when I do,
he puts a huge smile on my face.
Today I saw him, and he said hi.
[driver] It's a good start!
Why'd you never say hi before?
I'm not going to say hello. Are you nuts?
[driver] You can say hello.
No way! Are you crazy?
He'd think I'm flirting with him.
[driver] I say hi to lots of people.
You flirt with everyone.
-You're not ashamed?
-No.
[Olivier in English] Shame on you,
Mohammed.
[in French] It's great!
[he moans]
[indistinct conversation]
[Olivier] Bonjour, Madame Figaro!
We're at the Balmain show.
We're in the Paris city hall,
super stressed with Anina.
-[in English] Can you say "bonjour"?
-Bonjour!
[indistinct speech]
[inaudible]
[inaudible speech]
["The Sun Always Shines on TV" by A-ha
plays on speakers]
[cheering]
[cheering and applause]
[in English] Thank you.
Oh my God!
That was pretty chill at the end, no?
That was great!
You fucking rock, girls!
[cheering]
[Olivier in French] When I started,
people would applaud.
Today, they don't applaud anymore.
Now, the applause
is an Instagram post, a like.
It's interesting.
Seven years ago, it was the applause
and the noise in the room.
Now, it's more the number of flashes…
in the room.
Today, I felt those flashes.
It was nice.
In one interview, I was asked,
"Why the grandeur every time?
City hall, Paris, the opera house?"
Actually, I've always wanted to affirm…
my nationality,
my "passport," so to speak,
because I was scared
of not being French enough.
But, in the end, I am French now.
[he sings along to pop song]
[indistinct conversation]
Here.
Thank you.
Ah.
Ah!
It's fantastic.
[he sniffs]
[he sniffs again]
[Mom] So this is your whole story.
Before Dad and before me.
It's from before we went
to the children's home.
[Olivier] It's a lot to handle.
I just came back from a show.
CHRISTMAS 1985
NOVEMBER 25, 1985
Wow.
[parents chuckle]
[Olivier sniffs]
[Mom] I wrote it all out for you there.
There's a message from Benoît and Marie.
You're really nasty, you know that?
[Olivier laughs and cries]
This is crazy.
There's this smell
of the paper that hasn't been opened
in 30 years, and you know
that the last person to touch it
was this woman, so…
It's quite a powerful…
emotion.
There are all the letters
that you guys sent.
-[Mom] We sent letters?
-Yes.
There's a short letter saying the period--
-Of adjustment.
-Yes, the adjustment period was over.
You sent that letter to tell her
that I had started to smile
and walk a little bit
and that the family had accepted me,
and I was with my grandparents.
There was your letter
saying you really wanted me to stay.
-It's…
-Of course!
[woman on phone] I understand
that you're waiting to hear something,
but, at the same time,
we have to see what is most relevant
so that you have the best chances
of succeeding in this process.
This is the kind of process
that can't be rushed.
Will someone contact me if they find her
or only if she gives her consent?
Oh, no, they contact you before.
The Council for Personal Data
doesn't handle the whole process.
They conduct the investigation
to find her.
The process is broken down into steps,
both on your mother's side and yours.
You're in it together.
You'll receive feedback
after every step taken on her part.
When she's been contacted,
if she responds or not,
what she says and so on.
This is the case for you too.
You're both informed.
-[Olivier] Mohammed?
-Yeah?
[Olivier] I did something last night.
I signed up to use a dating app.
-[Mohammed] Which one? Meetic?
-Come on. Meetic?
Look at me.
You think I'm going to go on Meetic?
I joined Adopteunmec.com.
No, I'm joking.
[Mohammed] It seems to work.
No, so I actually signed up
to use this crazy app
that's actually linked directly
to your Instagram.
It's only people
who are looking for love or friendship,
but who are often very well-known.
And so you actually have to wait for…
Registration takes a little bit of time,
while they check your profile,
then they accept you.
Still no hearts for me.
[Mohammed] It hasn't even been 24 hours.
-It'll happen.
-And if it doesn't?
[Mohammed] If it doesn't happen,
it will one day or another.
Apps always work.
I don't know, Momo.
[Mohammed] You don't give yourself
enough time.
-Really?
-[Mohammed] Yes.
It's not because of your work, but…
Maybe you should
fit in a day when…
At least one day a week
when you do something else.
I know you love your work, that it's…
It's what you love to do,
but it takes up all your time.
Does your contract say,
"Chauffeur and shrink," or what?
[sirens wailing]
[indistinct chatter]
[woman in English] There you go!
Now we're getting somewhere.
-[Olivier] Now we talk.
-Yeah.
Yeah, now it's starting to fit.
There they go.
Good?
-Fave.
-[in French] Grab a tape measure,
and we'll see
exactly how much needs to go.
Give me a pin.
[in English] There's a bag behind you.
Shall I try the next one? I love this one.
[man] It's so good.
[Jennifer Lopez] When it has
a bit of light on it, it's gonna be nice.
It won't look like a rug. It'll look like…
When it has a little bit
of the beads in it, the black beads,
yeah, it won't look like a rug.
[woman in French] I need to know what time
the pieces have to be ready tomorrow.
Because, depending on whether
she wants her fitting extra early,
we have to work out
who's sleeping tonight, who isn't…
How to organize the work.
[in English] Do we have a crown?
Don't ask us!
This crown is stuck in customs.
But you already have
the cross of the queen here.
Yes.
Yeah, this is it!
-Maybe we will…
-Sometimes.
Depends on how I feel.
Yeah, it's beautiful.
-Happy?
-[Olivier] Yeah.
-Are you happy?
-Very.
…with two more people.
Are you able to work non-stop
between now and tomorrow noon?
I have to go to a class
and come right back.
-[woman 1] Until 11 a.m.?
-Yeah.
[woman 1] Straight through till tomorrow?
You feel you can physically manage that?
You think you can manage that
without any sleep?
-[woman 2] Oh, yeah.
-Yeah? Okay, cool.
As soon as I'm done with this,
I can move to a different…
If you keep giving me coffee.
I can get you… I can get you
as much coffee as you want.
[serene music plays]
[music becomes more upbeat]
[Olivier in French] You're going to
blow away in this wind.
She looks divine.
It's stunning.
It's really stunning.
[on phone] Hello,
this is Sophie Anat here,
from CNAOP, the National Council
for Accessing Personal Origins.
I was just calling to update you
on the progress of your file.
So, if you are available,
call me back on my direct line
at the number displayed.
Thank you. Speak to you soon. Bye.
[woman] As I told you, we were waiting
to hear from the private pension office.
I only received a reply on…
-July 17th, I think.
-[Olivier] Okay.
Uh…
They found a corresponding address.
I also heard back
from the health insurance office
two days later.
They also found a corresponding address,
and it's the same.
That's where we are.
But that means
we're talking about an address--
[woman] In France.
-Wow.
-[woman] That's what I'm saying.
But…
we really have to…
I mean, I'd really like to get across…
that nothing is certain.
No, it's crazy.
But it's still something positive,
this discovery about the address, because,
on the face of it,
she's not on the other side of the world.
That was unexpected.
You have her first and last names?
[woman] Of course.
Which I can't have, obviously.
-Nope.
-That's right.
What's the origin of her names?
Can you tell?
I can't answer questions about that.
-I'm wondering if they sound foreign.
-[woman] I can imagine.
Is it a… I mean,
could it be a French name?
[woman] Yes.
-Okay.
-[woman] It's--
I mean, it's not at all…
It's not extraordinary or anything.
-Or especially unusual.
-Okay.
You know so much more than me.
It's horrible.
Do people address their parents
formally or informally when they meet?
There's no rule.
Each person decides for themselves.
Everyone is free to choose
depending on what they experience or feel.
Even what you call them.
When people…
We might suggest, for example,
that people write a letter
to the biological parent,
if they agree to it.
-That they exchange letters.
-Of course.
For letters,
you write to the person
according to how you see them,
how you feel.
You can write "Mrs." and her last name,
you can write "Mom"…
It's not straightforward. And…
At the same time, it speaks volumes.
You have to say things as you feel them.
Which part of France does she live in?
Can't I know that either?
-[woman] She lives in the Southwest.
-Okay.
That's big.
You know,
you could tell me the town. I mean…
I'm sure a lot of people live there.
Yeah, okay.
Uh…
Would you like to write…
-Yes.
-[woman] …to her?
I suggest you do that.
But I can't guarantee I'll be able to…
I'll explain the circumstances in which
I can give her the message.
If I manage to reach her on the telephone,
I'll tell her about you,
what you're hoping for,
our conversations, all that.
-But those are just my words.
-Of course.
What I can do is tell her,
"Olivier has written you a letter."
"Would you permit me to read it to you
and then forward it to you?"
-Reading it to her first.
-That would be amazing.
-[woman] I've had people say no before.
-Okay.
[woman] People who say,
"No, I don't want that,"
because then it makes you too real.
Mm. Yes.
[woman] For the moment, you're a baby
who was entrusted into state care…
Uh…
I think, in the file,
it said she didn't see you.
-No, I don't think she did.
-[woman] Right.
Mrs. Lamothe told me
it was a bit of a mystery.
She took it to mean
that she didn't see me.
-She had a Cesarean.
-[woman] I read it. I'm positive.
Yeah, I know, but she had a Cesarean,
so they put her to sleep
and took the baby.
[Olivier] Dear…
Three little dots.
I obviously don't know
how to start this letter.
Which last name. Which first name.
Should I address you formally or not?
I could say
I've spent a year looking for you.
But my approach
in this letter is to be honest.
So I've spent 32 years looking.
Thirty-two years of doubt,
but 32 years of happiness too.
Thirty-two years of questions.
Thirty-two years of love,
of solitude, of worry.
My position is both simple
and very complicated.
You are my biological mother.
And for that, I thank you.
I thank you for the person I am today.
I thank you for giving birth to me.
But also because I've had
so much love in my life.
So many values, so much protection,
to face a world that can be very tough
and does you no favors.
I've had a great family.
I have a great family.
One that loves me.
I have friends.
My parents who dried my eyes,
comforted me, and wiped away my tears.
Who heard my first laughs,
saw my first steps
and felt my pain.
But I thank you for all of that.
But within all this,
I've become an adult full of doubts.
Inexplicable fears.
And maybe only you can help me.
-[Olivier] Mohammed.
-Yes?
[Olivier] Want to hear
something funny that happened?
-[Mohammed] What is it?
-I read an article, and…
It was about me,
and the title was The Wonder Boy.
-[Mohammed] "The Wonder Boy"?
-Yeah.
-Do know what that is?
-[Mohammed] No.
[Olivier] A wonder boy is a boy
who has achieved success
without necessarily much luck in his past,
who fought to make it.
He's a success
who you could say is…
[Mohammed] Deserving?
Not deserving. He's a success…
that wasn't supposed to happen.
Do you think I'm a wonder boy?
["Unforgettable"
by French Montana feat. Swae Lee]
Olivier has not met
his biological mother yet.
"I'm afraid of a second rejection,
opening the wound left by this woman
who gave birth to me.
My only hope is that
she recognizes herself in this film."
["Unforgettable"
by French Montana feat. Swae Lee]
[serene music plays]
FEBRUARY 10, 1985
WE ENTRUST OLIVIER TO HIS PARENTS
HIS AUNTIES
Subtitle translation by: Sarah Robinson