Run... Save yourself!
Run!
Get out of my sight!
Go to hell! You filthy scum!
I had three shops.
Three!
I had my job, my life,
my dignity.
And now
I'm struggling to survive.
Everyone I trusted...
...screwed me over.
They're all useless.
Where's my government now? Where
are all those people I voted for?
Do you know
how many times...
...those scumbags destroyed
my shops over the past years?
Five!
No insurance company
will cover me.
Do you know how much I owe due
to the damages they've caused?
A year ago the bank
took everything I had.
I have nothing...
Nothing.
Everywhere I go,
everywhere I look...
...the streets are full
of those filthy people.
Enough is enough.
I refuse to wait until things go back
to what they used to be.
I refuse to accept
that my city has come to this.
And I refuse to do nothing about it.
I want them vanished
by any means.
I want them out
of our country.
I will support
any decision you make.
I believe racism is increasing as a result
of people being under pressure.
Hence, they don't think.
Or they're trained not to.
So thinking becomes a luxury?
- Yes.
When I'm in danger, for me,
thinking is a luxury.
And this applies to everyone in here,
but they don't want to admit.
Look at what happened
to Dafne!
Sorry.
The man who saved me that night
was an immigrant.
Not a Greek.
Your ticket, please.
It doesn't seem to be fake.
The guy who forged it has helped
many others to escape.
How can we be sure
that we won't get caught?
There's a guy on the train
and in Customs. He's in on it.
When will we have them?
It'll take some time.
Once they're ready, I'll let you know.
Do we have another option?
- No.
Then don't think about it.
This is how it should be done.
No.
This is God Eros!
But I'm so glad that I've met you...
What are you doing there?
- Nothing.
I was looking for some
old sleeping bags and I found them.
What do you want them for?
For Lydia.
We want to go camping.
Daphne?
- I'm running late.
Is there something going on?
- Like what?
You're never here,
you're always on edge.
So are you.
Have you met someone?
- Am I not allowed to?
I'd like to know.
- I'll tell you when I feel like it.
"Swimming".
"Food".
"Happy". "I want you".
"Hello".
"What is your name?""
"You are beautiful".
"Crisis".
"Time".
"I am in love".
"I am afraid".
"I miss you".
When did you learn all this?
- All of this for you.
Farris...
Yes.
I miss you too, all the time.
I am also in love.
I am also afraid.
I want to ask you
to come with me so badly...
But I can't do this
to you.
Everything is falling apart.
Did you know that they've been living
at the old airport?
They've been gun
and drug dealing.
We have complaints every day.
People are suffering!
Why are you looking at me
like that?
You are completely ignorant!
Like most of you people!
You don't realize that these parasites
don't let us live our lives anymore!
You really believe that the problem
is the immigration issue...
...or that the whole world
is changing at our expense...
...and we focus
on what they feed us?
Yes, one who becomes a fascist
is an idiot.
It leads nowhere and prevents
from noticing what's really happening.
On the one hand, they empty Syria's
chemicals in the Mediterranean.
At the risk of destroying
the whore ecosystem and tourism.
And on the other hand, they want
to enforce laws prohibiting people...
...from cultivating their land
and having access to water.
This has never happened before
in human history.
They'll control food, water...
...and soon enough common sense
will be obliterated.
Daphne?
Are you with us?
Do you want to add something?
- No.
Why is that?
Because, the way things
have turned out...
...I don't know if it's worse
for an immigrant or for a Greek...
...to be trapped in Greece.
"I love you".
"I miss you".
"I am in love".
"I want to be with you".
"Wherever you go".
"Wherever we can be together".
I love you.
I love you too.
Dad?
- Yes.
Is our home going through
an economic crisis?
Our country is going through
an economic crisis.
And when a country goes through
an economic crisis...
...parents stop sleeping together?
Of course not.
Why would you think that?
Then why do you sleep
every night on the couch?
Is this what happens
in every home?
No.
- Then why is this happening in ours?
Have you broken up with mom?
No. Play!
Then since you don't sleep
with her anymore...
...can I go and sleep
in your bed instead?
No, you have your own room.
Come on now, play.
How about only when it's raining
and there's thunder?
LOSEFT 50mg.
Treatment for depression...
...panic disorder, anxiety disorders
post-traumatic stress disorder.
Loan installment for the house
was settled. Sign here.
Remittance
for your parents' rent, here.
Life insurance
installment.
You sign here for your wife,
and here for your child.
Gas, electricity and property tax
has been deposited. Sign here.
You have yet to pay insurance for your
wife and father and your credit card.
How many times must I tell you?
- I don't want to study!
Damn it!
I won't say it again!
I don't care!
- Stop playing this goddamn game!
Dad!
- You never listen!
- Just like your father!
Giorgos, can't you hear me?
Come out, for God's sake!
I need you, goddamn it!
I can't do everything on my own!
I can't handle
this child anymore! Come out!
Giorgos, I can't do it all
by myself!
Spyros? She asked me
to put out my cigarette.
Put it out, man.
We don't want any trouble.
Bitch.
That's why.
We're more hospitable.
We don't kick people out.
For fuck's sake.
Unbelievable.
She's throwing me out.
Fucking bitch...
Problems at home?
- No.
Everything's fine at home.
What's up?
Do you have a minute?
- Yes, of course.
I wanted to tell you something.
I want to ask you for a favor.
And I'm not asking you this
as a colleague, but as a friend.
What kind of favor?
Can you switch me
to your department?
Why?
Because I'm afraid
that I might get fired.
They fired eight of us
last week and...
OK, in my department
the damages are irreversible.
I don't have anyone to protect me.
There's a lot of backstabbing.
First of all, calm down.
- I can't.
I can't afford to get fired.
I don't know what to do.
No one will touch
your department.
You've been working here
for 15 years. They trust you.
If you ask for my transfer,
they might do it.
But if I ask
for your transfer...
...that means that I'll have
to let go one of my own people.
I can't do that, Odyssea.
Could you at least
say something?
To that chick?
You're a manager.
She'll listen to you.
She doesn't have a clue
what's going on here.
She just carries out orders.
- Odyssea...
...we're all on the same boat.
- Yes.
Even if I ask for something like that
they'll turn it down.
Despina is pregnant.
That's good.
That's something
that you wanted, right?
Tomorrow I'm taking her
for an abortion.
When you have so many
unnecessary accountants...
...you'll have to get rid
of half of them.
Look, I don't give a damn
that they confiscated my home.
I shouldn't have believed I could
afford to own a house anyway...
It's all my other debts...
If my wife leaves me too...
How are you doing?
Is the family OK?
We've lost touch. We should
get together some day.
If you could please help me...
Too bad.
Because I wanted to tell you
that I'm falling in love with you.
Say you're sorry,
say you're sorry.
No, you'll have your checks
next month. I promise.
You've nothing to be afraid of.
All this is for the company's
best interest.
Odyssea?
Odyssea!
It's a real mess, isn't it?
Departments
are being merged.
Ten more will be fired. Sure, I know
we're not yet affected by that.
But until when?
Excuse me, doesn't this
stress you out at all?
Ilias, I'm busy
and I'm not in the mood.
Yes, so I've heard.
I don't care what you've heard.
I told you, I've got work to do.
What have you heard?
Those love affairs...
You know,
they're the most tricky...
If, in fact, one can distinguish
passion from love.
No one wants them...
Everyone gossips.
Then comes all the guilt, that
we fell for the wrong person...
...and you try to find a way
to change everything...
So it's best to pretend
and look the other way.
You suffer, you miss her,
you meet in secret.
You listen to music, you want
to get away with your lover.
And you keep thinking
"It can't be. We feel the same way."
And, of course,
we keep ignoring things...
...believing that whatever happens,
we'll make it.
And then comes a day
when we hear...
...that our friend who got fired
killed himself.
And that the idiot was too weak
to handle it.
Expendable.
He's neither the first
nor the last one.
So what? Because
he asked for our help?
"Love, invincible in battle".
Odysseas' wife
just called.
They found him this morning.
He hung himself.
The funeral is tomorrow.
But she doesn't want
to see your face.
It's unfair, I know.
But that's the reality.
It's over.
"Danke!"
Anyway.
Vinaigrette, prosciutto...
...parmesan...
You eat well and we don't even
have money to buy feta cheese.
You know?
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
We don't even have money
for cherry tomatoes.
Thanks to you.
Okay, it's not your fault.
It's just me.
No, it's okay.
I have coffee at home.
I have to go.
Out of habit.
I don't buy anything.
I have to go.
Historian!
So you know better. Won't you
give us back what you owe us?
You started two wars.
You destroyed nations.
Have you forgotten all that?
It used to be.
Now, very different.
How do I say that?
That's why you say that.
I almost forgot.
This is a patch for your back.
That's what happens
when you ride bikes at your age.
I always loved to walk around.
Watch people, observe them.
Try to figure out
if they're happy, or sad.
If they feel lonely,
just like I do.
I didn't have the chance
to do what I wanted.
I wanted to study,
but I got married, had children.
Time slipped away.
Now I'm talking to you...
You don't understand a thing, do you?
But who knows?
Perhaps you can feel me.
Soap.
Soil.
"Occupation Compensations".
You have such beautiful eyes...
Knowledge.
Faith.
Oh, lentils...
I almost forgot.
Dear God!
From politics to Greek tragedies.
God Eros.
Me too. If you only knew how
I long to see you every week.
Sixty.
I'm crazy.
We'll go to jail!
Let's go back, it was a mistake!
Jesus, what are we doing
at our age?
You're just as good at bribing
and then you judge us!
"Age".
"Excitement".
Well done.
"Routine".
"Imagination".
"Guilt".
"Strength".
"Habit".
"Change".
"Denial".
No, this doesn't count.
No, I'll stop playing.
A lot.
And what if it's too late?
It's never too late.
What's this? In English?
I can't read English.
"Second chance"?
Together.
You believe that we'll be together
for so long?
I miss you. A lot.
Spring.
These two
must be related somehow.
On Sunday
it's my grandson's birthday.
We'll all get together at home.
I'll cook roasted lamb.
We'll sit at the table,
as always.
And I'll be so happy
to have my family.
My children, my grandson,
my health.
That's just the way it is.
Then they'll leave,
I'll clear the table...
...I'll wash the dishes while
my husband watches TV.
And me, above the sink...
Wondering if I'm happy or not.
When I'm washing dishes
it's the only time I question it all.
Is this what I wanted
in my life?
I've made terrible mistakes,
Sebastian. I'm to blame.
I taught them this way.
It's all on me.
How can I change it all now?
I just need some time.
Just some time.
Your father must not find out!
- I don't care!
I don't give a damn if they all
find out! I'm not ashamed!
Please, I beg of you!
- What can he do to me?
You're very young. You can't destroy
your whole life over an infatuation!
You're all a bunch of hypocrites.
All I want is to be with him.
Mom, I'm in love.
Have you ever been in love?
Happy birthday!
Dad, Anna and I have been
separated for six months now.
You think I don't know already?
You think I'm an idiot?
Just because I keep quiet?
I don't want to be with Anna.
The normal thing is to be
with your wife and child.
You're 40 years old.
How long, you suppose,
this fling will last?
Do what you want to do
with her...
...and once you're done,
fuckin' ditch her.
Have fun, if you need to...
...but keep your family as well.
Are you listening to me?
And don't you dare tell your mother
any of this.
She's already stressed enough
with our finances.
So, you'll come
on Sunday...
...and we'll have
a great family time, as always.
That's how I keep
my family together.
Sometimes, we parents ...
... we make mistakes
which can confuse you.
Why?
Because we are afraid.
Are you afraid of what?
Truth.
-And what is the truth?
It's true...
... that both Mom and I love you very much.
But we will be happier if we are
... lived separately.
Will you have your own apartment?
Yes, you will have your own room
in that apartment.
When can I come?
Every week. We will make
schedule.
You will have two homes and two rooms.
I promise ...
that you will not miss anything and
you will not lose anyone.
Is that true?
Yes.
-I do not like.
That this sometimes happens with the truth.
We don't always like it.
But ... Antonis?
I love you so much.
And from now on I will always tell you
truth.
So that nothing
confuses you anymore.
That's not easy.
No it's not.
In the second house, when it rains,
and thunder, can I sleep with you?
When it rains and thunders, you can.
Alright.
What is this? For protection. You never
know which can happen. We all have.
I do not need. I have my methods.
-Antonis ...
It's pretty hard now.
- I said I didn't need it.
You're scared. You have no reason to fear.
Our team always covers its people.
We will never leave you
unprotected. You have my word.
Maria, why is the door locked?
What's the matter, why did you lock up?
-By accident.
What do you mean, by accident?
- By accident, Antonis.
Our daughter is still out.
And you'll see he won't tonight either
to come home.
She turned off her cell phone.
Where were you?
Out.
I hate when it disappears like that.
I know she met someone.
I tried to be kind to her,
to tell me something but nothing.
Did she say something to you?
Not.
I'll wash it myself.
Everything got out of hand.
Everything is destroyed.
Have you heard of Anestisov
mini market on the corner?
They broke in and stole everything,
you disgusting people.
They ran away from us by a hair.
They camp in every empty
the building they find.
And this damned state does not
nothing to drive them away.
Do you know they live on the old
the airport?
They have weapons, they sell drugs.
Did you know they are smugglers?
Do you know how many complaints a day
receive in the municipality.
People are suffering!
Why are you looking at me like that?
You know nothing!
Like most!
You don't realize that
because of these parasites ...
... we can no longer live normally!
If we do nothing about it
question, who will?
Which is why you think I'm working
all this?
Because you failed at nothing else.
What did you say?
Maria, what did you say?
You don't think it's your fault
for this?
He. Do you hear me?
You are my failure!
You never understood me!
Where were you when I needed you?
Where were you when my world
turned upside down? Where?
Everything I do, I do for my own
land and your children!
What did you do?
Nothing. Nothing.
When you're already proud of it
what are you doing...
Why don't you tell the kids what to do
deals with their father when he goes out.
You think I don't understand you?
When you are so sure of your own
beliefs,
why don't you admit them
in front of everyone?
Do you want me to tell you why?
Because you're ashamed. You're ashamed.
Because deep down you know you are
an ordinary jerk.
Mediocrity, illiterate. That
trying to prove through violence.
Fascist, it's you.
Not because of the state.
Not even for the kids, nor for whom.
What do you want?
Back your old life?
You won't get it because you don't
deserve.
You don't even know how to love,
nor how to give.
You just know how to hurt.
Why should I feel sorry for you? Why are you a
victim, and not all those people you're destroying?
And you think you should
proud of it?
I don't want to see you again.
I'm glad I'm your failure.
I'm just sorry I didn't
realized earlier.
But I'll tell you one thing.
That you never used our children again
as an excuse for what you have become.
What do you think?
That you are better than those who
making fun of?
You became like them.
Same!
Yes.
When?