Be strong.
You can do this.
Everyone's counting on you.
Hello. You could knock, thanks.
Dad wants you downstairs...
Hey, wait a second.
Are those my socks?
- What? We have the same ones.
- No.
Yours are the purple ones,
mine are the pink,
so, you better
take them off now, Talia...
- Skank.
- Bitch.
Hey, you know what?
- Mom!
- Oh, and you know what?
You are never borrowing
my car again because...
- I don't wanna borrow your stupid car.
- ...the last time you did,
you and your friends
left potato chips...
- I don't eat potato chips!
- ...all over the back of it,
not to mention no gas in my car.
Dad, gave you a gas card Jazz!
Oh, you know what?
Not all of us rely on dad.
- Are you done?
- No!
Actually, there's quite a lot
more that I could say.
Girls, good morning.
Yeah, it was a good morning till
Jazz came bursting in my room
bitching about everything.
Jazz, lighten up!
- Thank you, Mom.
- Oh, really?
I don't wanna hear impossible.
I wanna hear "I'm Possible".
And I don't care
about your kid's ball game,
your poker tournament,
or your sister's ass.
The only reason for you being
on the face of this planet today
is to be in Dallas at 2:00.
Get the contract signed
and keep your job.
- You got it?
- I understand that, Mr. Medici, but...
Good.
Okay. You're right. Yeah. No,
I'll... I'll get it done today. I'm sorry.
- You're right, sir.
- Okay.
I haven't heard from you all week.
Can you take about 4 minutes
and get me caught up to speed
on what's been going on
in your life.
4 minutes to explain
the last 168 hours?
Okay.
Well, let's see.
Short version, Leah and I bought
tickets to see a Broadway show.
Oh, and I got new speakers
for my car
and they sound like,
totally awesome.
Oh, and I won. I won a free month
of tanning at the Golden Spas.
You know those, like,
little raffle ticket things
they have next
to the cash register?
Listen to yourself! I'm not
interested in any of that trivial crap.
Can you tell me something
about your future, your career,
something that I would be
interested in.
Yeah.
I've been doing really good
in my studies.
I aced my exam on Tuesday.
And, today is cheer tryouts.
So, I'm recruiting new members and I'm
getting ready for the competitions next week.
Well, it's very important
that you win those competitions.
- You know, those competitions...
- Yes, Daddy. I know!
My mother's a state champ. My sisters are
state champs. I have a lot to live up to.
- You've told me every day since I was 5.
- Well then, good.
You know what's expected of you.
Why does everyone
have to be so powerful?
Can't we just like, I don't know,
be what we want to be?
Well sure, if what you wanna be
is #1 then yes.
- Well, we did place at prelims.
- "Place"?
- Yeah.
- What do you mean, "place"?
Do you even know
what the word means?
Place is an undescribed area.
I mean, if my firm placed
on every case we took on,
you and your mother would be
buying clothes off the rack.
I mean, just using one wrong word
can lead a client to jail
and change their life forever.
You really need to understand
what words mean.
- Second place.
- I'm sorry?
I said, we got second place.
You're really not listening
to what I'm saying, are you?
Second place is first loser.
Sweetie, I... got to go.
And can you kill that lipstick?
It makes you look like a hooker.
What?
You know what!
Calling your daughter a hooker,
Gio? Come on.
I mean,
she's probably in there crying.
I'm the one that should be crying.
I mean, c'mon,
what do you want me to do?
I didn't call her a hooker,
I said she looked like one.
It's the same difference.
A hooker wearing my socks no less.
You know if she touches my stuff again,
Dad, you need to take away her car,
or better yet you need to take away
her credit card 'cuz heaven forbid,
she can't buy a new outfit
every two weeks.
Okay. Love you.
Mother...
And who cares
if she doesn't win state?
I mean, there is no need for her to
feel like she let the whole family down.
Let's assume you're right.
Let me ask you a question.
Don't give me
that lawyer bullshit, Gio.
We're not in a court room,
we're in my kitchen.
Don't be like your father, Gio.
That was different, and we agreed
never to bring that up again, Priscilla.
No, it's not different.
Don't you see? You are treating her
exactly the way your father treated you.
I'm not about to spend 24 months
with a shrink her like I did with you.
Look, I'm sorry
but you have got to back off.
You know the number one reason
why most men die before their wives?
They want to.
Yeah. And the number 2 reason?
Poison in the coffee.
Have a good day.
Did you wanna see me?
That's six complaints
from parents, Mitch.
Two letters from the board,
and as the principal, I am being held
accountable for all of it and I don't like it.
And?
And... we've been over this!
That's enough.
No more derogatory name calling
to these students.
You cannot be
calling them pussies and faggots
or anything else for that matter.
And just so that we don't have
this conversation again,
from now on, you will address
each student by their jersey number.
Not their name, their number.
Not their nickname, their number.
Understood?
All this because I called some boys
that are one year removed
from fighting
for this country a name?
This ain't the military.
They can quit.
No, Mitch.
It's more than that, okay?
It's forcing them to workout
and then playing them hurt,
and then calling them babies or
mommy's boys when they don't want to.
Look, I know you're not
physically beating on these kids
and that you practically
live on that field...
Hold on.
Beats the players up?
I'm the one that gets beat up.
I'm the one who plays hurt.
Check your records.
I've never taken a day off
during the season
in the eleven years
I've been here.
I've destroyed two marriages because
of the time that I put in around here.
Nobody's saying that you're
not trying to do your job.
Wait a minute, don't tell me
you're whacking me?
- I have a right...
- Relax.
Nobody's gonna lose their jobs
over this.
Well,
it certainly wouldn't be mine.
What are you talking about?
I think it's pretty obvious.
You need to understand.
Football at Seneca is a religion.
A choice. And let's not forget
a source of revenue.
Look, there will always be that handful
of malcontents who need to be dealt with.
And it's your job
to shut those people up.
Do you need me for anything else?
No, thank you.
- Coach.
- Yes.
You just keep them boys winning,
whatever it takes.
Whatever it takes.
At least the Vice Principal
wants a winner around here.
Are my eyes puffy?
No, babe. You look great.
What is that?
Oh. My. God.
Oh, my God.
I guess it's safe here, right?
You know, these retro cars
are really coming back in style.
Really?
- No!
But seriously, do you have to park
this "thing" next to my car?
It's a parking lot.
Yeah, but when the tow truck comes
to take it away, it could scratch my car
which is probably worth
more than your house.
Oh, and...
Have a good day, short bus.
Let's go.
I'm totally nervous about how
today is gonna be. Hi, Principal Banks.
- I'll see you at tryouts, babe.
- Bye.
- Hey, girls.
- Hi.
- Big day for the Cougars.
- Yes.
I want y'all to pick
some winners for me.
We'll do our best.
We need some champions 'cuz
you're gonna be gone next year.
I mean, you know.
Well, it's gonna be hard
to beat this.
You certainly are a part
of history here so...
- Thanks Mr. Banks.
- ...just do what you can.
- 'Kay, bye.
- Alright, y'all be good.
A part of history here?
So is your name
on the bathroom wall.
Oh, what? You jealous
'cuz yours isn't up there?
Oh, not at all, sweetie.
Mine's right under yours.
Except it says,
"Call for a better time."
Good one.
Right.
We are so gonna get that.
What about her girlfriend?
Who wears sweatpants to school?
I wear sweatpants.
She does wear pants
around her ankles.
Accurate.
Wait. They're coming.
Hurry up. Get in the stalls.
Really?
That is frigin' disgusting.
Can you not do that in my face?
In fact, can you not do that
in my school?
We're sorry.
Look. I get it.
Ugly girls can't get guys so you hook up
with each other. It makes total sense.
I mean, I guess you could
hook up with other ugly guys
and have ugly kids but, you
just can't fix ugly, I suppose.
Look, we didn't mean
to offend you, okay?
Oh, you didn't offend me,
my little bulldyke. No.
Make me wanna throw up my intestines
in the toilet? Yeah, maybe.
Speaking of toilets...
Girls.
Okay, girls, we're ready to begin.
Hi there, how are you?
What's your name?
- Marie Carter. Senior.
- Marie Carter.
Senior. How are you?
There you go. Good luck.
Please take a picture.
Next.
Hi there, what's your name?
- Trish Malone, junior.
- Hi.
There you go. Good luck.
- Get your picture taken, please.
- You know...
- I got it by memory.
- Next.
- Hi.
- Lori Cobalt, freshman.
Lori. You're so cute. I like it.
- There you go.
- Thanks.
- Good luck. Get your picture taken.
- Smile.
Next.
- Hi there.
- Hi. Lisa Mullin.
- Sophomore.
- Oh. Cute bracelet.
I love that. Nikki, that's so you.
Check it out.
Oh, so cute. Give it to me.
- I'm just kidding... relax.
- It's so cute. Here you go.
Talia forgot to wear
her contacts this morning.
What do you mean?
Next.
Hi, Maddie McKinem. Freshman.
There you go.
Next.
Did you just give that girl
a form?
Oh, I don't know. Which one?
The one over there.
Get it back.
Okay.
Demi.
Can you get the form back
from that loser...
Now! Please.
Next.
- Hi.
Julie Klein, sophomore.
Turn around, Julie.
Okay, you'll do.
Great. Here you go.
- Good luck. - Read it over.
- Have your parents sign it.
- Thank you.
Look at these girls.
Yup, Geek.
- Accurate.
- Anorexic.
- True.
- Daddy issues.
- Also true.
- Okay, hey!
I didn't line 'em up. Okay?
You're picking them.
Next.
I said next!
Hi. Elle Wurthmore. Freshman.
Hello?
What the hell is that on her face?
Hi. Elle, is it?
We, We've reached
our limit today. Sorry.
- Oh, oh, my...
- Clearly, you're in the wrong place.
This is for the Seneca Cougars,
not the Kruegers.
Don't fall asleep!
But the school paper said that...
I know what the school paper
said. I wrote it.
But we've reached our limit.
- So, I'm sorry, Miss...
- Wurthmore.
Wurthmore. Of course.
You know what? Maybe you could try
the drama club. I hear they're looking.
Peter Pan, fly away.
Tragic.
It's Wurthmore.
More like Worth-less.
Next!
Do you ever not wanna go to work
because the weather's so nice?
Today is one of those days.
Gorgeous day outside.
Lots of sunshine.
Thanks for hanging out with us
on WMNT The Mint Radio.
It's 7:06.
Really, Mom?
I think that was loud enough to
wake up the whole Davidson family
and they live 3 blocks down.
What are you talking about?
I didn't hear anything.
Can you leave me some money?
I'm going over to Kendra's and we want
to buy from the ice cream truck.
What did I tell you?
No more ice cream!
You're getting a belly already
from eating all that crap at Kendra's.
- And I'm not raising a fat kid.
- I'm not fat.
Yeah, not yet, but if you keep
eating all that crap, you're gonna be.
You need to be more selective
of who your friends are.
I never hung out with fat people.
Okay...
Then, can I order a fruit cup?
I think they have fruit cups
on the truck.
Yeah, that's okay.
- Who's it?
- It's Daddy.
Alright, give me the phone.
I'll meet you downstairs in a few. Okay?
Listen, babe. Little change
in plans. I'm really sorry.
I'm not gonna be able to make it
by this morning.
I got a shot to close
that deal I've been waiting on.
I'm at my sister's house now and she's gonna
drive me to the airport in a little bit.
Oh, come on, Cody. You promised.
Won't you please come
and work for my dad,
then we can spend
more time together.
This is huge for us.
Hold on, my phone's dying.
And besides, nobody just works
for your father.
He possesses their soul.
Alright, be safe.
Because I'm gonna need you in a few weeks
for our marriage. That's kinda important.
And tell your cheerleading crew
that tonight isn't a bachelorette party.
Bye.
- Oh, no, no donuts. No donuts.
- Oh, c'mon. Really?
- Please!
- Go get ready for school.
We have to take your uncle
to the airport.
Really, bro? Donuts?
How did she take it?
It's Talia, but I love her.
Well, here.
You can give her this
when you get back.
It's more her style
than mine anyway.
You truly are the best.
5 more minutes guys.
- Can we have pretzels?
- Just one.
- Can we have two?
- Hey, Talia?
- What, Jazz?
- Show me how to get down.
- Okay!
- You guys are good.
- Thank you.
You liked it?
My luscious, leopard lady...
Excuse me, ma'am, sorry...
Woo! Who saw the dance moves?
- Jeez!
- C'mon, bro!
Come on. Ma'am. I'm so...
You know what?
That stain will definitely
come out.
My mom got the same dress.
She wears it all the time.
- Are you kidding?
- Yeah. It's a nice dress.
- Guys, seriously?
- What?
Demi, can you just shut up?
Shut up! Just order us food, please.
Hey, Hey, Jen.
Have you seen Talia?
Try the terrace.
I just tried to say hello to her but
she's in one of those moods again.
Well, some jackass
just spilled a drink on her.
Yeah.
That's no reason to blow me off.
She's a little upset.
What do you expect?
You should know her by now.
You're her business partner.
On paper. Her father controls everything
in her life including our business.
You should know that
better than anyone.
Unfortunately, I do.
Yeah. So, you...
- Do you want to come with us
or go with Tommy? - With you.
- Okay.
- Wait, have you met Lucy?
Hi.
She's the new CFO of
Harley Medici cosmetics.
Oh, yeah.
No offense, but, Jen?
When are you guys gonna start
hiring some hot guys?
Stay away from this one.
- Listen, we gotta go but good luck upstairs.
- Thanks.
How is it possible
that out of everyone
bumping into each other
down there,
you're the only one who gets
a drink spilled on them.
Are you kidding me? I thought he was coming
up to me and then all of a sudden "boom".
He like, goes into the other girl.
I'm so not the hot topic anymore.
Stop!
You're getting married
in two weeks
and you're worried about
being in the spotlight?
I don't know, it's like
I feel like I'm getting old.
And, you know, I had my child
when I was too young.
Abby is doing great in school
and I just bumped into your
business partner down there.
And the cosmetics company is doing great.
You're with an amazing guy.
I don't know, I just...
I feel like me and the girls should
come over again tomorrow and talk.
Whatever, I have to make that
speech tomorrow at the reunion.
Talia, there is no reunion!
I don't know if this is coming from
the alcohol, or the prescriptions,
or even if you're gonna remember
this tomorrow but there's no reunion.
You're so messing with me!
I'm not!
Yeah, you are.
Look, I know you're sick
and tired of hearing it from us
but please, just do it for Abby.
Right? After last night who knows.
Leah drover her home.
Are you and your mom
still doing to the shower?
We weren't invited.
Hold on.
Skyann, get that spoon
out of your mouth.
One of these days, you are gonna
fall down and knock all of your teeth out
and all the kids at school are gonna
call you a freak. Is that what you want?
No, I don't wanna be a freak.
What did we say about freaks?
Freaks eat their lunch by themselves
and they don't have any friends.
And no daughter of mine
is going to be a freak.
So just stop running around
and watch TV or something.
Alright. Sorry, Mom.
Sorry, what was I saying?
We weren't invited.
Yeah, of course you're invited.
You're in the wedding party.
I sent out the shower invites.
Shut up!
That dog.
The neighbor's dog
is in your yard again.
Hey, let me call you back.
Leah just got here.
I will call you back.
Bye.
Why don't you just call
animal control?
On who?
The dog or the neighbors?
Is that the new guy on the phone?
No. That was dead
before it even started.
It's Demi.
She was gonna bring Skyann over
but as usual, Vinny was late so...
Of course, he was. He's a scumbag.
Yeah.
What were you guys talking about?
Talia and how nice
it must be to have Daddy
that pays for private school
for Abby.
I personally think that she needs
more help than she's getting.
She's on the meds and mixing them with the
alcohol, I mean, that's not helping any.
- Yeah.
- I was with her 'til 3 in the morning.
What's her deal
with the whole reunion thing?
You should have seen her.
I'm not kidding.
I don't know where she's going but she
thinks she has this big speech to make.
I'm worried about her.
I'm not.
Okay, where did that come from?
I don't mean it like that,
I just mean that, you know,
she's had everything
handed to her.
You think she's co-owner
of this cosmetic company?
You don't think Daddy had
something to do with those contracts?
Must be nice.
I mean, I just live.
I barely get by. You know?
Like, I have to go to court to get support
from my ex, and then my bills are behind.
Like, I haven't paid my mortgage
in two months.
Speaking of mortgages,
you remember her?
Trish?
Trish Ma... Home Alone Malone.
Yeah, how could I forget her?
I mean,
we used to torment that girl.
She married a New York lawyer.
And I just showed them a
2 million dollar home last week.
Does this lawyer have
any brothers?
Or sisters? I mean, I'm not picky.
You know what's sad?
I didn't even recognize her
but she knew exactly who I was.
I have no idea
how many trainers it took
but she sure as hell does not
look like that anymore.
Did she say anything about us?
No.
She did mention Talia
and what a bitch she was.
Yeah, well, we all followed
her lead in high school.
Yeah, but we followed her lead, so,
we didn't become one of her victims.
And come on, somewhere along the way,
we did become her friend.
What's wrong?
Sophie's been coming home
crying lately.
I guess some kids on the bus were making
fun of her for where she got dropped off
and then, you know, they were
like making fun of her clothes and...
I don't know. I'm doing what I can,
you know? Like, I just feel bad.
I can't imagine feeling like that.
She's five.
They're just kids being kids.
It's not even the same.
It's not kids just being kids. Do you
remember Trish Malone when we were five?
She hid from us in the bathroom.
She ate her lunch in there so,
she didn't have to deal with us.
- Do you believe in karma?
- What?
Karma, you know, like if you
do something, and like...
Yeah, I know what karma is,
Nikki. I'm not an idiot.
We were all the same.
We were all assholes, bitches, whatever
you wanted to call us, that's what we were.
But if karma were going to happen,
don't you think
it would've happened by now?
Why do you even have
the Paw Print out?
I don't know,
Talia at the reunion.
I guess I just wanted to think
about good times, you know?
Okay.
How about this?
Why don't we crash
Talia's reunion?
Dressed like that?
Why not?
I mean, let's make our own
theme, "Come As You Are".
I mean, you think she's home?
Should we call her?
I'll call her.
Alright.
I mean cool, use my phone.
I wouldn't go through pictures
if I were you.
You're disgusting.
I mean, you could,
if you're into that, that's cool.
Hey, it's Abby.
Mom and I aren't home right now.
If you leave your name and number,
we'll call when we return.
Thanks. Bye.
Hey, Talia, it's Leah.
Listen, I'm with Nikki right now and we were
just gonna stop by to see what you were doing,
but apparently, we missed you, so,
I will give you a ring on your cell
and hopefully you didn't leave
for the reunion yet.
Alright, I'll see you in a bit.
Oh, Mama Mia. Come to Daddy.
You better not be messing with me.
I know you must know
about the reunion.
Sorry to interrupt.
I'm Mario Tressi, limo driver?
Is that the luggage
for the car, Ma'am?
Obviously,
they're there for the car.
The guy is so annoying.
Wait, hold on. The address is on
the bottom, assuming you could read?
No, it's just that
he's annoying, and... Wait!
The luggage. It costs more than your
house. Would you please be careful?
My apologies, Ma'am.
...nothing, this guy's retarted.
He's like, 35 minutes late.
Whatever, there goes his tip.
Alright, let's see what we got.
Seneca High School.
I'll talk to you later.
Alright, bye.
Hello?
Everything okay, Ma'am?
Are you going to open up
the door for me?
Oh, yes, Ma'am, right away.
And stop calling me Ma'am.
You're making me feel old.
Yes, Ma'am.
Of course, of course.
Mario Tressi, Black Tie Classics,
hoping that you'll consider us
for all your limousine needs.
I can think of a few
other needs too.
I don't have to have the car back 'til
Monday. If you know what I mean.
Perfect.
Is Abby inside?
- Yeah, she's inside.
- Okay, great.
Oh, and by the way, I absolutely
love the reunion themed attire.
Why? What's wrong with my clothes?
Nothing, great concept, I mean,
if they don't recognize you,
they'll at least recognize
the same outfit.
Is there anything else derogatory or
negative that you want to say to me?
No. I'm good. Thanks.
Are you kidding?
You scared the shit outta me.
Sorry.
I thought maybe
something happened to you.
- Where is everyone?
- I don't know. Maybe they parked out back.
Hello?
Are you here with the reunion?
You scared the shit outta me.
That's the second time now.
What? You fell asleep again?
Yeah, I fell asleep standing up.
Where the hell is everyone?
I don't know.
Could be a surprise party for you.
I mean you are a Seneca High
Goddess legend, right?
Well, yeah. I used to be.
Yeah.
Well, I'd say you still got it.
Perhaps you'd like
to freshen up a bit
before you make
your grand entrance?
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Stay here. I'll be back.
Hello?
- We are so gonna get that.
- - What about her girlfriend?
- Who wears sweatpants to school?
- I wear sweatpants.
She does wear pants
around her ankles.
Accurate!
Wait. They're coming.
Hurry up. Get in the stalls.
Really?
That is frigin' disgusting.
Can you not do that in my face?
In fact,
don't do that in my school.
We're... sorry.
No, look, I get it.
Ugly girls can't get guys, so, you hook up
with each other. It makes total sense.
I mean, you could actually
hook up with ugly guys
and have ugly babies,
but you can't fix ugly.
Look, we didn't mean
to offend you.
Oh, you didn't offend me,
you little bulldyke.
No.
Make me wanna throw up
my guts in the toilet? Yeah, maybe.
Actually, speaking of toilets...
Girls!
Why are you being so mean?
Mario?
Mario!
I don't know what just happened
but I'm losing my mind!
I swear to God!
Hey, I'm only the tour guide.
You wanted a reunion?
Now you've got it.
Who is this?
By your words
you shall be justified.
you shall be condemned.
...you just can't fix
ugly, I suppose.
...ugly girls...
You can't fix ugly, I suppose.
Do you even know
what the word means?
Place is an undescribed area.
I mean, just using one wrong word
can lead a client to jail.
You really need to understand
what words mean.
Can you come to the principal's office,
please, sweetie?
Mr. and Mrs. Medici.
How you doing?
Thank you for coming in.
My name is Principal Banks.
Yeah, I know who you are.
Just, how long is this gonna take?
And what's this about?
It shouldn't be long.
As soon as we get
your daughter Talia in here...
Oh, sweetie.
What's going on?
- Nothing.
- Talia, please sit.
Daddy. You disrupting the entire
planet again and my schedule no less.
- What schedule?
- What are you even doing here?
One, I am a part of this family,
and two, I have a reputation
to protect and the family name
which, by the way, you are
so carelessly destroying.
Okay, Jazz. That's enough.
Talia, did you throw toilet
water in somebody's face?
What? No! I did no such thing.
Case closed.
She said she didn't do it.
It's not something my daughter
would do.
Okay, Rebecca, can you come in
here for a second, please?
Rebecca? We have rules here
against making up stories
in an attempt to get another
student suspended.
She threw water...
No, no. That's okay.
You're dismissed.
Well, I guess we'll be on our way.
C'mon, sweetie.
Yeah, just hold on
for a second. Just...
What do you say
we give Talia two days off just,
you know, make the other side
think that she's suspended.
What?
Woah, woah, woah.
Did you not just hear
what my daughter said?
She didn't do it.
Your logic makes no sense
whatsoever.
And I'm agreeing with you,
Mr. Medici.
I just think that we can...
Just because some bimbo comes
in here and makes false accusations
because she's jealous
of my daughter,
she's gonna have a permanent
suspension on her record?
Gio, calm down.
No, I won't calm down.
Okay, alright.
This conversation's over.
I can't... I can't allow...
When it comes to my daughter,
it's over when I say it's over,
so, you can just sit back down.
- Gio!
- Dad.
Who do you think
you're talking to?
I am the principal,
this is my house.
You don't get to come into
my office and disrespect me.
Okay, enough! I did it.
Okay? I splashed the tramp.
Hello?
Talia, where are you?
I don't know.
I was at Seneca and now,
I'm in some kind of jail.
A jail? Just go find the locker.
What lockers?
Just find the locker.
See something you like, Colten?
Keep walking.
Who is that?
Hey. Hi. What's your name?
I'm Tricia
but you guys can call me Trish.
I can see your trash.
Your skirt short enough?
Look, I didn't mean to start
any trouble.
I mean, it's just a skirt.
Oh, honey, that skirt
is the least of your problems.
I mean, did you put
your makeup on in the dark?
Like she would do any better
in the light.
So, where you from, Trash?
It's Trish. And Idaho.
Oh, that's sweet.
I mean, she admitted it.
She's a hoe.
I said Idaho.
- Can you not touch my stuff?
- Hey!
Listen,
you potato picking prostitute.
There are 5 girls around here
the boys can look at
and you are certainly
not one of them. Got it?
I certainly wasn't looking for attention
from any boys and I'm not a prostitute.
Do you see this?
It's definitely not her shade.
Is anything her shade?
But around here,
I tell you what you'll be.
Understand?
Go back to
where you came from, Trash.
Who has a picture of themselves
in their locker anyway?
Accurate.
- We got us a slut here, boys.
- Bye!
Also accurate.
Honey, are you okay?
- What happened?
- I don't know.
I was just getting my books and
these girls, they started insulting me...
I'm sorry, sweetheart, one second.
Hey. Hold up a second,
I have to talk to you.
I'm so sorry.
Sweetheart,
there are policies against this.
I just don't know exactly
what they are.
I would say speak to the janitor
and get this graffiti taken care of.
You are not allowed to have
anything derogatory on your locker.
You could get in really
big trouble for that.
Okay?
Yeah, did you get my voicemail? I'm sorry,
sweetheart. Are we still on for tonight?
I don't wanna be here anymore.
Hey.
It's okay.
Stop.
Stop it.
Stop it!
We got ourselves
a slut here, boys.
Trash.
Mom!
Do you have a girlfriend, Gabe?
No girlfriend?
More like a boyfriend.
He definitely doesn't swing this way.
C'mon, look at him.
Hey, Talia, did you remember to bring
a uniform for little Miss Gabe-y Wurton?
Oh, right.
You know, I haven't gotten
his skirt size yet.
Stand up, sweetie. C'mon.
The water boy can't go out
on the field without a uniform.
Turn.
I'm thinking like a real
short skirt, don't you think?
Yeah?
Maybe something that shows your butt
cheeks kind of like Nikki always does.
Accurate.
Or you could always go commando
like Pam does.
I think they're more than grateful
for the motivation I provide.
Shut up.
Trust me. We're grateful.
Hey! Really?
But you know, we really don't wanna see
your jewels dangling when we lift you up.
- You know what I mean, Gabe?
- Not too.
Bye!
No!
Hello?
Who is this?
What do you mean
who is this? It's your fianc.
How do I know it's you?
Excuse me?
What the hell's going on?
Where are you?
I'm in the auditorium.
Everybody's here waiting for you.
I...
I'm at Seneca.
I'm at Seneca I think,
I'm not sure.
Yeah, I'm at Seneca too.
You are? Where are you?
I'm in the auditorium.
There's really a reunion?
Hello?
And I know
we've all come a long way.
Welcome back after fifteen years.
Today,
I learned a lot about myself...
that I'm selfish, I'm egotistical,
I'm self-centered,
and I'm a bully.
In high school, it's supposed to be
some of the best memories of your life.
And I know that I've ruined them
for a lot of you people...
and I'm sorry.
That's just all I've ever known.
Seriously,
is computers a real skill?
No, it's such a waste of time.
When are we ever gonna
use computers?
Nice try.
Well, well, well.
What do we have here?
What are you doing?
Give me that! That's my...
- Give it to me!
- Hey!
Watch it.
"Dear Mom..."
- Awww.
- It's a love letter.
- It's personal.
- Don't even try.
- "I hate Seneca. The girls are so..."
- Seriously?
- Move along, tramp, let's go.
- Busy here.
"These girls are all bullies."
Hi, Ms. Price.
Let's keep it to a minimum.
Of course, Ms. Price. Of course.
"These girls are all bullies and
they make me feel like the biggest loser."
"I hate Talia. I hate her so much.
I'm afraid to give you this letter but
I keep thinking about killing myself
and I want you to help me."
You want your mother
to help you kill yourself?
Sweetheart, listen.
It's really not that hard.
Instead of putting bleach in your hair,
just put it in your mouth.
Or, I have razors. You clearly
don't know how to use one
but I can help you out.
- You think that we're the bullies?
- Accurate.
We didn't make you a loser.
Your mom did.
- It's in your blood, babe.
- Genetics.
So, you might as well
just kill yourself.
I'm sure she probably
won't even care,
and you know,
at least you'll be famous.
Bye!
I'm done.
I quit.
It's over when I say it's over.
You know what's expected of you.
I'm not interested
in any of that trivial crap.
Can you tell me something
about your future, your career,
something that I would be
interested in.
By your words
you shall be justified,
by your words
you shall be condemned.
Don't be like your father.
Can you do something about that lipstick?
It makes you look like a hooker.
One wrong word
can lead a client to jail.
can change your life forever.
...forever.
Okay, girls, we're ready to begin.
Hi there. How are you?
What's your name?
- Marie Carter. Senior.
- Marie Carter.
Senior? How are you?
Here you go. Good luck.
Please take a picture. Next.
- Hi there, what's your name?
- Trish Malone, Junior.
Get your picture taken, please.
You know, I got it by memory.
Next.
- Can you hear me?
- Lori, you're so cute.
Don't listen to her.
I like it. There you go.
Good luck.
Get your picture taken.
Next! Smile.
Don't listen to her!
Hello?
- Hi, Julie Klein. Sophomore.
- Turn around, Julie.
Okay, you'll do. Great.
Here you go. Good luck.
- Read it over, have your parents sign it.
- Thank you. Next.
I said next!
Don't do it.
Give her the application.
Hi...
Elle Wurthmore. Freshman.
Hello?
What the hell is that on her face?
Shut up!
Elle, is it?
Elle Wurthmore.
I know you can hear me.
Give her the application.
I'm sorry. We reached our limit.
Give her the God damn application.
Wurthmore?
Don't say it!
More like Wurth-less.
By your words
you shall be justified,
by your words
you shall be condemned.
Can't you do anything right?
You never fail to disappoint me.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
Are you serious?
You aren't at all
how I thought you'd be.
You're going to have
to suck it up.
Why are you the way you are?
What's wrong with you?
You're gonna have to try harder.
You make us look like failures.
You can't be that worthless.
Why can't you be
more like your sister.
- What's wrong with you.
- Shut up!
- This is the best you can do?
- Look at you.
Please.
When are you gonna live up to your
potential? Don't stop until you win.
You're worthless.
I'm sorry!
I'm so sorry.
What is my name?
It's Elle, right?
Elle what?
Wurthmore.
I don't know.
- Everyone thought that you...
- I killed myself?
No.
I didn't kill myself.
You killed me.
Over and over and over again.
All I ever wanted
was to be accepted.
I used to imagine
what life would be like
to be a part
of the cheerleading squad
and the day of the tryouts,
I rehearsed for hours
and hours on end.
A simple hello
would've made my day.
"Worthless".
I got "worthless".
My life has been turned
upside down.
I died because of you.
I'm so sorry.
How does this make you feel?
This is the choice you made.
I'm egotistical, I'm self-centered,
and I'm a bully.
In high school, it's supposed to be
some of the best memories of your life
and I know that I've ruined
them for a lot of you people.
Talia, hey, it's Nikki.
I know you didn't get in
'til like 3 AM or something,
but there's no way
you're still sleeping
so, can you just please
pick up the phone?
Leah's left like four messages
and she's flipping out.
Hello?
Okay, well whatever. We're gonna be
there in like 20 minutes anyway.
Bye.
Hello?
Hey, what's up, Jim?
Sorry to hear that.
So, obviously,
you're not gonna make it.
I completely understand.
Listen, my granddaughter Abby's
picking me up any minute now
and I still have to learn the speech
that she wrote for me.
Alright, we'll take care of everything
down at work. Don't worry about it.
Alright, I gotta run.
Alright, bye-bye.
Pap?
What are you doing?
It's 12:37.
Grandma's already left.
Have you even looked over
the speech that I wrote for you?
Yeah, I have everything
right here.
Yeah, I can see that you have them,
but have you read them?
Well, I looked at everything.
Can't I just say
what I want to say?
And can't you just allow me to...
Alright. Alright.
Thank you.
You know you get that
from your grand mom.
Let's go.
Come on.
Foundation color.
Much more suitable.
Okay.
Pap.
Like your grandmother.
One more time?
I think I got the first part down.
What is it that makes someone
feel so lost and alone
that they would take
their own life?
What are you trying to do?
Butcher my speech?
I'm sorry.
I should've done more.
We had the best doctors,
had the best medication...
Stop.
Just stop, will you?
Every year, I have to hear
the same thing again and again.
None of us knew what was going
on in my mom's head.
We did try.
And she did have the best doctors
and she was on every medication
that she could've been.
And I was the one that found her.
Not you, remember?
I found my mom.
I run one of the most successful
anti-bullying
and suicide prevention organizations
in the world because of her.
Stop beating yourself up
and look around
at what she did for us
instead of what she did to us.
I love you.
The car's outside.
Here, I have to go grab
a few things
but we'll go over this again
in the car before we get there.
You're gonna do great.
Got it?
Good.
Let's go, Pap.
You can do this.
Everybody's counting on you.