Mutation--
it is the key to our evolution.
It has enabled us to evolve
from a single-celled organism...
into the dominant species on the planet.
This process is slow and normally taking
thousands and thousands of years.
But every few hundred millennia,
evolution leaps forward.
Niagara Falls. Up...
the Canadian Rockies, and then it's
only a few hundred miles to Anchorage.
Well, won't it be kind of cold?
Well, that's the point, stupid.
Otherwise, it wouldn't be an adventure.
And when are you gonna do this?
I don't know.
After high school. Before college.
- Marie! David?
- I don't know what happened to him.
I don't know what--
I just touched him.
I didn't--
I didn't mean--
- Call an ambulance!
- Don't touch.
- Honey--    -Just get away from me!
- Call an ambulance!
Don't touch me!
- Don't touch me.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
we are now seeing the beginnings
of another stage of human evolution.
These mutations manifest at puberty...
and are often triggered by periods
of heightened emotional stress.
Thank you, Ms. Grey.
It was quite educational.
However, it fails toad dress the issue
that is the focus of this hearing.
Three words: "Are mutants dangerous?"
I'm afraid that's
an unfair question, Senator Kelly.
After all, the wrong person behind
the wheel of a car can be dangerous.
Well, we do license
people to drive.
Yes, but not to live.
Senator, it is a fact...
that mutants who have come forward
and revealed themselves publicly...
have been met with fear,
hostility, even violence.
It is because of that
ever-present hostility...
that I am urging the Senate to vote
against mutant registration.
- To force mutants to expose themselves will only further--
- Expose themselves?
What is it the mutant community
has to hide I wonder...
that makes them so afraid
to identify themselves?
- I didn't say they were hiding.
- Let me show you what is being hidden, Ms. Grey.
I have here a list of names
of identified mutants...
living right here
in the United States.
- Senator Kelly--
- Now, here's a girl in Illinois
who can walk through walls.
Now, what's to stop her
from walking into a bank vault...
or into the White House
or into their houses?
- Senator Kelly--
- And there are even rumors, Ms. Grey,
of mutants so powerful that they can enter
our minds and control our thoughts,
taking our God-given free will.
I think the American people
deserve the right to decide...
whether they want their children
to be in school with mutants,
to be taught by mutants.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the truth is that mutants are very real,
and they are among us.
- We must know who they are,
- That's right!
and, above all, we must know...
what they can do.
Eric.
- What are you doing here?
- Why do you ask questions...
to which you already
know the answers?
Don't give up on them, Eric.
What would you have me do, Charles?
I've heard these arguments before.
It was a long time ago.
Mankind has evolved since then.
Yes,
into us.
You sneaking around in here, Charles?
Whatever are you looking for?
I'm looking for hope.
I will bring you hope, old friend.
And I ask only one thing in return.
Don't get in my way.
We are the future, Charles, not them.
They no longer matter.
This is it.
Where are we?
I thought you said you were gonna
take me as far as Laughlin City.
This is Laughlin City.
Gentlemen, in all my years,
I've never seen anything like that.
Are you gonna let this man
walk away with your money?
I'll fight him!
Ladies and gentlemen, our savior!
Whatever you do,
don't hit him in the balls.
- You said anything goes.
- Anything goes, but he'll take it personal.
Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight's winner
and still king of the cage,
the Wolverine!
You want something new, honey?
Or are you sticking with water?
I'll have a beer.
Ellis Island, once the arrival point
for thousands of American immigrants...
is opening its doors again.
Preparations are nearly completed for
the upcoming United Nations world summit.
With nearly every invitation confirmed,
the event promises to be the largest
single gathering of world leaders in history.
The leaders of over 200 nations will discuss
issues ranging from the world's economic climate...
and weapons treaties to the mutant phenomenon
and its impact on our world stage.
Many American legislators have contended...
that debate over mutant issues should be
the primary focus of what is, on the surface,
a strictly diplomatic affair.
- You owe me some money.
- Come on, Stu. Let's not do this.
No man takes a beating like that
without am ark to show for it.
Come on, buddy.
This isn't gonna be worth it.
- I know what you are.   - You lost your money.
Keep this up, you'll lose something else.
Come on, buddy.
Look out!
Get out of my bar, freak.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm sorry. I needed a ride.
- Thought you might help me.
- Get out.
- Where am Is up posed to go?
- I don't know.
- You don't know or you don't care?
- Pick one.
- I saved your life.
- No, you didn't.
You don't have anything to eat, do you?
I'm Rogue.
Were you in the army?
Doesn't that mean you were in the army?
- Wow.
- What?
- Suddenly my life doesn't look that bad.
- If you'd prefer the road--
No. No. It looks great.
Looks cozy.
Put your hands on the heater.
I'm not gonna hurt you, kid.
It's nothing personal. It's just that...
when people touch my skin, something happens.
- What?
- I don't know.
They just get hurt.
Fair enough.
When they come out, does it hurt?
Every time.
So, what kind of a name is Rogue?
I don't know. What kind of a name is Wolverine?
My name's Logan.
Marie.
You know, you should wear your seat belt.
Look, kid. I don't need advice
on auto safety from--
You all right?
- Kid, are you all right?
- I'm stuck!
Weren't you supposed
to bring someone back with you?
- What happened?
- They knew.
Charles.
Hmm.
- Where is the mutant now?
- With them.
I have made the first move.
That is all they know.
Come. The U.N. summit is approaching.
Time for our little test.
Where's he going?
Where are you going?
Over here.
This way.
He's overt here.
- Let's go.
- What's your hurry?
Good morning, Logan.
I'd like your definitions of weak
and strong anthropic principles...
on my desk on Wednesday.
That'll be all.
- Bye, Professor.
- Bye, Kitty.
Physics.
I'm Charles Xavier.
Would you like some breakfast?
- Where am I?
- Westchester, New York.
You were attacked. My people
brought you here for medical attention.
- I don't need medical attention.
- Yes, of course.
- Where's the girl?
- Rogue? She's here. She's fine.
Really.
Ah, Logan, I'd like you to meet
Ororo Monroe, also called Storm.
- This is Scott Summers, also called Cyclops.
- Hello.
They saved your life.
I believe you've already met Dr. Jean Grey.
You're in my school fort he gifted. For mutants.
- You'll be safe here from Magneto.
- What's a Magneto?
A very powerful mutant
who believes that a war is brewing...
between mutants and the rest of humanity.
I've been following his activities for some time.
The man who attacked you is an associate
of his called Sabretooth.
Sabretooth?
Storm.
What do they call you? "Wheels?"
This is the stupidest thing I've ever heard.
Cyclops, right? You wanna get out of my way?
Logan, it's been almost 15years, hasn't it?
Living from day to day,
moving from place to place,
with no memory of who or what you are.
Shut up.
Give me a chance.
I may be able to help you find some answers.
How do you know?
You're not the only one with gifts.
- Where are you going?
- Where's he going?
What are you doing there?
What is this place?
Anonymity is a mutant's first chance...
against the world's hostility.
Hey, no powers!
To the public, we're merely
a school for gifted youngsters.
Cyclops, Storm and Jean
were some of my first students.
I protected them, taught them
to control their powers...
and in time, teach others to do the same.
The students are mostly run a ways.
Frightened, alone.
Some with gifts so extreme
that they've become a danger...
to themselves and those around them.
Like your friend, Rogue.
Incapable of physical human contact,
probably fort he rest of her life,
and yet here she is with others her own age,
learning being accepted, not feared.
-John.
- Sorry.
I'm Bobby. What's your name?
- Rogue.
- What'll happen to her?
Well, that's up to her. Rejoin the world
as an educated young woman...
or stay on to teach others...
to become what the children
have affectionately called X-Men.
Welcome to Mutant High.
But the school is merely a public face.
The lower levels, however, are
an entirely different matter.
When I was a boy, I discovered I had
the power to control people's minds,
make them think or do whatever I wanted.
When I was 17,
I met a young man named Eric Lensherr.
He, too, had an unusual power.
He could create magnetic fields
and control metal.
Believing that humanity would never accept us,
he grew angry and vengeful.
He became Magneto.
There are mutants out there
with incredible powers, Logan,
and many who do not share
my respect for mankind.
If no one is equipped to oppose them,
humanity's days could be over.
I'll make a deal with you, Logan.
Give me 48 hours to find out
what Magneto wants with you,
and I give you my word
that I will use all my power...
to help you piece together
what you've lost...
and what you're looking for.
Senator, listen,
you favor gun registration, yes?
Well, some of these
so-called children...
possess more than ten times
the destructive force of any handgun.
No, I don't see a difference.
All I see are weapons in our schools.
Well, that's fair enough. All right.
So?
It's gonna be close.
A vote this loaded is always close.
What about the U.N. summit?
The whole world will be watching.
Maybe there's some way
you could use that toy our advantage.
We're Americans, Henry.
Let the rest of the damn world deal
with mutants in their own way.
You know this situation?
These mutants?
People like this Jean Grey?
If it were up to me,
I'd lock'em all away.
It's a war.
It's the reason people like me exist.
Where the hell are we?
Pilot!
People like you are the reason
I was afraid to go to school as a child.
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
If I hurt you.
So, couldn't wait to get
my shirt off again, huh?
The metal is an alloy called domatium.
Supposedly indestructible. It's been
surgically grafted to his entire skeleton.
How could he have survived
a procedure like that?
His mutation. He has uncharted
regenerative capability,
which enables him
to heal rapidly.
This also makes his age
impossible to determine.
He could very well
be older than you, Professor.
- Who did this to him?
- He doesn't know.
Nor does he remember anything
about his life before it happened.
Experimentation on mutants.
It's not unheard of.
But I've never seen
anything like this before.
What do you think
Magneto wants with him?
I'm not entirely sure
it's him Magneto wants.
Yech!
Toad has a wicked tongue, Senator.
Just like you.
Who are you people?
Where's Henry?
Mr. Guy rich has been dead
for some time, Senator.
But I've had Mystique here
keep you company.
She takes so many shapes.
Whatever you do to me,
you'll make me right.
Every word I've spoken
will be confirmed.
Are you a God-fearing man, Senator?
That's such a strange phrase.
I've always thought
of God as a teacher,
as a bringer of light,
wisdom and understanding.
You see, I think
what you really are afraid of is me.
Me and my kind.
The Brotherhood of Mutants.
Though it's not
so surprising, really.
Mankind has always feared
what it doesn't understand.
Well, don't fear God, Senator,
and certainly, don't fear me.
Not anymore.
What do you intend to do to me?
Let's just say God works too slowly.
I think you'll be comfortable here.
- Where is your room?
- With Scott down the hall.
Is that your gift?
Putting up with that guy?
Actually, I'm telekinetic.
I can move things with my mind.
Really? What kinds of things?
All kinds of things.
I also have some telepathic ability.
- What, like your Professor?
- Nowhere near that powerful.
But he's teaching me to develop it.
I'm sure he is.
- So read my mind.
- I'd rather not.
Come on. You afraid you might like it?
I doubt it.
What do you see?
Scott.
Good night, Logan.
You gonna tell me
to stay away from your girl?
If I had to do that,
she wouldn't be my girl.
Hmm. Well, then, I guess
you've got nothing to worry about,
do you, Cyclops?
Yeah, it must just burn you up that
a boy like me saved your life, huh?
You ought to be careful.
I might not be there next time.
Oh, and, Logan,
stay away from my girl.
Logan.
Logan. Logan, wake up.
Help me.
Somebody help!
Scott, grab a pillow.
It was an accident.
- Logan?
- What happened?
- Is she all right?
- She'll be all right.
What did she do to me?
Whenever Rogue touches someone, she
takes their energy, their life force.
In the case of mutants, she absorbs
their gifts for a short while.
In your case, your ability to heal.
I feel like she almost killed me.
If she'd held out any longer,
she could have.
How are we feeling, Senator?
Advanced, I hope.
Hmm.
What the hell
have you done to me?
Senator, this is pointless.
Where would you go?
Who would take you in
now that you're one of us?
Tommy, let it go!
Tommy, please let it go!
I'm telling Mommy.
Is that a mutant?
...of this week's U.N. summit.
With the leaders
of over200nations attending,
the secret service
has transformed Ellis Island...
into a veritable Fort Knox
for tomorrow night's opening gala.
Ellis Island rests less than one mile
from the shores of Manhattan.
Rogue.
- Bobby.
- Rogue, what did you do?
They say that you're
stealing other mutants' powers.
No, no.
I borrowed his powers.
You never use your power
against another mutant.
I had no choice.
- No, you have to understand me.
- If I were you,
I'd get myself out of here.
- What do you mean?
- Listen, the students are freaked.
Professor Xavier's furious.
I don't know what he'll do with you.
I think it'll be easier
on your own.
You should go.
What are you looking for, Eric?
It's strange. There are
more powerful mutants out there.
Why should this one
be so important to him?
- Maybe it's his way with people.
- You don't like him.
- How could you tell?
- Well, I am psychic, you know.
- Where is she?
- Who?
Rogue.
She's gone.
Welcome, Professor.
Welcome to Cerebro.
This certainly is a big, round room.
The brain waves of mutants
are different from average human beings.
This device amplifies my power,
allowing me to locate mutants
across great distances.
That's how I intend to find Rogue.
- Why don't you just use it to find Magneto?
- I've been trying.
But he seems to have found
some way to shield himself from it.
How would he know how to do that?
Because he helped me build it.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Have you ever--
Used Cerebro?
No. It takes a degree of control,
and, uh, for someone like me, it's--
Dangerous.
...now boarding on track four.
- She's at the train station.
- Where is it?
A few miles west of here.
Logan, you can't leave the mansion.
- It's just the opportunity Magneto needs.
- I'm the reason she took off.
- We had a deal.
- She's all right. She's just upset.
Storm, Cyclops, find her.
See if you can talk to her.
- What?
- Where's my motorcycle?
Hey, kid.
I'm sorry about last night.
Me too.
- You running again?
- I heard the professor was mad at me.
- Well, who told you that?
- A boy at school.
- When's the last time you saw her?
- She was supposed to meet me for lunch.
You look around.
I'll check with the ticket agent.
Welcome, Professor.
- You think I should go back.
- No, I think you should follow your instincts.
The first boy I ever kissed...
ended up in a coma for three weeks.
I can still feel him inside my head.
And it's the same with you.
There's not many people that'll
understand what you're going through,
but I think this guy's
Xavier's one of them.
He seems to genuinely wanna help you,
and that's a rare thing...
for people like us.
So, what do you say?
Give these geeks one more shot?
Come on. I'll take care of you.
- You promise?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I promise.
Come along now.
She's about 17. Uh, my height.
Has brown hair, and she--
Scream for me.
Quit playing around.
You must be Wolverine.
That remarkable metal doesn't run
through your entire body, does it?
Stop! Stop it!
What the hell do you want with me?
You? My dear boy,
whoever said I wanted you?
Young people.
All right, hold it.
Hold it right there.
Stay where you are.
Put your hands over your heads now.
You Homo sapiens and your guns.
- That's enough, Eric.
- Let them go.
Why not come out where
I can see you, Charles?
- What do you--
- Want her for?
Can't you read my mind?
What now? Save the girl?
You'll have to kill me, Charles.
And what will that accomplish?
Let them pass that law. They'll have you in
chains with a number burned into your forehead.
- It won't be--
- That way.
Then kill me and find out.
Huh? Then release me.
Fine.
Care to press your luck, Charles?
I don't think I can stop them all.
Still unwilling
to make sacrifices.
That's what makes you weak.
Good-bye, Charles.
- You said he wanted me.
- I made a terrible mistake.
His helmet was somehow designed
to block my telepathy.
I couldn't see what
he was after till it was too late.
- Where are you going?
- I'm gonna find her.
- How?
- The traditional way. Look.
Logan, you can't do this alone.
Who's gonna help me? You?
So far you've all done a bang-up job.
Then help us. Fight with us.
Fight with you?
What, join the team? Be an X-Man?
Who the hell do you think you are?
You're a mutant.
The whole world out there is full
of people that hate and fear you.
And you're wasting your time trying to
protected? I got better things to do.
You know, Magneto's right.
There's a war coming.
- You sure you're on the right side?
- At least I've chosen a side.
I'm looking for Dr. Jean Grey.
Senator Kelly.
I'm Professor Charles Xavier.
I was afraid if I went
to a hospital, they would--
Treat you like a mutant?
We're not what you think. Not all of us.
Tell it to the ones who did this to me.
Senator...
I want you to try and relax.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Welcome to the future,
brother.
The machine emits radiation that triggers
mutation in ordinary human beings.
But the mutation is unnatural.
Kelly's body is rejecting it.
His cells began...
to break down almost immediately.
- What effect does radiation have on mutants?
- There appears to be none.
But I fear it will seriously
harm any normal person exposed to it.
- So what does Magneto want with Rogue?
- I don't know.
Wait a second.
You said this machine
draws its power from Magneto...
-and that it weakened him.
- Yes.
In fact, it nearly killed him.
He's gonna transfer his power to Rogue...
and use her to power the machine.
Is somebody there?
Yes. I'm here.
Please don't leave me.
Don't want to be alone.
All right.
Do you hate normal people?
Sometimes.
Why?
I suppose...
I'm afraid of them.
Well,
I think you've got one less person to--
to be afraid of.
Cyclops, you and Storm ready the jet.
I'm gonna find Rogue.
-Jean, get Logan a uniform.
- Whoa, wait a minute.
- He's not coming with us, is he?
- Yes.
I'm sorry, Professor, but he'll
endanger the mission. And if--
Hey, I wasn't the one who gave
the train station a new sun roof, pal.
- No, you were the one who stabbed
Rogue through the chest.     - Scott--
Hey, why don't you take your
little mission and stick it up your--
Senator Kelly is dead.
I'm going to find her.
Settle this.
I'm sorry.
You cans till hear me, can't you?
You've taught me everything in my life
that was ever worth knowing.
And if anything happens,
well, I'll take care of them.
Jean?
Jean!
No!
Jean?
Jean.
Answer me. Please.
I know where Magneto's going.
Magnificent, isn't she?
- I've seen it.
- I first saw her in 1 949.
America was gonna be
the land of tolerance,
of peace.
Are you going to kill me?
- Yes.
- Why?
Because there is no land of tolerance.
There is nope ace.
Not here or anywhere else.
Women and children,
whole families destroyed...
simply because they were born different
from those in power.
Well, after tonight, the world's
powerful will be just like us.
They will return home as brothers.
As mutants.
Our cause will be theirs.
Your sacrifice will mean our survival.
I'll understand if that
comes as small consolation.
Put her in the machine.
I'll raise it.
Magneto is here. Liberty Island.
Now, presumably, his objective is to mutate
the world leaders at the U.N. summit...
on Ellis Island.
He doesn't know his machine kills.
And judging from what the Professor saw,
if Magneto gave Rogue enough power--
He could wipe out everyone
in New York City.
We can insert here
at the George Washington Bridge,
come around the bank
just off of Manhattan.
We land on the far side
of Liberty Island here.
What about harbor patrol? Radar?
If they have anything that can pick up
our jet, they deserve to catch us.
You actually go outside in these things?
Well, what would you prefer,
yellow spandex?
Whoa!
Okay, there's the bridge.
I'm taking her down.
Storm, some cover,
please.
Toad, Mystique, stays harp.
We're not alone.
And you stay here.
Once I give my power to the girl,
I'll be temporarily weakened.
You'll be
my only defense.
Sounds like
a storm's coming.
- Sorry.
- You call that a landing?
The torch.
...within a mile oft he proceedings.
The first dignitaries
started to arrive about an hour ago,
greeted with a sort
of garden-party atmosphere,
which was designed
to entertain them,
as the others
traversed the rigid security.
- There's someone here.
- Where?
- I don't know. Keep your eye open.
- Logan.
Damn it.
- Anything?
- I know there's someone here. I just can't esteem.
- Wait!
All right, back up. Back up.
Jean!
Oh, God.
Don't move.
Don't you people ever die?
Do you know what happens to a toad
when it's struck by lightning?
Same thing that happens
to everything else.
Logan, is that you?
Shh.
The other one ain't far away.
Come on. We have to regroup.
I know, but there's a problem.
You're not part of the group.
Hey, hey, it's me.
- Prove it.
- You're a dick.
Okay.
Hey.
Everybody get out of here.
- What is it?
- I can't move.
Ah, my brothers.
Welcome. And, you,
just point those claws of yours
in a safer direction.
You'd better close your eyes.
- Storm, fry him.
- Oh, yes.
A bolt of lightning into
a huge copper conductor.
I thought you lived at a school.
For those of you who may not be familiar
with the historical significance--
Mystique?
- Mystique?
- I've seen Senator Kelly.
So the good senator survived his fall...
and the swim to shore.
He's become even more powerful
than I could have imagined.
- He's dead.
- It's true.
Is a whim die.
Like those people down there will die.
Are you sure you saw what you saw?
I would also like to thank
the president of the United States...
for hosting this event...
under the lights of
the great city of New York.
Why do none of you understand
what I'm trying to do?
Those people down there, they control our
fate and the fate of every other mutant.
Well,
soon our fate will be theirs.
Help! Please help me!
You're so full of shit.
If you were really so righteous,
it'd be you in that thing.
Help! Somebody help me!
Please!
Somebody please help me!
Somebody!
Help--
Logan!
- I'm sorry, my dear.
- Don't do this.
This is mine.
You owe me a scream.
Hey, bub. I'm not finished with you yet.
Jean.
- Scott, when I tell you, open your eyes.
- No.
- Trust me.
- You drop something?
Now.
- Thanks.
- Don't mention it.
We gotta get her out of there.
Cyclops, can you hit it?
- The rings are too fast. I'll kill her.
- Just shoot it.
- Storm, can you get me up there?
- I can't control it like that.
- You could fly right over the torch.
- Then let me go.
If I don't make it, then at least
you can still blast the damn thing.
All right, do it.
Jean, use your power. Try to steady him.
Hang on to something.
Scott, wait.
- I have to.
-Just wait.
I have a shot.
I'm taking it.
Come on.
Hey, this one's alive.
Let's get him out of here.
Welcome back.
I knew you'd find your way.
I had you to guide me.
How did we do?
Oh! Oh, that tickles.
Hey.
- How're you feeling?
- Fantastic.
That was a brave thing you did.
- Did it work?
- Yeah. She's fine.
She took on a few of your more
charming personality traits for a while.
But we lived through it.
I think she's a little taken with you.
Well, you can tell her
my heart belongs to someone else.
- You know, you and I--
- How's the professor?
- He's good.
- Good.
There's an abandoned military compound
at Alkali Lake in the Canadian Rockies,
close to where we found you.
There's not much left,
but you might find some answers.
- Thank you.
- Are you going to say good-bye to them?
The Mutant Registration Act
lost its main proponent today...
with the dramatic reversal
of Senator Robert Kelly,
who until this time had provided the loudest
voice in the cry for mutant registration.
I was wrong on this particular issue.
And I hope in time I may be forgiven.
Thank you.
- The Mutant Registration Act
continues to draws up port...     - Mystique.
Son of a bitch.
from many Parents Rights groups...
who feel threatened by unidentified
mutants in their school systems.
In a related story,
the body of Senator Kelly's long time
aide, Henry Gyrich, was found today.
Preliminary coroner reports seem to indicate
that Gyrich was mauled by a bear.
Hey.
- You running again?
- No, not really.
I have some things
to take care of up north.
I kind of like it.
I don't want you to go.
I'll be back for this.
Doesn't it ever wake you
in the middle of the night?
The feeling that someday
they will pass that foolish law...
or one just like it and come for you...
and your children?
It does, indeed.
What do you do when
you wake up to that?
I feel a great swell of pity
for the poor soul...
who comes to that school
looking for trouble.
Why do you come here, Charles?
Why do you ask questions
to which you already know the answers?
Oh, yes.
Your continuing search for hope.
You know this plastic prison of theirs
won't hold me forever.
The war is still coming,
Charles, and I intend to fight it...
by any means necessary.
And I will always be there,
old friend.