Keep your eyes open.
Let's go.
-Alo
-Alo, is this the police department?
I am Cengiz Arslan, officer.
My life is in danger.
Yes.
No, they want to kill me.
Several people I don't know.
They were threatening on the phone, the last
few days. I don't know anything about it.
-Please continue.
-3 of the people who has been selected by
your magazine as one of the 10 most
fashionable people, are murdered.
Besides, perpetrators are still unknown.
Doesn't it sound a little strange to you?
-I couldn't understand what you're implying.
You mean I am accused of murder?
-No, no...
-We can't have an opinion about anyone for now.
As you know, our company has insured this
ten people including you for large sums of money.
This is quite a hard situation.
And you know that the insurances
were made by your magazine.
We are paying one million liras for
each person who dies.
Up until now, we payed 3 million
liras for the 3 people who died.
-So, why do I care?
-Of course, for now there is nothing
you should worry about.
Only, I want to state this:
If these murders don't stop, the
police may arrest you.
-Is it over?
-Yes... For now...
-If you excuse me...
-Hello, Betmen.
Firstly, we congratulate you for
the success on your last heroin mission.
Let's talk about your new mission now.
You have probably read about the murders
commited in the last few days on the newspapers.
You will see their pictures when
you look in the folder next to the stereo.
As we predict the rest will be murdered as well.
If you want the ringleader's name, we can
only give you Altan Soner, the magazine owner.
Despite there is no proof, he is the only suspect.
That means, he is the only person
to benefit from these murders.
Victims and the others have been insured
for one million liras by his magazine.
He is in a conclusin that he will
loot a great deal of money this way.
Because, he has chosen the jury
that conducted the contest...
...some illegal actions appeared.
and his men silenced the ones that have objected
He is not a reliable person.
The interesting part of it is that
he insured himself as well.
It's clear that there is
something wrong about this.
He may try to kill everyone who opposes him.
He is too interested in a beautiful
girl called Emel among them.
We suggest that he feels close to her.
We have no certain proof against him
His men are faithful to him to the death.
We learned that he runs a night club in Beirut.
It's certain that he will flee abroad if he succeed.
In that case, we will lose a criminal and a lot of currency.
I guess you understand the importance of this mission.
If you succeed this mission and
catch him with all the proof,
the insurance company has promised a prize for you.
Our confidence for you is limitless.
You may ask our help if you need it.
We wish you good luck.
As usual, destroy the tape after it ends.
-Bravo, Robin.
You're still in good shape.
Listen what I'm about to say very carefully.
-I'm listening.
-You may have read about the
three murders on the newspapers.
-Yes.
-3 of the 9 people insured by our company.
-Is this a conspiracy
-I think it is certain.
The others will be killed too.
So, someone who insured them will have the money.
-Who insures them?
-A magazine owner.
His name is Altan.
Altan Soner...
Nothing can be done because the lack of evidence.
Before the others get killed, we must
intervene and clear the case.
We will start with Seher, the stripper.
-Okay!
-Someone's coming!
-She's dead.
Speak!
-I was expecting you.
What will you discuss with me?
-The people who are selected by your magazine and gets murdered one by one.
-How dare you? What does
it have to do with me?
-Don't get angry all of a sudden.
We were only going to ask a couple of questions.
-Like what?
-Can you give me the jury list of the
competition that your magazine conducted?
-Unfortunately, I don't
remember the juries now.
-Maybe you remember
but you don't want to give it.
-Look, you can't accuse me like this.
My magazine conducted a
competition and 10 people won it.
What is it to me if they keep dying?
In the other hand, I am
one of those 10 people.
-And that's what I don't understand.
-Please stop this conversation here.
-Have a nice day.
-Have a nice day, sir.
-What do they want?
-Nothing.
They're coming from the insurance company.
-I've seen you a little angry.
Has something distasteful happened?
-No, sweetheart.
What can be distasteful when you're around.
My tasteful...
-So, what do we do now?
-Let's go to Emel first. Let's
see what she's doing.
We should also learn if she has insurance.
-What about Altan?
-Don't think about him for now.
But we won't forget about him either.
We will find out what he's up to.
C'mon
-Thank you.
I won't forget about your favor.
Don't exaggerate what we do.
But take care of yourself.
Be careful when you go out.
And don't forget to lock the door when you're inside.
-I won't
-By the way, do you have insurance?
-No, I have no intention either.
-Spot on!
If you had any, you could have been in trouble.
-Like what?
-Anyway, forget about this now. We
will keep an eye on you.
You will help us solve all our problems.
-Have a nice day.
-We can't accuse anyone without a proof.
-But you have to do something. You
have to broaden the investigation.
Our men are after the suspects as well.
-Investigation continues day and night.
Of course we have some information.
But the result is not satisfactory yet.
-To pay all that money would shake our company.
The others are insured as well. They might get killed too.
-You don't worry. We will do as much as we can.
Justice always comes at the end.
-Alright. Thank you.
-You had womething to do outside,
right? Let's go have a walk.
-You, fools.
How come you let her slip away, idiots?
-All of a sudden, two men like bats have shown up.
We couldn't understand how it happened.
-Cut it out!
Always have an excuse!
Is that why I'm giving you fistfuls of money, you fucking idiots?
-Listen to me.
We won't change the row.
You'll finish Funda today.
As I understand, we're dealing  with Betmen.
That's why we need to be very careful.
-What is it, honey? Are you scared?
-You know I'm not.
But still, we need to be careful.
-Leave him to me if you want. I can finish him.
-No, we will defeat him without killing him.
I will play such a game to him,
even he won't understand it.
-You know the best.
-Come, come, darling.
-Did Altan make an offer to you?
-He said that he is a prosperous man. Bu
he said it doesn't satisfy him.
-Did he want to get you insurance?
-Yes.
But of of course I didn't accept it.
He is a dangerous man.
-Nevermind. It doesn't matter.
-How did you become Betmen? to
be more exact, why did you?
-There is a power inside me against evil
that I don't know the foundation of.
And my bat costume gives terror to evil people.
-So, you're powerless against the good?
-Yes.
And especially against a pretty girl like you.
For the good people, my fists are like turkish
delights, and my kicks are candies.
-You're so humorous!
I feel more comfortable with you.
I feel prideful
-Thank you for everything.
-Don't worry about anything. be calm.
I'll call you.
-Goodbye.
-Yes?
-May I come?
-One moment.
Yes, I'm listening.
-Your name was Funda, right?
-Yes.
-I will discuss some metters with you.
-Alo?
-Alo, I'm Emel.
-Holy shit.
Yes, darling.
-Sorry, darling. Can I see you?
-Oh, yes, of course. I would be delighted.
But I've got a terrible fever. See you tomorrow, right?
-Betmen!
Betmen!
-Shit.
Now, I'm fucked.
-Wear it quickly.
-Now, I'm sick and you're the nurse, okay?
-We will fool them with this trick. But
don't ever let them understand.
Now, run and open the door.
-Come in. I'm the nurse.
-Oh, my darling. What happened
to you? How did you get cold?
Oh god. What to do? I
should better get a towel.
-50
You're medically not alive, son.
-It's 50 degrees.
-Just be busy with your patient.
I'm so sick, okay? If you care about
your life, you'll tell her that I'm sick.
-Understood?
-Okay, Okay...
-What a pity, darling. How did you get this fever?
-Do I know what the hell I'm doing?
-He's got a terrible fever. I must give
you a prescription. Take them immediately.
-You have to take these medicine immediately.
-I am going to the drug store. I'll be right back.
-Don't rush. Take your time.
Finally, they're gone.
It's over now.
-It's me, Robin.
I've gone to Funda's house but she's killed.
-What did you say?
I'm going to Funda's house.
-What a pity. We're late.
I know what to do.
To solve this, we must get going
Robin
C'mon Robin.
We're going to Altan's house.
Now, it's all messed up, Robin.
He's killed
The other one's killed.
This one's killed as well.
-So, what do we do now?
-Let's go to the company.
-4 more people must die for us to reach our goal.
You'll deal with Emel, like you did with Funda.
Only, we must capture the important hints from her.
-You don't worry about it, chief.
The best man for this job is me, Ceyhan.
-I planned the rest flawlessly.
I guess there will be no mistakes.
And we have already reached the end.
-You're welcome. Who are you looking for.
-Is your name Emel?
-Yes.
-I have come here to talk about a proposition.
-Of course. Let's have a seat.
-Would you want anything to drink?
-If it won't be a trouble, yes.
-Here you go.
-Merci
I'm coming from the insurance company.
-If you've come here to sell an insurance
to me, you whouldn't have bothered.
-Look, there is a lot of things
beneficial for you. Let me explain.
-Don't bother. I'll never do it
-Oh, my head.
-What is it? What happened?
-I just felt dizzy. Do you have any
medicine for nausea and dizziness?
-It must be. Let me have a look.
-This might help, I guess. Take it.
-Thank you.
You should drink it.
-Things are going according to my plans, darling
If the boys succeed the last part
as well, we will have a good fortune
And then, hello to Beirut.
-So, what about me?
-You will come with me too.
-But I don't want another women.
When we get there, I want to
have a life only with you, darling.
-Don't you ever worry, sweetheart.
You will be my only woman.
We will be living in a great fortune.
Now, let's drink for our upcoming happy days.
Well, well... Are you a dream or a fairy?
-I'm not either a fairy or a dream.
-I'm only a mankind.
-A mankind?
Aren't you supposed to be womankind?
-You are so witty.
-It looks that way.
-What are you looking for here?
-Love.
Let's not waste our
time. How do you want it?
-Up in the hole.
-You!
are the girl I saw in Altar's house.
Now, I get it.
Tell me! What are you up to?
Tell me!
Yes.
Tell me! Who do you work for?
Who's the chief? Tell me.
-Don't hit me. I'll tell you.
Let me have a smoke first.
-Tell me!
Who killed the girl, tell me! Why did you kill her?
-Yes, it's me.
-Okay, okay. Very well.
Okay, I'll get it done.
Right, right. I'll do it.
Okay, fine. Goodbye.
-Yes, I'm listening.
I'm sending it right away.
Send a crew immediately.
Be quick.
-Yes, sir.
-It's you!
-Yes, It's me.
-Weren't you murdered?
-Don't worry. I didn't rise from the dead.
-So, you didn't die!
-I didn't, madam.
-Did you kill all nine of them?
-No. All eight of them.
Because I didn't die.
I played dead to get the money from insurance.
And after I have you, I will kill you too.
Come here. Come...
You just can't run away!
-Let me go!
-No matter how you resist, you'll be mine.
You'll be mine! Mine!
-Congratulations, Betmen!
-We are very proud of you for both saving our compony
from bankruptcy and saving our nation from these evil people.
The end.