My name is Subramaniyam.
I always wanted to be on top in life...
...but didn't think
I will be on top like this.
If I fall from here,
everything is finished.
No One can even identify my body.
- Help!
If a lion or tiger kills you
it atleast makes for a grand story.
Maybe I am the only person
to die in the hands of a goat.
My weight is 70 kilograms.
If my hands take the entire weight,
I might manage for 30 minutes.
Ifl alternate both hands
then maximum one hour.
It doesn't look like this goat will
let me live even for one hour.
What is this?
How did I get here? Who am I?
My father is a bank employee.
Though he counted lakhs
of rupees in the bank daily...
...we would fall shod
of money at home.
He told me that happiness is being satisfied with
what we have, and everyone can't become Ambani.
That logic just didn't get into my head.
The World recognises you
only by your bank balance.
I was ready to do anything
for that recognition.
I felt school was a waste of time.
I wasn't earning.
I felt the sooner
I got out of it the better.
I reached 10th standard when
my children my age were in 8th standard.
Soon all teachers and
parents became my fans.
I wake up at 4am daily
and take bath with cold water.
It is very good for my concentration.
Actually I follow everything
according to time table.
Chocolates and
ice-creams are banned.
Ifl really feel like it then maybe
on some national holiday...
...or Sunday, I will eat one.
- He is acting too smart
- Catch him!
- Stop!
Stop!
- Please leave me!
- Where will you go?
Tell me your rules again..
It's wrong to eat ice-creams, is it?
Ice-creams are very good,
I will get you the best ice-creams.
So why were you acting smafl
in front of my parents yesterday?
Hey! Umbrella.
Hey! Stop...
That's when I saw him for the first time.
I didn't know then, how drastically
my life was going to change.
- Who are you?
- Rishi! Class 10 B.
This is 10 A's matter.
Don't interfere.
Which section is not the point here...
Even you are acting smart aa...?
The point is who makes the first move!
Hey, Subbu! This is my house.
Keep it inside.
- Hi, mom!
- Hi, Rishi!
- That's my best friend Subbu!
- Oh! Hi, Subbu!
- Hi.
- Rishi's friend?
Which class you are studying in?
- 10:00 AM
Why are you eating the boost powder directly?
But, I like it like that only mom.
Rishi's father is a big businessman.
Rishi is a big disappointment for him.
You can never say how friends
like Rishi end up becoming your best friend.
They become a part of our life
as if they have been there forever.
So many first time experiences
because of him.
Stop!
Being chased after stealing for
the first time.
Stop I say!
Watched a movie from the best seats..
...for the first time.
I rode a bicycle for the first time.
I fell for the first time.
I almost drowned
for the first time.
Rishi would do whatever he felt like.
Life was a Bollywood movie to him.
"Popular Hindi film song"
Hey, get out!
Sit! Sit! Hey!0
Rishi would spend more
time outside class than inside...
...except in Telugu class...
Prabhakar sir.
Rishi liked Prabhakar sir very much.
He told more stories than lessons.
"The World is a illusion."
"Life is a illusion."
"This is the essence of the Vedas."
What great poetry...what a poet!
This family,
jobs, societal responsibilities...
...they tie you up, blind you.
Take you away from the truth.
- Good morning, teacher.
- Good morning. Sit down.
Thank you, teacher.
Who are you?
Where is Prabhakar sir?
First sit down!
I am your new Telugu teacher.
Prabhakar sir has quit his job.
No!
Subbu! Subbu!
Why did you come at this time?
my timetable...
Happy birthday, Subbu!
How do you know?
How wont I know..
Come I have a surprise for you.
- Open your eyes and see.
- No, thank you.
- Hey! Where?
- Come, follow me.
On a birthday you take someone out
for a movie or a hotel but...
...why did you bring me to
a graveyard man!
Come. I said its a surprise.
This is enough surprise man.
Come, lets go back.
- Hey, no!
- They are Aghora sadhus.
- People say they eat human flesh.
- Why are you telling me this?
Yes...
Come.
Hello, sir.
- How did you find me?
- Your apartment watchman told me, sir.
Who is that? Subbu?
Yes, sir. Today is his birthday.
Hey, happy birthday.
Seek blessings from Guruji.
- Go.
- No, sir.
Seek blessings.
- It's o-k.
- Seek.
- No!
Go!
Seek.
Doesn't your guru have an ashram?
Why is he sitting in a cemetery like this?
Whether it is graveyard or temple...
...whether diamonds or stones, you or me
Everything is the same.
That is the first principle
of the Aghora way.
That sounds great sir, but.
when are you coming back to class?
That new teacher is super boring.
I have given up these worldly illusions.
I am going to
Doodh Kashi with Babaji.
- He wants to leave his body in that holy place.
- Where is that?
In the shadow ofthe tallest mountain in the Himalayas
there is said to be a secret lake.
Our scriptures mention it
as Akasha Ganga.
When will I see you again?
Can we also come there?
It must be written in your fate to visit
Doodh Kashi. Not everybody can find it.
WOW!
So now we HAVE to go there at any cost.
Ask your Guruji.
Is it written in my fate?
Will I go?
Will I take Subbu along with me?
Who must go where and with whom.
Only the Lord Shiva knows.
Himalayas! A Secret lake!!
We definitely need to go there.
First I need to go home.
My time table got
spoiled because of you.
- Now I should revise twice.
- Forget your timetable man..
Whatever happens,
we will definitely go to Doodh Kashi.
- Hey! Look in front!
- !!!
I thought you will learn
some good from Subbu...
...but you are spoiling him too.
- Uncle, actually...
- Subbu!
Where are you roaming in the night?
Where are you going?!
Doodh Kashi!
Sorry. I will make sure
this won't happen again.
Rishi's father became
very angry after the accident.
They shifted and left Hyderabad.
Since then I lost touch with Rishi.
Now there was no distraction.
My plan was back on track.
Is the measure of progress only money?
Should the Future of farmers
who live by the earth...
...be decided by those in these skyscrapers?
Ramaiah seeds company.
Since 50 years, their priority has
been the farmers welfare rather than profits...
...and are treating their
thousands of employees like family.
Company's MD Mr. Ramaiah.
On another hand
Pashupathi Industries...
...this company has
built many Hi-Tech Industries.
Now they have set their
eyes on Ramaiah Company's lands.
We have built this
company together...working hard.
We have invested our lives in it,
not just money.
We will not sell
our lives, whatever the price.
For buying my shares
in Ramaiah Company...
...this is the offer
letter given by Pashupathi.
This is my answer to him.
What is this?
Mani, what the hell is this!
I even offered 10 percent
premium on those shares.
- I didn't think he will do this.
- Enough.
I told you to make
this offer privately.
Now he came on TV and spoiled
my reputation.
Call the PR depaflment and
ask them to fix it immediately.
. OK@V'
Where is Subbu?
Hey, Subbu. Are you watching TV?
Dad is very upset.
You know he tried many
times to buy Ramaiah Company.
Come fast, we need to do
some damage control.
- I'm here.
Subbu...
The Mistake is mine.
I bought so many companies
over these years.
Only this one has eluded me.
A jewel in my crown.
- I wished for it
- Sir, there is nothing wrong in wishing.
- Ramaiah Company is yours.
- Hey! Don't talk rubbish.
Ramaiah has been protecting
his company since 50 years.
He will not sell it at any cost.
I already tried it.
We saw what happened when you tried.
- Now, Its my turn.
- Pashupathi... Look, Pashupathi.
He is talking without
showing any respect to senior.
Subbu, this is not easy.
In spite of offering a blank cheque,
shareholders are not selling.
It's not money that they need to see...
...its their needs and liabilities.
Are you teaching me only?
You think he Will come looking for you?
- Sir! Sir! Stop, sir! Please, sir!
- Who is Subramaniyam here?
Can't you understand if I tell you once?
I tore it in front of the media.
And you send it again?
Fine! I will tear in front of you.
Tear it! Tear it!
I lose just 50 rupees if you tear it.
But you will receive
5 Million if you sign it.
Double the value of the shares you own.
- Is this a Bribe?
- No! No! Sir, I know about your honesty.
But can you send your son to America with
your honesty and a 30,000 rupees salary?
Can you perform your
elder daughter's marriage?
How do you know about these?
Anyway, that's not related.
We lived on Mr. Ramaiah's grace.
Whatever you may say,
we will not betray him.
This same dialoguemsounds familiar...
Oh Yes, Mr. Ranganath.
Before writing over
his 10 percent shares.
Mr. Bhaskar also..same dialogue
All of you speak alike.
- Mr. Bhaskar too"?
- Kiriti.
- Sir
- Tea.
Okay, sir.
Mr. Ramaiah's company is
incurring losses since four years.
Sales have reduced.
They are unable to pay salaries.
If it continues like this then
company will shut down in one year.
After that thousands of employees
will lose jobs. That is...
That is...real Betrayal.
Mr. Ramaiah will look into it.
H OW?
People like Mr. Ramaiah cannot do
business these days.
Business needs people like me.
Otherwise companies will shut down.
- You have it, right?
What?
Sugar. You have it.
See, I am thinking more
about you than yourself.
Look, Mr. Gopal Rao,
your 10 percent shares.
You must be thinking
that by keeping them safe...
...without betraying Mr. Ramaiah
is correct now...
...but after your company shuts downs in
six months...and your shares become worthless.
...after your son's studies and
your daughter's marriage get spoiled...
...you may not find
it correct at that time.
Presently, You have tea...
...peacefully.
And...Sign for your future.
For Mr. Gopal Rao--
By the way, I forgot.
For Mani also...He tried.
Hey, Mani!
I really don't believe this.
Subbu, how did you...when did you..
Sir, I know how important
Ramaiah's deal is to you.
I have been working
on it for few months.
- Oh, totally--
- 50 percent shares, sir.
Sir, we need 51 percent
to have our control.
I was thinking why
you didn't enter yet.
Believe me, sir. Ramaiah's nephew...
they have pampered him a lot...
...he is in deep debt...
...he committed the mistake which
we need. The shares in his name...
...l am going to buy them.
- Are you sure?
100 percent, sir. Those shares
will be in our name in two days.
Amazing! Amazing, Subbu.
What I couldn't do all these years... Mani,
call for a press meeting immediately
We will announce
Ramaiah Company belongs to us.
QKZV -
Sir, amazing how you convinced him
in the time it took me to make tea.
Sir, you are really superb... okay.
- By the way, my marriage is fixed
- With whom?
A family friend... she stays in my village..
I know her since childhood.
What do you want
to do in life, Kiriti?
Sir, I want to become like you.
You are my role model.
If I marry my villager relative now...
...then forget my position,
I will come to your position.
Excuse me, sir?
Kiriti, if you marry
your uncle's daughter...
...at best you will get pickles
on festivals from the village.
Yes, recently I received mango pickle.
- Is it good?
Yes, sir. Chilli was bit strong,
also I like garlic pickle more.
- Kiriti.
Jump..
- Hi, Subbu
- Hi, Riya. Come.
So Mr. Subramaniyam.
So Riya.
The company my father couldn't buy
since 20 years will belong to us now.
And that...is because of you.
You know I don't like anything easily?
I want the best in everything.
- Me too
- But I like you.
If your father likes me too...then...l'm ready.
Hi!
Hi! For Riya's marriage...
...l thought they will
choose a big business family.
Don't know how they agreed
for a guy having no background.
Did you see Mrs. Aggarwais necklace.
It is a imitation jewellery.
They had to sell everything
after the income tax raid.
No bad, they are still
maintaining the show well.
- Hello
- Hello, I love your necklace.
- Thank you, dear
- Congratulations.
Congratulations!
I was just telling my husband...
...how lucky Riya is.
What a perfect couple!
Hello everybody!
Thank you very much for coming today.
Thank you.
When I met Subbu for the first time,
I felt I had seen him somewhere.
And then I remembered...
...it was me.
Hunger is essential for business.
A Hunger that can consume this whole world.
It took 30 years for
me to reach this position.
But Subbu...
he is here in just five years.
To be precise and simple.
Subbu is the future.
And I think my daughter has made
the smartest decision in her life.
Riya my darling, come.
I love you very much today.
You know why?
Somewhere I always missed having a son.
Today that wish is fulfilled.
Welcome to the family my boy.
Subbu... here.
I got something for you.
For now key is here, within ten days you
will receive a car designed personally.
Thank you so much, sir.
Praveen!
"Who is Subramaniyam!"
Riya, did you invite him?
- No, dad.
- Then who the hell is he!
Subbu!
Idiot, How can you not call ME
to your engagement?
Anyway, how can you escape me...
Rishi..This is not your type of pafly.
Leave, We will talk later.
Hey, is this...my sister-in-law.
You won the jackpot! She is hot!
I mean..beautiful.
There is still time for marriage.
Just remember,
if you have any doubt on Subbu.
...l am single.
- This is my friend Rishi.
Friend aa? Best friend!
We are best friends!
Hey, uncle... father in law?...
we are best friends.
- Aunty! Greetings!
- Hey! Hey!
I don't... I don't like this.
Get him out of here.
Hey, You haven't see Subbu
dancing to this song, right?
Hey, Subbu! Let's show them.
Ready! One! Two! Three! Go!
Well, now you are pan of our gang,
right?
- Come..
- Subbu.
- Hi, Subbu!
- Hi!
Today is the appointment
at Casa Paradise.
We can't be late, Subbu. We have
to wait for another month if we miss this.
I am starting right now.
Come fast, Subbu.
- Hello?
What is the sound?
Riya, I'll just call you back.
Yellamma!
Yellamma! Back straight, Yellamma.
- Do this for ten minutes.
- Like this! Like this!
From the navel.
Hey, what is this?
Subbu, finally woke up!
Come and join us.
Yellamma, why did you stop?
What did Baba say? Daily 10 minutes.
Yellamma, enough of doing yoga.
Go do some cooking.
- This sir is not letting me go
- Hey, let her stay.
Yellamma, holiday for you today.
I will cook food for sir.
Tell me what you will eat.
Baked beans, pan cakes, hash-browns...
- Omelette
- You know how to cook?
Know how...? Do you know from how far people
would come to eat my cooking in Goa?
When did you go to Goa?
After Hampi.
I worked there as tourist guide.
I had sent you postcard.
- Didn't you get it?
- ok..so now what?
Glad you asked.
Let me show you.
Hey.
- Where?
It is a surprise.
Dada!
- This is still alive?
Dada is forever man.
Isn't it, Dada?
Come, let's go for a ride.
No thank you.
I still remember last time's fracture.
Dude, I went for the
first ride with you on it.
I want to go for the
last ride also with you.
What last ride?! I'm not coming.
Hey! Stop!
Do you know where all Dada's taken me?
He took me to places where
professional bikers wouldn't go.
I will miss him.
Why miss?
- I am selling him
- Selling it?
Who will buy it?
I need money for Doodh Kashi.
So I am selling it.
- What is Doodh Kashi?
What is Doodh Kashi?
Hey, Babaji, childhood, graveyard...
did you forget it?
Didn't you forget it?
So what? Will you go there now?
I am going. You too are coming.
It is very cold there. Let us pack
sweaters, monkey caps and go, Subbu.
Stop it man..Won't you settle down in life anyiime?
Will you roam around like this forever?
Hey, say anything you want...l heard about
Doodh Kashi for the first time with you.
I planned to go with you,
this is final. It is a magical place.
How can you believe some rubbish
told by someone in graveyard?
Subbu, Baba said that one
should be destined to go there, right?
Do you know what my grandfather said?
*old folk tale*
- If that is true and this is also true.
- But this is truly true.
Doodh Kashi is calling us.
When I was roaming aimlessly,
I met a man who climbed Everest.
He had a guide named Pemba.
He told him a story.
It's the same story of Doodh Kashi..How can that
story and the story we heard in childhood match?
I have his contact. I called him
up and have set everyihing. It means...
...it is calling you and me.
- When did it call me?
Why do you involve me?
If it called you then you go.
- Yes, Riya?
Why did you cut the phone?
- I was just half asleep--
- Come fast, Subbu.
- Hello?
Already on the way... heavy traffic.
Nobody is following the signal..
I will reach in five minutes. Bye.
Sister-in-law? Date? Where?
- Casa Paradise
- What is it? Hotel?
House. We are buying.
It is a gated community.
We cannot go there without invitation.
Nobody will invite me.
I too want to see the propefly which we
cannot see unless he invites me. Can I come?
' Yes!
' Hey! Sit!
- Rishi, so what do you do?
- Anything.
Anything means? Don't you have job?
Of course I do.
A full time job.
Every day, 365 days,
I don't get even a single holiday.
- Oh! What is it?
- Life.
What is a more
impoflant job than that? Tell me.
You tell everyone these stories
and escape very well from life.
I am making sure that life
doesn't escape from me.
What will you say if someone asks,
when did you enjoy yourself last?
You'll say, "I enjoyed myself
at Ramesh's marriage..."
or, "..we had a good time when we
went to noflh India with my family."
I don't want a life where I can
count my happy moments on my fingers.
I want to live life. Fully,
every second.
- What about money?
What about money??
There are 100 ways to earn enough to live.
Hello. Welcome Casa Paradise.
I am Naina, your hostess.
- Hello, Naina
- Today I will be showing the property...
...and before entering
into the property...
...please wear your shoe covers.
- Sure.
Can we enter by removing our shoes?
Waste of plastic, right?
Sorry. No barefoot. Management rule.
You should have said it before.
We would have come with our own covers.
I'm right na?
- Come
- Please.
This villa has a private swimming pool
with automatic temperature control.
And it also has a special
water cleaning system...
Very sad.
What happened to it?
This is an imported
ikebana tree from Japan.
Japan? It doesn't look imported,
it looks ill.
Please come in.
Shame on this society, for not letting
a tree also live like a tree.
Also we have a 24 hours
concierge service...
...and the entire marble floor
is directly imported from Italy.
All these wall furnishing
designs are from England.
This furniture is from Paris.
State of the art security is from Germany.
What does state ofthe an mean?
- This?
Hey, come.
These designer chandeliers too
are ordered specially from Belgium.
So except the people, there is nothing
related to India in this house, right?
Yes, sir.
You'll feel like you're living abroad.
- Very good
- And toilets, fittings...
meveryihing is from Italy.
- And designer toilet papers too are from...
- Hey, this is bit too much.
Designer toilet papers?
Are they going to save them after using?
Sir, you may not be
aware of these comforts...
...but nowadays people
are expecting all this.
My phone. Excuse me.
Hello? How is the pickle
that I sent you recently?
Are you eating it or not?
Our neighbours saw your picture and
think you've lost lots of weight...
- Please! Give the phone. Please, sir
- They are all.
- Tell him, sir. Please
- What?
- My phone!
- Hello?
Mother, I will talk later. Bye.
Yes, sister?
This is our real background, right?
What is this Naina?
It doesn't seem to match.
Naivedyala Nagamani. Naina in shod.
Nagamani? What a nice name!
Why do we need Naina and all?
Shall we continue?
- What about this slum over there?
- That's not a big problem, madam.
That slum, huts and people
will be cleared after sometime.
We talked to the commissioner already.
- So where will they go?
- Who knows?
- They are used to this
- Yes.
The Poor man's end is
a rich man's beginning.
- Sir
- Do you like the propefly, madam?
- Sure. I like it.
- What?!
No, sir.
But sir, I--
But--
lam coming, sir.
- What happened?
- He is not taking the call, sir.
- I confirmed with him two days back--
- Subbu!
This project was your responsibility.
I trusted you even though
everyone warned me.
I gave you a free hand
and let you spend as much money as you wanted.
I even gave you my daughter's hand
thinking you are the future.
Forget about the money.
My company's reputation.
My name... you spoiled everything.
Sir, I already took his bank
account details..it was planned...
- In the meantime--
- Subbu!
You underestimated Ramaiah.
He bought those shares before you.
No problem... no problem...
everyone makes mistakes.
I will start afresh thinking
I made mistake in your matter.
Sir, I will talk to Ramaiah.
I can fix this.
And...“ you doth...
...not just your career...
meveryihing will be finished.
Sir--
Riya... Riya! Riya!
Sir, an emergency.
My aunt is unwell.
Kiriti!
Excuse me.
I want to meet Ramaiah.
Not Ramaiah.
Ask for Ramaiah Sir.
Oh, okay. I want to meet Ramaiah Sir.
Come.
- Sir, someone came to meet you
- Hello, sir.
My name is Subramaniyam.
You must have heard of me.
I didn't think you will be so simple.
In fact had we met and talked before...
...we would have saved a lot of time.
So here's my plan.
A plan that you cannot refuse.
All Plans are those of God.
Not ours.
Sir, your company has not
made profits since four years.
You NEED this more than I do.
My grandfather used to say...
...nature gives what we need...
...not what we THINK we need.
So you can understand better,
Let me tell you in English.
Nature gives us enough for our need,
not for our greed.
We are always dissatisfied.
If we have one car,
we want another one.
If we have one cell phone,
We wish to earn more
money than what we have.
Well said, sir.
Needs increase as we progress.
That's why we invented a bullock can
so we could go faster than walk.
It was not enough,
so we invented cars.
After we invented planes and so on...
But remember, Whatever you board,
we should land on our earih.
We need to walk on our own feet.
Sir, well said.
Yours is a seeds company.
Sir, what if a seed says I'm not greedy
and I don't want to grow.
They are not growing for themselves.
They are growing for us.
Grow for others...
...and not yourself.
Sir, I cannot make you understand.
That's because You don't understand yet.
Sir, we have dispatched
the entire seeds.
Okay, sir.
lam coming to the point directly.
I will give whatever price you want.
You can continue
as long as you want as MD.
I will convince them saying that the name
of your company also remains Ramaiah.
It will change only on papers.
- Greetings, sir
- Greetings, sir.
- Greetings.
Sir, anyway, is it necessary for you to take tension
of business and employees at this age?
Your Children are already settled. You will get
lot of money if you sell the company.
You can wake up every morning
and read your newspaper peacefully...
...and play with grandchildren
in the evening...
...and sit on verandah at night and
talk to friends and spend life happily.
Will you do this job
ifl give you all the money you want?
Sir, why will I do a job
if I have all the money I want?
LWill!
Even if I have all the money in the world,
I will still do this work.
I am not working for
the money I am getting.
I make Money for the work
I am doing.
Sir, it is not that...
Now let me come to the point. Listen!
Thousands of people trust me
and work for me.
Millions of people are farming peacefully
because of the work I do.
Whatever you may say,
This company is not for sale.
Subbu! Subbu! Subbu! Good news!
- You will be shocked if you hear it.
- What is it?
Tomorrow...we are leaving to Doodh Kashi.
Okay, if not tomorrow
then day after tomorrow.
I am going mad. Cannot you think of
anything else other than Doodh Kashi?
My Entire life is falling apart
All these years work,
my planning, everything ruined.
Riya also is not taking my calls.
This close... I came this close to
becoming a partner in the company.
Everything is--
Did you lose the job?
Means from tomorrow you are free,
then we can go to Doodh Kashi.
Okay, cheer up.
You are Subbu! You won't lose.
Don't give up. I will help you. Come.
- This is--
- All this is waste.
- They are 50, 100... petty shares.
- Are they waste?
Rangarao, 35 shares... waste.
Sunita, age 53... really waste.
Krishnamuflhy,
100 class A shares, waste.
Sorry, A class waste.
What did you say now?
- I said we will go to Doodh Kashi.
- Not that-- Just now.
Krishnamuflhy, 100 class A shares.
Class A shares mean
one multiplied by thousand.
Total one lakh shares. Give it!
Oh! I will give if you say you
will come to Doodh Kashi.
Hey, if they are really Class A
shares then I will come anywhere.
- Rishi...
- Subbu??
I've only thought of you as a friend...
- Subbu!
- Ouch!
Krishnamuflhy... here's the address.
Let us go, come.
If we go now,
They will think we are thieves
Shall we go tomorrow morning?
I will give you a party.
- Let us go to Taj
- Not Taj, I will take you somewhere. Come.
Doodh Kashi... at least closer to it.
This is very strong. Great kick!
- This is only a quarter..
- the booze?
Both the booze and our life.
- Talk some interesting topic
- Interesting?
- Tell me about Riya
- Riya? ok.
Riya was born in Banjara Hills,
studied fashion in America...
...walked the ramp in Paris...
...the only heiress to
Pashupathi Industries... she is perfect.
That's it. Perfect.
I asked for a love story man,
not bio-data.
- Is there love? Love?
Love?
Love means Riya... Riya means life.
- Life is a ladder...how you climb this ladder of life, is life!
- Hey, stop it.
How can there be no love!?
- You will get married, right?
Yes.
And then your first night.
Do you think your first night is
a board meeting...
...so that it will start
if you say, let us start?
How can I tell you...0k
think this is you.
This is Riya...
if you both meet... where--
Hey! She is drinking you man!
- Who?
- Who she?
- She! She!
I have only one bottle...
...how can she drink.
- Thief!
She took it.
My bottle! ls this fair? Tell me.
Happy binhday to me!!
First time... I am drinking
alcohol for the first time.
I never drank even
a soda till now.
Iam not drinking
because it is birthday.
I'm drinking because
Nobody knows it is birthday!
I don't have friends
who pester me for a party.
I don't have a family
to scold me ifl go home late.
My life is like this only...
I going to stay alone...forever.
Hey! What are you doing?
- Just checking what's behind that hair
- Just because you find girl alone...
...you acting smafl?
Hello, I am already engaged.
Her name is Riya.
Riya is my future. Riya is my life.
- Life is a ladder..and how you climb that ladder--
- Hey, hey stop man...
Hi!
- I am Rishi
- I am Subbu.
- So what?
So friends?
We should know each other to
become friends, right?
We should become
friends to know each other, right?
These are just empty words.
I know.
You will leave me after two days.
Never... once I give you my
hand then life time guarantee.
Hey, now only two of us are here.
You too join. We will become three.
The Three musketeers.
And we will be together always,
we will be happy all the time.
Friends forever!
- Promise?
- My name is Nandi
- Nandi.
Nandi, Subbu and
I have to go to Doodh Kashi.
What are you whispering in her ears?
They say what we tell in Nandi's ears,
will come true.
- Tell my matter too.
- Done! Done!
- What is Doodh Kashi?
- Doodh Kashi!
A magical place near the
tallest mountain in the Himalayas.
Since childhood it's been
my dream to go there.
If only I could do one thing
in life, then I wish to go there.
Hey, if we go there then
you will know who you are...
...and I will know who I am.
You go find out if you want.
I know who I am, very well.
So tell me who you are.
- Subramaniyam
- Not your name. Who are you?
I am General Manager of
Pashupathi group of industries.
Not your job, who are you?
Who am I? Subramaniyam IIM,
Ahmedabad--
Not your qualification.
- Who are you?
- Who?
Who is Subramaniyam?
Train! Train! Train! Come join!
- Hey, where are you going?
- Doodh Kashi.
- What is Doodh Kashi?
- You too don't know?
If you want to know who you are,
then come to Doodh Kashi wish us.
Who are you?
Tell him, who I am man.
Im also asking him
that since a long time, sir.
- Who is Subramaniyam?
- You shut up.
Hey, tell me who you are.
- Look, Sai Kumar!
- I am not Sai Kumar.
Sai Kumar or Rajashekar...
...when we both were drinking,
this girl came and took my bottle...
Girl? What girl?
Over there.
- Where?
- She went that way.
- Come!
Hey! Hey!
Subbu, Let's leave
for Doodh Kashi tomorrow?
First let me look into this matter.
Hey, I called up Pemba.
He settled everything.
- My packing is done.
- House is--
- What about your packing?
- How can it be locked?
Maybe they also went on a trip.
Hello, this house--
Yes, this is a house.
- Mr. Krishnamuflhy.
- Yes, this is Mr. Krishnamuflhy's house.
He is not home?
- No, He is not home
- We can see that.
- What happened to him?
- He passed away.
Passed away? How can that happenl?
Somehow it happened.
- Hey! those are clothes?
- Yes, They are clothes.
So someone is staying in the house?
Naturally, it's a house.
Someone will stay in it.
I mean who?
Not polite to bother others.
Hold him once.
Come... come.
- Will you come to Doodh Kashi?
- I will, first hold him.
Hold me... hold me.
Hey, what is your problem?
Wait.
Krishnamuflhy's daughter lives
in the house. Her name is Anandi.
Where is she now?
She will be on terrace at this time.
- You go.
- Rishi, come.
Something is happening to the girl.
My shares!
- There is nobody here.
- Look here.
I must find Krishnamuflhy's
daughter in this lot.
She alone seems to be his daughter...
...rest look like Krishnamuflhy's
classmates.
The move that I am going
to show you now is Tiger Claw. Okay?
This is the best self
defense in Karate. Do it.
Now leg up, yes... kick.
Kick... kick.
Au nty!
Nothing happened... nothing to worry.
Just ten minutes rest.
See! why do they need to do all this
instead of quietly staying in the house?
You too join, uncle.
Self defense is necessary
for everyone these days.
What is the need for us?
We are men.
- Oh! really?
- Yes.
Rama aunty, come here. Come.
- Uncle, you too come.
- Why?
Come I say.
If you have guts, then touch your wife.
Everyone is there, might not be appropriate.
Just Touch her and see,
you will know her power.
I am living with her since 30 years.
I think I know her power.
Uncle, just touch, ok!
Aunty, take your attack position.
Aunty, what is this?
After all, he is my husband.
This is Anandi?
Hey! Nandi!
Violent girl!
Hey, how come you are here?
I said ill be your friend,
so I will not leave you now.
Well, yesterday you said your
name is Nandi, now I find out its Anandi.
What is this?
As soon as I say Anandi, every idiot
remembers that girl from the tv serial.
That's why I said Nandi.
Actually I am--
This is Chandramukhi.
This is Arundhati... the big one.
This is 'Sitaramaiah gari Manavaralu.'
She is looking at you.
Hey, Subbu. Now, THIS is a house.
Ok, but where do I sit?
Let me show you.
Hey... hey. Wait! Wait!
- Here.
- Trunk sofa?
Superb!
- Your father is Krishnamuflhy, right?
Yes.
- I heard he passed away--
- Ya, Both mom and dad passed away.
A Lorry hit them while they were
returning from the market...on the spot.
I've been alone since then.
Hey, Do you drink tea or coffee?
- Coffee for me.
- Tea for me.
Hey, tea for me too.
I don't like coffee at all.
Okay, tea for me too.
Hey, good... nice.
Why is she just sitting there?
Should we get it ourselves?
Tea for both of us.
Actually there is nothing in the house.
I asked for the sake of formality.
Hey, will you eat paani-puri?
The Old man downstairs makes it very good...
come... come.
Hey, what happened?
- Maybe She asked this also for formality.
Hey, come.?
Regarding my business, I want to--
Small Problem--
- Hi, Sreeja!
- Hi!
- I searched everywhere for you.
- What?
You are not coming for
playing shuttle these days.
My marriage is on 23rd.
You should definitely come.
Marriage? you??
What happened?
Everyone is getting married.
I am going to be left alone.
Oh! But what's the hurry for your marriage?
What's the hurry for your marriage thenl?
Mother, I am coming!
Why are you sitting?
Don't you want paani-puri?
Hold it.
For you--
I don't want paani, puri is enough.
Who is he?
Hey, how will you eat paani-puri
without paani? Come... come.
He is like that only. He acts smart
It will take lot of time
to tell you all his antics.
I will tell later.
Hey, how is it?
Superb!
It is nice, but best paani-puri
is only in Kolkata.
Wow! Kolkata?
I haven't gone anywhere except
to Tirupati...for Girija's marriage.
Do you know I haven't
even gone out of the state?
Should I tell you something?
Your life...live however you want.
True...
Sometimes I fear how shod our life is,
when I imagine how big the world is.
Hey, you're like me!
Hey an idea! Come to Kolkata with me.
I will make you eat best paani-puri.
- Deal?
- Deal!
When?
We should go to Kolkata on
our way to Doodh Kashi.
My parents too live there,
you can meet my mom.
Actually my friend Pemba--
Hey, actually I came
to talk about some business.
Oh! Not to meet me?
I came for your dad. He worked in
Mr. Ramaiah's company, right?
Yes.
He has some shares in his name--
- Oh'. Shares').
- Hey'.!
What happened?
Oh! Now those shares are in my name.
I had received call from Ramaiah
Company asking for them.
How lucky!
I forgot completely.
Had you not reminded then,
I would have totally forgot.
- N0!!
- What?
I want those shares. I will buy them.
But, He asked first.
I will give you more money.
- Will you give any amount?
- Yes, How much ever.
Chi! I don't do things for money.
I do things only if I feel like it.
And now I surely don't like how you're
trying to bribe me like old-time movie villain.
- Bye.
She is right for you.
Ms. Anandi! Ms. Anandi!
Actually I am sorry,
I didn't mean it like that.
These shares are very important for me.
I am depending on you. Please Think about it.
Okay, I will think tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
Today is Friday.
Lord Shani's influence is more.
We shouldn't stafl any new work.
I have to go. Rama aunty
said she will put henna for me.
Hey, will you too put henna?
My shares--
Okay, we will meet tomorrow.
Why did we come here?
- My shares--
- They are coming out today!
What's coming out?
Welcome to butterfly park.
Butterflies!
Uncle! Uncle! Uncle! Have they come?
Sorry, dear. They came out
in the morning before I arrived.
Aww!! I missed them again.
I'm trying since so long
to see a butterfly when it comes out.
Bad luck!
What about them?
Where?
There is still time for them.
It is very rare to
see butterflies coming out.
I myself have never seen it in
these 50 years.
These caterpillars just eat and eat.
Non-stop.
They eat thousands of times more than
their body's weight.
But the same Insects that spoiled
the trees by eating them...
...will turn into butterflies
and then save the tree again by pollination.
Man is destroying this
earth by eating everything like an insect.
He has forgotten that there is a
butterfly hidden inside him.
A man can learn
everything in this world...
...from a butterfly.
- Free like a butterfly.
Everyone is crack!
Hi!
So what did you think?
Hey, don't kill the fly.
It will be reborn and seek revenge again.
Fly?
It is not that... my shares?
Oh, that?
I cannot take such decisions easily.
Not about the money...
...but I should get a
feeling that it is correct.
I mean approximately
when you will get this feeling.
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
Yes, let's meet tomorrow.
She is bringing to a new place daily.
Whose house is this?
My friend's house.
Will your legs melt if you
stand patiently for two minutes?
Granny!
She is my grandmother Susheela.
She is getting more Glamourous with age.
Enough! Don't stand like a statue here.
- Go inside.
- Okay.
Hmm.
Should I invite both of you specially?
First keep your legs down.
What is this beard? fashion?
No, granny.
I had grown it casually.
Your face!
See his face, your friend.
Why can't you be like that? Neat.
What do you do? Government job?
Or this job of sitting in front of computer
and pressing buttons.
No! No! I am a investment banker.
I came to talk about shares with Anandi...
...and she got me here.
- What are these clothes?
There are so many tears.
Do you think anyone will give
you job by looking at you?
What if nobody gives me a job, granny?
I'll come and stay with you
without any salary.
I can take care of my work thank you,
but you go and shave your beard first.
Well said, granny.
You shut up! Keep quiet!
What is this? The Medicines are
just like that.
Doctor told you to
take them on time, right?
You are suffering from Blood Pressure.
I am telling for the last time.
Take them.
- Your nagging has become intolerable.
- Granny!
- Gems?
- Do you want them?
First tablet.
Give it.
Only two? Give more.
I am going to a place
called Doodh Kashi with them.
Who is she? Your maternal
grandmother or paternal grandmother?
Neither, im not related. ljust like to spend
time with her at least once a week.
I do the entire household work.
Oh! Like a helper in an old age home.
God didn't give me grandmother.
That's why I found my own.
Do you just do anyihing, so randomly?
Not anything,
I do whatever I feel like doing.
I will make this mad
girl sign today at any cost.
You keep nagging her of shares
daily and one day...
...she will go climb a tree.
- Madam! Madam!
- She already has.
Do you think there is nobody to ask?
Give it, madam.
I have to cut the tree.
Otherwise I will lose myjob.
How can you cut a tree?
- It wrong, right?
- Madam...
...everyone cuts the trees
in rainy season? What's wrong?
What if somebody broke your house wall,
is that ok?
Not today,
I think her mood is not good.
No, it should happen today only.
She has an axe in her hand.
Let us come tomorrow.
Come.
Nandi! Nandi! Nandi!
Where have you been?
- Everything is finished.
- Hey, what happened?
She left without telling me.
- She left without telling anything.
- Who?
Chandramukhi.
Chandramukhi, I didn't think
that you too will leave me and go.
Such a talented fish!
I miss her.
Chandramukhi.
I don't know her well, but...
...when I saw her,
I immediately knew she was a good swimmer.
It is a very good fish.
Hey.
Hmm.
Chandramukhi.
It is a gold fish. It is also called...
...which is a fresh water
fish from the family of...
It is one ofthe earliest
to be domesticated...
...and one of the most commonly
kept aquarium fish.
It relatively belongs to
the small member ofthe carp family--
Hey.
- Google aa?
- Wikipedia.
- Enough now.
- Okay.
Riya called after so many days.
Everything is set!
Sure?
- What?
- About Riya?
Of course sure, 100 percent sure.
I already talked to Anandi
and anyiime now ill have those shares.
Okay... okay... Lock?
Mr. Computer, lock A, Riya.
It looks like some accident took place.
Auto turned upside down.
Hey, stop! Stop!
Hey, there are people,
they will take care of it.
Rishi!
Hey!
Did you call for an ambulance?
Does anybody know about the ambulance!!
- Who called?
- Don't know.
Why is everyone nodding their heads?
Subbu, we need to take her to the hospital.
Hey, if we call an ambulance,
they will look into it.
If everyone thinks like that,
nothing will happen!!
Looks like her head is injured.
Lot of blood!
- Door! Door! Door!
- One minute!
What are you doing?!
Let's go.
Subbu! Start! Start!
- Come on'. How hug'?
- Okay').!
- Subbu, fast!
- I am going fast!
Overtake them!
- Subbu, fast!
- Hey, move! Move aside!
Madam, hold her tight
so that blood is not lost.
Subbu, lot of bleeding.
Move aside! Move aside!
- Drive!
- I am driving!
Drive faster! Faster! !
Baby! Baby! Get up, baby!
The Hospital should be somewhere here.
- Doctor!
- Yes!
Doctor! Emergency!
Yes, come!
Hello? Riya.
Nothing... I am coming.
What is this..We are just sitting
here since morning,
and they made this girl sit on this branch.
Poor girl, so skinny.
They haven't given her any food also.
Shit!
Hey.
You are looking amazing, Riya.
Do you why I chose you, Subbu?
Because you were the best.
I thought id be on the Vogue magazine's cover
and you on the Forbes magazine cover.
We would make the dream couple.
Everyone will talk about us.
Everyone would want to be like us.
Hey, relax, Riya. I am working on it.
The Shares matter is almost solved.
It is actually very simple, Subbu.
I am going back to America in two weeks.
If the Ramaiah's deal is
cracked before that, then Great.
Madam, your shot is ready.
Otherwise--
Rishi!
Hey, Rishi!
What? Inside--
It was too late.
What happened?
That girl...
...died.
Such a young girl.
10 years old...
what did she see of life?
In my hands.
Hey.
What can we do?
We did whatever we could, it is okay.
No! It is not okay!
How the fuck is it ok!
Do you know what the doctor said?
Had you brought 10 minutes
before then she would have lived.
There were so many people around!
Girl was bleeding on the road...
...and they were all watching like sheep.
No..not sheep...
Even Sheep would react.
Like zombies...
they stood like zombies!
You thought they will take care.. they think
others will take care... 10 minutes.
- Hey, don't over react.
- I should react!
We are alive!
We all should react!
All of us have killed her together.
Not like this... no.
- Come... this is not right.
- Rishi!
Listen to me, stay here.
I will find a good job for you.
Settle down here.
- Forget Doodh Kashi and crap.
- This is not life!
This is not life!
These people... this selfishness.
I don't know how I should tell you.
This is not life!
Life is not about earning money.
There is so much more to life!!
- Come with me. Come.
- Hey!
Hundreds of people die daily.
Life will not move forward if we sit and cry.
Is it moving forward now?
Is this forvvard?...
...without having any responsibility.
How can you talk about responsibility?
- Did you do even one job properly?
- That is my life. My wish!
At least I am living.
Not like you, for promotion, status.
I'm not marrying my boss's
daughter and selling my life.
That is not promotion.
- Its Prostitution!
- Hey!
Don't dare say One more word!
who are you?
Who are you to talk about my life?
I am tolerating you because
you are my childhood friend.
Leaving your parents responsibility,
you are roaming places by begging.
Don't go there.
I will go anywhere.
This is my house, my wish.
I am not staying in other's
house like a beggar.
By the way, who are you to tell me?
Iam telling you again...
...ambition, status, money!
This is the world!
If this is the world.
If this is world...
...l don't want to have anything
to do with this world.
Fine!! Go away!
Hello! Rishi! Rishi!
Rishi! What are you doing here?
I was searching the
entire school for you.
Subbu, see there.
This nest would have fallen
down due to rain, but now its safe.
Okay, but I heard
you didn't submit your science project.
Today is the late date for submission.
Where is your project?
What? You tore your project
to suppofl the nest??
Its 20 marks man!
Hey, Don't panic?
I will write it again.
I don't understand this guy...
Hey, is this yours?
Yes.
See yours...
how expensive and awesome it is.
See mine... boring and useless.
Did you like it? Take it.
What?!
Hey, it will cost at least 200 rupees.
Mine is just 20 rupees.
Not at all a good deal!
There are no deals in friendship man!
Sure? Because if you
give once then no returns.
Of course I'm sure! You are my best friendl!
Is the hangover over?
Shut up and come home now.
Hello. I am Inspector Ramakant speaking.
An accident occurred at Shadnagar.
Spot dead! Body was lying
there whole night, nobody bothered.
This is the last dialled
number from the phone.
Hello? Hello!
Body is in JJ Hospital.
Call back if you want any details.
Hello?
You won't find him in any photo.
Only his Bag or his bike.
That's it.
Since four years...
...l am seeing his life
through these moments.
Four years?
You know how stubborn he
is since childhood.
He does whatever he likes.
He has a big fight with his father.
Father got angry...
...and said not to show
his face again. That's it.
I didn't think he will leave me forever
without showing me his face.
I want to see him once more.
Just once more, I want to hear his laugh.
My son.
He had such a big head.
If anybody was in trouble...
...he reached out first.
My Rishi is a beautiful soul!
I was always afraid.
Where is he? What is he doing?
At least he had you.
The Last call...
...he made the last call, to you.
Don't cry, madam.
Control yourself.
Come.
Hello? Yes, Riya.
All the ceremonies are over.
I am coming tomorrow.
Aunty, so sorry!
This shouldn't have happened to Rishi.
I was shocked to hear the news.
Riya, I will call you later.
Subbu! What is this?
I can't believe this.
How did you come here?
- What is this?
- Rishi left this with me.
$0'?
Subbu, why did I meet Rishi?
Why did he tell me about Doodh Kashi?
He left the most important
thing of his life with me...
"what does this mean?
It is destiny. He is telling
us to finish his journey.
Don't talk rubbish.
There is nothing.
No destiny, no journey,
no Doodh Kashi, no Rishi-
Rishi is not there.
Hi, uncle. I am so sorry.
It is okay. Who are you?
My name is Nandi.
Rishi's best friend.
Actually we three are best friends.
Come, Subbu.
Subbu, your friend?
Uncle, you are not like Rishi at all.
Maybe he has taken after aunty.
Uncle, I have to ask you something.
Do you know about Doodh Kashi?
Uncle, I mean Rishi
must have told you.
This secret Lake in the Himalayas...
Rishi found the way.
Now Subbu and I are going with him.
What are you talking about?
Uncle, we want Rishi's ashes.
We will take it to Doodh Kashi.
- Get out!
- Uncle, listen to...
Get out!!!
He spent his entire
life in that madness.
It has killed him.
Now you don't start it again.
Uncle, please... please...
listen to me.
Not another word!
Get out before I call the security!
- Sorry, uncle.
- Out!
Uncle, it is not that.
- Why does he shout like that?
- Have you gone mad?
How can you ask for ashes
like as if you're asking for some address?
Do you know why I made you
run around without giving you the shares?
Nobody stays with me.
Everyone leaves me and goes.
But that day in the bar, you found
me as if you came searching for me.
You said we were friends,
you took me into your group.
I felt so happy.
I thought you too will leave me
if I give the shares.
Rishi anyway has left.
I will give those shares, I don't care.
But we have to take Rishi's
ashes to Doodh Kashi.
He had a hundred ideas,
we can't just blindly leave everyihing-
It is a sign, Subbu.
Rishi would have wanted us to do this.
Only you can help me! Please!
- What is this boost bottle?
- It must be under the table.
What is all this?
Hey, it should be here.
It's not here, let's go.
It has to be there. See properly.
I knew you would come.
He always treated you more
like a brother than a friend.
That fact that You are doing this for him,
...he is blessed to have friends like you.
Surely he too would have wanted this...
Au nt--
What is that?
Boost... ashes...
Anandi... Doodh Kashi.
That's right.
It was His favourite.
Here...
Take Rishi to Doodh Kashi.
Till Ganga.
- It looks like airport.
- Airport?
If we give these planes to
a scrap dealer...
...he will ask us for money in return.
Pemba!
Pemba! Pemba! Pemba!
Finished? Satisfied? Shall we leave?
All of Rishi's plans are like this only.
Rishi?
- Anandi!
- Subbu!
Subbu?
- Pemba!
- Yes!
- Pemba! Pemba! Pemba!
Thank God, we found you.
Thank God, but who are you.
My friend Rishi wrote
your name in Doodh Kashi's map.
- Oh, Rishi? Hello.
- Wait... wait?
Not that, listen fully.
- This is Rishi.
- Rishi?
This is boost.
His Ashes... he died.
Oh God!
I am so sorry.
Subbu? Anandi?
Good. Come.
Now we have to take
him to Doodh Kashi.
Why do you keep saying we?
My car is waiting outside.
I will tell you.
- Thank you.
- This is my friend's plane...
...and I am the only pilot.
Pilot? He looks like
a bullock-cad driver.
But you have to pay money.
- What else do you want? Tell me.
- Nothing.
- Only money.
- Subbu, say okay.
Why don't understand my troubles.
Ifl don't acquire Ramaiah's
company in the city...
...my marriage, career...
everything will be finished.
- Subbu!
- Hey! Hey!
You go around carrying those papers,
right? Do you have them now?
Yes..of course...
you can sign then even now too.
Actually I said I will give
20 percent premium too...
...you didn't care all these days.
- Subbu.
- One minute.
Rishi travelled to so many places.
He could have visited
Doodh Kashi also...
...but he wanted
to go with you, Subbu.
Do you know how many times he told me?
Subbu, this trip will have
a meaning only if you come.
Rishi's soul will be happy.
If you last wish was to
visit some stock exchange...
...then Rishi would have
definitely fulfilled it.
Subbu, I don't want money. You come.
I... I will give those
shares to you for free.
- Deal?
- Yes.
- How much you want?
- Only 100 dollars per day.
What happened?
' MY Purse--
' N0 money?
- What?
- Subbu, show me.
Nice watch.
You can buy a Business class ticket to London
if I sell this watch.
Then go to London.
Hey...ok..wait.
Here.
Good! Very good!
I love your decision. Come on.
Push!
What push?
Does he think its a share-auto?
It has starting problem,
so you have to push.
Push! More push! Anandi, push!
Easy for you...
You are sitting like a pig inside...
...and telling us to push.
- Subbu, push.
- Yes! Started!
- Come on!
- Come! Come! Sit! Sit!
- Come fast!
Come inside!
Give it! Get in! Get it!
Hey, slowly.
Are you okay?
I would have died!
So exciting!
Please fasten your seat belts.
Hey! There are no seat belts.
Yes. Only said for formality.
Why did I come here?
How did I get into this?
This is crazy. I'm going to die.
I have to get down.
- Stop.
- Fly high!
Like a diamond in the sky!
Doodh Kashi is very holy lake.
In olden days,
it would take many years to reach...
...but you are very
lucky to have my plane.
Lucky ??
This is the first time
lam sitting in plane.
This is probably my last time.
Get ready for landing.
Landing? I can't see the airport.
Airport? Haha!
This is not a landing,
it is called crashing.
Finished!
It's all over!
Welcome to Himalayas!
Now get out!
Take care... take care... both of you.
Come on!
I think he worked in a circus before.
Anandi.
Stand there... hold the bottle up.
Nice pose... Very good. Fantastic!
Okay, nice.
Doodh Kashi is very nice. Let us go.
What?
I mean Doodh Kashi is very nice.
It is bit cold but...
...it is okay. Let us go.
This is not Doodh Kashi.
Doodh Kashi is further away.
You should have taken us there,
why did you drop us here?
No plane there, only walk.
How far from here.
5 days, 10 days, maybe more than 15 days.
Give my watch back.
Okay. Relax.
I will take you up to there...
...but you have to
pay me 100 dollars per day.
No need.
I have my GPS with me.
I will go myself.
- Hey, Nice mobile.
- Stay back! I will not give this.
- Do you have the map with you?
- Yes...
It is better to trust Google than him.
Come, I will take you.
- But what do we know, Subbu.
- Hello! Wait!
- Come.
- Not that way!
- This way.
- We know.
Welcome to Google maps.
Keep going straight.
After 200 metres.
Why did it stop?
Hello?
- Take a right.
- It is there.
Go straight.
Keep going on.
Further?
- And then?
- Take a right.
Take a right.
Keep climbing till
you reach flat ground.
How far, Subbu?
- Pemba can help us.
- No need.
Now keep going straight
for 100 metres.
Where do you want us to go? See.
You want to kill me? Tell me?!
Now go straight.
Oh. Subbu...
lam feeling hungry.
Is there anything in your bag?
Ooh...You're feeling hungry?
Eat me! Eat me!
- All this is because of you.
- Done blame me!
Pemba said he will take us.
You only said Google maps, this-that
and brought us here.
No! No!
No!
- What happened?
- Battery dead!
Subbu, are you afraid of ghosts?
I heard they like living on mountains.
Mountain spirits!
Is that topic necessary now?
Don't worry, Subbu.
All ghosts are not the same.
- Some are good too.
- Who told you?
- Granny told me.
- ls it?
Look, I think that's one.
Good one or bad one?
Come! Come!
Head down! Head down!
Too much cold outside.
Thank you.
Good night.
- Bye.
- Okay.
Yellamma! Coffee!
"The beautiful sky."
"Which poet's imagination is this..."
"Which poet's imagination
is this miracle?"
"Who is the painter?"
All is good.
Sleep well?
Sleep well, my foot!
Subbu, see.
Rishi's purse. So what?
This is the money Rishi got
for selling Dada.
Everything is happening
according to Rishi's plan.
Rishi is taking us to Doodh Kashi.
Now we have money for Pemba.
QKZV -
Now Pemba will take
you to Doodh Kashi.
Okay'?
Wow! Looking so pretty.
- Come. Come. Sit here.
- Thank you.
Where is Subbu?
- He is still inside.
- Inside?
- Okay.
- I am ready.
Are you ready?
So funny!
Now Subbu, Anandi.
Here we begin ourjourney to Doodh Kashi.
What a wonderful view!
Look, Anandi.
Hello! Riyal!
Hello, Subbu.
- Yes.
Hello?
Signal is weak.
Subbu, can you hear me now?
Yes, signal is there!
You wait.
I am coming. Can you hear me now?
Yes!
What about the shares?
Two, three days... that's all.
Hello? Hello?
Why did it get cut?
What a funny fellow!
Subbu, Anandi.
Welcome to the mountain luxury hotel.
Okay mountain but where is luxury.
Come inside.
- It is so cute.
- Cute?
- Very beautiful. Come.
- Beautiful?
As long as he doesn't make
us sleep next to a cow again.
This is your room. Get in.
You said room, it looks
like store room. Who are they?
Your room mates.
I might compromise regarding room
but I'm very particular about the toilet.
Show me.
Welcome to the mountain toilet!
How can this be a toilet!
There is no toilet paper also?
Use leaves.
I will never!
- It has been one month since I came.
- Oh.
This is all a new experience for me.
Hey, Subbu! Subbu!
His name is Robert. He says he is
staying in this area since one month.
Greetings.
I felt very sad after hearing
about your friend Rishi.
What you are doing
for him is really great.
Apparently he has no plan at all.
He doesn't even know when he
will go back to his country.
Just taking it one day at a time.
Just Like Rishi, isn't it?
Yes, like Rishi.
He doesn't know what to do in life...
...and also no money to live in city,
so he is roaming in the mountains.
Subbu.
Did I say something wrong?
- I am sorry.
- Yes, you should be sorry!
There should be some responsibility.
Work, ambition.
Who will make the world go round?
What will happen to the
world if everybody is aimless like this?
You are just wasting your life.
It was a pleasure meeting both of you.
And all the best for your journey.
And ifl have hurt your friend,
I am sorry.
Take care.
What is your problem?
Why did you talk
so rudely to Robefl?
Who the hell is Robefl?
Why are we here?
I can't even pronounce
the name ofthe place we are in?
My life was perfect until a week ago.
I was becoming CEO of the company,
got engaged to Riya...
...l had a car,
house and everything.
Now I just have that Pemba,
his horse, the horses dung and the stink of dung.
And every day all we have are these momos!
I'm sick of them!
By trusting Pemba's words...
...we are going to some place which
we don't know if it exists or not.
- Subbu! Subbu! Relax.
- Anybody will think we are mad.
Why think, we are indeed mad.
Breathe.
Breathe out.
Ok, tell me... how was Subbu as a child?
There were no business
problems at that time, right?
I decided in 9th class that
software will not have a future.
I predicted MBA will have value.
So I stayed one step ahead of everyone
and today I am in this position.
So much over action in 9th class only?
So did you do things
which kids ofthat age would do?
Cricket, football.
Talent in sports is
seen in the first ten years.
They was not practical use in playing them
just for fun, so I stopped.
Dear God!
At least girls...
crushes... love stories.
Yes, yes. There are many.
Hey, thank God. Tell me.
But I realised they are feelings
which come out of...
...the chemicals that get
released from hormones.
Hey, so what about the
feelings you have for Riya?
They too come from hormones, right?
No, Riya is my future.
A very Practical choice.
There is a formula call SWOT in MBA.
Strength, weakness, opportunity, threat.
Whatever decision I take,
I check my score using the formula.
Do you know my score with Riya?
- How much?
- 98 percent.
Superb, isn't it?
- Wow... how romantic!
- Thank you.
SWOT this!
She's a mad girl, sir.
See that mountain.
- Is it Doodh Kashi?
- No! No!
Behind that mountain.
- Further away.
- ls Doodh Kashi there?
No! No! No! There is a lake.
Does he know anything?
Cant believe we trusted him!
No! No! You don't know.
Last year...
...from south India, a man...
...l took to Babaji.
- Want to see his photographs?
- Yes.
Raj n I kant?
Show me! Show me!
Didn't I say he is lying?
It is photoshopped.
You think I am stupid?
- Why did you stop?
- You go, I am coming.
QKZV -
- Come.
- There is no signal here.
Tell me the truth.
You are afraid of water, right?
You mind your own business, I will come.
My Phone! My phone fell down!
Subbu! Subbu, chill.
- Why don't you jump and take it?
- What jump? I am afraid of water.
My phone... it is lost.
I-phone... 5S... 64 GB.
Lost! Lost!
Actually it's a good thing, Subbu.
Do you know how much
time we have without a phone?
To do whatl?
See this.
Such a beautiful place around us.
What is thisl?
- Subbu, momos are--
- I don't want.
Leave me like this.
Be like that.
" Hi!
Where is the toilet?
Outside.
Your place is very peaceful, calm.
I like it.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
Yesterday one tiger attacked.
And killed a small yak.
Oh! You said you need to
go to the toilet, right?
I don't need to now.
Do you have a problem?
Hey, what is the name of the tiger?
Tiger ate a small yak!
She said as if it ate momos.
Subbu.
Subbu, come out.
My head stopped beating.
Don't ever do it again.
It's so beautiful outside...
Come!
Tiger is also there outside.
I will not come.
Tiger ate a yak yesterday, right?
So it will not be hungry.
Did it tell you?
It is true, the villagers drove it away.
Come.
They say dead people
become stars in the sky.
- Who said it?
- Granny.
Do you think Rishi too became star?
Hey!
See! See! Over there!
Why does God take away
people like Rishi so soon?
Subbu.
Is this you?
Long back.
So who is this?
Divya.
His first love.
He would enter the
class and sing DDLJ songs.
Bollywood romance. Full drama.
Oh, what happened after that?
What else?
First love, school love...
they don't work out.
They don't mean anything.
He had her photo till the end,
...l am sure it meant something.
- Hey.
You said it is not hungry.
Hey, what should I send
to granny.
Whatever.
Don't you have anybody to send to?
Give one costly card.
All are the same price.
Actually granny would like this.
Hi, Riya.
Can't wait to be back.
Riya my future.
- Where did you come from?
- Hyderabad. Telugu! Telugu!
Oh, power star! Pawan Kalyan!!
Yes... yes.
- Trekking on road.
- Yes, trekking.
You can take helicopter, right? Fly.
Helicopter?
Hey!
Nandi! Nandi!
You too come, I will take a photo.
Good news! Good news!
Is it? Which month?
Ugh! Not that.
There is helicopter to Everest.
No need to carry the bags
and hear his nuisance. Let us go.
No helicopter.
Don't think of money.
- I will manage it.
- Anandi!
Nandi!
- Where are you going?
- Nandi! Nandi!
I am not saying we will go back...
...l am saying we will go directly
instead of climbing these mountains.
Lot of time will be saved.
You don't get it, do you??
Had Rishi been here,
he wouldn't have taken a shod cut.
To reach Tirumala we don't have to climb steps,
we can go by car too.
But we feel satisfied only
if we climb steps for Tirumala.
Okay... okay... your wish.
Give it once.
- Now tell me. Will you come or not?
- Subbu, give it.
- Give it. Please.
- You said we will go...
...we came till here.
- Give it.
- Please don't play.
- Subbu, it is--
How can you set
conditions for everything?
No! Subbu, give it.
Give I say. Please.
- Should I give?
Give it to me.
I will never give. I will give only
if you say we will go by helicopter.
Subbu, please give it.
Don't play!
Subbu, please stop!
Subbu!
I will not stop!
Anandi!
Nandi!
I am dead!
Hey! Gone! 22,000 Rupees!
Gone!
Help!
God, save me!
If you save me, In the temple at home...
...l will give food for 50 people.
100 people?
HaPPV7
I'll find out who I am,
ifl go to Doodh Kashi?
I am coming, wait.
You wait there.
Hey, come on.
Who am I?
The teachings of
Bhagwan Ramana Maharshi.
Hey...
...is this your wife?
Yes.
She is Mary.
My wife.
My business partner. My everything.
Business partner. nice...
So, what do you guys do?
Bluetooth technologies.
Bluetooth technologies...
Oh, I know it. You work there?
No... no... that is my company.
What?!! But that's a Multi-million
dollar company.
Its listed on Wall street too.
I mean what you guys doing here?
I started the company when I was young.
I was hungry. I wanted to be first.
it was a race!
I told Mary at that time that
I will retire at the age of 40...
...and will show
her the entire world...
...and enjoy life.
We reached 40.
There were so many clients and sources
to earn more money at that time.
Of course, we couldn't stop now.
So, we reached 50.
I thought of extending
retirement by another five years.
Actually I too don't
become satisfied easily.
So you and your wife...
...decided to visit the entire
world after retiring.
So you guys are on a trip together.
Mary died last year.
What?
I had time, so many, many years...
...to go anywhere with her.
But I postponed it.
Funny thing is...
...the work for which I
postponed my personal life...
...l don't even remember what it was...
...except Mary.
- He is missing since last evening.
- Don't panic, Anandi.
Hey, your friend.
You know one thing? Real success is
finding someone who cares for you.
Don't panic.
- People are searching. Don't worry.
- Just go.
Why did you get so worried?
I was frightened.
About me?
About Rishi!
Hey, what happened to your glasses?
They are lost.
Are you able to see?
Actually, I don't have sight.
What?
It's just that...l calculated that
8 percent people will take you more seriously
if you have glasses, so I started wearing them.
Oh my God!
Hey!
Here... here?
Lost.
Come.
- Oh... yes.
- This is the way!
- Okay.
- This way?
Hey, fool!
Where to go?
See the map.
Nice map!
- Where to go from here?
There is one tree.
From there, take right.
Where that tree gone.
One tree??
Oh, yes. I got an idea.
Near my village.
There is a Baba, who might know the path.
- Come along with me. Come on.
- Okay.
This is last village
before Doodh Kashi?
My mamma is great.
She is the best cook
in the whole village.
Thank God!
We will eat something special at least
today, bored of eating momo daily.
- Crap!
- Eat, eat, very nice.
Best momo in the whole world.
Who is this sitting inside the tree?
Where do we go from here?
Baba will tell.
Then ask him...
Baba doesn't talk.
So how will a dumb Baba
tell the directions?
Baba.
We have come a very long way.
Our friend Rishi's last wish.
Was to go to Doodh Kashi.
You have to show the way. Please.
Take... take.
What is this?
Holy Baba's offering.
Eat... eat...
it will give all the answer, 1, 2, 3.
This is not just any offering.
I love my mother.
I will never leave her again.
Subbu... okay?
Actually super okay.
For completing the
deal of Ramaiah Company...
...l tried a lot to escape from coming here.
Actually I want to tell you something.
Thank you...
...for bringing me here.
Actually you should
thank Rishi...not me.
Thank you, Rishi.
Subbu...
Subbu, be careful.
Subbu!
You died right?
Dead?
The Old Subbu wouldn't have jumped had I fallen
into a river. Now see, he jumped just for the bottle.
He was very practical in childhood.
What's happened to him now?
He even put a towel on his car seat
so that my blood won't stain it.
- He is very practical.
- Hey, Subbu.
I didn't say bye to you, right?
This girl?... How is my mistake?
- What did we do?
- True.
We didn't do anyihing.
Iam saying, Do something.
I didn't understand.
Hello.
I understood.
Greetings.
How is the hand?
I found you last night by the river.
You are very lucky.
Hey!
This is my garden's cabbage.
What should I do?
Keep it in kitchen.
I will come and make soup.
Help!
Come.
Anybody there?
Help! One girl.
No! No! I don't know.
Help!
One girl.
You go outside.
How is she?
Something--
What happened?
Yes!
True, We didn't do anyihing.
Iam saying, Do something.
Sorry, Rishi.
It was a Mistake.
You were correct.
Subbu! Thank God.
Mamma, here is your medicine.
Drink.
Your fever will go.
Keep this money, you will need it.
- We will go from here.
- No! No!
I do not deserve this money.
I am sorry,
I failed to take you to Doodh Kashi.
You should stay with your mother,
we will somehow manage.
You brought us so far, thank you.
Bad weather there, you can't go.
We will go if we are destined.
It is okay.
You keep this money.
You are good funny fellow.
Shake now!
Funny fellow.
All the best. Come... come, Anandi!
- Pemba.
- Remember those directions...
...which I have shown you.
" Okay?
" Okay,
Mother, bless them.
They are going to very dangerous area.
Let us go back, come.
Subbu, can't you seei?
My fate is like this.
Something bad always happens to the people
close to me. I am bad luck. Jinx.
If something happens to
you then I cannot bear it.
I can't take a chance. Come. Come.
- Let us go back.
- Rishi...
...didn't reach Doodh Kashi yet.
How can we go back now?
The second time I broke my hand
because of Rishi.
Come.
We are very close.
Nandi!
What happened?
Subbu, I am unable to feel my fingers.
Get up.
Come.
Sit.
Hey!
Sorry, Subbu.
All this happened because of me.
Quiet! If not for you...
I wouldn't have come so far for my friend
...my best friend Rishi.
I don't know how to repay your favour.
No... I am a mad girl.
That is also correct.
But actually you don't
know how cool you are.
You are special, Nandi.
Nandi.
Slept?
Really slept.
Nandi!
Hello, Subramaniyam.
See what I found.
When did you wake up?
Long back...
The bedrooms on top, dining room below.
How cute it is!
Oh really? Wait, I will
go and see the weather situation outside.
Hey!
- How is it?
- Still too cold.
I never thought much
of my dream house.
But really, where can I find
a more perfect house than this.
What about food?
Hold for a moment!
A Bag full of potatoes.
See no problem.
What do we really need in life?
Food, clothes and shelter.
- Subbu, we have everything.
- Potato!
Wonder whose house this is?
Wonder how old are these potatoes?
Don't know if we can eat them or not.
Do you know what
granny always says?
Every grain of food has the name ofthe
person who is destined to eat it.
Wonder how many
days these potatoes waited for us.
We shouldn't make them wait anymore.
Now, chef's special.
- What is this?
- Subbu, Rishi, Anandi.
One minute.
Sit here, Rishi.
Eat this, where is mine?
Now potato soup.
I never knew one can cook
so many varieties with potatoes.
- Hey, do you know to make chips?
- Do you want ketchup also?
Eat first.
- What is this?
- Horse.
It looks like a dog.
Happy Diwali.
You made them from potatoes...
superb idea.
Subbu.
Are you sleeping?
Say yes if you're sleeping.
Do you know how happy
I was in these few days?
For the first time I felt
there is someone for me in life.
Subbu, listen.
I love you.
Hey, I love you means not that
like you. I love you means, I love you.
Nandi!
Nandi, what is that bag?
For how many days are
we going to stay here?
It is cleared outside.
Nandi!
Nandi! Nandi!
- What is all this?
- Your shares?
- Why now--
- So when?
I said I will give if you come.
That was the deal.
- Why are you talking about deals now?
- Subbu, I know your life is different.
I also you know are engaged.
Sometimes I just don't think.
I am mad, remember.
- I didn't say it like that.
- Subbu, it is okay.
We came for Rishi.
Come, we still have to go to Doodh Kashi.
I think we are close.
Subbu, these stones are the same way
the Baba in the tree put them!
Subbu! Subbu!
Come here.
Subbu!
Where are you, Subbu?
Anandi.
Come here.
Ouch!
Come... come.
- Subbu!
- Anandi.
What is this?
Rishi... Doodh Kashi.
Doodh Kashi.
He made it.
Finally he achieved it.
- So beautiful.
- Come.
We have reached.
- Congrats, sir.
- Thank you.
Sir, I knew you will do, I knew it.
You did it, sir.
You need to earn the right
to sit in this chair.
Subbu has earned it today.
Subbu, I knew you would win.
I always believed in you.
Come on, boy. Come, sit.
Subbu is our company's future.
He will take it to
a higher level than me.
Congrats, sir.
So good to have you, sir.
Sir, Ramaiah Company.
Pashupathi sir told me...
...to take the responsibility
of the takeover.
If you forward your
share papers to me...
...then that old man
will have to leave empty handed...
meveryihing by day after tomorrow.
Quality is good.
Polish the grain a bit less.
- Okay.
- You said It's not for sale.
Finished. It is done.
Their trust and respect on you...
everything.
Everything is finished.
This company will not be
in your name in another two days.
Had you listened to me then at
least something would have remained.
Come. We will sit and talk.
You said something at that time.
That you will do this work,
no matter what?!
This company will shut
down in another two days.
Why are you still doing it, sir?
Go home and take rest.
Sit.
Sit!
You used to have spectacles, right?
Specs are--
ls that your problem now? You have
worked hard to set up this company.
You fought and saved it,
someone is snatching it away...
...don't you feel sad.
Aren't you getting angry with me?
You know the Bhagavad-Gita?
Let me tell you my favorite verse.
Do you know its meaning?
Man shouldn't work for expectations...
...he should simply do his duty.
Whatever has to happen will happen.
Sir, why do you tell lines
from Bhagavad-Gita...
...when you are losing
your entire life's work?
You talked about being selfish.
Now, selfish people like Subramaniyam
and Pashupathi are winning.
So why has the Subramaniyam who won...
...come to this Ramaiah who has lost...
...why did he come to him?
Isn't it?
Correct. Why did I come?
Let anything happen to you
and your workers, why should I care?
Is he still working in that company?
- Who?
- The one who came last time.
Subramaniyam.
Ask him a question if you meet him.
Ask his conscience.
Ask who Subramaniyam is.
Okay, so nowadays this theme is popular...
...but I would suggest to you is...
"some good...
...so I will get a designer...
...who will recreate the atmosphere
ofthe pantheon...
...and it is amazing.
And the water sewed at the wedding...
...will be exclusively
imported from the Himalayas--
Wow! Did you hear that, Subbu?
Isn't that a wonderful idea?
Subbu.
Sorry.
Sorry, Riya.
I not correct for you.
This marriage is not taking place,
it is cancelled. You may go.
Subbu, are you joking?
No, Riya. I am not joking.
I am very serious.
I lived in a pent house till recently.
I wanted to reach the level of
Casa Paradise...
...now I reached here.
Next New York. After that?
I met a person called Robert
When I remember his words
and look back into my life once...
...l don't see these buildings,
cars and money I've earned.
Do you know what I am seeing?
I can see the face of a...
...a new born girl who
I held in my hands in the Himalayas.
Who needs anyihing else?
Subbu, did you get enlightened
after going to the Himalayas?
Yes in a way.
I had to go till there.
But there is no need, Riya.
Truth is truth anywhere.
Yesterday...
what did you tell me yesterday?
I asked why you are marrying me,
you said I am a winner, clever.
But you didn't say you love me.
How can you say?
Where is the love? Love is not there.
Once Rishi asked me
to tell our love story.
I too couldn't say it.
It is not there right?
It is not your mistake in
it because I too thought like that.
That's why we were a perfect
couple at that time.
Not now.
Because the Subramaniyam you liked...
...l left at Doodh Kashi with Rishi.
He and I are different.
Subbu, don't talk rubbish.
Rubbish?
Don't you understand? See.
See you are beautiful, I like you.
I like you means I like you,
not that I love you.
Hey, I love you means
not that I like you.
I love you means I love you.
Actually I need to leave.
I wrote this card for you,
it arrived bit late.
Subbu!
It is over if you exit the door.
I am serious.
You will not get a second chance.
This is my second chance!
Say hi to your dad.
Actually say bye.
Don't trust anybody.
Don't trust friends,
strangers, not parents especially.
What is this?
Nobody is permanent.
Everyone in this world
lives for their own needs.
We all live a lonely life.
Like a crow.
Hey, girl. I thought you will teach Karate
to children. What is this crow rubbish?
I am teaching them.
Hey, listen. We should
be ready for everyihing. Okay?
Attention! Come on!
Make pairs... face your partner.
Do exactly what I am doing, okay?
Follow me! I need a volunteer
for demonstration. You?
Sorry, I received a call.
Hey somebody come.
It is just five minutes. Please come.
Great! Great! Come.
If you have come to give me your wedding invitation
then I will break your other hand also.
- I didn't come for that.
- So why did you come?
I don't have shares
left with me to give.
Give me a share in your life,
that is enough.
- Hand... hand.
- So what happened to Riya?
Did you forget your MBA formula?
Strength, weakness, etc.
Subbu, our score will be zero.
Riya is only correct for you.
That was then, not now.
It is not correct to spoil
Riya's life by marrying her.
So you want to spoil my life?
That's not what I mean.
Even though I am living
in a ten crores house...
...l am thinking of the moments spent
with you in the hut.
I am ordering for potatoes
even in a five star hotel.
- What did you understand by that?
- You like potatoes.
Your face! It means I like you.
Earlier I had a
calculation for everything.
Now it feels like its enough ifl have you.
I really. . .really--
Wait.
I love you.
I love you means I love you,
not that I like you.
- I really...really--
- Teacher.
Wait.
- I really...really--
- Teacher!
Hold it!
This is a Matter of life and death.
Where did we stop just now?
Rishi once asked me
to tell my love story.
I didn't have love story at that time.
Now I have a love story
but Rishi is not there.
You are my everything now.
This life is yours.
What if you find
a better girl than me?
This entire life will be
enough to handle your madness.
I will not have time
to see another girl.
If you do, I will pluck out your eyes.
Done! Done!
Subbu.
- You are frightened of ghosts, right?
- Yes, why bring that up now?
I have to tell you a secret.
- My father Krishnamuflhy--
- He is no more, right?
He comes to meet
me daily at mid night.
Floating in the air... white.
- One minute... get up.
- What?
- Whom are you calling?
- Riya. She might cancel the marriage.
- I should tell her to stop.
- Oh..you will call her!
You will call only if you have hands.
- Stand here!
- Hey, I am joking.
Sir.
We have received the Shares!
What is it?
It is a job application sir.
Subramaniyam.
How did you get Dada?
I gave him the car, he gave me Dada.
Exchange offer.
He is happy, and I am too happy.
"Jantar Mantar!
Should I perform all magic tricks..."
"...on you?"
"Sorrow, grief."
“Should I convert them into zeros?“
"Sunday, Monday... have fun any day."
“Life is full of wonders.
Enjoy everything I say.“
"Lot of twists and
turns in small life."
"Why? Why?"
"Small wishes...
you jump to catch them."
“There are no tensions
before taking birth.“
“Everything is cool
if you take it easily.“
"lf you share each
and every moment..."
"...every day will
be a colourful day."
"Beautiful! Beautiful! You have just one life.
This moment belongs to you."
"Beautiful! Beautiful!
You have just one life."
"Don't think and enjoy it."
"lf you behave as you want..."
"...the world around you..."
"...will appreciate you."
"It follows you!"
"lf you help then..."
“...friendship will remain intact.“
"It will remain with you..."
"...and it will never leave you."
"One, two, three, four...
there are very few moments."
"Life is too shod
so think with your head."
"Work with love, live your life."
"Don't keep any unfulfilled wishes."
"Beautiful! Beautiful! Life is one.
This moment belongs to you."