He's not going to take you.
Who?
No one.
No one's going to
take you from me.
Who is it that's coming
to take me, Mum?
Surrender yourself to God.
Before we proceed to completion
of this execution...
...I, as representative
for the County Council...
...shall read the sentence.
Through the defendant's voluntary
and credible confessions...
...it has been concluded:
Partly that Anna Mansdotter
has committed fornication...
...with her son Per Nilsson...
...even after he had entered
into marriage...
...with Hanna Johansdotter.
Partly that the defendant decided
to take Hanna Johansdotter's life...
...and on the night of
the 28th of March...
...1889...
...brought that decision...
...to its fruition.
What's up with the girl?
Give her something to eat.
There's a light on
at Per Nilsson's.
They're up late.
The in-laws are visiting.
They're staying a few days.
But the light's on
in the farm-hand's room.
Really?
Yes, you're right.
Isn't that Anna Mansdotter?
Looks like her.
She's probably going to get to
Vittskovle early for market day.
I call the meeting to order...
Quiet please!
There seemed nothing untoward
when I called on the Nilssons.
But then I thought it odd they'd left
without locking up.
It was strangely quiet.
I called out to Hanna.
Hanna!
The cellar hatch was open.
Per Nilsson came to see us
at 7 in the morning.
He had an arrangement
with my husband Ola.
Ola was to help him
with a saw-log.
He was acting so strangely.
Hi Per! You seem very happy.
- Aren't I allowed to be?
- Of course you are!
Ola will be back soon.
He's out in the paddock.
Would you like a coffee
while you're waiting?
It's such a lovely morning.
Really lovely.
Have Hanna's parents arrived yet?
Hanna's parents?
Yes...
She said they were due
any day now.
Goodness, I haven't given you sugar.
Good heavens!
No, they haven't come yet.
They wouldn't get here
before dinnertime.
So this is the time...
"The time"...
What do you mean?
Then he was back
to his usual self.
- Ola!
- Hi, Per.
Erik Olsson!
A couple of hours later,
I went back to Per Nilsson's.
He was home.
I asked after Hanna.
He said she'd gone
to see a neighbour.
Something didn't feel right.
I said I'd come in
and take a look.
Hanna!
Why is the the hatch open?
What's happened?
She's not moving.
She couldn't be dead,
could she?
She's dead.
She's killed herself.
Good heavens!
What's that?
The mark on her throat...
...like from a noose.
Do you think she's taken
her own life?
Taken her own life?
She couldn't have.
Why would she do that?
This is a serious matter.
It's not up to us...
We need to speak
with the pastor.
The pastor?
We don't want anything
to do with him.
"We"?
We who?
We... here in this house.
You mean you
and your mother?
You're not churchgoers...
True.
But this is about Hanna,
and her rights before God.
If she was driven
to take her own life...
...or if someone else
has taken it.
Who would that be?
We've sent word
to your mother.
Mother?
She wouldn't be up
to taking the long way.
It's 15 km to grandma's.
Johanna saw her leaving
around 5 this morning.
Saw her?
- Mother?
- Anna Mansdotter, yes.
She saw it was mother?
She didn't see her face clearly,
but she was pretty sure.
She shouldn't talk about
things she doesn't know!
She's coming now.
So how did this happen?
- Lost your tongues?
- No one knows what happened.
Was no one here
when it happened?
Nope.
That was odd.
There's usually lots of people
running around here.
Are you quite sure
shes really dead?
Quite.
Have you nothing to do?
We have to respect
when someone's died.
You believe that?
A bunch of ignorant peasants.
To be sure she's not buried alive,
she should be bled.
That will be up to the pastor.
Pastor?!
That's right.
The men are writing a letter
to the pastor.
What about?
What letter?
What's the point of that?
Don't you want to
see the corpse?
Per...
Don't you want to see
your wife?
No... I can't.
Your mother's a hard woman.
You think so?
You don't know her!
Listen, lad...
It's best you stay apart
from your mother...
...until this matter
is cleared up
No... I need
to discuss it with her.
Things have to be done right.
We'll take her home
to your grandmother's.
- Come on.
- No!
You've no right to separate
my mother and I!
I have to talk with her.
Come with us.
It'd be for the best.
You need to stay away
from your mother.
She has sat down
with the devil himself...
...and had something to do with this
as you well know.
You'll pay dearly for this!
We'll see who'll be paying!
Let me go!
Jesus, I hope they lock her up.
Shall we see her again?
She'll be locked up
so long as we stick together.
We know what she's going for.
But whatever's going to happen
with poor Per?
Can't be any worse for him.
Such a kind, modest boy.
Why can't I be with my mother?
I must go to her.
I have to be with her.
From the depths...
to the heights...
there rules an invisible hand
And eyes that never close...
...watch over every little thing.
Beat your chest and tremble...
You are stirred
by the Avenger's gaze.
You that witness shall not die...
...as it followed you
where e'er you went.
Can this thing also be hidden...
...culprit for a baffled world.
God help me!
Help me, God!
I've killed her!
Do you admit to
taking your wife's life...
...of your own volition?
Yes.
Has anyone else put the idea
of murder in your head.
No.
But your wife would have
been in bed
How could you dress the body
on your own?
It wasn't hard.
When I pulled on one of the sleeves,
Satan was there to pull on the other.
How did you get the body
into the cellar, alone?
Satan helped me.
We'll ignore that.
You've made admissions in the presence
of Hanna's father and Johan Olsson.
First you choked your wife...
Then you hit her in
head with a mangle roller.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Your mother said
that you hit her a log.
I should know...
I hit her with a mangle roller.
- Why did your mother say that?
- She didn't.
They lie
to get her locked up.
They've always
been against her.
They've no respect for her.
How can that be?
They can't stand her,
because she's not like them.
I call this meeting to order.
Quiet please.
Why did you kill your wife?
What was the motive?
I felt repugnance for her.
For what reason?
I can't really say.
Was there something...
...wrong with her?
No...
Not wrong, exactly.
Something must have been wrong,
to give you a motive.
She wasn't happy
at the farm.
She just wanted to move.
And she couldn't
stand my mother.
Nothing wrong to give
reason for her murder!
There was the dowry question.
She didn't bring as much
as had been promised.
Do you think your motives
sound convincing?
I don't know...
I thought so then.
Bring in Anna Mansdotter.
How was the relationship between you
and your daughter-in-law?
Witnesses say she was always
crying in your presence.
Yes.
Why was that?
She could never explain why.
Because you treated her badly?
I never did that.
There was no reason.
She was nice to me.
Sometimes...
...she gave me food
behind my son's back.
Behind his back?
Yes.
Per refused to give me food.
What reasons did Per have
for killing his wife?
Per is bad with money.
When my husband died...
...there was 1,600 kronor
in the bank.
After a few years,
only debts.
If Hanna's father had helped Per
as he promised...
...I'm sure the murder
would never have happened.
So you didn't influence your son
to commit the murder?
No.
Weren't you there
on the night of the murder?
No.
4 witnesses saw you the same morning
going from Per's to your mother's.
They're lying.
They'll keep on lying
until I'm locked up.
You'll see!
You say I've committed murder!
What about me?
The whole mob of you
want ME dead!
The dead woman was properly dressed...
...all nice and neatly
That is... nice and neat and properly.
Are you saying that a man on his own
couldn't do it that well?
Well I certainly couldn't.
Particularly the suspenders...
I noticed how well
they were tied.
Men can't do that.
Are you still denying
that you assisted your son?
Yes.
Why did you make the mysterious visit
the day before the murder.
On the morning you went
from your mother's to Per's farm...
Paid a visit... didn't you?
No.
Think carefully.
Yes... perhaps...
I looked in on the Grave-Karnas.
Grave-Karna... that witch!
She's been seeing her
for years.
What did you and Grave-Karna
talk about?
What?
About trying to fix things
between Per and Hanna.
Weren't things good
between Per and Hanna?
- No.
- Why?
How would I know?
Did she say
she could help them?
She said...
...that they should
be patient.
Did Per know that
you visited that... woman?
You don't like
talking about that?
Per Nilsson, do you know that woman...
Grave-Karna?
Yes, I've heard about her.
Have you heard that your mother visited her
the day before the night of murder?
No, I didn't know about that.
That's remarkable.
It was for your sake she went.
For my sake?
Exactly!
To help make things up
between you and your wife.
Did my mother say that?
Yes.
Then it must be so.
But she's never said anything
to you about it?
Could you see Grave-Karna
for me...
Tell her I didn't say anything
that could hurt her.
Tell her she's not to take revenge.
What was it she wanted?
She was worried...
...about the daughter-in-law,
who was troublesome.
What did you tell her?
I said that...
...Hanna was a nice girl...
..and she should
just be patient...
...and things would
sort themselves out.
That was good advice.
I usually give good advice!
Was Anna satisfied
with that?
As far as I know.
You didn't promise
to help her?
In what way?
In fixing things up
between Hanna and Per, of course.
I never make promises.
Just give "good advice".
He can always call in
to see me.
I can't take
any more of this.
Now the truth will come out.
Hanna herself went to Grave-Karna,
begging for help.
Help with what?
With Per of course!
Coz he didn't treat her
like a wife.
What's meant by that?
Your worship would surely know
what a man does with his wife?
You've been married
and had children.
Well, Per Nilsson...
Had you had sexual intercourse
with your wife?
Do you not wish
to answer that?
No, I hadn't.
Why not?
Well, I shall tell you!
It's something not spoken about.
Everyone in the district knows.
It was that Per
and his mother have...
The two of them...
They have...
Yes?
Anna was jealous of Hanna.
That's the honest truth.
She couldn't stand Per
sharing a bed with his wife.
Did you dissuade Per from being
intimate with his wife?
No.
You were aware that it was
not a proper marriage?
Yes.
Did you not think it strange?
No.
Did you share your bed with your son,
before his marriage?
No.
Did you two fornicate?
Did you promise not to
get close to Hanna?
No.
So explain why you didn't?
It is natural behavior
between spouse.
Well?!
I was in love with someone else.
Yes... well, who were you
in love with?
Do I have to say?
Of course.  Otherwise,
we can't believe you.
It was...
Anna Jonsson in Yngsjo.
No...
I never noticed that Per
was in love with me.
He certainly never said anything.
Maybe he was too shy.
No... I don't know.
No...
I really don't think he was
at all interested in me.
A girl can sense those things.
No, Per Nilsson...
Anna Jonsson was unaware
of your feelings for her.
But you committed a murder
on account of her?
Yes.
She's got the devil on her side.
The old judge was an idiot
who let himself be fooled.
But the new one is clamping down
on everyone.
Describe how you killed your wife!
It was 3 or 4 o'clock
in the morning.
Speak up!
I leaned over her...
...and grabbed her
by the throat.
- Did she resist?
- No.
You have said that
she begged for her life.
She did.
So she must have resisted.
No, she didn't.
How is that possible?
- I was on top of her...
- Speak up!
I was on top of her...
She couldn't move.
What did you do
when she'd stopped breathing?
I hit her with the mangle roller.
You must have got blood on the clothes
when you dressed her.
I hit her after I'd dressed her.
According to the medical report,
she was hit right after being strangled.
I don't understand that.
What about the stockings?
Did you pull them on
first or last?
I don't remember.
How did you secure
the suspender belt?
I don't remember.
Will someone give me
a suspender belt?
Show me how you tie
a suspender belt.
You must know
some other way.
Another way!
Don't you know
any other way?
Well?
Bring in Anna Mansdotter!
That's just the way
it was tied.
Were you present
at the murder scene?
No.
But 3 witnesses saw you
at the farm.
- They're lying.
- All of them?
Yes, they're all lying.
So it's only Per
who tells the truth?
Yes.
Empty the room!
Now they'll be poking in the dung-heap.
Probably best
not to have to listen.
Is it true that before
your son's marriage...
...you used to sleep
in the same bed as him.
No, it's not true.
Bring the witness
I was a maid with Anna's husband.
He died.
When he died, Anna and Per
slept in the same bed.
She was afraid to sleep alone.
Anna and Per were living
with our sister for a time...
...and they always slept
in the same bed a night.
One early morning
when I came to Per farm...
...they were asleep
in bed together.
Anna said that she was afraid
of the dark.
Well, Anna Mansdotter...
What do you say to
these witnesses?
They're lying.
Have you never shared a bed
with your son?
Only when he was younger.
Did you fornicate?
No, never.
Were you jealous of her?
Why did you want her
out of the way?
I didn't want Hanna
out of the way.
Why did you share a bed
with your son?
We have the right to sleep
wherever we wish in our own house!
But you knew it was improper?
It doesn't bother me
what people think of me.
Tell me truthfully...
Why did you never touch your wife?
Had you promised
your mother?
No, I was in love
with someone else.
No one believes that.
We need another explanation.
- Hanna wasn't interested.
- And why was that?
According to witnesses she was most
unhappy that you didn't behave normally.
Did your mother not have
anything to do with that?
No.
But you and your mother
used to share a bed.
That's a fact...
Your mother has admitted
that it has happened.
- Mother said that?
- Yes!
Why would she?
Witness have seen you in the same bed,
a short time before your marriage.
It's not true!
Did you fornicate?
No.
What happened
after the murder?
After?
Exactly!
When the corpse
had been dressed...
and dumped in the cellar,
and the house tidied...
Was that coffee time?
No, we didn't have coffee.
We? We who?
- I didn't say we.
- What did you say?
It's not what I meant, anyway.
Take Per Nilsson out!
I have to protest.
Protest?
Now that you have her
in custody.
They could be contradicting
each other's statements.
With suspect evidence.
She denies it, and there's
no evidence that's conclusive.
You're surely not thinking
of acquitting her?
I have no choice.
The people are going to protest.
They're not going to like it.
I know.
She'll lose her head,
if I'm any judge.
What's wrong?
Why are you standing there?
You're crying!
What's up?
I was thinking of Anna
being beheaded.
It was our fault.
Maybe she's innocent.
You swore that she was guilty.
But no one saw it.
Don't forget that.
Nobody saw it!
So you get a reduced penalty,
if you confess?
Yes, that often happens.
Maybe you weren't involved
in the actual murder...
...but only helped
to hide the evidence.
- Yes.
- Good.
Then I'll help you to present
your confession in the right way.
Per must attest to it.
It would be enough for ONE head to fall,
wouldn't you say?
The trial continued on Saturday
of Per Nilsson from Yngsjo
and his mother Anna Mansdotter.
There was no new evidence,
but it was moving to hear
the murderer's grandmother...
...the near 80-year old Anna Tufvedsdotter
who hobbled up to the judge and said that
she fell asleep about 10 on that night...
and that her daughter was
in the process of making...
Who is it that's coming
to take me, Mummy?
My poor child.
What is it I'm doing?
What am I doing
to hurt you?
Here is your confession...
...where you admit that you
were present at the murder...
...that you did nothing
to stop the murder happening...
...and that you helped
to conceal the evidence.
Do you confirm to your confession?
No.
Am I to understand that
you're retracting your confession?
Are you maintaining your innocence?
No.
It was I who did it.
I alone.
Per wasn't even
in the room.
So you're admitting
that you alone were guilty.
Yes.
I was the one who killed Hanna.
Because I loved my son.
So it was out of jealousy?
You indulged in illicit love
with your son?
Answer my question.
You indulged in illicit love
with your son?
Yes.
Did you continue to fornicate with him
after his marriage?
Did you get him to promise...
...not to have intimate relations
with his wife?
Yes.
How did the murder happen ?
I sneaked into Hanna that night...
...while Per was out
in the stables.
So I strangled her.
When Per came back in
she was dead.
That's not true!
My mother's only trying
to save me.
Allow me to point out...
As your mother has confessed...
...you can no longer save her
from punishment.
What has she said?
I have to know
what she said!
Why?
You know very well
what took place.
I don't remember everything.
You have to tell me truthfully
exactly what happened.
You say one thing,
and Per another.
Trying to protect each other
won't work.
No, I think so.
It doesn't matter what we say.
Per insists it was he who hit Hanna
with the mangle-roller.
How could he do that
if he wasn't present?
He was in the room,
and helped out.
The other day you said
he was out in the stables.
I misunderstood the question.
So in fact the two of you
were involved in the murder?
Yes.
How did the murder happen?
Per hit her with the mangle-roller,
and then we strangled her.
Both of you?
No...
Per held her,
while I strangled her.
Why did she need to be held
when she'd been knocked senseless?
He just stood to one side
and watched
Did per take part at any stage
of the actual murder?
He wasn't all that innocent.
But it was you
who drove him to it...
Right?
Through jealousy!
How old was he the first time
you pressed him into fornication?
I don't remember.
Was it before the death
of your husband?
No.
I don't believe you.
How long had you been fornicating,
before your husband died?
Several years.
How many years?
I don't remember.
How long were you fornicating
before your father's death?
We didn't.
- You didn't fornicate.
- No.
Your mother stated
that you did.
My mother said that?
I don't believe it.
Do you think we lie in court?
No, but...
She can't have said that.
Your bother has confessed
that the two of you fornicated.
Do you deny her assertion?
No.
How old were you
when you started?
I don't know.
Did your mother make you promise
not to tough your wife?
No.
Your mother has stated that she got
such a promise from you.
Well, then...
Yes, she did.
This is getting ridiculous.
The mother comes up with
incessant contradictions...
... and the son says anything
that comes into his head.
We're not making progress.
It's not all that complicated.
The mother is possessed by jealousy.
And he is a slave to her will.
That's the basic explanation.
Yes, that's possible...
you could be right
But it may also be
that you're wrong.
Food.
Just have to wait
for a new verdict...
We'll see what happens
this time.
At least it should be
the final one.
Are you happy?
Yes, aren't you?
Yes...
So long as it works out.
Of course it will.
But only if we're in agreement.
And we might finally put a stop
to all the evil gossip.
I'll see you when you come home.
Are you leaving already?
I have to get home tonight.
But it's dark.
You're so afraid
of being alone in the dark!
It's something I'll just
have to get used to.
You have your wife
to hold onto, now.
Well, Per...
You're looking pleased.
Yes... music, food, lots of people...
That's the life!
I wasn't thinking of that.
I was thinking about Hanna.
You got yourself a good girl.
I agree with you there.
I can't say I like her
leaving home.
Hanna and I are very close, you know.
I do trust that
you'll look after her.
I assure you I'll look after
your daughter.
Don't dance too much
with the other girls.
Hanna can get angry if someone
plays with what's hers.
- Cheers!
- Cheers.
Are you there?
Yes.
You're so quiet.
You were talking and laughing
all evening.
Yes.
Aren't you getting undressed?
There's no hurry.
Yes, we've plenty of time now.
You're so serious...
I hardly recognise you.
You do think that
we'll be happy, don't you?
Don't you think so?
You're going to be nice.
Do you understand?
Of course!
Your hair feels so stiff...
Almost like horsehair.
Don't you like it?
It's so unusual.
You'll get used to it.
Things will be better
when we get home.
I wish we could stay here.
Stay here?
Not go home?
What do you mean
by that?
Nothing. It slipped out.
I didn't mean anything by it.
But I'm the lady
of the house, now.
Your mother has to
understand that.
Do you want to create difficulties
with my mother?
I don't want to be difficult,
but I know my rights.
Father has promised
to buy her out from the farm.
What is it?
Aren't you going to bed?
In a while.
You go though.
You have your wife
to hold onto, now.
Go and wait inside.
No, I'd rather wait for you.
Look... Mother has
set the table for us.
Doing it herself...
As if I'm supposed to feel
like a visitor in my own house.
The house is not yours yet.
I hope the food is good enough to eat
even though it's me who set the table.
Aren't you going to eat, too?
You can't make it so obvious
you'd hate Hanna running the house.
You think I should accept
being pushed aside in my own house?
Should I be kept
in the stables instead?
No... no...!
We don't have to rush things.
Do you know what I think?
There won't be any  money.
She'll push me out of here.
She'll take everything...
You... the farm...
without paying anything.
You think she's that cunning?
I'm starting to believe that
your marriage was in vain.
I've missed you.
I've missed you so much.
Your hair is so soft.
I can't stand looking at her
any more.
She bursts into tears
whenever she sees me.
That crying is so tedious.
So you think things
are fine as they are?
No...
But you must give me
a little time.
It seems as if it were best
that I left the farm for good.
I can't see myself staying.
You don't need me.
You have your wife now.
What is it you're saying?
You know I can't live without you.
I don't know
what to believe.
For God's sake,
what do you mean?
We had agreed that we'd make sure
we got our dowry money for Hanna.
But you haven't done
a thing about it.
I can't go asking him for money
when I haven't done
the right thing by Hanna.
What does that matter?
I simply can't face him.
Do something with her then.
I just can't do it.
I can't stand her.
Sometimes I sit up half the night
so I don't need to be near her.
Hanna?
Would you do something for me?
We need peace in this house.
I can't put up with this
any longer.
Nor I.
Things can never work out
between you and me...
so long as your mother
is in the house.
Everyone around here says
she's a hard and nasty woman.
She has no business being here.
You and I are the ones
who belong together.
You think you can go on
getting away with it, don't you!
You get me my money,
and I'll get out of your life.
I should be able
to get the money.
- Mother!
- Be quiet!!
You don't understand the game
she and her father are playing.
Do you really imagine...
...that you can be
a surrogate for me?
That you can take my place
in my own home, with my own son?
Well then?!
Answer me!
Don't you have a tongue?!
I only want my rights.
Your rights?
What rights?!
You can't even give my son
what he needs in bed.
What can you give him?
Nothing!
Nothing but tears
and sniveling!
You could give him money!
But he doesn't get it...
...as that gives you power.
You think you'll drive me
out of the house...
..and drive him to death afterwards!
You'll drive him to death!
You want to drive him
out of his mind!
Get out!
Get out of our sight!!
I couldn't help it.
I have to protect us.
It's my fault.
If only I could.
If I could...
It's not your fault.
I can't even try.
Where were you?
Do you think your mother has a right
to treat me the way she does?
Are you going to sleep
on the sofa?
Why can't you answer me?
Per...
You have to talk to me.
I'm so lonely here.
I don't have anyone.
It's so wrong.
He doesn't have me
as his wife.
Don't you get together at night?
No... there'll be reasons for that.
What do you mean?
There's nothing wrong with you.
But you've come a cropper here.
You've come a cropper,
falling into that family.
They're created in their own way,
they are.
I don't understand.
It's just as well.
Bring me a pillowslip
that Per has slept on.
A pillowslip?
Yes, a pillowslip.
But he must have SLEPT on it.
Understand?
No.
Bring it as quickly as you can.
We'll see if we can change
who Per's in love with.
I'll be back this afternoon.
Wait in the bedroom.
Come in.
You have to help me.
It can't go on...
It has to be stopped.
You shouldn't drag anyone
into your mess.
I told you that
We had to...
You know that.
Now he doesn't want
to sleep with her?
He can't stand her.
It's time to think about it now.
What's the point
of giving you advice?
You never follow it.
Never have.
If you're not going to accept
what I say...
...find out for yourself.
I'll do whatever you say...
...so long as we get rid of her.
You have to be patient.
Leave them in peace...
...and move home
to your mother's.
I'll try and come up
with a solution.
- We can't wait!
- No, of course.
Do as you please...
you always have.
But remember...
If I'm not on your side...
...I'm against you.
And you and I have
some old garbage...
...that you wouldn't want
people to smell.
Shut up!
Just reminding you...
...in case you'd forgotten.
We need to know
where we stand with each other.
For God's sake
come up with something.
God?
What would YOU know
about God?
Do you follow His way?
I don't care which way I follow.
I'm well aware of that!
But other ways also
demand obedience.
Don't forget that.
Who was that?
Anna.
Good God!
You needn't be frightened.
Bring me the pillowslip.
Then you'll sleep on it
every single night...
...until it takes effect.
I knew it...
She wants to harm me.
Per!
Per...
I just can't cope,
until your mother's moved out.
I was thinking about what we
talked about the other day...
About that house for your mother.
I could write to my father.
I can't stand it any longer, Per.
He kissed me!
Today he kissed me!
Only on my cheek...
But at least he did!
How did it come about?
I found out he owed a lot of money
to Wahlstrom's store...
400 kronor!
I told him I could get the money
to pay the debt.
So then...
Then he kissed me!
So that's all it was.
At least he gave you a kiss.
Yes...
Not what you would call
a real kiss...
But still...!
Can't bear the sight of me?
It's just I didn't know...
You thought you were rid of me?
You thought you could separate us.
But nothing can separate
Per and I.
Nothing!
Least of all the likes of you!
Mother...
I shouldn't have come...
But I had such a longing
to see you.
It's hard being away
from here.
Awfully hard
You have to come back, Mother.
I'm so unhappy.
We have to be patient.
I can't go there alone
any longer.
But it's awful having to reveal
how things stand.
You were quite right to confide.
You just never know.
The worst thing
that could happen
would be to let Per build
for his mother on the farm.
But he's so anxious to do it.
He made it quite clear...
...that it was the only way things
could be made good between us.
I could ask my father.
I say it's the worst
that could happen!
Because Per... he...
What about Per?
Per only has love
for his mother.
That type of loving that
he should have for you!
No...
No... that can't be true.
Get Per to move from here as far away
as possible, so his mother can't see you.
It's the only way you'll ever
get a proper marriage.
I'll write to my father.
I'll have to beg him
to help me.
No... there won't be any money
for building.
Your mother and Hanna
can never get on together...
...and you are to stay
with your wife.
There are two properties for sale
in the Albo district.
If you'd like to sell
here and move there...
...I could help you with money.
But if you reject that proposal...
...I'd have to reconsider the situation.
I'm trapped now, Mother.
I can't even pay the interest
on the 25th.
I'll have to sell,
move where they say.
What shall I do with Hanna?
She's telling people we don't live
as man and wife.
There's one way.
What way?
To get Hanna on our side.
How can that work?
Just leave it to me.
It's easily done.
If she were to die...
What are you saying?!
If she died...
It would be the happiest day
of my life.
I sometimes feel
I want to strike her down.
It'd be the first time
in my life, if I hit her.
She hangs over me
like a bad conscience.
I was wondering if you'd like
to come and visit my mother.
Get to see how we live.
Maybe on Sunday.
I was going to cook eel.
I know you like it.
What do you say?
I don't know.
It's just that I was thinking...
You've never met Mother.
I don't know...
I don't think...
Do not be so terrified...
I don't want to hurt you.
I can't stay there any longer.
I don't dare.
I'm disappointed.
I never expected my daughter
to run away from her husband.
Father, can't you understand
that I'm afraid!
I don't dare go to sleep at night.
She makes me want to scream.
I don't want to hear
about such things.
Who can I turn to,
if even you won't listen to me?
That's not the point.
A woman is to stay
with her husband.
That's the law.
What am I to do?!
My husband's not human!
You go back home
to him now, my child.
I've promised that
there'll be a move.
I'll keep that promise.
That I shall.
You'll get away from that woman,
and live in peace with your husband.
But until that happens,
you simply must stick it out.
I'll try, Father.
No tears, now!
You're the one
with the upper hand...
Don't forget that.
No, Father.
Where is she?
At the Hansson's.
She's there all the time lately.
Tomorrow...
Tomorrow I have to go and look
at that Albo property.
What are you thinking?
I'm going to be
in debt to him forever.
There's got to be
a way around it.
Grave-Karna... She can help you.
Go see Grave-Karna.
That's no good.
Then everyone in the district thinks
I need to see her, to sleep with my wife.
I just want to live here
with you.
It can't happen.
Don't you understand?!
We have no choice.
Per...
...dearest...
Let me be!
Don't nag me...
Get away.
Get away!
Mother...
When shall I get
to live with you again?
When can we be together
like before?
Just keep calm.
Laugh and be happy.
It'll never be the same again.
Yes it will, darling boy of mine.
It'll be the same again.
We must be patient.
If we're both not to be destroyed,
listen to what I say.
You have to be patient.
Do you promise?
Yes, I promise.
If I could trust you...
Of course you can trust me.
Come on Mother...
Forget everything.
I want us joined together.
Come on now!
What about Hanna?
She won't be back
for hours.
Come on!
Where have you been?
It's too late to be running around
at night.
What have you been out
gossiping about?
Only about what is true.
True about what?
You'd be the best judge of that.
Where have you been?
At Ola Svensson's
if you must know.
What did you talk about there?
About the saw-logs
of course...
....that Ola will be helping you with
in the morning.
And...?
What else did you say?
- None of your business.
- What more did you say?
Nothing!
Let go of me!
You watch out!
Running around gossiping
can be dangerous!
I'm not afraid of you!
I was told.
Now I know enough
for sure.
Mother and father are coming tomorrow,
and soon we'll be far from here.
And if I don't move?
What else can you do?
I can tell Father about you
and your mother.
He can have you both locked up!
Tomorrow's too late.
I can answer for myself...
...but not for Per.
He's unable to resist
any longer.
He can break at any moment.
Tell him to come here.
I can't help someone
who doesn't want to be helped.
You two don't want to be helped.
You just want things
your own way.
I have to trust you.
Where are you going?
To see to the cattle.
Per...
Don't go!
I don't want to be alone.
Why's that?
Your mother's here.
- She's here to kill me.
- Stop that!
I don't want to have to
listen to that!
I know... I don't want
that you two do it together!
Mother?
What are you doing here
in the middle of the night?
I had a foreboding.
I was afraid...
Afraid of what you might do.
I've done nothing.
I saw Grave-Karna....
I couldn't think what to do.
All she could say
was to be patient.
I'm not doing anything.
I don't trust you.
I'm not doing what you said.
I'll stay here tonight.
As you wish.
Per...
Why is it so hard
for you to like me?
Why wouldn't I do as
well as your mother?
Aren't I prettier?
As soon as we get away from here,
everything will be good, you'll see.
You'll soon forget her completely.
Let me be yours tonight.
I can't stand this any longer!
You say nothing
and turn your back on me.
After all, I'm your wife!
Look at me .
Look at me.
Come into me.
Come into me!
Do it, and I'll say nothing
to Father.
Make her quiet before she wakes
the whole neighbourhood.
Be quiet!
Is she dead?
I don't know.
She's breathing.
Tomorrow, everyone will know.
Now she won't tell anyone anything.
You can relax.
She's alive.
Jesus, what'll we do?
Calm down.
No she's still.
We'll go to prison.
Not if you listen to me.
Do as I say.
Alright...
I'll do exactly what you say.
I'll never go against you.
It's amazing...
I'm almost happy.
Now it's just you
and me again.
The sentence for each one...
Anna Mansdotter is sentenced...
...for incest, to life with hard labour...
...and for murder, to be put to death.
Per Nilsson, for incest,
4 years hard labour...
..and for murder,
to be put to death.
I bring some relief to your suffering,
my child.
A veritable message from God...
A wonderful piece of news.
A light to your darkness.
It's about your son.
He has won his appeal.
He's avoided the death sentence.
Him?
Only him?!
Yes.
The village folk felt convinced
of his innocence.
They know Per for his
open, friendly nature...
...and no one could believe
that he could have been involved.
The village folk...
The village folk sentence and acquit.
That's divine justice for you.
The village's favour,
or the village's hate.
Is that what decides
between life and death?
Is that justice?
Answer that for me.
Aren't you glad your son's life
has been spared?
No!
They could have spared him
before we got this far.
But it was me.
I was the only one
who gave him that love...
That love that he needed.
Not the one that
others decided on.
I was the one
who protected him...
...against God...
...who took my other children
from me...
...who for all her crimes
shall lose her life...
...having forfeited for all time,
all rights as a citizen.
The time has come, my child.
Push her head down.
It was a bit crooked...
not my fault.
She lifted her head
at the last moment.
You saw that didn't you, Pastor?
She repented.
So she wept.
I'm sure she repented.
Subtitles by FatPlank for KG