...:::Lord Sadler:::...
lordsadler2012@gmail.com
In Yor's World
He's the man
Yor's World
Lost in the world of past
In the echo of ancient blast
Yor's World
There is a man from the future
A man of mystery
Yor's World
No tribes to lead the way
In his search for the yesterday
Yor's World
Misty illusions hiding
His famous destiny
Yor's World.
Yor, the touch of fire
Yor the proud and free desire
He never sees the sun
He's always on the run
Him and his days are gone
They say he will go on
His search goes on and on
Yor's World
He's forsaken the name
And the world looks like fire
He's gonna make all the wild
Things look tame tonight
In his fight
In Yor's World
He's the man
Yor's World
He's forsaken the name
And the world looks like fire
Yor's World
On the sun there's a soul
And the world looks like fire
And finally we must give thanks
for we have reached this prosperous valley.
By raising our childrens to
the heavens in homage to the gods.
Now for that matter,
may this day be celebrated...
with celebration and joy.
Look!
Leave with me!
Look out, stranger!
Drink, drink it.
It burns like fire!
The blood of your enemies
makes you stronger.
- Drink!
- I rather stay weak.
Who are you?
Where you came from?
I'm Yor, the Hunter.
I'm came from the high mountains.
Thank you for saving Ka-Laa.
She is the most precious thing
of my life.
My name is Pag.
Her father was my king.
Let's take the meat of the beast.
What a strange piece of metal.
What is it?
I don't know, I have this
since I can remember.
- I've never seen anything like it.
- I have seen a similar medallion!
- Are they your people?
- Yes.
- Where?
- Beyond the mountains.
It was worn by a woman
who lives among the desert people.
I have seen gleaming on her chest
when the sun rays strike it.
- Who is she?
- She is the daughter of the Gods.
They say she descended into the earth
in a tongue of fire.
And now she is worshipped
as a queen.
Come, Yor.
Welcome to our village.
Good!
Take some, you did well, Ka-Laa.
Yor, you're so different
from the other men I've seen.
Kill them!
The women!
Take him!
I want him alive!
- Yor!
- No!
Ka-Laa, come on!
After them!
We must find out any of your people
who's still alive and bring them with us.
Do you know the big tree
in middle of the river? - Yes.
There's a cave underneath.
We'll met you there, Pag.
Ka-Laa, go with Yor.
He will protect you.
No! Don't go, Pag!
It's not safe to go back alone!
This man seems very loyal to you.
Yes. Since my father died,
he never left me.
Come on. I know a place where
we can rest the night.
- Pag... Where is Ka-Laa?
- Ka-Laa is safe.
She's with Yor. But they took
all the women as prisoners.
They were beasts, they butchered all of us.
And the children too and the elders...
Save yourself, and Ka-Laa...
Go with Yor.
Your fate lies with him.
He...
We'll be safe here, Ka-Laa.
It's where I used to hide
when I was a boy.
I'll not sleep,
I'll stand guard.
What a strange thing.
What is it?
I wish i knew.
It's like fire burning inside me,
a question without an answer.
Remind the sun of fire.
No mother, no father.
Oh, Yor, you'll find the answer.
There must be a tribe of men
like you.
And there must be women, too.
Get out of here, Ka-Laa.
Get out of here, I've said!
His power is now mine!
Oh, Gods of rock and water,
high, the great Ucan!
No!
Take her back to the cave!
Yor!
Throw him off the cliff.
Hurry!
The gods must be a thirst
for fresh blood. Hurry!
Thank God you're alive!
C'mon, it's not safe to remain here.
No! First we must find Ka-Laa!
- Where is she?
- We lost her in battle.
Ka-Laa now belongs to him.
That's it.
No, Pag!
I don't recognize your loss!
That way!
You, you and you!
Now we'll fight and our prize
will be this woman here!
We can do nothing now.
There are several of them down there.
The beast of the night.
Stay low.
You're mine.
You know the great Ucan?
Yor!
After them! Hurry!
Thank you, Yor. You given me back
to me that which I love most in the world.
Thank you, Pag.
You did your best.
Now let's get going.
Pag, why is Yor so different
from the other men?
I don't know Ka-Laa.
I'm curious too about Yor's life.
Where's that steam come from?
From the depths of the earth.
The bottom of these must be
a great heat which causes these vapours.
- And the smoke?
- I don't know.
This is the land of diseased.
Of the men of the desert.
They worship the god of fire.
I've heard they practice magic
rituals with supernatural powers.
I'm afraid death rules
this land.
Listen, I'll be back before
day break.
Yor, please!
Don't go to that woman.
I'm afraid only evil happen there.
You both stay here.
Don't worry, Ka-Laa.
And don't try to follow me.
Last night I had a dream,
and I saw you helpless...
surrounded by fire.
Please don't go, Yor.
I'll be fine.
He will return?
Yes, Ka-Laa.
He'll return.
Where did you get that medallion?
- What is it mean?
- They say I came here togheter with those men.
There, cold in the ice.
Why am I alive and they are dead?
I don't know.
And why the ice is formed
in this part deserted...
is a mystery without an answer.
But...
The little water that comes from me
is vital to these people.
And they worship me
as a divine goddess.
Now you're a living proof
that we represent a race.
Together we will find
an answer.
Why did you come to this land of death?
I came looking for you.
I was told of your existence.
I don't know how I got here.
But they would never let me leave.
You see? These people are
threatened by land in which they live.
The poison of these vapors
in the ground which kill their plans.
They are convinced that sacrificing
every stranger they captured...
is the only way to placate
the wrath of the gods.
- What's your name?
- Roa.
Listen, now we both know
there are others like us.
We got to escape. There must be
some place in this world...
where we can live in peace
with our people.
Now release me,
or kill me now.
Wait, Ka-Laa!
If Yor came this way,
I feel for his life.
This is no place for man
or beast, we must turn back!
No, Pag!
We promise we wouldn't follow him.
I want to go to Yor!
Look out!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Roa!
Try walking.
Let's go!
Yor!
Here!
Who are you?
We will need a lot of more hemp
before you throw.
I have to thank you and Ka-Laa,
but there's no need you accompany me.
If you wish to settle here,
Roa and I will continue alone.
Ka-Laa is uninterested to my care.
She will not leave your side.
You're a good man, Pag.
And that's no lie.
My life's taking now a new meaning
with you and your friends.
Ka-Laa!
Come help us!
Yor!
A little different from the desert?
I loved this place.
I could stay here forever, Yor.
Do you know that I've never
belonged to another man?
And that I've never felt the desire
and longing that I'm feeling now for you?
Beautiful, Roa.
I'll go look for them.
The meat is burning.
Your jealousy is burning.
A man of our people
can have many wives.
- So why can't Yor have two?
- You don't understand, Pag.
That woman is from
the same race of Yor.
And can take him away forever.
If that has to be,
you can not oppose their destiny.
Get up!
- Only one of us can belong to him.
- You can not understand.
I understand that one of us
must die.
- Where is Ka-Laa, Pag?
- She went looking for you.
Yor!
Yor, look out!
Roa!
Die!
Die, you bastard!
Damn Ucan!
Yor... you see?
Dreams are only dreams.
No, don't leave me.
Things seems coming back to me.
I see an island...
In the middle of a big sea...
And on the island,
there is a magnificent castle.
That's where we came from.
Where our race lives.
Take my medallion
and give it to Ka-Laa.
It's the emblem of our world.
She loves you.
Kiss me, Yor, quickly.
My gods are calling me...
A part of me will always
remain here.
We always lose something,
but life goes on.
The country you seek
might be far away.
- Have you ever seen the sea before, Ka-Laa?
- No, it's so big!
Ka-Laa, the water is salty,
Don't drink it!
Smells good.
- Where is Ka-Laa?
- Fishing.
Eat, you must be hungry.
I'm sure I will, I'm hungry.
What was that?
Come on, it came from over there!
Ka-Laa, stay there!
...:::Lord Sadler:::...
lordsadler2012@gmail.com
Thanks, Pag.
We must go back to the sea,
quickly.
May could it be another beast
out there, come.
Come with us.
Our village is near.
Why did Yor risked his life
like that?
He did the same thing
to save us, remember?
A generous man does
what's heart commands.
It's not safe here, let's go!
There are my people.
And that is our village.
Why are the guards
watching the sky?
They're watching for the gods!
- He is your man?
- Yes.
Where are your children?
And his other wives?
You're getting heavy!
Tarita, what happened?
- This man saved our lives.
- I'm grateful, it was nothing.
My name is Kay.
Tarita and the little ones
are my children.
According to our customs,
Tarita's life now belongs to you.
She will be your mate.
Take me with you, stranger!
You're a sweet child, Tarita.
But I already have a woman.
- At least accept our hospitality.
- I'd like that, Kay.
What did your son mean when
he said you are looking for the gods?
Two moons passed since we killed
the man who drop from the heavens.
- We now fear the revenge.
- If you killed them, it cannot be a God.
I promise you, it was a god.
He descended from the heavens
in a strange fire bird.
Fell over there.
We all ran to see.
One of my men overcame its fear
and approached the visitor.
In pieces, we couldn't strike him.
In fire.
So we threw our arrows at him
and there was a great explosion.
And he fell back in the flames.
Now all that remains of that bird
on fire is this strange object.
There.
It's made of a substance
unknow to us.
It was threw here in the explosion.
It might explode too.
That's why we leave it here.
Come, the women have prepared
a feast in your honor.
You know, Kay...
I was thinking about that bird
of fire that fell from the heavens.
It could be part of the answer
you're looking for.
The bird? The destruction?
I think the man wanted to kill
because he was much afraid of you...
as you were of him.
And you didn't understand each other.
Yor, come with us.
Ka-Laa! You come too!
I must go too. I have to retreat my weapons
on the cave of that strange object.
You'll have time enough.
Now enjoy your food.
- The village!
- Oh, my God!
Father! No!
Dad! Dad!
No, let me go!
No! Father!
- Eagle to M1.
- The box speaks!
Eagle to M1.
Mission completed.
- Eagle to M1.
- This is what they heard.
Eagle to M1.
Mission completed.
Damn talking box!
They're not gods.
Gods couldn't be this cruel.
I'll find them!
And I'll revenge Kay and his people.
I must leave, Tarita.
Stay, Yor.
We need a new leader.
No. My destiny cares me elsewhere.
Just as yours is to remain here
and make a new life with your people.
Your father wanted that, Tarita.
Our fishermen used to talk
of a mysterious island...
always surrounded by
violent storms.
If you feel that can be
the one you seek...
you can have my father's boat
to take you there.
Thank you.
It's truly beautiful!
This island that your
fishermen saw, Tarita...
- In which direction they said that was?
- In the direction of the setting sun.
I'll never forget you!
Thank you!
Thank you for everything, Tarita!
Yor, the wind is freshening!
- Look!
- Check the sail, Pag!
It's stuck!
Pag, rush up the sail!
I keep trying, but I can't!
He'll drown!
Hold tight!
Ka-Laa!
Ka-Laa! Ka-Laa!
He has reached the outer limits
of my territory.
A decision must be made.
You! You'll bring it here!
This rebel must be analyzed.
Search Unit six to patrol.
Six to patrol. Leader.
Search unit, six or nine.
Overlord, two more
intruders in the sector 1-6.
We await your orders.
I want them both captured
and brought here!
Alive!
There's no need to be afraid,
I'm a friend. Come on!
They are the androids of Overlord.
Come on!
Don't be afraid.
I'm your friend.
And this is the land you left
when you were a child.
- My name is Ena.
- If you're my friend as you said, release me!
I must obey orders,
but I'll free you hands.
Only Overlord can free you.
We've learned a lot about you,
from your medallion.
Your record is fully
registered on it.
Your name is Gallahah, and you're
the son of the rebel, Asgard.
Your ship was destroyed
when you left many years ago.
Your father was vanished
and he took you with him.
How you survive the explosion and grow up
in the outside world is a mystery.
What you mean you know all about me?
How do you know who my parents were?
I will allow this poor fool
to learn the secrets of his existence.
That is the far of my
generosity will go.
No, I don't want him killed!
Not yet.
He's perfect for
what I have in mind.
A great blow for the genetic engineer!
And last...
a chance to prove my greatness.
Daddy! Daddy!
Those are your parents.
And the child is you.
My Father, my Mother...
How beautiful she is.
I remember that. That's when
I was learning to hunt.
Sometimes I have to thrown back.
And you do know all about me,
don't you?
The machine speaks the truth?
Oh, yes. And even has a record
of your new friends, Pag and Ka-Laa.
Free me, Ena,
so I'll go look for them.
- I already told you...
- Free him, Ena!
Who are you?
I am the Overlord.
Ruler of my people.
And yours too.
- You are completely in my power.
- What have you done to my friends?
Ah, your friends?
Yes, we have separated
during the storm.
As you can see, they still alive.
Unfortunately, they disappear
just after they came the shore.
But you'll find them.
And given the welcome
that they deserve.
The girl's records will be
analyzed, then executed.
Don't be afraid, you're welcome
to no home. We are friends.
You are Pag and you are Ka-Laa.
The man you love
and who loves you is alive.
- I just left him.
- Is it true?
- Yes, you can trust me.
- Take me to him!
That wouldn't be wise. The Overlord
released him only few minutes ago.
He hopes to use him as bait
to capture you and Pag.
He knows you've landed on the island,
but can't find you.
What did you call him?
The Overlord? Who is that?
We are all that is left of
a civilization that was wiped out...
by a great atomic blast.
Whenever man discovers something
greater than itself...
he abuses it until them destroy.
Overlord has leding us as longer
to the same path.
He commands all of us.
And his main intention
is unquestionably...
to do evil.
Go check the access points.
The androids are searching everywhere.
Your world is forbidden to us.
According to the Overlord,
he still contaminated by nuclear fallout.
And It's a barely wasteland
where life no longer exists.
But tell us,
what is it really like?
We are proof that life does exists.
There are many dangers,
wild animals barbarously striking.
But there are also people
who live in peace.
- Ena.
- Yes?
- Has the girl gone.
- Yes.
Damn!
Where is she?
What have you done to her?
Do not worry. We are planning
a revolt for years.
And now that Yor, the son
Asgard, has returned...
- He will be our new leader.
- I don't understand what you're talking about.
- I wanna go join Ka-Laa!
- Be patient, you'll see her soon.
I'll attend to the robot memory banks.
- Go now, Ena.
- Come on, Pag.
Ka-Laa!
Where are you?
Ka-Laa, which one is you?
Which one are you?
It's you!
Don't be afraid.
Come look at this, Ka-Laa.
C'mon, I'll show you my past.
I hope I figure it out.
Welcome, Ka-Laa.
The rose of fertility.
She is my woman, Overlord.
I am the only one who can own
anything on this island.
Who are you, anyway?
I am one of the survivors who
came here at the time of great destruction.
But many of us carry the genes of the
radioactive fallout that destroyed our cities.
At that time many of us died
until we neutralize the disease.
For generations, I have defending
my subjects against the great plague...
that continues to rubbish
the outside world.
I want my people to procreate,
multiply and grow strong.
That eventually,
I may conquer the world.
And exterminate all barbarians.
You believe you're a God,
but you think as a murderer.
You talk just like your father,
and those who plot against me.
But now...
They will replace all humans.
They're a part of my military power.
I will create technicians,
scientists, magnificent minds!
Who will all think
according to my will.
You'll command a world of puppets,
is that your golden life?
Yes.
I'm the giver of death.
But also of life.
You are to be the forefather
of a new race...
together with Ka-Laa, this
genetically perfect woman that is your mate.
As I said, I am experimenting
with a new type of android...
which requires the seed of
a specially like yourself to produce...
a new race! Superior to these
slower intelligence models.
You will be genetically
perfect too.
And you'll think as well
I want too, you'll see.
I will operate on your mind!
Until every thought that's not
proper has been eliminated.
And you will have a new mind and
its memory will shall transmitted to your genes.
And when you have inseminated
this woman...
You will die.
We have to act quickly.
Pick your weapon, c'mon!
Soon you will be two new
individuals, calm and docile.
Who knows I may even
let you live, Gallahah.
- Are you ready to fight?
- Yes!
- Let's go, Yor!
- Right!
The rebels have been unmasked.
We'll shall destroy every one of them.
As we always have done
with all rebels in the past.
They have dared to threaten
the authority of the Overlord!
All androids make a hunt!
Go to your positions.
We'll place this trick in the
command station of the atomic pile.
- The others can begin boarding.
- Boarding to where?
You will be taking our culture
with you to help you build...
a new world.
You talk like you're not
planning to come along.
I don't know how many of us
will make it.
Come on!
Damn!
Kill them! Kill them!
Block all access
to the atomic pile!
These fools thought they can beat me,
the Overlord!
- He acted before us.
- We can't just give up.
- There must be some other way to cross.
- Yes, over there.
Set it!
No, Yor!
It's too dangerous!
We have no choice, Ka-Laa.
We have to let him go.
I've set it for eight minutes.
Someone shoot him!
Kill him! Kill him!
I'm surrounded by fools around me!
Damn!
Save yourselves!
Go! Get moving!
Come on, Pag!
Pag, you did it!
Now we gonna hurry, c'mon!
They activated the atomic pile!
The bomb must be stopped!
Overlord, there's no escape!
Your reign of evil has ended.
You are quite powerless
without your army of robots.
They are not programmed
to shut down the atomic pile.
So you have launch to go reach
to the control concil to yourself.
While I deactivate your
electronic puppets, sector by sector.
Level by level.
- Pag! Shoot him! Shoot him!
- No, Pag! It's useless!
You can't kill somebody who
is an illusion, a shadow.
No, dammit!
He must push the button physically!
Overlord!
No, Ka-Laa!
Come on, the bomb will do the rest!
I've done it, Ka-Laa!
Let's go!
I'm beating your ambition
to create a master race.
You have kept the world in darkness
in hidden progress.
It is the man, with all its
faults, that represents the future.
Not your dream race
of hybrid clones...
that can be deactivated
with the touch of a button.
Follow me!
The old man doesn't block off all!
I'll take care of them,
get on to the ship. Go on!
Come back down!
It stop!
Overlord, now you'll never
rule the mainland.
Inspired by the purity of
the strifes, one of our own race...
has sent them back to destroy you.
Pag, get a move on!
Come on! What you waiting for?
The survivors of this island
will return to the main land.
And let us pray that this time
our youth will not repeat our mistakes.
And them bright what
we've learned over wrong.
May the stablishment
of a brave new world.
Made of love and tolerance.
And may God forgive us.
Yor returns to the primitive
tribes of the main land.
He is determined to use
his superior knowledge...
to prevent them making
the same mistakes as their forefathers.
Will be successed.
...:::Lord Sadler:::...
lordsadler2012@gmail.com