- Hey, blondie, got a cigarette?
- No. - Giulio? Come!
- Leave him alone, can't you see
he's innocent? - Bye!
He still has to put some meat on
his bones..
- He's under age! - Hi! - Caroline
Cherie! - Take him to his mother!
Giulio, when we were your age, I and your
brother got in with uncle's ratio card.
Come on!
Come on, boys!
All together, go!
One... One, two, three!
Go!
I had you all!
How happy we were.
Happy to be twenty,
happy to enjoy those summer nights,
and above all,
happy to be together.
Ours was the most beautiful pack
in the city.
My brother, Giulio, the innocent.
Ettore, the women's idol.
Marcello, last in races,
first in love.
Franco, the craziest, merriest
and happiest of us all.
And I.
Boys, I 'm not sleepy, I wanna have
fun! Roars the lion!
- Where should we go? - The bar at the
station, there's where women are. - Yes.
- Home you go. - You go.
- Don't you see he's still a suckling.
Suckling my ass!
Let's find him a woman.
- Think I can't find my own women?
- Move it!
- We'll get you one! - I'll kick your ass
if you don't! - What's he gonna do with her?
- No!
- More, more, more!
Go!
I want to have fun, guys,
I'm not going home tonight!
- Don't be afraid, Giulio, we'll
find you too a woman tonight. - Who?
- The fatty!
- Let's go to fatty!
Hurrah!
- Ops! - Fatty? - Eh,
fatty... - No fatty!
- Nothing, nothing! - Come on!
- Pull! - Come one, come on!
And the bottle?
Another bottle.
- Come on! - Now you'll go home?
- Yes, tomorrow! - Balls, balls!
Hey, spanish cows, I'm drinking!
Disgusting!
It's venom, but...
- Hey, guys, who's goin' to pay?
- I've also won!
You've ruined me! Bastards!
- Franco! He's leaving.
- Where're you goin'? - Franco!
- Franco!
- Where're you goin', Franco? - Franco!
And a one!
Two... and a three!
- Spanish cows! Jump, if you got balls!
- Here we are!
Who'd have ever thought that in a
few days one of us...
.. was to get married?
Our seemingly endless way of life
was to be changed,...
.. as our friendship and youth
would be.
Come!
Come on, Marcello,
we 'll all get drowned!
Hey, sirens! Let's go!
And we, the sons that were,
we drank, drank...
Hey, help, they're stealing my
underwear!
- Help!
- Hey!
Hey, you! Hey!
Franco? Hey, Franco!
Hey, guys, Franco can't make it out.
Franco! Franco!
- Imbecile! - Stupid
- Look at what he does!
Moron!
This water gets you drunk!
- Ah, how I'd like getting married!
- Shut up, suckling!
We're drunk again!
"Guido, I'd wish that you, Lapo and I
were bewitched away... "
".. and put in a vessel
that all winds... "
Long live freedom! Ole!
I'm going up!
Up and up!
Hey, guys, I'm flying!
Good evening, good...
I don't want to sing anymore!
- You don't want to sing? Hey?
Answer! - No.
- You're crying because they've taken
your underwear? - No, no.
- I know why you're crying.
- Why?
- Because I went with Maria on Sunday.
- No.
In fact, I took Maria away from you on
Sunday, as I did with all the others.
Ah, yes? And then,
why are you crying?
Boh, how should I know?
Here, put this on.
You are for me...
Oh, hear the music?
Antonio, the music!
.. the fairest in the world,
and a deep love...
.. ties me to you!
Antonio, the music! Let's go!
A sweet babe to me you are,
heavenly spring...
- Hi, guys!
- Hi! - Hi.
.. for the sake of my love!
- No, no, wait, wait!
Guys, where're you going? - Home.
- No, let's have a drink at Dente.
- It's closed now.
- We'll drag him out of bed. - But we
haven't got any money. - I'm paying.
- I'll buy you all one. - If he's paying,
then fine! - Lucky me!
Hey, wake up inside!
- Hey, Dente!
- Dente!
- Is Dente at home? - He's sleeping. - Hey,
guys, let's drag him out of bed.
- Hey, Dente, wake up! - What happened?
- What is it?
- We want an omelette.
- With how many eggs? - 100 eggs!
Music!
Let's show them how you
dance merengue.
- We're on Biscione street.
- Guys, shall we go once again?
- Come on!
- Let's go!
Roars the lion!
Come on, guys!
- Ma'am! - Ma'am!
- Here we are! - Open up!
- Ma'am, we want to talk to you!
- Just a sec!
What do you want? Go away!
Want to wake-up the whole street?
Go away! Go away!
Go back to bed, snotties!
Snotties!
Down with women!
We don't give a damn!
- Happy you, Donatella, getting
married. - Careful! - Are you crazy?
Donatella, how do you feel?
Happy, Lauretta.
So happy I could die!
Wow! You've even got a transparent
nightgown, Donatella!
- Have you seen? - When will it
happen to me also? - Boh!
I'll help you with the panties.
- That'll make me the first of your
friends to get married. - She promissed me.
Moron! You'll die an old maid.
Come on, don't fiddle, it's late!
I've chosen you two to make Donatella's
wedding night bed.
Let's go, come with me.
- Donatella, we're off making your
bed, understand? -Let's go, Ornella.
Poor mother. She thinks Ornella and
Laura have never kissed a man.
- Say, do you know how to make a bed?
- You'll see what a mess!
How'd you like your husband?
Catch it.
Cute, like Franco?
Serious, like Marcello?
Intelligent, like Antonio?
Or handsome, like Ettore?
Handsome, like Ettore.
Just imagine what a couple I and Ettore
would make!
- It's late, we have to go.
- Yes, let's hurry up.
Congratulations to
the married couple!
- Here she is... our baby.
- Baby my foot!
We, the Marchetti, at 23 years
we're full-fledged men.
I'm not serene, I'm not.
It's like I was afraid.
- Afraid of what? - He's not like you,
nor is he like your father.
We've always spoilt him,
we've given him everything.
He knows nothing about life,
he's always been pampered.
Words! The chip doesn't fall far.
But he's so young,
so unprepaired.
It feels like it's only yesterday that
I baptized you.
Say, Big Eyes,
would you be scared?
I would.
I wouldn't.
Franco Marchetti, will you take Donatella
Nicolai for your lawful wedded wife...
.. according to the rite of our
Holy Mother, the Catholic Church?
Yes.
Bye!
Goodbye!
- Goodbye to all of you, guys.
- Goodbye.
- Are you nervous?
- A little. How time flies by!
- She duped him. Think they'll be happy?
- Yes.
- Are you going straight home? - Yes.
- We're in the mood for some fun!
- Honey! - Happy you. Bye.
Let's go. - Bye.
- Can you imagine Franco tonight?
- Sst! You don't say that.
He'll have to tell us everything when
he gets back!
Franco's honeymoon was an unusually
long one.
In the meantime we indulged in our
favorite hobby: women.
I'm ready.
It was a Sunday, and my brother
Giulio seemed kind of strange to me.
There was something hatching in his
body for a long time.
It looked like if he was not getting
ready for the Mass, but for the Quirinale.
What are you waiting for
to get dressed?
- Antonio.
- Stop it!
- Say, whose is that shirt?
- Yours. - Take it off right now. - No.
- Come, get the shirt off.
- I can't, I need it today.
Listen, when will you stop from getting
under my feet?
When is it going to get into your skull
that you must do what I tell you to? Well?
- Come, take the shirt off.
- No! - Come on!
It's useless, I've got to
speak to Laura today.
Day-dreamer.
What do you think,
are plans useful?
- Not to me, I'm too candid.
- Only men are always good at it.
These scoundrels...
Anyway, when he comes,
I won't even look at him.
As if he doesn't even exist.
You'll tell me everything he does:
where he sits, who's he looking at...
- And then nothing, I just follow the Mass.
- And then?
Then, at the Club it's a different story.
I'll drink two Martinis and...
- What will you do?
- I think I'll slap him.
What has he got that you like
him so much?
He's handsome... he's handsome.
Here he is,
this Apollo del Belvedere..
Have a good Sunday.
- Ettore.
- Hi.
I've found a job. A great one,
it's almost for sure.
- Work is exhausting. - It's the
most beautiful thing in the world.
- Hi, Marcello.
- Hi, Laura.
Do you see these ones here? Ready to fall
into your lap like pears.
It's too easy, I'm bored with it.
If I may. Sorry.
Hi.
- Hi, Laura.
- Ssst!
Who's the one in the back?
Didn't you say you were bored?
- Good morning.
- Hi.
Antonio, you know the job at Montecatini?
Well, it's mine.
Ah, at last. Now you'll be pleased.
I'm happy for you.
Hi.
What's on?
You know what I say to you?
Deep down, Ornella is nice.
Ite, missa est.
- We, men, are blind. - You want charity?
- No, I'm not joking, Ornella.
Then it's even worse,
I should be careful.
You know I'm kind of mad,
don't you?
Well, I set it for myself
to find the ideal woman.
- That's what you tell them all.
- It's true... but where's the pleasure?
There is, there is...
- Hi, Ettore.
- Hi. - Hi, Mariline.
Lucky you who don't like women.
- Hi, Laura.
- Hi. - Hi, Giulio.
Who were those that have
greated Ettore?
- Mh! Sucklings.
- Your school mates?
- Laura, is it me, or we dind't say
hello this morning? - Hi. - Hi.
You've made your mind, finally...
Here we are, granny, let's get down.
- Eh, the billioness has arrived.
- A beauty.
- Who, she, or the car?
- She.
You, guys, go out with us, either
'cause we're rich, or beautiful.
Never for more serious reasons.
You're rich and beautiful
and, still, I had never looked at you.
No, I don't think I'll make it.
Yes, bye. Alright.
Bye, see you later.
Livio, another Martini.
What a life life: Mass and Club,
Club and guesthouse Azzurra.
Always the same muggs.
Always the same words.
And always the same 1,000 lire
in my pockets.
Happy her, coming into the provinces
only three days a year to see her granny.
Is it possible nobody knows her?
- I don't like her.
- You don't understand anything.
- Nothing at all. - Ettore, finish it,
I'm already a little hammered.
- Oh! Giulio, I'm sorry.
- How unlucky.
- I'm going into the garden. Coming?
- Yes.
Another one?
- Little wife?
- Mm... - Eh?
- How many times did you come here
with a girl? - Many.
- And where did you take them?
- Down there, behind the bushes.
- Come.
- You're disgusting!
- Let's go back. I'll go with you.
- Who's keeping you?
I'm begining to think you're
not a man.
- Sometimes... wouldn't you be in
love with me? - Stupid!
- Hi. - Hi.
- Laura, it's late, we have to go.
- Bye, Antonio.
- Bye.
You know, I've slapped him.
And l, I've kissed him.
I will too, I will kiss him!
- I'm begining to like Laura.
- Ornella is sweet, but she's a woman.
- Hey, come on, l'm hungry!
- One sec.
- She's still here.
- Are we going, or what? - Who?
- The daughter of the master of our city.
- Antonio, let's go! - Wait.
- Are you coming, Ettore? - What?
- Aren't we leaving? - See you later.
Alright, we've got it.
- Bye, champ.
- Bye.
- Bye, Ettore.
- Let's go, Mara! It's late.
- Let's stay a little more.
I had only one man in my life,
your grandfather.
You have one at every corner.
- Let those from your ancestors' city
alone. - Grandma, please.
They are stupid.
They only want...
And they're provincial, boring
bourgeois, not countryfolks like us.
Good morning, princess. Remember me?
General Barbieri's son.
Oh yes, it's true.
How much you've grown up...
- How's the general doing? - He's dead,
princess. - Oh... I'm sorry.
Have you met my niece, Mara?
How are you? Alright?
- Aren't you bored here?
- Yes, I am.
No...
- No?
- No.
Alright.
- I find the provinces amusing.
- What do you see in it?
You're all so full of faith,
of ideals...
Cities like ours are the healthy
side of the nation.
- How long will you be staying?
- I'm leaving tomorrow.
I don't believe it.
- Why not? - You've said it,
because you find provinces amusing.
The call of the forest
is too strong.
Waiter? The check, please.
Shall we go, grandmother?
- It was about time.
- What a pity.
I'm paying today.
What shall we do?
Well, I'll see Ornella, I'll break the
engagement, and then we'll be together.
For the rest of our life!
Hey, look! But that's Donatella!
- Franco's back, and didn't call on us?
- Franco! Franco!
Hey, show yourself, honeymoon!
- Hey, spanish cow!
Blue prince! Come down!
- Hi.
- That's how you treat your friends?
- You're a traitor.
- Get down right now.
- Hi, Donatella.
- Madame... - Hi.
He's paying today.
Same old ways, isn't it?
How can you shout like this?
- Franco! - Franco. - It's almost
been a month since we've last met.
You've made such a noise
you've woken the entire palazzo..
- Donatella doesn't like such things.
- Cut it out, hypocrite.
No, I mean it, I really don't like
your tone.
Idiot.
That's how you'll learn not to
forget us.
- When did you get back?
- Two days ago. - Two days?!
I didn't have a free moment.
Franco, come here.
- Tell me, how did it go?
- What?
- Hey, you must tell us everything, but
everything. - Uffa. - How is it? - Uffa!
Ornella told us she had a transparent
nightgown, is it true?
And... was she afraid?
- How was she? - These are things that
don't concern you, alright?
You've pissed me off!
- You'll talk, you'll talk!
- Yes, good night, farewell!
Franco, shall we meet after lunch?
I can't, I have to go with Donatella.
- Then this evening.
- We're having dinner at her parents'.
- See you tomorrow, bye.
- Bye. - Bye.
We should reeducate him.
Do you want to mess with Donatella?
Mind your business!
She's been a petty bourgeois for seven
generations. The perfect wife!
- Franco?
- Yes?
- Have they angered you?
- No. - Cut them loose.
- They think they can play boys for ever.
- They're my friends.
- Friends?
- They're the only friends that I've got.
It's ready, madame.
You can go.
Why not boots also?
I thought it was better to get her used
to it right away. But if it bothers you...
Not for me, for her,
the poor thing.
- What is it?
- Nothing, the salt.
- Adalgisa?
- Have you called for me?
- Could you bring the salt?
- It ain't? Me thought it was.
It doesn't fit!
If you think we've got 72
like this one...
- It's your aunt's gift.
- The salt.
Your grandmother wasn't joking
at all, either.
- Won't you finish that?
- No.
I'm not hungry. All this new stuff
took my appetite away.
It's like being in
a shop-window!
Excuse me.
You think I'm not finding it hard
to get used to it, too?
The nest...
It's as if I still don't matter at all
for you, everything displeases you.
The glass is ugly,
there's no salt...
- Are you through? - Wasn't it good?
- Very good.
Could you please take
your gloves off?
- You don't want them anymore?
Should I take them off? - Yes, it's better.
- Now why are you crying?
- If I cry, it's because I love you.
If I wouldn't be loving you,
you've got no idea how I'd laugh!
Unfortunately, you're right, Franco,
the glasses, Adalgisa's gloves,...
.. let's throw everything,
and have lunch in the town.
- Where you used to go with your friends.
- With my friends? - Yes.
The last night we went at Dente's,
near the river. An enourmous omelette!
I was so drunk that evening, should have
seen me! You wouldn't have married me.
Should have seen Dente's face when we
threw him out of bed.
- Let's go right now! - Is it alright
like this, madame? - Very well.
Let's hope I won't get chilblains.
Two or three weeks went by,
I can't remember exactly how many,
the days went on being
the same for us.
One as hilarious as the next
and full of lightheartedness.
We each followed our love.
- Why are you coming with me?
- To get to know you.
You must have something special,
if they all fall for you.
And now you're curious to find it out?
I've been looking for you for two weeks!
Well, here I am.
It's nice here...
Why don't we go down?
I like countryside so much,
the solitude...
I'm the one who'd like to know you.
Don't you find me a little romantic?
Yes... like all girls.
Of course, like all girls.
I've got nothing special,
I only am very rich.
It's a quality, but it's not
everything.
After all, it's a boring place,
I'm begining to get drowsy!
You're a moron!
No!
Hi, blackbirds!
Who's winning?
Hey, what's the matter with you?
Speak.
- Oh, what's the matter with this one?
- How should I know?
- Giulio!
- Boh! And three!
- Oh, and so what?
- And stop annoying me.
- Stop it!
- If you want to speak, speak, if not...
- I'd like to know what good is being
friends... - That's what I say.
- You're against any temptation...
- Very funny!
And new!
Say, Antonio, you've asked me a short
time ago what good is being friends.
- You should ask this someone else.
- Who?
You know I was sure of having a job,
I was keen on it.
Not so much for me,
as for my father.
Well, they've told me I haven't
got it anymore.
I wanted to know why.
- Franco's taken it away from me.
- Franco?!
- Come, let's go right now to Franco.
Come, Ettore. - Yes, let's go.
- What do you want? - You know it
too well. - You're a swine and a coward.
Come in.
Ettore's right,
you're a swine and a coward.
- You knew what that job meant to
Marcello. - I knew it, and you knew it.
- Donatella's father is the one that
got me the job. - That is a good reason!
Of course, if you see it this way, l
can only look mean.
Donatella wanted me to work.
And this is a reason.
Marcello knows very well that you
can't find a job everyday.
I've looked for one,
but in vain.
Donatella found it for me, and I found
myself facing a done deed.
And I didn't move a finger to
cheat Marcello.
- You should have refused.
- I know it, but I'm married.
A new life has begun for me.
I've got a wife, a house...
and a baby is on it's way.
- It's like hearing my father. - You
don't know how married life changes you.
I've childishly taken on
responsibilities,
and now that I'm facing them I must
show no weakness, or scruples.
You can wait, I can't.
You're playing heroes now,
but our friendship has always been the
only morals in our life.
Cut it out, Antonio.
Cut it out!
Donatella's pregnant,
what should he have done, hit her?
And then, we've all been a little
in love with her...
She has had me,
and not this stupid here.
Let's go, guys.
Bye... heroe.
Bye.
I think you've been too kind, one
must take care of one's interests!
That's what Franco did, and maybe
you'd have also done it.
- It isn't true.
- What a shitty world!
- Women are to blame for everything.
One should never fall in love. - True.
Guys, remember one thing:
"sin is in women's nature,
like drinking and eating".
"There always is something tainted in
their faith."
- It's from Baudelaire.
- You're right.
- And everytime we think we've found
an angel. - What a shitty world.
We should have thousands of women.
Thousands! They're all the same.
- Like those in Biscione street.
- Correct.
I'll get married when I'll use a woman
just for ironinig my shirts.
This is correct, too.
As far as I go, don't worry,
even then I won't marry.
- Bye!
- Bye. - Bye.
And no love!
I've never had a greater disillusion
than this in my whole life.
- Bye, Marcello.
- Bye. - See you later.
And remember: no love.
- Bye, Marcello!
- No love.
If you want...
Ah, thanks.
We're there.
This is where I live.
- So long.
- Give it to me, I want to hold it!
- No, no! - Wait for me!
The days of youth melt away
like snow in the sun.
Even that week flew away.
Franco called all of us, several
times. What were we to do?
Let's make peace.
On the day of the reconcilation
we were all at the club,
only Marcello was missing.
- Guys, Marcello's on the line.
- I'll get it. Let's go, kiddy
Come on, Antonio.
- Who's winning? - Antonio.
- Didn't he dump you?
We're still friends.
And then it seems the fraternity of four
has decided they should become monks.
Can I cut in, then?
- Hey, guys. Marcello's not coming.
- How come?
Confused call.
If you ask me, it's about a woman.
- Are you sure? - Sure? If I don't
smell these things...
- He's voice was trembling.
- He's not a man.
Guys...
Shall we go pick him up?
Sure thing. Let's go.
There are two spots where to fish
out that desertor.
By the walls,
if he has carnal objectives,
or behind Mazzini's monument,
if the chick isn't yet ripe.
There's no way out of here.
- Hi, Ettore. - How's it goin'?
- Fine. - I'm glad.
Sorry!
- Are we going? - I'm not coming.
- And where're you going? - At the cinema.
Now you're going at the cinema,
you're always pestering us,
and when it's about helping a friend,
you get lost.
- Some help... - Let's go. - I don't
feel like it, and that's that. Bye.
- Same slacker as always.
- Come on. - Same as usual.
At last! Is Ettore there?
No. But what are you doing at home?
Why don't you come here?
There's fresh merchandise.
If you'd only see how gorgeous...
What do I care?
And Ettore...?
I've told you,
he went away, he's gone.
- Where?
- Phew, Laura...
How should I know, they were here
and, suddenly, they were gone.
- Hi.
- Hi, sit down.
- Has he asked about me?
- No.
Idiot!
- Ornella, tell me, how was he looking?
- Delicious.
He was wearing a cute
blue jersey. Bye!
What a nuisance!
- Why aren't you with the others?
- Wasn't I supposed to come here?
We have to translate
the sixth chapter from Sallust.
He wasn't wearing the blue jersey.
Comitatus, comitatus... comitatus.
- Comitatus!
- Cut it out, you're annoying me.
- Do you like Sagan? - She's too
pushy. She doesn't know what love is.
Oh, yes? Listen.
"There were times, in his arms, when
shyness follows love,
I wanted to tell him: 'Luca, love me,
let's try. Let's just try'.
But I didn't, and just kissed his
mouth,
his forehead, his eyes... "
- Yes, it's nice.
- Hear this one also.
"Yes, I'm next to Luca,
I'm by his side,
I only have to stretch my hand to
be able to touch him.
I know his body, his voice,
his way of sleeping. "
I think there are sentiments
better kept to oneself.
Not everyone is like you.
And you, do you know what love is?
No.
Then you can't understand what l
feel about Ettore.
If you'd know how bad one feels...
So bad, you want to be dead.
- But, Ettore never speaks about me?
- Yes he does, often.
- Do you think I could make him fall
for me? - He already has.
Since I've slapped him,
the idiot hasn't shown himself.
Will you come with me at the cinema,
afterward?
At the Globo? See the Bergman movie?
- Wherever you want.
Guys, he must be behind the wall.
- Marcello! - Marcellino?
- Show yourself! - Marcello!
- Get out, Casanova!
- Get out!
- Guys, call lieutenant Pizzoglio.
- Quickly! - Lieutenant!
- You took young to searching the bush.
- Yes.
- I've said it, he isn't, it's serious.
- Serious my foot... - Yes, it is.
Charge!
Roars the lion!
It's the first time I've been here,
it's really beautiful.
Where's my home?
There, do you see those two towers
and the big dome?
Well, it's there, in the middle.
And yours?
The same direction, a little further away,
almost in the suburbs.
My family's not rich.
My father is the manager of the asylum
for old people, and makes so little...
Where's the asylum?
Down there, in the back,
behind those gardens.
Your town's so beautiful.
You've been here for two months,
two more, and it will seem
less beautiful.
I think I'll like it even more.
Look at it, it's an italian town,
like there are hundreds more.
Had it's heyday
during Renaissance.
Now, it's very plain.
Families overflow with good
traditions.
And still, it's terrible living
in the provinces.
It's a never ending fight...
against meanness,
slander, hypocrisy...
Everything's wrong...
and everything's for ever.
Why don't you go away, go live
somewhere else?
- Because the lion's here.
- No love! - Hey, Marcello!
- Now it's too much, no? - Marcello,
remember, no love.
- Who are they?
- My friends.
Don't encourage him, miss, look at me,
I've already been fooled.
- No love. - Marriage is the grave of
love and friendship.
Do you know these two almost fought?
For a job!
- Come on, introduce us.
- Come on. - Come on.
- Ettore, Franco, Antonio... Lucia.
And now, goodbye. - What? - What?
Hey, just a sec, we haven't even
shook hands, have we?
- And the lion... it's them? - What
lion, they are four mangy cats.
- Yes, we're the lion.
- We.
Congratulations.
- Can we leave?
- Come on, what's the rush?
- ldiots, Lucia must go back home.
- True? - No.
Then, let's go. And now, she's
compromised.
Tomorrow, as far as the town's concerned,
you'll be my latest conquest.
- There's only one worse than me with women.
- Who? - Marcello.
You wouldn't say, with that face...
That's what you do when one of
you is with a girl?
- Women are common property.
- And if you fall for the same one?
- We pass her.
- Then pass her!
- Come on, don't get mad. A little
spirit won't kill you! - Let me be!
Straighten up you tie.
The hamster.
- So, you aren't saying anything?
- The lion's depressed! - Oh, no! No.
- Go with uncle Marcello, go.
- I don't want him. - Then throw him.
- And... what is your name?
- Lucia. - Ah.
You know, Antonio is a great thinker.
He was writing poetry since a child.
- He wrote for a wonderful girl
who was in love with me. - Ah.
He even wrote for Marcello,
when he took his First Communion.
- Did he also write for your wife?
- No, I wouldn't have allowed him.
- You can't trust him that much,
true, Ettore? - Very true.
- I wanna pee. - Afterward.
- No, now. - Enough, come.
Why don't you tell me the poem you
wrote for Marcello's First Communion?
- I don't remember it. - Not even the
one for Franco's girl? - No.
Come on, improvise.
"Oh, love, listen to your
sweatheart's tale.
A man pain will suffer,
when friends abbandon him...
Because he will then now
men are infidel. "
- Do you know this poem?
- Yes.
- Hey, Marcello, they're talking poetry!
- Go to hell.
Shame!
What way of talking is this?
Excuse him. Let's go.
- I wanna pee.
- Afterward I said. - When?
Do you see him? He always is like this:
sad, melancholic, boring... and vulgar.
- And what else?
- He hasn't stolen... yet.
Once arrived here, we go back.
What a life!
I'd have rather let myself be killed
than admit it,
but, for the first time in my life,
when with Lucia,
I understood l had lost my head.
- I want the donkey. - Cut it out.
- I want the donkey! - Let's go.
- Then let me pee.
- No, move on.
In fact, we had decided
to save Marcello.
We had met at the Club,
made a plan,
the usual one:
take away the girl.
I knew it'd come down to me.
Franco was married, and Ettore was
seeing a mysterious girl.
It was only me remaining to save
him from Lucia.
I let the others do everything;
my conscience was clear.
- Hi, Lucia.
- Hi.
You know?
It's the third day...
It's the third day I've been
loving you.
I've rediscovered the world,
and I find it wonderful.
Even this sham of a city seems
different.
What I've told you the other day
were bollocks.
I love it's streets,
it's palaces, everything.
The falsity of it's people,
the "Good evening, lawyer"...
The evenings at the cinema
and the keys under the door.
You know something? It's not true that
when in love you care less your friends.
You love them more.
I've forgiven them immediately
their behaviour from the other night.
Remember? When they
tried to separate us.
Especially Antonio,
because he is...
Where are we going? Tell me.
- I can't stay with you. - If you have
to go some place, I'll go with you.
No, Marcello, I'd rather go alone.
- Have you got a date?
- Yes.
- Do I know him?
- It's Antonio.
- Where's the date?
- At the promenade roundabout.
Can I go with you a little?
It seemed too good you'd come.
I had strong forebodings.
- And if I hadn't?
- I even hoped it, for a moment.
But now you're here,
and I'm lost.
On the other hand, I ask myself why
I did come to you.
Because I like you.
That's something I say to all girls.
And have you never found one you
really liked?
We have our fill with Elenas, Marys,
Luisas here...
One no different from the other.
Like they had branded on their forehead:
"I'm a good family bore".
- And l, am I not like the others?
- No.
- I'm looking for the ideal woman.
- Does she exist? - Yes.
She's the most beautiful girl,
subtle, and like transparent.
Two eyes like those of a little animal,
high cheekbones,
softness in all features,
and she likes poets.
No, my father is the one
who likes them.
Shall we walk?
- There's where you go to make love?
- Let's turn back.
No, no, let's go all the same.
What good is it, Lucia?
What good is it?
We can try.
- I know what I feel, I don't need
any proofs. - And what about me?
Does Marcello also come here?
- How old are you, Lucia?
- Twenty, in ten days.
Will I be enough of a friend,
in ten days,
so to make the present I'm giving
you acceptable?
Sometimes a kiss is enough
to become friends.
No love...
I don't want to stay,
Antonio, sorry.
I didn't understand why she had come,
nor why she had left.
But it was a very simple thing:
it was Marcello she loved, not me.
Can I have a smoke?
Let's go back.
You've got a date with one
of your girls?
What do you think, I've put on
a chastity belt?
Everytime I came back from one of our
dates, I went with another girl.
- Shall we go back?
- Our date isn't over yet.
I must go back to the Club,
I've got friends waiting for me there.
They're right:
what little good life my have in store,
it comes from our friendship.
It's me that's mad.
Do you want to drive?
Console yourself, if you've had enough
of being with me,
I was just going to tell you:
I'm leaving tomorrow.
Quite sudden.
In this boring town of yours I had
never stopped for more than a day,
and now, it's been two months
I've been here.
Don't you think it's enough?
- Where are you going? - Rome, first,
to say hello to my father, then lschia.
- And then?
- Then? I don't know.
Cannes, maybe,
or even Saint Tropez.
Even if it's off-season,
it's still nice.
- When shall you be back? - In one year.
Seeing grandma, if she'll still be around.
- Weren't you in a hurry?
- Not anymore.
- And your friends?
- I don't care.
Shall we get down?
No, here, in your car.
How beautiful Lucia was on the
day of her engagement.
The pure and spiritual beauty
I had always dreamt at.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations, Lucia.
- Thank you, Giulio.
How happy I am!
She's nice Lucia, isn't she?
But I assure you, I'll also be cute
as a fiancee.
- lmagine what a couple we'd make.
- You're stupid! Stupid and frivolous!
- Yes... Yes, I know it, I'm not
the ideal woman. - Leave me alone!
Ornella!
Give me a Martini.
Go, go! Go gossip.
We're inconstant and frivolous,
aren't we, Laura?
- Ornella, can you do me a favour?
- Two, even.
Please, go to Ettore and tell him I'll
be waiting in the garden.
Poor Laura... even you...
- Ettore? - Eh?
- Ettore... - Say.
If you can guess who's waiting for you
in the garden, I'll give you a kiss.
A flower.
Can I have a smoke?
- Where are you going?
- Eh? Where could I go?
- I want to speak to you.
- Right now? What do you want?
Alright... Tomorrow.
Giulio, I've understood what you wanted
to tell me. Laura, eh?
Go ahead, I don't care!
You wanna know something?
You'll be the first to find out.
I'm marrying Mara.
I'm marrying a billion.
- Hi, Laura.
- Who knows what you'll think of me.
- I'm so ashamed!
- If it's because of this, I'm used.
But I love you more
than the others.
But you don't even know me.
We've barely met.
Say... how do you think I am?
- Handsome, inside out.
- You're wrong.
From all the boys you know,
I'm the worst.
I can't love.
Because you haven't found the one
that really loves you.
Imagine finding a woman capable of
love. True, Laura?
I am.
- You're a little girl.
- No, it's not true.
And I've been loving you for more than
a year... and you know it.
Kiss me here, then, where you've
slapped me before.
What a pity.. It's I that should
have known you better.
There's still time.
No.
- Bye, guys!
- Bye.
- Going away?
- Mm? - Shall I walk you? - Yes.
No!
I don't want to go back home.
Can you walk with me a little?
- Where?
- Wherever.
- You're happy tonight. Why?
- You're happy, too. - Yes.
- Do you think I'd make a good wife?
- Eh, depends who you'll marry.
- I know who I'll marry, do you?
- I know who I love.
- What's the difference?
- Well...
I, for one, could be with a man I loved
even... without being married.
No, I couldn't.
Sometimes I've thought about getting
married, having children,
playing, wrestling with them...
- And if they were girls?
- Well, I'd be jealous.
- Do you want to know something?
- Tell me.
- I've never been with a woman.
- Never?
No, never.
Why?
Because I only love one.
Have you heard about Marcello?
- What? - He's leaving. Says he'll
have a job in Milan and he's going.
Where were you when he said that?
In the garden.
- How stupid!
- Who, Ettore?
No, no... I'm not talking about Ettore,
I'm talking about Marcello.
He only got engaged,
and he leaves her.
And you saying he was
so much in love...
- Would you have done it?
- Yes.
- And then you talk about love!
- It's just because I'm in love!
You can't even imagine the suffering
Marcello goes through.
He was on the point of leaving thousand
of times... before knowing Lucia.
And yet, he stayed. It was great staying
here, in our town.
With the girls, with his friends...
Now, that he's known Lucia,
the biggest happiness for him would
be... staying.
He's leaving because he loves her,
he wants to marry her,
he wants her for life.
Will you take me home,
Big Eyes?
Few months afterward,
Ettore got married.
How Laura cried that morning...
- If I'd be Laura, I'd kill myself.
- I'd kill him.
I prefer suicide to crimes.
The next day, everything's in the news.
- I'm going to pick Laura up, see you
in church. - So long, big mouth.
- Are you ready, Laura?
- Yes, one moment.
Hi. Laura, we're here.
Poor Laura... Courage.
After all, if he doesn't want you,
he doesn't deserve you.
I've got courage, don't you worry.
They say it'll be the most beautiful
marriage of the last ten years,
there will be important people from the
region, maybe even Maria Pia di Savoia.
They say Mara has a dream dress.
I can't take it anymore, I can't!
Well, you shouldn't give him this
satisfaction.
- When the "yes" will be said...
- What will you do, Laura?
When I'll hear him say "yes",
I'll faint, I'm sure.
- And then I'll start yelling,
yelling, yelling! - Swear it!
Watch Laura.
- What do you think she'll do?
- Mah...
Ettore Graziani, will you take Mara Rossi
Bandelli for your lawful wedded wife...
.. according to the rite of our
Holy Mother, the Catholic Church?
Yes.
Mara Rossi Bandelli, will you take Ettore
Graziani for your lawful wedded husband...
.. according to the rite of our
Holy Mother, the Catholic Church?
Yes.
Nothing... nothing at all.
Hi.
Don't move!
Another one, one second.
Done, thank you.
- Hi.
- Hi. - Hi. - Nice party.
Hi, Giulio. We hadn't said hi yet.
Hi, Laura.
- Could you bring me an orange juice?
- Yes.
- Laura? May l...
- Please. - Please.
- How do you feel, Laura?
- Alright.
- Long live the bride and groom.
- Long live. - Here it is.
Congratulations.
- All you've got to do now, is wait for
granny's funeral. - Shut up.
You don't want?
Know what's being said? That the bride's
already expecting the heir.
- Damn it, that Ettore!
- Here. - Thanks.
Well, I'll mingle for some news.
- You don't drink Martinis anymore?
- No, I feel like orange juice.
Nice wedding, isn't it?
Everybody's looking at you.
I was looking for you, Giulio.
I want to talk to you.
It was very strange.
You know, like when having a
nightmare,
and then you realise it was only
a dream.
Why tell me this?
Why not? Whom should I tell it to?
You don't tell such things to someone
who has never existed.
You exist, Giulio. You exist!
Like an idiot until now.
Don't regret it, we've always been
together, haven't we?
Sure, we've translated
Sallust together.
But I was alone,
alone like a dog.
But about Ettore! Why didn't you
never warn me about Ettore?
Why didn't you tell me he was cynical,
a liar, one who didn't believe in anything?
- It was my fault, I didn't know how
to behave like a man. - Giulio!
- Let's hope he won't ressemble you.
- Better like us, than like you.
Enjoy life while you still can.
This is nothing. Hear him at night...
It's them that are
in a so damn hurry.
That's how, inevitably, our life
went on, changing.
We were not boys anymore.
Franco had already had his first son,
Ettore was married, Marcello was leaving.
For Giulio and Laura after so many
clouded days and thunderstorms...
.. clear skies seemed to be
at the horizon.
On went life,
and love was it's name.
Livio, another bottle of cognac!
Finished the baptism,
Lucia and Laura had gone home.
No use mentioning Donatella.
So, we were left alone, the whole evening
ahead of us, like in the old good times.
The lion had awaken.
- Guys, I want to have fun, I won't go
home tonight. - Neither shall I.
We don't care a damn about anything.
- Come on boys, let's go!
- Hey!
- Franco! - Franco!
- Let's go!
- Wait, Franco!
- Hey!
- Put it on my tab!
- Franco! Franco! Wait!
- Come here!
- Me? - Guendalina!
- Here she is. Our turkish woman.
- I'm not Guendalina.
- Come closer.
- What do you want?
- Let's see the thighs
- Ah, you're in such a hurry!
- Alright, come on... - Ah...
Know what we say: go to sleep!
Scoundrels! Criminals!
Criminals, I know you!
- Come on. Let's go.
- Stop! - We've arrived.
Come on, cowards!
Let's see who jumps first.
- Let's get down!
- Get down, get down.
- Come, come, Marcello!
Marcello! - Go, go!
- Giulio, test the water.
- Right now, go.
- How is it? - Warm.
- Fine. You try it, Franco. - Yes.
- Eh?
- It's warm!
- Hey!
- Ah, let's take a nice bath!
- Hey, sirens!
- How is it? - It's cold!
It's the end of the world.
Hey, scoundrels,
give me a drink!
We are here, having fun,
and my son might have a fever,
or mumps...
Cut it out!
Give me a drink,
scoundrels!
Giulio? Where's Giulio?
"How beautiful is tender youth,
no man can stop her fly,
Be merry who so wish,
tomorrow nothing's sure. "
Giulio, bring me a bottle of
Chavlet '27.
- Did you bring it?
- Here it is, sir!
And now, a souffle al Grand Marnier,
.. and chocolate and strawberries
profiteroles.
- Have you brought them?
- At your service.
- I can't kick my arse anymore.
- You must climb the tree.
Opla! Always higher!
Hey, look at me.
You, who are in love and happy, say,
why do we always end up drunk?
How should I know?
Oh God, the mumps...
Who invented mumps?
- Why do women always fall for the good
guys? - I don't know.
Why are we here?
I'm here while my son's sick.
I can't hear my son cry...
I can't hear my son cry!
- Cut it out, Franco.
- But my son's sick!
Giulio, bring me blond virginian tobacco,
with honey.
- Have you?
- Yes.
And now, a bottle of Scotch,
I'll get drunk as a pig.
- Have you?
- Yes.
And now, bring me...
.. bring me Laura.
- "You, happy and in-love... "
- Cut it out!
No, I won't, you must answer me.
Are you happy I don't cry?
I'm not taking your girls away anymore.
- Cut it out, cut it out.
- No, we have to speak.
About what?
True.
The omelette! Let's go to Dente
and eat an omlette! Let's go!
- You're not drunk.
- No.
- You knew I had to go to work in
Milan, didn't you? - Yes.
I've received the cable.
Don't tell the others...
I'm leaving tomorrow.
It's closed, there isn't
a restaurant anymore.
- And Dente?
- He's dead.
Let's go, suckers,
I'll take you to town.
- What's the matter? - I feel ill.
- Stop, stop! Giulio's sick.
- Ettore, stop!
- He can puke, I don't care.
- I'll take the red-haired!
- And I the frenchie.
- Hey aren't you coming?
- Go ahead, I'll catch up.
Let's go! Giulio...
Cuckold, you're a a cuckold.
No, Giulio is not coming.
Giulio's going home.
She loves me... She loves me!
And I'll marry her!
Hey, you didn't forget!
Yes! What a beautiful car, it seems
a bedroom.
- Come, get in. Happines is here tonight.
- Yes!
- And Giulio? - He must have gone.
- Why didn't you stay with him?
- He did well to go.
- Why don't you also go?
Take your hands off.
- You disgust me!
- What have I done to you?
You have.
Where's your conscience?
You've left it at home,
with your wife?
You've always been Don Pizzuto's
favorite cleric, haven't you?
- Yes, but Mara's at home and you're
fooling with these... - Cut it out!
Why, what are you?
Why should shit like this happen to us?
I want to go back!
Shut up!
- What do we do afterward?
- How should I know? - Eh? - Don't know.
I was really hungry.
It ain't that good this mortadella,
is it?
- Do you have a kid?
- Hey, change the music!
You have.
Alright, I have.
Carmelo, put another record.
- Who takes this one? - You! You!
What do I care?
- Let's not start it all over!
- ldiot! What do you want to do?
- I don't need these!
- Then go!
We're disgusting.
- I'm going.
- Hey, blondie! - Farewell, friends.
Why, isn't she a girl like
any other?
You're drunk.
What do you think,
that Lucia's better than her?
You've said at last, what was on your
mind. You're jealous, that's it!
Since Lucia loves me,
you hate me.
- Get lost.
- Stay calm! - Hey!
It's always like this
when you go together?!
- Cut it!
- Don't mess with me!
Go to hell! Drop dead!
Dead!
- Are you late?
- If only you'd lose this train.
Sst... Don't say anything,
it's useless now.
I'm sorry. But how could l...?
And me? I can't conceive being
far away from you!
Here it is!
Milan is a big city,
you'll have fun.
And then, there's your work...
But I, alone, here...
What did you promise me?
Not to cry,
'cause you're not going to war.
Bye, fatty!
- Who was that?
- A ghost.
- Who knows how many ghosts dwell
on these streets. - Are you jealous?
Yes... and most of all
on Antonio and all the others,
all those that have seen you since
you were a little boy...
I was a fool, like now.
Damn! How many matches they'll
play without me!
I beat them all,
I was the strongest.
And they're still sleeping.
They were dead drunk
yesterday night.
If I only could give you something
in exchange for your love.
What are we hoping for?
One of those engagements
that go on for years and years,
Like those of our grandparents?
Some luck you had meeting me.
I'm happy like this.
We did so many things together,
I and my friends.
The entire city was ours.
Antonio was right with that poetry
of yours:
"Oh, love, listen to your
sweatheart's tale,
A man pain will suffer,
when friends abbandon him".
Why are you saying this?
You'll soon be back, and see them again.
Yes. But for now everything's over,
and we haven't even said farewell.