Come on. Come on.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Hurry up.
- How do you do, Mrs. Doray?
- How do you do, Judge Blake?
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
What can I do for you?
Well, I have to read a paper
on the juvenile court at-
at the next meeting
of our women's club...
and I thought perhaps you would be kind enough
to give me the information that I need.
- I'll be glad to help you all I can.
- Thank you
Why don't you sit with me this morning
and watch what happens?
- Could I?
- I wish you would.
I like to encourage interest
in the juvenile court.
It's more important
than most people realize.
You see, I know all about
every boy before he faces me-
mentally, morally and physically.
George, if I were sittin' over there
and you were sittin' here...
what would you do
with a fella like yourself?
- I'd like another chance.
- Sure you would That's what they all want.
In the past, your chances
have all been your own way.
This time it's gonna be my way.
I'm gonna give you a chance
to work hard, to study, to make good.
I'm gonna commit you to the state school.
Stop crying-
You're not crying because
you're sorry for what you've done.
You're crying because
you're sorry for yourself.
Get the right slant on things.
Forget what's happened
and go up to the state school...
with the right attitude
and make good.
Hold up your head.
And look the world
straight in the eye.
Will you do it?
Yes, sir.
Now this young lad
is above average mentality...
comes from honest,
hardworking people...
but for some reason
insists on running away.
Freddie, from the number of times
you've been running away lately...
it seems as if you want to be
a traveling salesman.
Is that it?
Seven times in one month.
That's a lot of times for one boy
to run away from home.
- What's the matter, don't you like your home?
- Yes, sir.
- Are you the boy's father?
Just can't seem to keep this youngster
of yours at home, is that it?
Judge, I've done everything but tie him,
but it doesn't seem to do any good.
Freddie, you got me
wondering about you.
I like to find out about boys.
Do you want to tell me just why
you keep running away from home?
You don't have to tell me
if you don't want to, but I'd like to know.
I want to see my mother.
Why can't Freddie see his mother?
Well, Judge, I-I kind of
thought you knew about that.
It's pretty hard to explain to a boy
why he can't see his mother.
- Freddie, you know your mother's
been sick, don't you? - Yes, sir.
Well, she's just been too
sick to have any visitors.
That's why you haven't
been able to see her.
But if I promise you that just as soon as
she's well enough you can see her again...
will you promise me that you won't
run away from home anymore?
Yes, sir.
All right, now go on home with your father,
and remember your promise.
Yes, sir. And-
And you'll remember yours,
won't you?
- Washington Lincoln Jackson.
- Yes, sir.
Have you ever been here before?
No, sir. And I wouldn't be here now
'“lessin“' I was forced to come.
I suppose you know why
Officer Weems arrested you.
Yes, sir. Because
I was the smallest kid he could catch.
Well, you're charged with stealing
Simon Bittke's vegetable wagon.
Are you guilty or not guilty?
What else has you, judge?
Did you take the wagon
or didn't you?
Oh, the wagon.
Oh, you mean the wagon.
The wagon. Oh, yeah.
Is Mr. Bittke here?
No, Your Honor. His horse was sick today
and he had to take him to the doctor.
What were the circumstances
of the arrest, Officer?
Well, Judge, uh, Bittke come up to me
a-hollerin' and a-pointin'...
and I seen this kid here driving his wagon off
with a lot of the other boys, sol chased 'em.
The, uh-
other kids got away,
and I arrested this one.
Were you trying to steal
Mr. Bittke's vegetables, Washington?
Oh, no, sir. I just wanted to drive
a horse, that's all.
- Oh. So you just wanted to go for a ride?
- Yes, sir.
Washington, I'm gonna let you go...
but I want you to promise me never to
take anything that doesn't belong to you.
And I don't want to ever see you
in this courtroom again.
How come, judge?
You gonna quit?
- Well, Sam, how you feeling?
- Just dandy, Judge. And you?
Fine. Fine.
Don't know what to do with you.
- Your hometown won't take you back.
- Is that so?
- No. Neither your mother nor your
father want you. - They wouldn't.
I have to hold your case over for a week
and see what we can do.
You go back to juvenile hall, Sam.
Okay Judge-
That boy has a fine face.
He's one of the worst boys
I've ever handled.
He's a gang leader, a daring thief
and very, very tough.
If he isn't restrained, he may develop
into a dangerous criminal.
Well, he certainly doesn't look it.
We find that most juvenile delinquents
come from broken homes.
- You mean divorced people?
- Yes. Divorces. Separations.
Or many times where
one of the parents is dead...
and the other one
has to earn a living.
In that case, the child is
deprived of a normal home life.
Now, take this next case-
an orphan living with a poor family.
He hasn't got into any serious trouble yet,
but he may be headed for it.
- Arthur Simpson.
- Yes, sir.
- Art, looks like you're in trouble.
What about this boy, Officer?
Well, Your Honor...
this Art Simpson has got the reputation
of being the worst boy in town.
Never mind that.
Why'd you arrest him?
Well, he took a car belonging
to Mrs. Ramsay for a joyride.
- How about it, Art? That right?
- No, sir.
But you did take the car,
didn't you?
No, sir. I just moved it
away from a fireplug.
The car was found
four blocks away, Your Honor.
Seems to me you moved that
car quite a distance, Art.
Well, it's kind of hard
to find a place to park these days.
The law says it's a crime to drive a car that
doesn't belong to you without permission.
- Did you know that?
- No, sir.
Well, remember the next time you see a car
parked by a fireplug. You can go now.
Don't let me ever see you
in this courtroom again.
Case dismissed.
Court's adjourned for an hour.
A few years ago, boys like that
were committed to institutions.
Few people realize
that in courts like this...
lies the solution to
our entire crime problem...
and that results are had through correction
and adjustment rather than punishment.
- That's wonderful.
- Young America.
Boys from all walks of life.
Young America at the crossroads.
All we can do is to try to set their feet
on the right road.
If you could pick one of these
boys at random-any one of them-
and follow him to his home
and observe his daily life...
you'd learn a great deal more
about this problem.
Where'd you get the car?
Oh, it was parked by a fireplug and I didn't
want the lady to get a ticket, sol moved it.
More darn fireplugs in this town.
Yeah. What you doing?
- Another invention?
- This here's a scientific experiment.
Yeah, I guess so.
Sure it is. I'm hypnotizing
these chickens.
Hypnotizing them?
Does it hurt 'em?
- Nah.
- Will they stay like that?
Sure, till I unhypnotize them.
- How do you do that?
- I ain't figured that out yet.
Wouldn't it be funny if you
could hypnotize people like that?
- Boy, wouldn't we have fun.
- Yeah.
Art!
- What are you doing with my chickens?
- I didn't do anything to them!
- I caught you dead to rights this time.
- I tell you I didn't do any-
I'm gonna take you
down to the police station right now!
Confound you, Art Simpson!
You're the worst boy in this town!
Thank you. Why, that was
a very brave thing for you to do.
You might have been hurt.
- You're-You're Arthur Simpson, aren't you?
- Yes, ma'am.
- What's the matter, Edie? - Well, this boy just
saved Sandy from being run over by a truck.
Oh, much obliged.
- Oh, that's all right, Mr. Doray.
- No more chocolate sodas.
Oh, Arthur!
Wait there a minute, please.
Jack, you need a boy here
at the store.
- Why not give the job to Arthur?
- Oh, now listen, Edie.
Oh, please. I-I know
he needs the work.
And besides, I have a particular reason
for wanting to help him.
Do you know that he's supposed to be
the worst kid in town?
- I don't believe it.
- Well, he's no rose geranium.
Oh, please Jack.
For me.
All right. But you're gonna find out
that I knew what I was talking about.
Hey, come here.
- Do you want a job?
- Yes, sir.
All right, be here tomorrow afternoon
right after school. Six bucks a week.
- Yes, sir.
- 3:30 at the latest.
Yes, sir.
Thanks, Mrs. Doray.
I give him the job,
and he thanks you.
Look at that old Clarence Paine.
- Every morning he walks to
school with Lily Schmidt. - Yeah.
- Always hanging around girls. Guys
like him make me sick. - Me too.
- Any guy that walks to school with a
girl is a big sissy. - I'll say so.
- Hmm. You don't see us walking with any girls.
- I should say not.
Of course, if, uh, two guys walk to school
with a girl it's different, ain't it?
I suppose so.
- Hello, cutie. Want me to carry your books?
- No, I don't.
Ah, come on. Don't be like that.
Nobody'll like ya.
Say, who is that fresh guy?
Why, that's Bull Butler.
He just got transferred here
from the southside.
I heard he licked every kid there.
I don't care who he is.
He's not gonna get fresh with Mabel.
So you're gonna red apple me, huh?
You let my apple alone,
you big old thing, you.
- Were you looking for me, Mabel?
- Yes, I was, Art.
I want you to walk
to school with me.
Hey, wait a minute.
Don't get funny, shrimp.
You want to make
something big out of it?
Well, well, well, well.
Tough guy.
Battling Kid Four-eyes.
Don't you call me four-eyes.
Ah.
Now what are you gonna see with?
Give me my glasses.
Four-eyes!
Hey, wait a minute!
I'm gonna tell you just one thing.
Nutty doesn't like to be
kidded about his weak eyes.
And if you do it again,
I'm gonna knock the stuff in' out of you.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
No matter where we are
or what we're doing...
if you call him Four-eyes again,
I'm gonna poke you good.
- Why don't you start in now?
- All right.
Well, come on.
- I'll wait for you after school.
- Okay.
Four-eyes. Four-eyes.
Four-eyes.
Hey! You lay off of me, will ya?
- I told you I'd do it!
- Artl Art!
Arthur Simpson!
Arthur Simpson, how dare you!
I told him I'd do it, the big bully.
- I didn't do nothin', Teacher.
- You big liar.
That will do.
Come with me, Arthur.
- Don't forget about after school either.
- All right. That's enough now.
Now I'll appoint Clarence Paine
class monitor until I return.
And mind you,
no noise and no talking.
Yes, Teacher.
Children, hush! I'll report
everyone that talks.
Children, who did that?
Come, come. Who did it?
You'll be suspended for this.
- Come on! Come on!
- Give it to him!
Come on! Come on!
- Come on, get up! Get up!
- Guess I beat him there, boy.
- Get up. Art! Get up!
- Get up!
Come on, get up!
Get up! Come on, get up!
Go on, you big bully.
Always fightin' somebody who's smaller.
Three, six, nine, the fight's mine.
I can lick you any old time.
- Oh, yeah?
- Ah, you big bully.
- That's a good fight.
- Good fight.
- Are you hurt, Art?
- No. That guy don't know how to fight.
Gee. I guess I'll have to
go to work now.
- So long, Nutty.
- So long.
- Hello, Mr. Doray.
- Where you goin'?
You told me to come to work
after school, didn't ya?
Yeah, I told you to come after school.
That's half past 3:00, isn't it? Not 4:00.
All right, you don't have to come to
work now. You can go home.
You're through before you start.
- I'm awful sorry.
- Are you? I'm not.
Oh, hello, Art.
- Hello, Mrs. Beamish.
- Come in.
Come-Why, what's the matter?
- Been fighting again?
- Yes, ma'am.
I got suspended
from school today too.
Oh, now that's a shame.
What happened?
I'd rather Nutty-
I mean, Edward would tell you.
- Is he suspended too?
- No. just me.
Well, well. Never mind, Art.
It'll come out all right.
They got a lot to do putting you
out of school. The idea.
Don't you worry.
Gee. You're the only one
don't pick on me.
Everyone else thinks
I'm the worst kid in town.
Nonsense!
You're not bad at all.
There's a lot of mischief in you-
and deviltry too-but no real badness.
Wonder why a lot of people
always pick on kids?
- A lot of folks think that boys are
just small men, but... What are they?
Sometimes I think they're angels...
and sometimes I think they're devils.
- But whatever they are, I love 'em.
- Gee, you're swell, Mrs. Beamish.
So are you, Mr. Simpson.
Why don't you call me Granny
like Edward does?
- Gee, can I?
- If you don't, you'll hurt my feelings.
All right, Granny.
- Hi.
- What are you making?
- Apple turnovers.
- Oh, boy. - And you'd better eat
your fill of them this time.
There won't be any more till
my next pension check comes.
Say, wait a minute.
I just got an idea.
Supposin' you put popcorn in the dough,
then you put them in the oven.
The heat pops the corn,
they turn over by themselves.
Now I've got an idea.
Suppose you go out
and get me some wood in.
Okay, Granny.
Practically done.
Did you tell her yet?
- I told her I was suspended, but you can
tell her why. - Why didn't you tell her?
Oh, sound like I was trying to
make a big guy of myself.
- Baloney.
- Hooey.
- Well, thanks for stopping that
Bull Butler for me. - Oh, shut up.
- You been home yet?
- Not yet.
- She'll give you the dickens, I bet.
- I'm used to it now.
- What are you gonna do? - Guess I'd better
go home and get it over with. So long.
So long.
Oh, Mama, he's got my candy.
Let your sister alone.
Hurry up, Betty.
Hello, Aunt Mary.
Is there something you want me to do?
Oh, there you are.
You never forget to come home
in time to eat, do you?
Running the streets all afternoon...
when you could have been here
helping me with the wash.
No, there's nothing you can do now
except get out of my way.
Ma, he got put out of school today.
What's that?
- You did?
- Yessum. But I was gonna tell ya.
More disgrace.
More trouble.
You worthless,
good-for-nothing brat.
If you weren't
my poor sister's kid...
you'd been out
in the streets long ago.
- Please, Aunt Mary, let me tell you how-
- Tell nothing!
You got put out of school and I'm gonna
give you a lashing you'll never forget.
Come back here!
You'll get worse for running away!
Oh, dear. You’re just
too good for me.
I never can beat you at this game.
That makes an even
$10,000 you owe me.
- $10,000? - Well, you see, we usually
play for a hundred dollars a game...
but Granny was getting behind and she wanted
to get even, so we played for a thousand.
Serves me right for being so extravagant.
Oh, 10:00. Bedtime.
Art, after what happened
at your house tonight...
would you like to
stay here with Edward?
If I go home, I'll get hit, and
if I don't... I'll get hit worse.
You stay here then.
I'll speak to your aunt in the morning.
You will? Then I'll stay.
Thanks, Granny.
And I'll see that
school principal too.
- Oh.
- What-What's the matter?
- Oh, nothing.
- I'll get your medicine.
Just one of my spells.
It's empty.
Is there any more?
- I'll run and get a doctor.
- Wait a minute, Art!
Granny don't like doctors.
- She's afraid she might have to go to the hospital.
- Why don't she go to a hospital?
Don't you know that in hospitals, if you're
poor, they slip you the black bottle?
- Black bottle?
- Sure.
- To put you out of the way and take the expense
off the county. - Gee, we gotta do something.
My-My medicine.
It's all gone.
Got any money?
Come on.
We'll get some.
We'll be right back, Granny.
- It's locked up, doggone it.
- Let's go to Doray's.
Hey, what's the name
of that medicine?
Dr. Watson's Famous Remedy.
- Gee, what are we gonna do now?
- I don't know.
Let's go to Doray's home and he can
open up the store and get it for us.
- He must be out.
- We gotta do somethin'.
We got to get that
medicine for Granny.
Come on.
- Say, this is steaiin', ain't it?
- I don't care.
But if we come around tomorrow and pay
Mr. Doray, it'll be all right, won't it?
Sure.
- I'll come in and pull you in.
- Okay.
- Do you know where it is?
- I think so.
Here it is.
- How many did you get?
- I took two.
Well, come on.
Hmm.
Here it is.
Hurry up and take it, will you?
Well, well, well.
I caught you right in the act, eh?
I knew I'd get you sooner or later.
Say, who was that with you there?
Whose car is that out there?
You know what this is, don't you?
It's burglary
and stealing automobiles.
Now if you tell me who was with you,
I can make it a whole lot easier for ya.
Oh, all right. Come along.
Hey, Sarge-
Say, I caught that Simpson kid breaking
into Doray's Drugstore.
Yeah. I'm gonna take him over to Doray's
for a minute before I bring him in.
Yeah. See you later.
- Hello, Officer. - I caught this lad
climbing out the back of your store.
He stole some stuff.
I don't know how much yet.
He copped a car too.
All right, come on in.
Why, it's Art Simpson.
What's the matter?
Why, your little pet
was caught breaking into the store.
- Art, is that true?
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, Art, why did you do that?
I'll tell you why,
because he's a bad egg, that's why.
I tried to tell you that
and you wouldn't believe me.
Now maybe you'll realize
that I was right.
All right, Weems, lock him up. I'll come
down in the morning and sign a complaint.
Wait a minute, please.
Don't you want to tell me
why you did it?
No, ma'am. I can't.
All right, Weems.
Jack, I'm surprised at you.
Letting that boy be locked up
before you've even investigated.
They ought to lock up all the bad kids
in town. It'd be a better place to live in.
- That's right, Edith.
- I think so too.
I don't think there's
such a thing as a bad boy.
It's simply a matter of
environment and-and opportunity.
- Oh, Edie, you're an idealist.
- I should say you are.
Do you know what kids like that
grow up to be? Murderers.
If people like us devoted more
time to community affairs...
- there wouldn't be as many so-called
bad children. - Got a match, Jack?
I'm sorry to see you
here again, Arthur.
Put it there.
Now we can talk.
- Who are the witnesses?
- Just me, Your Honor.
- Who signed the complaint?
- Mr. Doray, Judge.
- Is he here?
- Oh, he'll be here any minute.
What'; the difficulty this time?
Well, I was making my rounds
about 10:00."
when I come to Doray's Drugstore,
corner of Main and Second.
I saw a car with the motor running, sol thought
I'd take a look in the alley behind it...
you know, just for fun.
Well, just as I got around in behind there,
I heard footsteps running.
Then I saw this lad here waving his hand
out of the window behind there.
He was handing out a bottle,
so I waited.
And when he climbed out,
I nabbed him.
- Had the window been forced?
- Yes, sir; it had.
And the car out front
belonged to Ed Wallace.
And this kid here
told me he'd borrowed it.
Did you find the car
near a fireplug, Art?
- What did you steal from the drugstore?
- I took some medicine.
Medicine? That's funny. I never heard
of a boy stealing medicine before.
They usually have to be bribed to take it.
What did you want with the medicine?
There was someone else
with you in this, wasn't there?
Son...
I want to point out something
that I don't think you realize.
According to testimony, you've committed
burglary and theft of an automobile.
That's a very serious offense, one for
which we send men to the penitentiary.
It lies within my power...
to commit you to an institution during
the term of your minority.
- How old are you?
- Thirteen.
That would be eight years then.
Eight long years.
Now I don't want to do that.
I want to help you.
But I can't do that unless
you're frank with me...
and tell me all the hows
and whys of this whole thing.
Who was with you?
Judge, I did break in the drugstore
and I took some medicine...
but that's all I can tell ya.
I'm sorry to be late, Judge...
but I was taking inventory at the store,
and I have to get right back.
If you want me to testify,
let's get it over with in a hurry.
Uh, Doray, john A. The truth, the whole
truth, nothing but the truth, so help me God.
Evidently, you haven't had
any experience in courtrooms, Mr. Doray.
No, sir, I haven't. As far as I'm
concerned it's a waste of time.
I'm a very busy man. Now just what was it
you wanted to ask me?
I want to ask you with as much emphasis
as the dignity of the bench will permit...
- to take a seat or leave this room.
- What?
You've been guilty of contempt.
Ordinarily you'd be fined.
But the court realizes that a man of your
temperament and ignorance of court procedure...
may not be responsible
for what he says.
So I simply ask you
to take a seat or leave the room.
All right, sir,
if that's what you want.
But frankly, with as-with as much emphasis as
the dignity of my temperament will permit...
I never got such a raw deal
in my life.
- Officer, arrest that man.
- For what? I'm not the burglar.
You're in contempt of court,
and I fine you $10.
Thank you very much.
All right, there's your 1 O bucks.
This is only the juvenile court,
but it's dignity must be maintained.
It's all right with me.
Maintain it.
I impose an additional fine
of$25 upon you, Mr. Doray.
- Looks like the county's too poor to
pay the judge’s salary. - What's that?
All right, Art. I want to know just
who was with you...
- the night you broke into the drugstore.
- It was me.
Well, these two kids are pals,
Your Honor.
He must be the one
I heard running away.
Come on up here, lad.
- What's your name?
- Nutty-I mean, Edward Beamish.
- Do you know Arthur here?
- Yes, sir.
- Pretty well?
- Pretty.
Were you with him the night
the drugstore was broken into?
Yes, sir.
Did you hear Arthur's
testimony just now?
No, sir.
I just now sneaked in.
Just now sneaked in? Why?
Well, I didn't want Art
to get all the blame for this.
I see. Well, now, you tell me
just what happened.
Well...
Art and me adjust moved
the car from a fireplug...
and we took a shortcut
through the alley by the drugstore.
And I saw the back window was open.
Sol said to Art, “I think
we ought to close that window...
because if it's left open, someone might
climb in and rob Mr. Doray's store. “
Sol climbed up and tried to
reach in for the catch...
but I overbalanced myself
and fell in the store.
Well, when Art saw me fall in...
he climbed up
and tried to help me out.
He held my hand, but...
I slipped and pulled him in too.
I see. Well, now you're
both in, then what?
Well, I managed to get out first.
- I heard someone coming, I ducked.
- Why?
Well, I didn't want anybody to think
f was robbing the drugstore.
Certainly not.
Well, why didn't you come forward before
and tell your story?
- Didn't you know your pal was in trouble?
- Yes, sir.
Well?
I guess I was scared to.
- Is that your story, Edward?
- Yes, sir.
You fell into the drugstore
and Art fell in trying to pull you out.
- Is that it?
- Yes, sir.
Well, then, how do you account for
the bottle of medicine that was stolen?
- '(our Honor?
- Are you concerned in this case, madam?
Yes, indeed I am.
I'm his grandmother.
- Do you wish to testify as a witness?
- Yes, I do.
Kindly raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear to tell the truth...
the whole truth, nothing but the truth,
so help you God?
- ! do. - Now then, Mrs.
Beamish, what do you know about this?
I know this much, that these two boys
wouldn't be here if it wasn't for me.
How's that?
Because I had one of my spells.
And there was no medicine in the house
and no money to buy it.
And they went and got it for me.
And I think it's a shame to punish them
for doing a good deed.
And I'll pay Mr. Doray for it
out of my next pension check.
Oh, so the boys took the medicine
for you because you were sick?
That's it exactly.
I've used Dr. Watson's Famous Remedy
for years. Mr. Doray knows that.
I buy it from him all the time.
Didn't you see my picture
in the paper?
No.
I wrote a testimonial
and they printed my picture with it.
Well, thank you
very much, Mrs. Beamish.
Will you just
sit over there, please?
Well, Mr. Doray,
Mrs. Beamish's testimony...
puts a different aspect
on the burglary, doesn't it?
How do you feel about it now?
Well, I'll tell you.
If I'm in contempt this time,
you'll have to take a check.
I'm a businessman
and a property owner, Your Honor.
Now if every time anybody happens
to need a bottle of medicine...
they can break
into a drugstore and take it...
well, then, of course, my property isn't
safe, is it, nor is any other merchant's.
I think these two boys
ought to be punished.
Because as I understand it, and I know
that you'll correct me if I'm wrong...
the courts were instituted
for the protection of property.
I'll issue an order committing
these two boys to the state school.
- Your Honor?
- Yes, Mrs. Beamish?
- Can I say just a word?
- Certainly.
Please don't send my Edward away.
Please, Judge.
He's not a bad boy.
Why, he's the best boy around the house
you ever saw.
He helps me with the housework...
and I never have to speak
twice to him.
And-And he works after school...
and gives me every penny he makes.
And, judge, he's so smart.
He's always inventing things.
Oh, he's got a good mind.
And he always says his prayers...
before I tuck him in at night.
And it wouldn't be right.
Why, he's all I live for.
He hasn't anybody but me.
His mother put him in my arms...
when she lay dying, and made me
promise I'd look out for him.
And I have.
I've done the best I know.
I've gone without things myself'...
so that he wouldn't
ever be cold or hungry.
Oh, judge, please.
Please.
Don't send my boy away from me.
Please!
As I said before...
I'll issue an order committing these
two boys to the state school.
But I'll stay execution
of the order indefinitely.
This means that if you're ever brought
before me again for any reason whatever...
the commitment order will go
immediately into effect.
- You understand that?
- Yes, sir.
There's one other condition
to your probation...
a condition which I always
impose where two or more boys...
are accomplices
in a matter of this kind.
That is this:
You're not to see, speak or travel
together at any time in the future.
H' you do, I'll consider it a violation
of your probation.
This may seem harsh, but it's the only
effective prevention I've found...
for something like this
happening again.
Mrs. Beamish, I'll release your grandson
in your custody on probation.
You'll be responsible
to this court for him.
All right, Edward.
You may go.
Art, I want to release you
on the same conditions.
Mrs. Mary Taylor?
- Y es, sh. - You're this boy's aunt,
also his guardian, I understand.
Yes, sir.
I want to release him in your custody. Will
you be responsible to this court for him?
No, sir, I will not.
I've kept him and fed him
and given him a mother's care.
I got my own to think about.
He's no good, Your Honor.
He's makin' hoodlums
outta my kids...
and I don't want him
in my house anymore.
Maybe the reform school
can make a man of him.
I can't.
Well, Art, I don't know
what to do with you.
Has the boy any other relatives?
No, sir.
Hmm, that complicates things.
Well, you're a ward of this court, Art,
and I gotta do something with you.
There are two courses open to me.
I can find some responsible person
who's willing to act as your guardian...
or I can turn you over to a state institution
and let the state take care of you.
I guess you'll have to...
send me away, Judge.
- Your Honor?
- Yes, Mrs. Doray?
I will act as the boy's guardian.
Edie, have you lost your mind?
Have you gone cr-
Why, she doesn't mean that,
judge. She's gone crazy. She's-
I'll adjourn this hearing
to my chambers.
Well, I-Well, you-
Uh-Hey, now listen, Judge.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Fun is fun, but you can't-
Now, then, Mrs. Doray, are you quite sure
you want to assume this responsibility?
- Yes, I'm sure.
- You'll do nothing of the sort!
I absolutely forbid it!
Do you think it's wise in view
of your husbands attitude?
Oh, I think I can change that.
It's a very fine thing
your wife is doing, Mr. Doray.
A year in a nice home
with the right inﬂuences...
would make all the difference
in this boy's life.
His life? Yeah, that's great.
What about my life?
Please, Jack.
This is something I want to do.
Your Honor, I'm of legal age
and a property owner.
- Does that qualify me?
- Yes, it does, Mrs. Doray.
Of course, there are a few necessary
formalities, but that can be easily arranged.
Well, Art, looks as if you're
going to belong to me for a while.
Gee, I don't know
what to say, Mrs. Doray.
But if you take me, I'll do my best.
- Mm-hmm.
- Honest, I will.
Edie-
- What'd the judge do with the boy, jack?
- What'd he do with him?
He gave him to me!
- Morning, Mrs. Doray.
- Good morning.
Can this be the same boy I brought home
with me yesterday?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Why, I can hardly believe it.
Turn around.
- Swell, huh?
- Swell!
Look, jack.
Doesn't Art look nice?
Beautiful.
I'm sorry.
Never dig your spoon
into a grapefruit.
Do it this way.
Oh, time for school.
The judge has had you reinstated
and you're going back to your old class.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Good-bye, dear.
- I don't have to tell you to be a good boy, do I?
- No, ma'am.
Good-bye, Mr. Doray.
Jack, if I hadn't been married to you long
enough to know you, I'd say you were a mean man.
I don't care what you say.
I'm sore, and I'm going to stay sore.
You brought that kid
into our home against my wishes...
and don't think
you're gonna make me like it.
Oh, please Jack.
Don't be so stubborn.
I want to give Arthur a chance in life,
and I want you to help me.
Never. I don't like the kid,
and I don't want him here.
All the talkin the world
isn't gonna change me.
- Jack, I'm ashamed of you.
- I've had my say.
I gotta go to work.
Bye.
Hi, Art.
Gee, I'm glad to see ya.
Boy, you look swell.
Better than I ever saw ya.
That's some suit, all right.
I was just sayin' to my granny,
“I hope I see Art on the way to school. “
And she said,
remember what the judge told me.
I'm not allowed to speak to you.
But, shucks, no judge
can bust us up, can they?
Huh?
Gee, Art, aren't ya gonna
say anything to me?
Ain't you even gonna say hello?
I know the judge said we shouldn't.
And I know you wanna
make good for Mrs. Doray.
But, gosh, you could
at least say hello to a fella.
Hmm, you're scared.
Afraid of the old judge.
Afraid to do anything, you big sissy.
You got a lot of nice new clothes now,
and you're stuck-up about it.
What do I care?
I don't care if you
don't speak to me.
I don't care if I never see you again.
- Edie, we can't go.
- Why not?
- Why, it's the maid's night out, isn't it?
- Well, what of it?
What of-Say, you don't mean to
tell me you'd go away...
- and leave that kid here all alone, do ya?
- Why, of course I do.
You'd come back and find the house
burned down or the silverware gone.
- Now, you mark my words.
- Jack, I think you’re being very unfair.
Now, you'll have to admit he's been here
a week, and he's been as good as gold.
Yeah, that's just it.
He's been too good. it's not natural.
You just hate to give in, don't you?
You know, in your heart I think
you really like him as much as I do.
Say, not me.
We are going to leave you
in charge of the house.
- You won't go out, will you?
- No, ma'am.
- Not for anything?
I want to show you
that I really trust you.
- You won't let me down?
- You can bet on that.
Hmm.
Ready, dear?
- You're gonna leave him here, huh?
- Well, of course.
All right.
Just wait and see, that's all.
Oh, hello, Granny. Come on in.
Gee, I'm awful glad to see ya.
Have a seat.
Mr. and Mrs. Doray just left.
What is it?
Is there something the matter?
It's Edward.
- What's the matter with him?
- He's sick.
He's awful sick.
He caught cold last week,
and it got worse and worse.
I made him go to bed.
I've done everything I can for him, but-
Oh, he's so sick.
And all day long, he keeps asking me
to get you to come and see him.
He just begged me to get you.
Run over, will you?
Just for a minute?
Why, sure.
I can't.
Not right now.
I have to wait till
Mrs. Doray comes home.
Art, he's awful sick.
I wouldn't have come after you
if he wasn't...
on account of what
the judge said and all.
But... he keeps on calling for you.
Oh, I think you ought to go.
Have you got a doctor?
Well, you have to have one.
- How about medicine?
- I haven't any money.
Here, take this and get a doctor, any
doctor, and anything else you need too.
What are you tryin' to do,
make a fella think you’re sick?
Hello, Art.
Gee, I'm glad you came over.
I was afraid you were sore at me
for what happened the other day.
- You ain't, are ya?
- No, I'm not sore. Course not.
That's good.
You're about the only
real friend I ever had...
and I wouldn't want you
to be mad at me.
I don't know why I did it.
I guess maybe I was jealous.
You had nice clothes and everything.
Want me to do anything?
Want me to get you a drink of water?
No.
Just sit here by me.
Hey, Art, remember
the time we put the frogs...
in the music teacher's desk?
Yeah. Boy, how she jumped.
Remember when we went fishin'
and fell in with our clothes on?
We used to have a lot of fun,
didn't we?
Sure, we did. We're gonna have
a lot more together too.
Why, hurry up and get well.
- Do you mean it?
- You bet I mean it.
I don't care about the judge
or old juvenile court or anything.
We're gonna be pals
just like we used to be.
That's great. That's what
I wanted you to say.
No judge or nobody...
gonna stop us from being together...
always.
You remember
that airplane I invented?
It ﬂies, all right.
Me and you ﬂy in it...
way, high UP-
Way up in the clouds...
up by the stars.
Floating along.
Just ﬂoating.
Clouds.
Gee, it's...
gettin' dark in here.
Awful dark.
Where's Granny?
I want my granny!
Nutty? Nutty-
Nutty!
Nutty, wake up.
Wake up, Nutty.
Nutty! Please wake up.
Wake up, Nutty, please!
Nutty! Nutty!
Granny.
He went to sleep,
and I can't wake him up.
Oh, Art?
Guess Art's gone to bed.
I'll go up and see.
Yeah, too bad he couldn't
turn out a few lights.
Probably all tired out,
poor little fellow. Overworked.
- Why, he's not in his room.
- Why, of course he's not in his room.
And he's not in the house!
He's gone, and your money's gone with him.
- Oh, I can't believe it. - You can't? Better
check around the house. See what's missing.
- Don't be so unfair.
- The kid was just waiting for a chance like this.
This was a cinch to happen.
I tried to tell you that.
- I won't believe he's guilty till he's had a
chance to explain! - If you weren't so stubborn-
Well, as far as I'm concerned, this is the finish.
You're gonna send that kid back to the judge.
I'll do nothing of the sort
until he tells me what's happened.
This is what comes of bringing
riffraff into a decent home.
- I knew this was gonna happen, Edie. I kept
telling you! - Yes, you've been telling me!
All you've done is to make it
as difficult as you could.
I can't figure this out. The boy leaves
your home when you tell him not to go.
He steals your money
and still you stick up for him.
- Oh, Edie, you're a fool.
- Don't you dare talk to me that way!
All right, Edie. I'll just say
one thing more, and then I'll shut up.
You know, I wish I could like that kid.
Honest, I do, for your sake.
But I can't.
There's no use.
And you know that before
that kid came into our house...
we were a pretty
happily married couple, weren't we?
And ever since he's been here, we've done
nothing but quarrel and fight and have trouble.
I mean, there's no use
kiddin' ourselves.
We can't go on like this.
Either that kid's got to go
or I do, Edie-one of us.
Really, I mean that.
And as much as I love you, Edie, I'll go-
even if it means a divorce.
All right.
Lack.
Art! Art, I thought
I told you not to leave the house...
not for anything.
- Why did you?
- Let me alone, will ya?
I'm sick and tired of everyone
telling me what to do.
I went out because
I wanted to, that's why.
And I took your money too.
What're you gonna do about it?
I never asked to come and live here.
I don't wanna stay no more.
I'm no good, and I never will be any good!
I'm bad! I'm the worst kid in town, that's
what I am! Now, how do you like that?
Never mind, dear. You tried hard
and you did the best you could.
But even you couldn't do anything
with a kid like that. Let him go.
- And I wanted to help him.
- I feel awfully sorry for you.
Really I do. But I'm glad it turned out
this way for both our sakes.
Hmm.
Come on now.
Forget about it, will ya?
Well, I just phoned the authorities
and told them to pick that kid up.
- What's the matter?
- Little Nutty Beamish died last night.
He did?
Aw, that's too bad.
And Art was with him when he died.
Art was?
How do you know?
The postman just told me.
That must've been why
he left the house-to go to his pal.
Hmm. Poor boy.
Gee, I wish he had told us that.
He heard us quarreling about him,
and he knew he stood between us.
Hmm! And he wanted to make me think
that he was unworthy.
I'm sorry, Edie.
Honestly I am.
Jack, surely this will change
your attitude about him.
- Go and find him, will you, and bring
him back? -You bet I'll find him.
Don't you worry about it.
I'll find him.
Gosh, don't you think I'm human?
Say, I'm awful sorry
to hear about Nutty.
Say, you haven't seen anything
of Art Simpson, have ya?
Well, I got orders to pick him up
and turn him back to the juvenile court.
I thought maybe
he might be around here.
Well, he isn't.
Well, I, eh-
Has he gone?
Gee, I thought I could stay here
and help you like Nutty did...
but I guess they won't let me.
The best thing for me to do
is get out of the old town.
Yes. I suppose so.
But don't you worry.
I'll go someplace else and get a job.
When I do, I'll send for ya...
and we'll live together.
That'll be fine, Art.
- Hello, Mabel.
- I brought Edward's school books.
- I thought you might want them.
- Thank you, dear.
- Ain't there something I could do?
- No, dear, thank you.
- We'd better take him with us.
- Yeah.
Hey, wait a minute!
- How long have you been here?
- Only a few minutes.
- Come on. We're going for a ride.
- I don't wanna go for no ride!
Sure you do!
We'll drop you off someplace.
What's the matter, Mr. Doray?
Well, what happened?
I've been held up. A couple of fellas
came in here in slugged me.
- I'll bet them's the two fellas I
just saw drive away from here. - Yeah?
My car's outside.
Come on, Weems!
Straight ahead, Mr. Doray!
There's a car behind us!
- Come on! Step on it!
- I've got it wide open!
That's the car!
That's them, all right.
He's gettin' closer!
It's that druggist we slugged.
He's got a copper with him.
Yes? Then plug 'em!
Gimme your gat.
I'm gonna get him.
What-What are you doin' here?
They tried to shoot ya...
so I wrecked the car.
Thanks, Art.
I don't know what
to say to you, kid.
I guess you think I'm a pretty mean
sort of a guy, don't you...
the way I've treated
you and everything, and-
Honest, I don't know what-
But I will make it up to you, Art.
Honest, I will.
I'm sorry.
So, he's mixed up in it too, eh?
Yeah, and it's a good thing
for us that he was.
“And as a result, Mr. Doray
is planning to adopt Art Simpson. “
- How's that, Art?
- Swell.
I'm sorry.
Okay, pal.