A TOEI FILM
GHOST MAN
Produced by Kazuo Takimura
Original Novel by Seishi Yokomizo
Screenplay by Tsutomu Sawamura
Cinematography: Kazuo Yamada / Art: Keiji Kitagawa
Sound: Masanobu Miyazaki / Music: Kyosuke Kami
STARRING
Seizaburo Kawazu
Haruo Tanaka / Joji Oka
Miki Sanjo / Yu Fujiki
Toyoji Shiozawa / Yoshiko Hirose
Gen Shimizu / Minosuke Yamada / Heihachiro Okawa
Ren Yamamoto / Tamae Kawai / Mitsue Tachibana
Directed by Motoyoshi Oda
KANO MENTAL HOSPITAL
Doctor! Doctor!
- Something terrible's happened!
- Tsumura's disappeared!
It appears he's escaped!
He's escaped?
BLOODSUCKING PAINTER KAZUHIKO
TSUMURA FLEES MENTAL HOSPITAL
What an odd incident.
For us, members of the Bizarro
Enthusiast Club, it's a little intriguing.
This is no small thing -
it's a big deal, is what it is!
Not to mention the
members of our club
have a connection with Dr. Kano...
MODEL AGENCY
"MUTUAL ARTS CLUB"
I'm after a model.
May I ask your name, or
the name of your referral?
"I HEREBY REFER GHOSTMAN SAGAWA"
DR. SANSAKU KANO
I see - Dr. Kano referred you.
"I HEREBY REFER GHOSTMAN SAGAWA"
DR. SANSAKU KANO
I see - Dr. Kano referred you.
This will do fine.
But this "Ghostman"...
...this is your name?
Quite the strange pen name.
That's a very typical Dr. Kano referral.
- Will the model be for painting, or photography?
- Oil painting.
- From when?
- 2 hours, every day.
10 days, from today.
From today?
What's the address?
This way, please.
We have 6 models
available for selection.
Keiko.
Yes.
There's something off about him.
I hope Keiko's alright.
What'll it be?
Thank you very much.
What're you doing
out here? Any news?
You got a big mouth
for a broke reporter.
You didn't see an odd
man over there, did you?
- An odd man?
- Like a ghost.
- How macabre!
- No clue.
I see. Let's head back.
- I'm ready, Manager.
- He's too strange!
- You must reconsider.
- But...
...it's been so long between jobs.
- Hello.
- Hello, there.
Mr. Kikuchi - don't you think Keiko
should turn that man down?
He's terribly weird.
What's going on?
What do you think?
There was a man here
that looked like a ghost--
Stop it!
I'm going.
They're decent terms, after all.
If I lose any more work...
...my whole family is done for!
The address was Nishi-Ogikubo,
wasn't it, manager?
Keiko! Wait, Keiko!
What's with you?
- I can't say.
- What's that?
Listen, you're just getting worked up.
That's not it -
I just feel like it's got to with that
crazed man from the paper...
That's a good one.
Sounds like you'd be perfect
for the Bizarro club too, Osada.
Good for you.
That's not what I'm talking about.
What's with the long face, Osada?
Are you cold?
Drink this. It'll warm you up.
Once you've finished,
take your clothes off.
This way.
What will you do?
I'm feeling numb.
It's cleaning your blood.
My blood?
Are you going to kill me?
Don't kill me!
Please don't...please!
My mother's very old...
...and my little brothers...
there's lots of them!
You're looking terribly
troubled, young man.
Your editor angry at you for
not getting any good scoops?
- Nothing like that.
- What's with the long face and quick retorts, then?
I'm bored.
Write this, then:
"GHOST MAN VISITS
NUDE MODEL CLUB"
Good, right? I'd read that newspaper!
Quit joking around.
Wanna dance?
They say nudes aren't even enough
to sell papers these days.
Oh, it's the Doctor!
Dr. Kano himself graces
us with his presence!
I'm sure you remember him, Mitsuko.
Shush.
Fewer girls here than usual.
Someone off working?
Oh - that reminds me.
A strange man with
your referral was here.
- My referral?
- That's right.
One "Ghostman Sagawa"...
Ghostman Sagawa?
Here.
Never seen it before.
What's wrong?
She'll be killed.
Come now, you
shouldn't joke about that!
That ghost man was Tsumura -
he ran an art class for women!
11:00pm already, huh?
She's late.
Good evening.
Have you seen your sister, Kokichi?
Nope.
I knew it.
What're you talking about?
We don't know anything yet!
Did something
happen to my sister?
Let's go and have a look, then!
- You have a car, Dr. Kano?
- Yes.
Let's get moving.
This concludes tonight's
Bizarro Enthusiasts meeting.
Take me, too.
Good evening.
Who are you?
Who are you,
and why are you here?
We're from a model agency -
a girl that we sent here on
a job hasn't returned home.
A job? This house is abandoned.
The lights were on,
so I thought I'd take a look.
Well, let's look inside and
see what's going on.
That door ain't going to open.
How did you...?
Nothing to it.
Hey...isn't this Keiko's?
It is - it's hers!
So we at least know
that she got naked here.
Don't say something so scary!
Sis!
MODEL MURDERED IN THE NUDE
MURDERED BEAUTY IN THE BATHTUB: CRAZED
SPIDER-OWNING PAINTER, WHEREABOUTS UNKNOWN
And why mustn't I associate with
the Bizarro Enthusiast Club?
By all means, you can -
but you're at the international
forefront of psychiatry:
if you get too curious, you'll
start to want greater thrills.
This vampiric Tsumura fellow
was also a member, I recall.
And just what do you take
the Bizarro Enthusiasts for?
You've been so careless about the club,
now the police are looking in our direction!
Hirota.
You must tell every newspaper that the
club has nothing to do with the ghost man.
Yes, sir.
It's too late, Dr. Kano.
It was one of our models
that was killed, after all.
What's that? How dare
you be so blasé!
In any case, the club has
nothing to do with this case.
Maybe, maybe not.
It's only natural for them to be
suspicious of high-profile members.
What? What exactly are you--!
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
Greetings, models from
the Mutual Arts Club.
This is the Ghost Man.
I trust you all enjoyed the superb
performance I put on for Act 1 of the show...
- Come out of there!
- Wait - it's dangerous!
And now, preparations for
Act 2 have been completed,
and I am now
looking for a co-star.
I truly hope the next one
will be as splendid as the first.
It's just a tape.
I truly hope the next one
will be as splendid as the first.
Let's listen to the end.
I truly hope the next one
will be as splendid as the first.
Let's listen to the end.
I look forward to your attendance.
That's all from me - good night!
Tea, please.
Hello? Yes, it's me.
Inspector Todoroki.
I'd like you to look
into one more guy.
Matsubacho 23, Taito-ku.
Goes by the name of
Kentaro Yamagata.
The kanji for "ken" is "kane".
That'll be it for today.
Look into him carefully.
I'll be here a while more.
Evening, Inspector.
Y'know...
...you needn't work so hard
sifting through all your suspects.
The tape serves as
great evidence, doesn't it?
Isn't there a more...
scientific way of investigating?
That might be enough for the
Bizarro Enthusiasts, but not for us.
We've got to be preemptive about this
second murder he's announced, in any case.
Exactly! Mr. Kikuchi's
acting all indifferent about it,
even though we're the ones being hunted!
- That's right!
Take it a little more seriously, OK?
Alright, alright. My apologies.
Yes? Yes, that's right.
Hello, sir. Inspector Todoroki -
it's from headquarters.
Thank you.
Yes, hello? Yes.
Yes. Hm? Taro Yamada?
Yes...yes...what?
Ah...yes. Alright, understood.
No such person as
"Taro Yamada", apparently.
Which girl is he hiring?
Let's see...
...it's Mitsuko!
Nothing to worry about!
Could just be a prank.
It doesn't mean
he's after you next!
Not to mention the fine fellows from
the police force will be there with you.
Do you remember what
kind of man he was?
Well...
...it says he called us on the 23rd.
I wonder which one he was...
Do you remember him?
How about you? And you?
Don't you remember him?
Now you mention it...
...there was one weird guy, right?
- Ah! Him!
Stop it!
I'm going to be killed...!
TARO YAMADA, PAINTER, AOYAMA.
MODEL NAME: MITSUKO MIYAKAWA
I'll keep you company overnight.
- You'll be fine.
- Thank you.
Don't leave me alone!
Mr. Kikuchi.
What a fright you gave me!
Anything out of the ordinary?
Of course not! Don't be silly.
Really?
Can you come along too, Kokichi?
Please...I'm scared.
Go on, then.
Sure, no problem.
Huh? Where are we going?
What's wrong?
You...!
Who are you?
Taro Yamada.
Please...spare my life!
I'll do anything!
I don't want to die!
Keiko said the same thing.
I like the way women look
when they are freshly dead.
No! I don't want to die!
Fine.
They won't find me,
anyway - I give up.
Your face...
...take off those bandages!
I don't want to die not
knowing who killed me!
Very well.
It makes no difference, I suppose.
I'll take them off for you.
Hello? Hello?
Hey, mister!
- She'll be killed.
- Huh?
She'll be killed!
- Mitsuko will be killed...
- Hello?
Pull yourself together. Who's that?
Who's Mitsuko?
Three-fingered man...
...three-fingered man...
- Three-fingered man?
Tsumura, the Ghost Man!
Hello? And who are you?
If he's telling the truth,
something bad's happened!
There's been an incident in Mitaka.
We just heard from the bureau.
Busy day today.
Call an ambulance, and
tell HQ to look into this man.
- What's their condition?
- Nothing serious.
Hey, you can't take photos yet!
Are they alright?
They've just been drugged.
They'll come to in about an hour.
How did you know about this?
This is the work of the Ghost Man.
Huh?
The Ghost Man phoned last night...
Why didn't you tell us?
Didn't think he would spare them.
I don't suppose you're related
to this Ghost Man, are you?
Take care of this for me, would you?
Get started, then.
This isn't a joke.
You think I'm related to
the Ghost Man, too?
No, you idiot.
I think you shouldn't keep
sticking your nose into this.
I'm a newspaper reporter.
You've only been focused on
the Ghost Man incidents, though.
Anybody would think that's odd.
You want me to be a small
fry reporter forever?
I'm worried.
Ayuko...
Y'know, Ken, I'm...
Forget it. I shouldn't just blurt
things out like you do.
Ayuko!
So...Tsumura and the Ghost Man
are two different people, then?
Yes.
I didn't make it to the
hideout, so I can't be sure,
but that's what Kokichi says.
Let's stop talking about it, OK?
Alright.
You were after a big scoop when
you heard about the incident, right?
Guess you'll have to wait a bit longer.
- What are you on about?
In any case, I wish Dr. Kano would hurry
back from Osaka and take us to a shoot.
I can't bear being
shut up in here.
Couldn't we do a shoot
somewhere far away?
Dr. Kano said he's
thinking of a hotel in Izu.
It'd be lovely there.
That sounds good. It's been a
while since we had a meeting.
Will Dr. Kano be back by then?
Of course he will!
Wait a minute...
...there's something
odd about Dr. Kano.
You said he's in Osaka,
but I remember seeing him at Ginza.
There you go making
strange remarks again.
NUDE PHOTO SHOOT - IZU HYAKKA-EN HOTEL
MUTUAL ARTS CLUB
Hey!
Not in front of everyone, you two!
I feel sorry for you
without Mitsuko around.
Why'd he return her, do you think?
There was nothing wrong with her,
right? I wonder why he took her.
She's not been the same since.
She's lost all of her spark.
- Big disappointment for me, too.
- Come, now.
Talk about that topic is
out of bounds for today!
Time to eat.
- Dr. Kano - have you seen Sadako?
- No.
- Have you seen Sadako?
- She headed off that way earlier.
I wonder where she's got to.
Let's go eat.
Where's the other half?
And just who might you be?
Kosuke Kindaichi.
The private detective?
What gives you the
right to be here?
I paid 5000 yen to become
a registered participant.
Seems it was all
for nought, however.
You knew this was
going to happen?
Don't be ridiculous - if I did,
I would've done something.
I'd like you all to
return to the hotel.
You mustn't disturb
the scene of the crime.
Please.
I apologize for the disruption,
but I must ask
you to wait patiently.
Inspector Todoroki from
HQ will arrive shortly.
It is of utmost importance that
the crime scene is undisturbed.
While it is cramped in here,
I must ask you to be patient.
Also, I want to ask you to turn
in the film you shot today.
It will be your alibi -
or at the very least,
it may be of some help.
- Go and collect them.
- What a waste of film...
- It's Todoroki.
- Come in.
- Hello.
- Hello, Inspector.
Another strange murder case, eh?
What time did you last
meet with Sadako, Doctor?
One o'clock, perhaps?
I'm afraid I don't recall.
I understand. An approximate
time will do fine.
Why are you treating
us like criminals?
We're merely asking
everyone the same questions...
- The murder weapon has been found.
- Has it?
- That's medical equipment.
- Dr. Kano?
Bellboy!
Do you remember
seeing that suitcase?
Yes, sir.
Someone who was referred by
Dr. Kano was carrying it last night.
You, manager - wasn't
the place fully reserved?
I received a call from Dr. Kano
asking if he could arrive early.
I do not recall
making that phone call.
People forget things.
Listen, manager -
is that man amongst these people here?
- Let's see...
He is not.
Damn it.
Show us his room.
- Take care of this.
- Yes, sir.
This one.
Give it a knock.
Try the key.
God damn it...
two in one day.
Look into where the mannequin
legs and hands came from.
Good day.
Making an order? We're
backed up for quite a while.
No orders today, thanks.
We've a few questions for you.
I'm too busy to stop
working right now.
I gathered as much.
You're considered as one of the
best mannequin makers in Japan.
Not really.
This one's just
like the real thing.
That one?
I just finished it.
She turned out pretty well.
- Satoshi!
- Yes?
We gotta hurry up and get
this packed and sent.
I'll get the packaging.
I'm spending way too
much time on her mouth.
Why's it gotta be such high
quality if it's just a mannequin?
I wonder what it's being used for.
Beats me -
the guy said it just needed
to show up well in a photo.
Nothing unusual.
What kind of person
made the order?
Someone just like you.
Sounds like a good-looking man,
if he's anything like me.
I didn't really get a look at him.
Said he'd had acid thrown on his face
by a woman - head was in bandages.
Where's it being delivered to?
Why are you getting so nosy?
Just wondering what
kind of guy he was.
Hey old man.
Old man?
So that's where you are!
You needn't be so shy.
What's this? Another act?
You'll catch a cold
in that outfit...!
It's...not her!
Then just who is it, Dr. Kano?
Now see here -
who's responsible for this?
We'd like to ask you
the same question.
What? Me?
Why do you and the Ghost
Man have the same hideout?
What are you saying?
That I'm the Ghost Man?
- Perhaps.
- Nonsense.
These are the doings of
someone trying to set me up!
Be that as it may,
it appears you were making a
rendezvous with a married woman.
If that's not the case,
what exactly are
you doing here?
I'll answer that.
Madam!
Let me say this,
just to be clear.
This is a good, honest man.
If you arrest him, he'll be
treated as the Ghost Man.
Until his alibi has been confirmed,
I'm taking him into my care.
What happened? Are you alright?
We're fine. Quick,
set up a perimeter.
"Towa Company, for luxury
Western clothing materials.
Towa Company, specializing in
Towa is widely adored by
everyone as a reliable,
cheap Western fabric store."
"In recent times, Towa has been...
Was it wrong of me to
meet with you, Ken?
- Not really.
- I'm sorry.
I've just been so lonely.
I wish you weren't so quiet.
I've got something I
need to discuss with you.
It's not like I'm angry
with you or anything.
- Ayuko, I--
- Hey!
Can't wait to hear this.
I heard you quit modeling
and became a stripper, Ayuko!
- Is that true, Ayuko?
- Well, now!
Even her lover doesn't know!
That spells trouble.
How did you know
that, Mr. Kikuchi?
I got sharp ears.
I know about how much you love a
certain newspaper reporter, and lots more.
Goodbye, then. See you
at the club sometime!
How did he know that?
Is it true, Ayuko?
That was what I wanted
to talk to you about today.
I agree with the
idea in general, but...
...do you have what it
takes to be a stripper?
I got a pretty good offer
from the Reijin Theater.
I feel a little frightened
being at the club these days.
- Have I made a mistake?
- But - listen, I...
Good day, everyone,
this is your old pal Ghost Man.
My apologies for the wait -
Act 3 is now finally
ready to be revealed.
This eagerly-awaited Act 3
features a mannequin made
at the Showa Mannequin Workshop.
And what kind of show will
this mannequin put on for us?
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
only time will tell!
If the show goes smoothly,
please show your appreciation
with thundering applause and cheers!
I repeat:
Good day, everyone,
this is your old pal Ghost Man.
My apologies for the wait -
Act 3 is now finally
ready to be revealed.
This eagerly-awaited Act 3
features a mannequin made
at the Showa Mannequin Workshop.
And what kind of show will
this mannequin put on for us?
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
only time will tell!
If the show goes smoothly,
please show your appreciation
with thundering applause and cheers!
SPECIAL PERFORMANCE - QUEEN OF
THE NUDE MODELS, AYUKO NISHIMURA
I...
...I can only think that these people
are here to watch how you're killed!
I know.
Is that all you have to
say? Foolish woman!
It doesn't matter where I go.
At least I'll be safer with
lots of people around.
I've got to earn a
living, in any case.
Ayuko...
...I'm sure my father will
listen to our predicament.
I don't think so.
I'm a nude model - a stripper.
I'm certain my father will
provide us with some money to--
Fire!
Hey! Everyone!
It's not a big fire!
Hey, listen! Calm down!
Hey! It's not a big deal!
There you are.
I decided to stay put
to avoid the rabble.
- Good idea.
- Sorry for worrying you.
Don't mention it.
Detective! It was just smoke!
They really pulled a dumb prank
this time. This is all it was.
- Show me.
-Here.
Is this one of the theater's?
Well...
...ours are much smaller.
We can't use those kinds.
You know what I think, Detective?
The theater's getting old
and run down these days -
I think some trickster just
wanted part of the action tonight.
I love these kinds of whodunit cases!
We're gonna catch this fellow for sure!
WE APOLOGIZE FOR THE DISTURBANCE
NO DAMAGE INCURRED - THE SHOW WILL CONTINUE
Yes?
Everything alright?
The girl third from the
left is pretty charming.
What's her name?
- You got eyes for her?
- She's already got 3 guys, you know.
Only 3?
Welcome.
But that's so cruel, Ayuko...!
The world's a
cruel place, you know.
You can't see it through
your naivety, though.
What a single woman has
to do to make a living...
...it's both thrilling, and terrifying.
Why, even you, Ken...
Stop talking nonsense!
I don't want your life
to be in danger!
Watch my performance carefully, Ken.
It's going to be wonderful.
They're ready for you, Ayuko.
Let's head out.
Could you get Mr. Kajiwara for me?
Yes?
Mr. Kajiwara, Ayuko sent for you.
Come in.
What is it?
Ah - I just wanted
to rehearse a bit.
Alright.
Let's see...
Huh? It's a mannequin!
Where's Kajiwara?
The manager went to look for him!
To think he'd use
a mannequin like this...
- How bizarre.
- Where's the real Ayuko, I wonder?
- Manager! Where's Kajiwara?
- I found him, but--
- Anybody else been here but you?
- No.
Looks like the
next act is starting.
Damn it!
Get her down, quick!
Ayuko!
Ayuko...Ayuko!
Hands off the crime scene!
What's this?
Wait...no!
No! It wasn't me!
Shut it.
Those three teeth are enough
to pin you to the crime.
If you please, Inspector.
Wait! No! It wasn't me!
You've got the wrong guy!
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATIONS
ROOM 6
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Here.
Alright. I was
the first Ghost Man,
but that was it!
I only threatened Keiko -
I would never kill her!
He's still out there.
Who's responsible for
the second murder, then?
- Not me, that's for sure!
- Whatever you say.
I don't care if it's one guy
or Ghostman brothers.
How'd you come up
with something like that?
As a newspaper reporter...
...I wanted to
get the best scoop.
Isn't your father working a
high position at your paper?
- Why'd you try so hard?
- That's exactly why I panicked!
I couldn't stand
disappointing my father.
"...more on that as
developments happen.
Next, the hospital escapee
and vampire Kazuhiko Tsumura,
who has the whole of
Tokyo gripped in fear,
has struck once again - this time,
the queen of the Reijin Theater, Ayuko -
despite arousing strict
vigilance amongst Tokyo police.
Due to the superb effort of the
investigation squad, however,
he was quickly arrested
afterward as prime suspect.
The culprit, Kazuhiko Tsumura, has--"
BEAUTY IN THE BATHTUB
GARDEN OF THE GROTESQUE
WOMAN BATHING
LEOPARD AND WOMAN
BALLOON AND WOMAN
BED AND WOMAN
It's your turn next.
Kind of a disappointing result.
- He's not admitting anything!
- I should think not.
- He doesn't know anything, after all.
- Huh?
He's the victim here. I asked
him to do a little job for me.
You think we're
safe releasing him?
He'll lead us to the Ghost Man
any minute now, I think.
Yes? It's for you, Mr. Kindaichi.
Yes?
What?
So he was at Yanokura!
I'll be there right away.
I'll be off then, Inspector Todoroki.
What did you do with him?
What do you plan
to do with him?
This man is getting in my way!
Let me go! Just
exactly who are you?
Everyone calls me Ghost Man.
Coward!
Kinuko!
Kinuko...do you
know what it's like?
For a man to truly
love a woman?
What? Let me go!
Let me go!
Get a good look, Doctor.
I'm going to do whatever I like
with her right in front of you!
Get off me!
I'm married, you know!
And your husband Tsumura
is a crazed maniac.
So then...
...what exactly is
that man to you?
Your lover?
I divorced Tsumura!
And he went mad as a result.
Is that what you wanted?
Why don't we see
what he thinks?
Tsumura! Tsumura!
Mind if I answer for him?
You!
I've finally seen him -
the famous Ghost Man killer.
No! The killer is Tsumura!
- We heard it all from Tsumura.
- What are you going on about?
- This man is a crazed maniac!
- And who used that maniac?
Give it up, you murderer!
Be a man and
turn yourself in.
It wasn't me!
I didn't mean to kill anyone!
Why'd you take Tsumura's
ex-wife hostage, then?
She's my girl.
I'm in love with her - she's
the one I ought to be with!
The woman that's trying to
become Dr. Kano's wife?
Tsumura's the one that
took those women!
Tsumura was known for his thirst for blood,
but you were the one pulling the strings.
You're a fiend. All in the
needless pursuit of one woman.
It wasn't me -
it was Ken Tatebe!
Ken might have
played the first prank,
but you assumed the lead role.
I know everything.
Lies! Lies!
Lies!
I'll shoot!
Throw down your gun!
This is the end of line!
FIN
subtitles by OHAKOSUBS
translation notes: ohakosubs.tumblr.com