FORBIDDEN SONGS
A SONG IS THE MAIN CHARACTER
OF THIS FILM.
NAÏVE, SIMPLE, REAL SONG.
DURING THE HARDEST DAYS OF OCCUPATION,
IT WAS ABLE TO MOCK THE ENEMY,
UPLIFT THE SPIRIT,
AND BRING SOME OPTIMISM.
AND THAT IS WHY IT DESERVED A FILM.
This song, the only song
I sing it for you, my girl
Maybe your heart full of love
Is at loss too
Maybe you keep your love in secret?
And you sob through the night?
The song, the only song
I sing it for you, my girl.
Why are you so glum?
Memories, my brother.
That is what brought us here.
It's time for celebration.
It's all over.
The occupation, the Uprising.
Pour me some, Jurek.
This song doesn't work on you, huh?
I like it.
Guys used to sing it in Scotland.
In Scotland? Very funny!
There, you could have sung
whatever you wanted!
You should have tried it
with  the Germans.
From what you're saying,
it wasn't that bad.
- Have you gone crazy?
- What is she saying?
- He;s mad!
- But you said that...
- You're a dolt!
- Wait, guys.
He got confused.
So you say it wasn't that bad
during German times?
If you were allowed to sing
such songs in public...
- in front of the Germans...
- Even the worse songs.
- You see?
- Jurek. Where are you from?
- Is that a new joke?
- It's not a joke. Answer me.
Where did you grow up?
Don't make a fool of me.
In Skawina.
You should have spent
more time in Warsaw.
And less in England.
You don't know Warsaw.
- Sorry, guys, but...
- Calm down. Stop arguing.
I'm not arguing.
You see, the situation was terrible.
You know that, even though
you were far away from here.
There were round-ups, street executions,
Majdanek, Auschwitz, Pawiak.
Each family suffered during
that time.
There was also our fight.
AL, AK, Peasants' Battalions.
And we had yet another weapon
we used in the streets of Warsaw.
You all remember it.
It was a laugh and song.
And it was a pretty good weapon
that kept our spirit up.
Oh yes!
Germans were scared to death.
- They did they best to cut it out.
- And they failed.
In Warsaw, nobody cared about
their prohibitions.
A lot of singers ended up
in Auschwitz.
- Many of them lost their lives.
- What's this lecture for?
Sit down and tell Jurek that
story you told us so many times.
How Warsaw fought against Germans
with a song.
- He is one of the heroes.
- Oh, come on!
A natural modesty.
- Play it!
- Sit down and play!
All right.
But don't you ever say that
we were doing nothing
but singing forbidden songs.
Come on, I never said that.
- You wouldn't dare!
- Sit down.
Good.
Let me warn you once again
that this is not
a national epic.
It's just a story of a forbidden song
and our memories attached to it.
Some of these memories come together.
The others create...
- Stop talking, start playing.
- Play.
Wait...
One second...
Where do I start...
No, no, no.
The beginning was different.
This is how it started.
October 1939. Germans have just
entered Warsaw.
The war is lost. Hopelessness.
Warsaw in ruins.
It's nothing compared to
the Uprising, but then we thought
it couldn't be any worse.
And the first forbidden melody came up.
The first revolt at the ruins
of the Warsaw National Philharmonic.
In the beginning, there were
few musicians. And then...
Is your brother home, miss Halinka?
- Yes. What happened?
- A very important thing.
Romek, someone to see you.
Hi, my friend. Sit down.
I don't have much time, Mr. Tokarski.
Grab your instrument!
- Where to?
- That's a laugh! Come on!
He lives a few steps from the Philharmonic,
and he can't hear it.
No wonder, since you are knocking
all the time.
Come on, sir.
And?
Can you hear it now?
The Varsovian!
- Where?
- Who is playing?
Who is playing and where?
We are playing! Varsovians!
We are not afraid of the Germans.
This is just the beginning. England
and France have just joined the war.
Hurry up! Take your instrument.
I'm coming. Mom, where's my jacket?
Halinka, give me my violin.
All right. I must move on.
Wait! I'm ready.
I have no time. I must tell the others,
including your neighbour.
Mr. Cieślak? No chance.
He is scared to death.
Come with us. Hurry up.
- To the shelter? Is it an air raid?
- What raid?
- So what happened?
- Oh, come on!
A rebellion! For destroying Warsaw,
for the philharmonic!
We're playing the Varsovian.
I'm ready. Let's go!
You will find out when you get there.
We will be waiting, Mr. Cieślak.
Mr. Neighbor, you have to!
Romek, your hat!
Aren't you going?
- Where to?
- Don't you know?
Oh, against the Germans.
With a bayonet and rifle.
And with my violin?
You are so timid.
I'm just careful.
- Come on, mom.
- Bring me my coat.
Oh! They're still playing.
God. Why put yourself at risk?
Wouldn't it be better to wait until Easter,
until the war is over?
This would be a good moment
to play the Varsovian or the Marseillaise.
Easter? What a pessimist!
Who would survive six months of the war?
It will be over for Christmas.
VALERIAN
It was not a forbidden melody.
Come one, Romek.
I can't listen to it.
You remember how they tortured us
with it?
The army, the party, even their children,
the Hitler Youth.
They loved to sing it on every occasion.
It was a special occasion.
They wanted to break us down.
They did it on purpose.
But we did not give up.
We returned with our song.
You remember?
Let's drink wine, chevau-légers...
They used to sing it before the war.
And during the occupation...
It was September, just after midnight
The power of the battle squadrons
Appeared with the hum of the engines
And turned the silent night into hell
They bombed towns and stations
While everybody was asleep
When we expected nothing
They struck a brutal blow
The defenders formed a wall
Their bayonets shone in the morning sun
When the fight felt went, they shouted
And pushed the enemy back
And then the aircraft appeared
To support its ranks
Our eagles were not there
So we have to move back
We were retreating from the city gates
Chased by the queue of tanks
There is no need to cry for the country
As this misery will not last long
Amen, our poor soldiers.
This misery will not last long.
The Krauts will fall soon, right?
Sooner than you think.
I keep saying that.
Forget about what these rags write.
They won't trick us.
We have better news.
"When the black eagle falls broken,
when he turns his eyes to the east,
Poland will reclaim
the Masurian land
and Gdansk will return.
In a vicious fight against
the Teutonic arrogance."
Enough.
- Stop it, please.
- What happened?
It's a samizdat. Burn it right away.
Their ears are everywhere.
You expect nothing, and then...
Ah, hello, neighbour!
Good morning.
I've been reading our new
prophecies to Mr. Cieślak.
Nice, isn't it?
- You are so timid!
- Careful. Just careful.
Guess what I brought, mother.
- What?
- Come on.
- Is it fixed? Really?
- It is indeed.
I am so happy.
Halinka will be delighted!
You see, this is our family heirloom.
Our mascot.
It was constructed by my grandfather
who was a watchmaker.
Just look at it.
What a beautiful piece.
Right. It's nice.
- Does it chime?
- Of course. You will hear it.
What?
The Varsovian again?
Isn't it a wonderful sound?
For God's sake! Stop it!
You will bring misfortune.
It is a forbidden melody.
It's like having radio in your house.
Aren't you exaggerating a bit?
Our neighbour is just very careful.
This is how you should live these days.
It's the only option, ma'am.
These are very dangerous things.
Dangerous? Can't you hear what
they are singing?
They are not afraid at all.
Just listen.
On September 1st
That memorable year
The hostile neighbour attacked Poland
They showed no mercy to our Warsaw
Our beloved Warsaw
They flooded you with blood
You used to be beautiful and rich
And now all I see is you dust
Churches destroyed, houses burnt down
Where your people can find shelter?
The bombs are dropping all day long
There is no water to extinguish the fire
A mother keeps seeking her child's body
She is calling God and cursing the enemy
They were torturing us like this
for more than three weeks!
God will punish the Krauts
For their awful crimes!
What I am singing now
Is just unbelievable
There will be the end of my tale
God's grace is with us
We will rebuild Poland
What are you writing?
Howdy, Halinka.
Sit down, please.
- I'm noting this song for Romek.
- This one?
He already has it.
- I thought you were writing a love letter.
- Only to you.
Black coffee, please.
How are you doing?
Bad news.
Only German successes.
All lies.
Don't believe these rags.
Alack.
The radio says the same.
It's impossible.
Do you know what they say in the city?
Food riots in Berlin.
The whole army from the Government
went there.
There is not a single soldier in Warsaw.
Only the officials.
Today, I myself saw...
Don't worry, Halinka.
Damn them all.
Cheer up.
Smile.
There will be a day when...
Beer, please.
Don't beat yourself.
It's a waste of teeth.
You see! Excuse me a moment.
- Howdy, Jurek.
- Hi.
- What's up?
- Nothing important.
- Today at 6, as always.
- Where?
- Same place as yesterday.
- Done.
- What are you writing?
- Nothing. Just like that.
- I thought you were writing a love letter.
- Only to you.
You're so lovely.
Remember it.
- By the way, this evening...
- Just as I thought.
- You are busy again.
- Are you mad at me?
- Rysiek.
- It's all right.
We can meet tonight at 8:30 PM.
Same place as yesterday.
Fräulein...
You think it's funny?
I was so afraid for you.
I had a feeling
something bad had happened to you.
Why? It's nonsense.
Can you hear it?
This melody brings misfortune.
People say wherever this busker
appears,
something bad happens.
Cursed melody?
An adult lady believes in such nonsense.
It's just a poor student.
Axe, hoe, January, booze
German and Italian lose their shoes
Axe, hoe, rope line, wire to be put
Mr. Painter is kaputt
Axe, hoe, hand saw, bay
Air raid by night, roundup by day
Axe, hoe glass, ban
Run away while you can!
Axe, hoe, gendarme, blast
Everyone is running fast
There's no need to stay in the Citadel
Or in another awful cell
Axe, hoe, hand saw, meat
This is Skaryszewska Street
Axe, hoe, hand saw, two planks, sow
We are in Skaryszewska now
How dream? How to believe?
Dogcatchers don't let us live
As in their culture it is allowed
to do this hunting in the crowd
Axe, hoe, hand saw, bay
Air raid by night, roundup by day
Axe, hoe, hand saw, blow
Take this note and let me go
If you don't have any money
You will be deported to Germany
Axe, hoe, hand saw, thinker
Here's the Prussia, there's Treblinka
We have no more place to hide
Dogcatchers lost their pride
They are running through the street
Looking for another meat
As in their culture it is allowed
To do this hunting in the crowd
There must be something wrong with them
Since they are coming after us
Axe, hoe, hand saw, stainer
The war is lost for the stupid painter
Axe, hoe, hand saw, my frau
He is losing now, now, now.
Axe, hoe, hand saw, gas, tier
When will they get out of here
Axe, hoe, electricity and gas
We will kick your ass!
But not only the lyrics
drove the Germans mad.
Even the music aggravated them
if it was Polish.
Mazur, polonaise, kujawiak.
It was all forbidden.
Forbidden melodies.
Those who came to forbidden concerts
took a huge risk.
But that didn't stop them.
They were in Poland,
even just for an hour.
It was the miracle of Chopin.
So it was worth the risk.
Such concerts lifted people's spirits.
Drag them away from the activates
with the help of which
Germans wanted to corrupt Polish slaves.
German propaganda replaced music
with some cheap tunes.
Childish entertainment instead of theatres.
Gambling in casinos.
They wanted to enslave the souls.
Why are you so happy today,
Mr. Antoni?
Great news.
I'm not interested in politics.
I don't want to hear anything!
From a certain person.
The war ends on September 15
at 3 PM.
- It's official!
- I can't hear you!
Seven Englishmen have already landed.
The end is near.
Warsaw Courier, the latest news!
- The latest news!
- Kid!
- What news?
- Hitler lost his shoes!
Long time, no see.
Welcome, my beloved friend.
Any news?
Nothing.
- Are you going to work?
- I guess so.
Did you hear?
After that, supposedly...
Radio says
that Hitler has gone mad
and it is for sure...
Quiet, for God's sake!
They hear everything.
It's too risky to even whisper
about it.
Mr. Antoni?
The latest newsletter.
Read it and pass it on.
Who is she?
The former Maria Kędziorek.
But now...
MARIE KENDSCHOREK
What a stunt.
Mr Roman?
- A cigarette.
- Here you are.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I dared to bother you.
I haven't smoked for days.
- I'm sure you understand.
- Of course.
- Would you like to take some for later?
- Thank you.
Come on.
I'm happy when I can talk
to someone.
So many months in hiding.
And that thought... that I can end up
in the ghetto at any moment.
It's terrible.
All I want is...
Excuse me.
FOR GERMANS ONLY
The enemy attacked Poland
He mucked the land
It is because,
Jesus is still asleep
God will wake up
And shout with his power:
Drop dead bloody Hitler!
For burnt cities, for burnt huts
We will kick your ass!
I am eating bread
You ate some cookies
You say you bought it
I'm sure it was stolen!
Although there are some Huns
I'm not scared to sing
Cause that bloody bastards
Don't understand a word...
Halt! Halt!
GERMAN VICTORIES ON ALL FRONTS
Stop, stop, stop!
- What are you playing?
- What's wrong?
It's c, a not cis.
What c? Can't you see a sign!
What sign?
It's a fly.
So let's start again.
Three, four!
Raging Vistula is flowing at Cracow
Dirty scumbags got comfy
On our Polish land...
For heaven's sake! What are you doing?
It's a forbidden song.
You can't even listen to it!
We will kill a pig
We will make some sausage
With these sausages
We will poison all
The German cockroaches and rats
I do not want to listen to this!
Damn it!
Where will I find new strings?
You want me to go with you?
You better stay.
It's safer when a woman goes alone.
But I don't know if
someone is in the house.
Here they are.
Good morning.
Good morning, sir.
What are you so confused?
Anything bad?
Are you going to the shelter?
Was there an alarm?
No. We're going to the countryside
to get some provisions.
What provision?
You are so timid.
I resent that.
I'm just careful.
- Here.
- Thank you very much.
You want to see my brother?
My string[s broken.
I would like to borrow one.
Romek has left.
I don't know where...
Oh, I see the case. Roman always
put his spare strings there.
Excuse me.
What happened, Mr. Cieślak?
It was the most dangerous
moment of my life.
Great job, miss.
Boys will be so happy.
I wish I could see them.
My train leaves in five minutes.
Anything for me?
Right. There's something for you.
Someone has to fix it in Warsaw.
- Burnt?
- I don't know.
- This should be replaced.
- All right.
- They asked us to hurry up.
- No problem.
It's dark outside
The train is crowded
And the idyll begins
He hugs her
She's fat as a cow
Chopped meat under her coat
Something is dripping from her heart
It's lard and pork,
Plus two hams
When he's admiring her body
Some loin falls out
With the unsalted beacon
Now there's a war
Who trades, survives
When I sell my chop
Lard, and blood pudding
I will get myself some hooch
Now there's a war
Who trades, survives
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
I will get myself some hooch
Before he finds out
What she has to sell
The train stops at the station
The gendarmes get on
They take everything
you give them
The one is searching the pockets
The other is looking on the ground
And that one is checking the packages
They took lard, chop
And black pudding
Damn them all!
Now there's a war
Who trades, survives
When I sell my chop
Lard, and blood pudding
I will get myself some hooch
Now there's a war
It's hard to live on trading
They took lard, chop
And black pudding
There'll be no hooch
Put something in the basket.
I'll but the Kraut a casket.
Now there's a war
Who trades, survives
When I sell my chop
Lard, and blood pudding
I will get myself some hooch
Now there's a war
It's hard to live on trading
They took lard, chop
And black pudding
There'll be no hooch
Violin, right?
Aber schwere. Violin.
Heavy.
Speck? Lard.
Guten Appetit. Bon appetit!
"Today is my gloomy anniversary.
Two years of hiding.
I haven't been in the streets
for two years.
For two years I haven't got close
to the window.
Good people saved me.
And if it hadn't been for them,
I would have starved to death."
My Warsaw...
I cry anytime I see you
Warsaw, my Warsaw!
In the ghetto, there is
Hunger, poverty, and cold
But the homesick is even worse, My Warsaw!
I'm sneaking across the wall
And I'm running like a chased dog!
Although, the authorities, the gendarmes
The Gestapo, and the SS are after me
My Warsaw!
There is a tear in my eye
I don't know if I will
See you tomorrow, my Warsaw!
I'm sneaking across the wall
And I'm running like a chased dog!
Although, the authorities, the gendarmes
The Gestapo, and the SS are after me
My Warsaw!
There is a tear in my eye
I don't know if I will
See you tomorrow, my Warsaw!
Although, the authorities, the gendarmes
The Gestapo, and the SS are after me
My Warsaw!
There is a tear in my eye
I don't know if I will
See you tomorrow, my Warsaw!
The red apple
Cut into cross
Why are you frowning
On me, gendarme?
Geese and duck behind the pond
They'll catch you girl cause you're young
You will give him a note
He will give you up
Look, a lady is walking with a Kraut
She's so proud
From the ghetto, her dress comes.
Father, aren't you ashamed
Of your beloved daughter?
Of course, he's not
He as well became a Volksdeuthe
Geese and duck behind the pond
You'll be a good nark cause you're young
You will give everyone up
You're useful to me, I'm useful to you
The boys from the conspiracy
Caught her at the gate
They shaved her to the skin
They didn't spare the perm
When that didn't work
They brought her some flowers
Roses in one hand
Machine guns in the other
Geese and duck behind the pond
He killed you girl though you were young
She won't give anyone up
There is no use of a dead nark...
...if this happens again,
hostages will be executed.
And now the follow-up of the massage
of the Oberkommando
der Wehrmacht.
A fierce fight is taking place
in the southern section
of the Eastern Front.
Our brave troops
are fighting against
the overwhelming forces.
Our soldiers retain their
relentless offensive spirit.
As a part of planned movements,
aimed to bounce off the enemy,
the city of Kherson was emptied...
The 1st SS Panzer Division
Leibstandarte SS Adolf Hitler
stood out during those
hard fights.
It's ready.
There is no hope for the enemies
of the new Europe.
German victory is inevitable.
Because the Führer...
Compatriots.
It's Polish Underground State.
Don't give up your hope.
Our freedom is imminent.
And now,
military and political news.
Yesterday, the Soviet troops
moved 26 km to the west
in an unstoppable attack.
246 towns were liberated.
The 1st Tadeusz Kosciuszko
Infantry Division
is engaged in the operation.
Yes?
What?
Unbelievable!
Yes, sir!
Damn it! Not again!
Halt, halt!
Is this her son?
This is your son... in the photo?
Yes. It's my son.
Where is he now?
I told you.
He didn't say where he was going.
Silence, finally.
Let sleeping dogs lie.
It was close. They were running
around the town like mad dogs.
Don't stop here.
It's always safer at home.
And your sonny is not here.
The curfew is coming.
Only Polish songs.
Can you play it?
I asked you a question.
Yes. These are my notes.
I can play it.
So play it, please.
Play!
I'm getting bored. Play something!
I don't know what.
Maybe something forbidden!
Deutschland, Deutschland
über alles! Go ahead!
- I can't.
- Now!
What are you doing?!
Play "Deutschland,
Deutschland über alles"!
Polish pig!
Hans! Sit down!
Play something usual.
Can you hear it?
This is our piano.
German melody?
What's this?
Nothing serious.
Some old woman.
What now?
We can't go home.
Of course.
Never. We have to disappear.
- That was predictable.
- We disappear together, of course.
- Absolutely not.
- Romek!
Neither you nor our mother is in trouble.
Fortunately, there is nothing
compromising at home.
Anyway, they need you here.
You know that.
Who the hell?
Wait a second.
- Rysio.
- Yes, my love?
So we have to split up.
It was bound to happen.
You think about the resistance?
I'm afraid for you. Don't laugh.
Maybe it's because our experiences
grew us together.
Our fight together.
It is, and it will always be
our common fight.
Although you are staying in Warsaw,
and we are going to the forest.
Maybe this separation
will bring us even closer.
Rysio.
And?
- Do you know who it was?
- Well?
Jurek.
They know who ratted us out.
So it was a denunciation?
Do you remember that busker
in a student hat?
Him?
You see? I told you that
this melody brings misfortune.
The girl started to cry aloud
Her eyes shined with tears
For the soldier's plight
Be quiet, our willows
Do not let heart-breaking grief
Make you cry, my girl
It is not that bad to be a partisan
We are dancing to
The music played by Stens
There are bodies everywhere
But we are not scared
Be quiet, our willows
Do not let heart-breaking grief
Make you cry, my girl
It is not that bad to be a partisan
We are dancing to
The music played by Stens
There are bodies everywhere
But we are not scared
Whether it's rain or scorching heat
- you can hear our measured footsteps...
- What's on your mind?
I'm thinking about what awaits us.
- Are you scared?
- No.
I would be sorry for Halinka if...
Why are you so girly today?
You're right, Romek.
Just keep playing.
I like it.
Fall in!
I'll play it later.
Ten of you will take care of the bridge.
The others will support them.
- Understood?
- Yes, sir!
Dismissed.
Damn it.
They should be here by now.
I don't know why they're complaining.
Maybe they are taking the whole
train on their backs.
- Krauts.
- You think so?
Follow me!
31 JULY 1944
1 August 1944
Where have you been?
Everything's fine, mum.
I've been waiting for so long.
- Dinner is in the oven.
- Thank you.
- What are you looking for?
- Nothing.
You seem so strange today.
Why are you dressed like that?
- Hala, we are waiting for you.
- I'm coming!
- Are you leaving again?
- I have to, mommy.
What's wrong? I'm so scared.
You sound like Mr. Cieślak.
Goodbye, mom.
I have an appointment.
I heard that Romek and Rysiek are back.
- Romek? Wait!
- Later, mommy!
Where are you going, Mr. Cieślak?
What are you doing here?
Can't you see?
Yes, but you have always been so...
- Careful, you meant to say.
- Right.
Nothing has changed.
Germans know everything.
I guess so.
Aren't you scared?
Me?
Boys, come here!
Tanks are coming from the station!
Destroy them!
Jesus Christ!
They're coming at us!
Can you hear them playing?
I wish their chests would play like this.
- What's going on up there?
- It's all fine and dandy, sir.
We came to breathe some fresh air.
Will they survive?
Don't be upset. Everything is fine,
seriously.
And you sob through the night?
The song, the only song
I sing it for you, my girl
It broke out from a young chest
In a great internal struggle
And followed the army
Someone's heart full of love
A soldier was marching along the road
He felt sorry for this little heart
So he put in his backpack
And he kept moving
The song, the only song
I sing it for you, my girl
Maybe your heart full of love
Is at loss too
Maybe you keep your love in secret?
And you sob through the night?
The song, the only song...
- Romek!
- Howdy, Halinka!
I finally found you!
You look nice!
I feel great.
I'm just a little tired.
Sit down.
How's mum?
Very good so far.
But where's Rysiek?
Don't cry, Halinka.
I'm not crying. I'm singing.
The song, the only song
I sing it for you, my girl
The Uprising was over.
And the song of Warsaw went silent.
And the crowds of the exiles were
only followed by the mournful chords
of its last song called
"With the smokes of Fires".
Radio speakers used to sing it to us
during the last days the of the Uprising
as a consolation...
Pruszków... Pruszków...
Train to Oświęcim...
Detrain...
Aussteigen... Birkenau... Oświęcim...
Dachau...
- Aussteigen...
- Calm down!
- Birkenau... Oświęcim...
- Quiet...
- Dachau...
- Hush, hush...
Detrain...
- Aussteigen! -
- Franuś, calm down!
- Aussteigen...
- Quiet, quiet...
Yes. It is a miracle that we did not
go mad as he did.
Thank you. That's enough.
So many killed. So many crippled.
The hell on Earth.
Pruszków... Pruszków...
Detrain... aussteigen...
Thank you, madam.
Mr. Antoni!
Mrs. Halinka!
You're alive!
Yes, for now.
We'll see...
Our tenement house turned
into a pile of debris.
Yes. I saw it.
I am the only survivor.
Your mum was right to move
to her relatives
in Poznańska Street a week before.
Is she here?
Would you like some hot coffee?
No. Thank you.
You need it more than me.
It's not for me. It's for the sick man.
You know him. It's the musician
who used to visit you.
He's lying there.
And you are here too!
Don't get up.
We did good out there, huh?
I can't even dream about my violin.
Each man has his own misfortunes.
- Ten or more.
- Thank you.
I can't believe you didn't go
into captivity!
To the Germans? Voluntarily?
I prefer the incertitude about the future.
And Roman? How is he?
He got to the other side of Vistula,
to his men.
That's good.
Can you hear it?
Their cannons are playing on Praga.
Our cannons.
Fire!
And then, a wonderful return
from Warsaw to Berlin.
With a forbidden song on our lips.
It was not forbidden anymore.
The song is free, just as we are,
just as Warsaw is.
Well, guys?
The song, the only song
I sing it for you, my girl
Maybe your heart full of love
Is at loss too
Maybe you keep your love in secret?
And you sob through the night?
The song, the only song
I sing it for you, my girl
From beyond the mountains and rivers
We got to the shore
How far we are to
The singing willows, lovely fields?
Yesterday rag, Today a uniform
Tighten your belt. It's time to go!
Ahead our First Corps!
From beyond the mountains to the West!
THE END