The Toho Company
A KATSU PRODUCTION
Executive Producers
SHINTARO KATSU KOZEN NISHIOKA
Screenplay by MINORU INUZUKA
Photographed by FUJIO MORITA
Starring
SHINTARO KATSU
KIWAKO TAICHI
KYOKO YOSHIZAWA
JOJI TAKAGI
TOMOO KOIKE
KATSUO NAKAMURA
Directed by SHINTARO KATSU
Blind man.
There are holes here and there.
Be careful.
Thank you.
I like the sound of the samisen.
Where are you going?
I have no destination.
I travel like the wayward wind.
And you?
I'm going to Choshi to see my daughter.
I heard Choshi is a busy town.
Many geisha houses in the red light area.
Do you by chance know one
called the Ogiya?
What's a blind man got to do
with geisha houses?
Goodbye.
Wait.
It's just my compliment. Don't be offended.
You give me money?
Thank you very much. I'm happy to accept it.
What's happened?
Why did he do it?
ZATOICHI IN DESPERATION
Would you tell me where to find the Ogiya?
I'll take you.
You know the Ogiya?
Yes.
Welcome! We've been talking about you.
Please come in.
Okimi!
Bring Namiji immediately. Get moving!
Is this the Ogiya?
Yes.
I came to see a girl that works here.
Her mother plays the
samisen.
A samisen player?
Name?
Welcome sir. Come on in.
Have a great time!
Age?
I don't know.
Hometown?
I don't know that either.
You don't know anything.
Are you trying to kid me?
I'm busy. Don't bother me.
What's this?
Thank you!
Her mother's name?
Look at this.
It says Nobu.
That's her mother's name.
Nice name.
Come in. I'll look for her.
Is the girl a geisha?
Maybe.
Aren't you sure?
Terrible, isn't it.
There are seventeen geishas
and thirteen maids here.
Am I supposed to ask them,
"What's your mother's name?"
Nobody'll come here.
You can say you're waiting for a customer.
Bedding.
It smells the same in every inn.
Ten men a night!
Don't try too hard.
It won't do any good.
Is her daughter a prostitute?
Was she going to buy back her daughter?
How'd you get here?
Over the fence.
I missed you.
I've a customer.
They'll look for me. I'll call for help.
I'm dying! Dying!
Nishikigi!
What's this?
I got it gambling.
Come to me openly next time.
What a show!
I want to feel like I'm dying too.
Nishikigi is her name.
We're back.
Thank you.
Come in.
Where was she?
In a cheap inn in Yokachiba.
I'm glad you brought her back.
Have some fun here tonight.
Some troublemaker you are!
You can't run away from here.
Didn't you know?
Don't scold her here.
Be careful.
Bring some water.
Wash them.
My term is over. Why can't I go home?
Don't you know? You're still in debt.
That's a lie.
Lie?
You mean I'm a liar?
Lock her up.
No! Don't torture me!
Forgive me!
Sister!
Don't come here.
When will you be back?
Tomorrow.
Honestly?
Take this and go home.
Coming.
I'm glad to have a girl.
Try to be nice.
You amaze me.
You have an eye for girls.
Nishikigi is beautiful.
Zatoichi!
A blind man who wants a geisha?
Boss lioka would give you 100 ryo for his head.
Big money!
Thank you.
You sound young. How old are you?
Fourteen.
Your mother?
She's dead.
Any relatives?
I've a brother.
Don't peek in my room.
Behave yourselves.
You loved me at first sight?
Where?
Not exactly. I like your voice.
"Love at first voice."
Can it be true?
About your mother, did she play a samisen?
I heard her play it when I was a child.
Will you have a look at this?
Look.
It says Nobu.
My mother's name. You know her?
Not exactly, but...
Give me a cup of tea.
I met her on the way... near Sakura...
She fell into the river.
Into the river? My mother?
Were you, at all, responsible for her death?
How much should I pay
if I want to redeem you?
Why do you ask?
Your geishas are coming.
You can bite them or lick them.
They're all yours.
We lick them?
No thanks.
You can be sure they won't give us nice girls.
We'd be better off getting Zatoichi.
20 ryo each for his head.
He's a blind man.
We'll go to lioka anyway. Take his head.
And we'll get 100 ryo.
That's my idea of good business.
You know I'm Zatoichi, don't you?
Don't you talk to blind people?
This wasn't my intention.
What was your intention then?
Not my net.
Take my wife instead. Take her as payment.
Odd or Even.
How old is she?
Over forty, but...
Beautiful?
What good is your homely wife?
Bring money, and you'll have it back.
Go home.
Will you let me play as banker?
You're blind. Can you handle dice?
I'm blind, but I have two hands
to handle them.
Alright. Let's have a go.
Dice box.
Don't use your private dice.
The 'man' character for one?
Peculiar dice.
Forgive my lack of skill, please.
That's fine.
Place your bets.
Three ryo?
One is enough.
Evens. Evens.
Three ryo on even.
Why don't you bet on odd?
Alright.
Even.
Look. All of you.
I have more.
Bet all the money you have.
That's gambling.
Everyone bets on odd?
No one on even?
No bets on even.
Oh, they rolled out of my sleeve.
Odd or even?
No answer.
Then it must be even.
'Man' and 'man'. Even.
I won.
Thank you.
Wait. Strange.
Where are your dice?
I have them in my sleeve.
You cheat! You hustled us!
You dirty blind ass!
You know where you are?
I thought I was in a gambling party
with dishonest men.
Did you bet on the dice outside
the dice box?
That's a funny way to dice.
You're supposed to bet on the dice in the dice box.
You must be asking for trouble.
I'll teach you.
Beat him up!
Give my money back!
Get off him.
You're Zatoichi! Aren't you?
Did you have fun?
Who are you?
I'm Mangoro, the boss.
You could pay your respects.
My compliments.
Buy yourself a drink.
Get back to the game.
What brought him here?
Boss lioka wants us to stop him
if he shows up.
Don't worry.
It's a good thing he's blind.
Leave it to me.
So his price is 100 ryo.
Are you tired?
They say blind men are passionate in bed.
Passionate or not,
I don't even know if
he can make love, so far.
You mean he didn't touch you?
Twenty... Thirty...
This will be enough for her ransom.
The mistress is waiting for you.
I'll be right there.
Thank you for coming.
Nishikigi told me you want to redeem her.
Is that honestly true?
That's right.
That's very nice. But she's our best geisha.
How much?
Fifty ryo!
Give me the bond.
Of course. Right away.
What are you doing?
I told you to give him a cushion.
This is the bond for her service.
Check it.
Let's go somewhere far away.
No. They'll catch me and beat me.
You too, Shinkichi.
They won't. We'll go down into the sea.
The sea?
We'd drown.
I don't mind dying if we're together.
When my term is over, we'll live together.
It's only three years.
Some day we'll live together.
Then we'll build a grave
for Father and Mother.
What's that?
Does it make you feel sexy?
I'll teach you how.
You dirty little moron.
Hurry!
Old man.
What do you think you're doing?
Did you use this boat?
It's mortgaged, remember?
If you want to use it, clear your debt first.
He doesn't. Teach him a lesson.
You forced my son to gamble
and swindled him.
What can a fisherman do without a boat?
It's been a long time.
I've been dying to see vou.
You're as charming as ever.
No joking. But I believe you.
Kaedé. Greet him.
She's nice.
I feel great. I like a good fire.
You came at the right time.
You can't burn our boats...
...just because we don't work for you.
How can we live without boats?
Don't say that. Let's go.
If you have any complaints, speak up.
My sword is listening.
We'll make it even. Pick them up.
Come on, pick up the weapons.
Draw them!
You did it!?
What's this?
Brat! Come here!
Devil!
You want a fight?
Kill them all!
You wrote you need 500 ryo...
...so I brought it immediately.
That's really good of you.
I'll borrow your 500 ryo.
He's backing you. Remember that.
I'm looking forward to your success.
Leave it to me.
This money helps me establish
my new business.
You're planning to catch tuna fish, whales...
...and whatever else you can.
You've monopolised fishing around here.
You're a shrewd businessman.
The fishermen's small boats and nets
are useless.
It's all over for them.
They'll have to work for me for low wages.
I'll be able to make eighty ryo a day.
Bring the girl.
Hurry up!
Greet him.
Pour him a drink.
What'll you use my money for?
I'll bribe Mr. Hosomi, the magistrate.
What're you doing? You drink it.
So you're smart enough to
rope the magistrate in.
She's too young. I'll drink it for her.
Fool!
Take her away!
Don't interfere!
She's nice.
She's a rare cherry.
It's true.
What is it?
A firefly.
In front of you.
It's glowing!
You smell nice.
You only smell? Can't you see?
I'm sorry.
I know you're beautiful.
I know, even if I'm blind.
Ever had a wife?
She ran away?
Love me.
It's no good if you don't have eyes.
Goodnight.
Sleepy?
Asleep?
Asleep or awake? Who knows?
Ushi!
Why did you let him redeem you?
But you couldn't raise the fifty ryo.
My money was included.
He cheated.
He's a notorious gambler called Zatoichi.
Boss lioka is offering 100 ryo for his head.
Goddamn it.
The thought of you in bed with him
breaks my heart.
Damn it! Can't I do something?
Stupid! I never slept with him.
Try me.
True?
You're all mine.
Nobody else can have you.
Welcome home.
I bought a fish.
Oh really?
What's that?
The fish.
A male fish.
Let's eat him.
Yes! Why don't we?
I'd lose face if I didn't help you.
Zatoichi is blind.
We can kill him by ourselves.
But we didn't want to disturb
your town on our own.
We must kill him no matter what.
We'll avenge our pal.
The four of us join together...
...we won't fail to kill him.
Well, I'll go with you.
Thank you.
I'll see how he kills you.
If they can't kill him, I've got nothing to lose.
I'll get his head anyway.
Why did you redeem me?
You don't even touch me.
I want you to live like an ordinary woman.
"Ordinary?"
How?
Without a man?
Without a way of earning money?
You can have a man.
Which one?
The one who can see?
Or the one who can't?
And then?
The child will grow up, have a child...
The child will grow up...
No kidding.
I'm asking why you redeemed me.
Because you killed my mother?
It's for your sake.
Not for mine or other people's.
It's your conscience.
I don't like it.
Take me back to the geisha house.
You raised the money by gambling.
Blind man.
You want to see the colour of...
...your blood?
Don't joke.
I couldn't see my blood whether it
was red or black.
I have no grudge against you.
Do I have to fight?
We'll be damned if we don't avenge our pal.
It was his own fault.
Shut up!
If we don't kill you, we'll lose face.
Lose face and live long.
See that you don't lose your lives.
How beautiful. It's very you.
You're a very lucky girl.
Using Nishikigi's room!
You should be grateful.
And...
Do whatever the man wants you to do.
Learn it with your body.
Understand?
Kaedé! Otsuné wants you.
Go.
Kaedé! Your brother is...
...dead!
I heard it just now, that he was dead.
We'll be together forever.
I think I'll help you get married to Nishikigi.
You love her, don't you?
But the blind man has her.
It's hot!
Yes.
She loves you too.
She prefers men who can see
to those who can't.
What'll I do?
When Zatoichi is making love...
...to her tonight, we'll kill him.
If you help us, I'll give you...
...fifty ryo.
Fifty ryo?
Yes.
So talk her into taking the job.
A letter from Boss lioka.
Idiot! Don't poke your nose in.
Ino.
It's from Boss lioka.
He's coming tomorrow to take Zatoichi's head.
Will he come here?
Great!
If you kill Zatoichi, you'll be as famous
as the boss.
Then I'll get even with Boss lioka.
Your dream will come true.
Idiot!
Why do I have make love to him
in your presence?
I don't like it.
But I'll bear it to marry you.
If I make love to him once, I'll be free?
Yes. And once you're free, we'll be married.
Who said so?
Boss Mangoro. No two ways about it.
Mangoro?
Can you rely on his promises?
Take me to Nishikigi.
Why do I have to be tied up?
Ushi! Where's Zatoichi?
Good of you to come, Zatoichi.
Gamblers should live humbly...
...in the shadows of honest people.
We shouldn't try for a place in the sun.
But you've abused honest people...
...and you're walking in the sun.
Maybe I've gone a little too far.
Let's have a joke and a drink together.
Nishikigi. Come here.
Go!
You can't see her.
She's tied to a post.
If you want to take her back,
you'll drop the stick.
Alright. Don't drop the stick.
Help me. Please help me.
What'll you do?
Next time, she'll die.
Do it!
Wait!
Untie her.
Put your hands on this table.
I'll have them smashed.
Ushi. I'll let you do it.
Those hands caressed her.
You do it.
Without a stick, you can't cross
the river to hell.
You can't use a sword anymore.
Give him the stick.
I'll take Nishikigi to you tomorrow.
Ushi. You guided him to this place.
Alright. Go ahead.
Alone.
To hell!
You want to join him?
I'll go back...
...to the Ogiya...
That's better.
Money still counts in this world.
You can still work.
Zatoichi is going to die. Enjoy the show.
It's my gift to you Boss lioka.
Zatoichi! How are your hands?
Mangoro is here, waiting and eager.
Come out!
What are you doing? Kill the monster!
Get moving!
Fight, you damn fools!
You go!
Let me in. I'm Mangoro. Open the door!
Please. Keep away.
Forgive me.
I said forgive me!
THE END