Here, boy.
I want Stripes, please.
Good choice, lady.
Very smooth.
Gum, so your
husband not kiss ashtray.
I'm not married yet.
Thanks, boy.
- What's your name?
- Ziko.
Ziko.
- Bye.
Hey!
Police, police!
Police!
Come kiss ass!
Churchill!
♪♪
boy: Churchill! Churchill!
man: He is.
class: He is.
man: She is.
class: She is.
man: We are.
Again.
He is.
class: He is.
man: She is.
class: She is.
man: We are.
class: We are.
man: They are.
class: They are.
man: He was.
class: He was.
man: She was.
class: She was.
man: We were.
class: We were.
man: They were.
class: They were.
man: You are.
class: You are.
Excellent.
Eh, Fahed, read.
Fahed.
Sir, sir, I have a question!
Your pilot is here,
come get him!
Welcome to Palestine Plaza
Hotel.
What is your name?
Your army's
moving troops north.
Are they planning
to visit us?
They will find me.
Then they will
destroy this place.
It is already destroyed.
man: I'll say it one
last time.
You will tell us everything you
know, understand?
Do you understand?
man: Ow!
Don't be a hero.
I'll be back.
Hey.
Palestinian Pele.
Segaya.
You speak English, huh?
Cigarette.
What is
your name?
You don't understand?
Your name?
You bombed here
seven days ago--
I don't know.
Where is
here?
Where are we?
Who is Alana--
- This her?
- Give me that.
She your wife?
Give me that.
She has
biggest ass.
She look like a cow.
Why don't you
shut up?
What this say?
Toilet.
Take me to the
toilet, please.
Hey!
What?
What it is?
Your map is
not right.
That is Israel.
Your brain is not right.
It's "Falestine."
There is no Falestine.
There are Palestinians.
And when we go home,
we make it Falestine again.
Who will go?
Him and me.
We go down this way,
in from here.
I come too?
You'll never get
past the border.
The fences are ten meters high.
We climb them.
They're electrified.
We dig under
them.
They're built on solid rock.
Swim around them!
You are
not coming.
Yes, I am and so is
Churchill!
You're taking
the dog?
It's Palestinian dog.
The border guards
have dogs this big.
They will eat your Palestinian
half-breed for breakfast.
Pele.
Let me out.
I'll take you with me.
I can get you in.
You and your
Palestinian dog.
Stay in your cage.
Fucking
terrorists.
We must kill all
the terrorists.
Put it down!
I said put
it down!
Put it down or
I'll break his neck.
Put it down.
Now get
the keys.
Get me the keys!
Do it!
Please.
Please
leave him.
He's my only brother.
That little
fucker.
He's crazy.
I want
a doctor.
I need a doctor,
you understand?
Relax.
I am a doctor.
You will be fine.
Just let me
do my work.
Is he your son?
He's
a good boy.
Move that thing away,
you fucker.
Shh!
I'll free you!
What?
Get me past border.
Make deal.
What deal?
You say you'll take me to
border if I free you, no?
Yes or no?
Yes.
Okay.
Deal.
You put clothes now.
This way.
Come, we make shortcut.
The American embassy.
You know
where it is?
We are going to border.
No, you take me
to the embassy now.
You are taking me to--
You do what
I say.
You understand?
Now get up!
Get up!
Get me the key!
Where is it?
Where is the key?
No!
Don't swallow it!
Open!
Shit!
Stupid.
Stupid boy.
Can't --
without your F-16.
Come here!
How do you say,
"American Embassy Please"?
How do you say it?
How do you say,
"Have a nice day?"
Okay.
You American?
Yes.
American.
Take me to
the embassy, please.
North Beirut is closed from,
pssh, pssh, shooting.
You go tomorrow.
No, I need
the embassy now.
You have a problem, sir?
Aboudi helps.
Aboudi drive taxi long time.
There's nothing Aboudi no
see before.
Oh, you get a Lebanon
girl pregnant.
And her brother
is looking for you?
You steal something?
Kill somebody?
Come on, man,
this Beirut, I see before.
The border.
Just take me
to the border.
Okay.
- We'll go Syria.
- No.
I want to go south.
Take me to
the border south.
No, no, no, no, no.
Nobody go to that border.
I'll give you $500.
600.
I'm thinking.
You're not American, no--
How much
do you want?
You pay American dollar?
Yes.
I will pay you
at the border.
3,000 American dollar.
Fine, go.
You know I'm thinking now,
it's a long way and a lot of
militia and checkpoints.
Maybe it will cost you
like 4,000 American dollar.
Deal.
Just go.
Okay.
We go now.
They kill everybody here.
Welcome to
Beirut.
Yoni: Stop.
Aboudi: What?
We must go back.
No, we must
go to border.
We have deal.
I forgot
something.
Turn around, I'll give
you $200 more.
Go home.
You shouldn't
be here.
Get out of here.
What are
you doing?
I said go home!
Militia!
Aboudi: Who is this
boy?
Yoni: I don't know,
get rid of him.
Aboudi: Move!
Shit!
Yoni: What's he
saying?
Let's get out of here,
come on!
Aboudi no
see this before.
Just drive.
Drive.
♪♪
Aboudi: Good song.
Staying alive!
♪♪
Aboudi sings
good, yeah?
Yeah...
♪ Ah ah ah ah staying
alive staying alive ♪
♪ Ah ah ah ah staying alive
Nobody's safe here.
What's going on?
Palestinians.
Those sons of bitches act
like they own this country.
But no problem, sir, we go.
No, get out,
they look for you.
Where are
you going?
- My money!
- Wait!
Just wait for us.
After the checkpoint.
How I find?
Where I find you?
Find us.
You will get your money.
Aboudi: How I find you?
What is the tree for?
Why did you
bring it?
What is that?
The key to Jerusalem?
The key to our house
in Falestine.
There is
no house.
There is no Falestine.
Don't you get
that?
Did it come out?
The key?
Did it come
out?
Go check.
Hey.
They didn't teach you to rub
two sticks together
in terrorist school?
Hey! Hey!
Wake up!
We need to
move now!
Let's go!
Come on!
Come on,
come on.
Fahed: I don't swim!
Yoni: Just hold
onto me!
Now!
♪♪
Come on,
let's go.
Aboudi: Do you want to
find doctor?
Yoni: No-- Turn right.
I said south.
Where are
you going?
Aboudi: You don't
trust Aboudi?
Aboudi take care of you.
Yoni: Why are
you turning?
What is this place?
What are you
doing?
Aboudi: Your Air Force make very
good business for them.
Don't worry, sir.
If you give money now,
I give discount.
I told you.
You will get your money
at the border, right?
Hey, leave
the kid alone.
Hey!
Shit.
man on radio: ...after
the Argentinean destroyer
General Belg--
was torpedoed by
HMS Concora--
with the loss of 368 lives.
British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher announced that the
attack was justified.
We must go.
woman: How may
I help you?
Come, we go now.
woman: American embassy,
how may I help you?
Shit.
Syrian whores--
Everybody come
shoot in Lebanon.
Shit.
He's coming.
What?
What's
going on?
Where are
you going?
Necklace, now.
You help Aboudi, yes?
You pay more?
What about my
money, huh?
Aboudi no
deserve this.
Everybody -- Aboudi.
We must get off
this road.
You want I drive?
Let me drive.
Let me drive!
You see?
You should let
me drive.
Let me see.
You did this
to me.
Don't forget.
Thank you.
I come back soon.
♪♪
Where did you
learn that from?
That was good work.
Terrorist school.
I think it's time
I know your name.
Fahed.
I'm Yoni.
Help me up.
Okay.
Let's move.
So Fahed.
Where is
this key?
It didn't come out yet?
No, Yoni,
it didn't come out.
Yoni: Gas-- more gas.
Yes!
Woo!
Good work.
Come.
We'll go get
your things.
Shit!
Go, come on!
You don't know
what a handbrake is?
Huh?
You want to tell me
about the tree now?
What's so special about it?
Okay,
fine.
You don't want to talk
about it, so don't.
Fahed!
Come on!
Five shots.
Winner gets
the dead camel.
Shit.
You shoot
like girl.
Just finish your shots.
Where are
you going?
Ow!
Now we're even.
Hey.
Looking for this?
Fahed: You come on
American F-16.
You go back
on Falestinian F-16.
What this say--
"Boy."
- Boy or girl?
- Boy.
You no make boy.
Shut up.
I only make
boy.
Will he be in
Air Force, too?
You don't choose
the Air Force.
The Air Force chooses you.
What?
"The best to the
Air Force."
Are you in trouble
for crashing plane?
I didn't crash it.
There was nothing
I could do.
How it feel to jump out?
It knocks your balls up your
nose.
Will they make
you pay?
No.
So who will pay?
The Americans.
Come on,
boy.
Come on-- good donkey.
How do you piss?
Hmm?
In F-16?
Use a bottle or
a pouch.
Or, you know.
A diaper.
I have never used it,
okay?
It's a short trip.
I go in, do my
mission and go home.
Go over here.
Border.
It's beautiful.
It is.
But you still have
to get there.
You want to play?
Let's see
what you've got.
Oh, not bad.
Not bad?
You call Ziko
not bad?
Go, go!
Ah, he's going
for the gold!
Stop!
Fahed, stop!
Don't move!
Do not move!
Stay!
Don't move.
You understand
where we are?
It's a minefield.
A little movement
can set it off.
What the hell is
wrong with you?
What did I just say?
I not care,
I want my tree--
Hey, it's just a tree.
Forget it.
No, I want my tree!
Okay,
okay.
I'll get it.
Crazy kid.
- Hey!
- Hey, over here!
Hey, it's electrified.
Get down.
They are not
ten meters high.
And where is the dog that
will kill Churchill, huh--
Yoni.
Thanks.
You're a long
way from--
Okay, thank you.
Okay.
Can I check you?
Can I take your
temperature?
No?
Okay.
It's yours?
You are Ziko,
right?
Platini is my favorite.
You know him?
Okay.
I hope
they are your size.
I'll get someone to
take you to the shower.
I not want shower.
Okay.
I'll come to you.
We work very closely with--
And I know the director,
he's a very good man.
Can he guarantee Fahed's
safety, after what he did?
Can he do this?
Then I'm not
sending him back.
Ilan--, say something.
Ilan: Yoni, the boy belongs
with his parents.
You okay?
Wow.
You look good, Fahed.
When are we going to--
That's Lieutenant Leclair.
She's with Una.
- She will guarantee you--
- I know who she is!
We make deal.
Look, Fahed,
this is for the best.
You will see.
You promised
to get me in.
Me and Churchill!
Leclair: Who is
Churchill?
His dog.
I knew this
would happen.
There's nothing I can do.
I'm sorry, Fahed.
You are
all the same.
You will be safe.
I will make
sure of that.
Sleeping at
Unifill--
Just dropping
the boy there.
I'll be back later.
Count the beats of my
heart until you return.
The kid!
Whoa,
whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa!
man: Fahed!
Leclair: Fahed!
What are you doing?
Come back here!
Don't be stupid,
Fahed!
Fahed: Leave me alone,
fucking alone!
Leclair: Fahed!
Come back
here!
Don't be stupid!
Take it easy,
guys, he's only a boy.
Slowly, slowly,
slowly&
♪♪
Hello?
Woman: Major--
It's Lieutenant Leclair.
I'm sorry, but we have
a problem with Fahed.
He-- to see you and he won't
speak to anyone else.
Can you come here?
Is he okay?
He is.
But he's sad.
When are they sending
him to Beirut?
Today.
We'll reunite him
with his grandfather.
His grandfather?
Why?
His parents
are dead.
I think this
belongs to you.
It is my baba's tree.
From our land.
Before we can take it
home to plant it, he die.
Nail bomb.
Four
weeks ago.
Are you sure you want
to do this?
I need 24
hours with him.
We'll be okay.
man: Hey, hey, hey!
Yoni, Yoni!
So what's the plan?
Where do we find
this village of yours?
I don't know.
Great.
So, left or right?
Left, I think.
You think?
We'll go right.
It's --
No.
What stupid map
is this?
Fahed!
♪♪
Where we go now?
To a fancy hotel.
It's runway 11.
The other is 9.
This is where he took off.
My baba--
Major --
Killed in action,
June 7th, 1967.
How old you were?
A little
older than you.
And you
miss him?
All the time.
I miss my
baba, too.
Listen, Fahed.
I have to take
you back.
We're not gonna find it.
Stop, stop,
tell him to stop!
- What?
- Bus 271!
It's going to--
Stop it!
That's the express,
it goes to Tiberius.
No, it stop in--
It doesn't stop
anywhere.
♪♪
Fahed: Turn, left,
turn, left!
Yoni: What? Where?
There's
nothing here.
Here, here,
I know it's here.
Where?
Down.
Down, down,
it's okay, I know.
- Where are we going?
- Down, down.
Go right,
go right.
Are you sure?
Yes, go to the big tree,
my baba told me about it.
- Stop, stop!
- Why here?
Stop, just stop!
Where there's a cactus,
there is village.
♪♪
Fahed: My baba was
right about the stars.
Yoni: It's beautiful.
♪♪
What's that?
Some herb.
For--
For who?
My grandfather.
♪♪
Good,
Fahed, good.
Do you want to stay?
If I can find a way,
do you want to stay?
Will-- come?
And Hassan--
And
Churchill?
You're taking
the dog, huh?
He is Palestinian dog.
I know,
I know.
Absolutely.
He's a Palestinian dog.
Yoni.
Will you
come visit me?
That depends.
Are you
behaving yourself?
♪♪
Leclair: Okay, --
man: Thank you very much,
good bye.
Hello, Fahed.
Thank you,
Lieutenant.
Thank you, Major.
I will tell him it's from
the Palestinian Ziko.
He will love it.
Leclair: Fahed,
we must go.
Maybe next, I will not
shoot you in the ass.
Hey.
Look after yourself.
Go.
♪♪