When I first came to Sing Sing
and I went to B Block...
it's just like this feeling
that came over me.
It was dark. It was dirty.
It was gloomy.
And I remember that night
silently crying in my cell.
I was like, "Oh, man.
What did I do to myself?"
"What am I going to do with my life?
I got 20 years."
"What am I going to do?"
I remember my son coming up one time.
And he said he wanted to talk to me.
He didn't want me to get upset.
He just wanted to tell me...
that he doesn't like it
when people talk bad about his dad.
It makes him feel sad.
But he told me not to worry,
because it was just words.
And he was, like, eight or nine
at the time.
But he was telling me,
you know, it's just words.
And I knew then
that I had to do some...
I had to give them something
to hold onto, to stand on.
My mom...
She received
a lot of undue criticism...
because of the choices that I made.
Never once had she ever told me
to break the law.
Never once did she ever tell me...
to put my ambitions or my desires
above anyone else.
But when I came to prison...
even my own family was like,
the whole world was like...
"She did something wrong."
And I had to find a way to fix that.
I had to find a way...
to show her that she didn't do
anything wrong...
that she raised a good son.
He just made some very bad decisions.
I was in the bed one night.
And a poem came to mind,
Langston Hughes' poem, Harlem...
a dream deferred.
And I feel that
it described my whole life.
I know what happens
to a dream that's deferred.
It is not dead. It's not over.
It doesn't cease to exist.
It's just deferred,
waiting for its point in time.
I remember my mom always
talking about me going to college.
I remember my cousins
always calling me a professor...
because I wore glasses
when I was younger.
So I decided to give it a try.
I mean, all through my life...
I tried everything else
that was negative.
So I thought I'd give it a try.
And here, they can take away
our property, our personal property.
They can take away your radio.
They can even confine you
to your cell.
But nobody can take away your degree.
That's yours forever.
That's something that you did.
You accomplished that.
And it's something that, you know,
your parents, your children...
can always look at on the wall
and say, "That's my dad."
Are you in that class?
All right, go in and sit down.
Hudson Link is a school
within a school.
It's a part of Mercy College.
And the students get a diploma
from Mercy College...
that is exactly the same.
Their diploma
just says Mercy College.
We teach the very same things that
we teach in the normal campuses...
at Dobbs Ferry or Manhattan
or White Plains or the Bronx.
It's just that it's at Sing Sing
instead of at the main campus.
But it's the very same classes,
the same teachers...
the same syllabus,
better students.
That's the biggest difference,
You walk into the classroom.
They're all in place.
They've done the reading.
They're prepared.
And they're excited and interested.
And they really want to discuss
what they've read.
As a teacher, it's great.
So tonight, we're doing
Raisin in the Sun.
And I know all of you read it.
So you know, my day classes,
I assign them one act at a time.
And maybe they get through
half of one act at a time.
A Raisin in the Sun is about a family
living on the south side of Chicago.
There's a matriarch, Mama Lena.
And she has a son, Walter Lee,
and his wife, Ruth.
Walter Lee's a chauffeur.
Ruth is a domestic servant.
Mama's always been
a domestic servant.
And as the play begins, they're about
to come into 10,000 dollars.
So let's start
by just talking about...
a little bit of background
on this play.
- Who's it by? What's it about?
- Lorraine Hansberry.
Okay, Lorraine Hansberry.
And where did she get the title
of the play, A Raisin in the Sun?
From Langston Hughes.
Yeah, how does that poem go?
Does anybody know?
"What happens to a dream deferred?"
"Does it dry up
like a raisin in the sun?"
"Or fester like a sore
and then run?"
Langston Hughes has a poem
that means a lot to these students.
It's called Harlem
or A Dream Deferred...
because their dreams are deferred
for a long time.
And it goes, "What happens
to a dream deferred?"
"Does it dry up
like a raisin in the sun?"
"Or fester like a sore
and then run?"
"Does it stink like rotten meat...
or crust and sugar
over like a syrupy sweet?"
"Does it sag like a heavy load,
or does it explode?"
So she could've taken
any of those images, right?
Why didn't she call it fester like
a sore or stink like rotten meat?
She called it A Raisin in the Sun.
Why, Raymond?
Because in the play, the dreams
that the main characters set out...
to achieve didn't get achieved.
And it kind of got dried up.
It dries up, but it's not rotten.
You still could eat it.
How long can you keep that raisin?
How long will it be good?
- Indefinitely.
- Forever.
Forever, indefinitely, forever.
And that's why she chose that.
Because the dreams
of the African Americans...
that she talks about in this play
have been deferred for a long time.
But they're not destroyed.
A lot of the tension in the play
stems from...
what are they going to do
with the money?
Mama has had this 40-year dream
of getting out of that apartment...
and moving into a house.
And Walter is desperate
to start a business.
Mama, look. Old Willy Harris
put everything on paper.
The lawyers just looked at it,
and everything is fine.
Son, I think you ought to talk
to your wife.
- I'll go out, leave you all alone.
- I'll talk to her later, Mama.
- Look, listen... Please.
- Son!
Will somebody listen to me today?
I don't allow no yelling in this
house, Walter Lee and you know it.
And there isn't going be
no investing in no liquor store.
That's his hope for his dream.
He's always scheming
on trying to make extra money...
trying to be this entrepreneur...
and break the mold of the
African American during that time...
during World War II.
And he's preying on his mother.
He's even going to use Ruth
to try to push up on Mama...
to get this money,
so he can open up this liquor store.
Why do you have to talk so much
about money?
Because it's life, Mama.
So now money is life?
Once upon a time, freedom was life.
Now it's money.
- No, it was always money.
- No.
- No, we just didn't know about it.
- Something's changed.
You're something new, boy.
What does she say when Walter says,
"It was always about money?"
- It used to be about freedom.
- It was about freedom...
Yeah, who said that? Who said that?
Okay, Chi, go with that.
She said it used to be about freedom.
Because at that time,
when she was coming up...
money wasn't an issue.
It was like, to be able
to pick up a book and read...
things of that nature,
was farfetched for them.
And now that they conquered that,
she's looking at her kid, at Walter.
Like, "You're all about money.
That's not even important."
He feels, betrayed by his family,
his friends, by everybody.
They won't give him a chance
to live out his dream.
Mama, look at me.
I'm looking at you, son.
You're a good-looking boy.
You've got a job, a nice wife,
and a fine son...
A job?
Mama, a job?
I open and close doors all day long.
I drive a man around
in his limousine.
I say, "Yes, sir. No, sir.
Very good, sir."
"Shall we take the drive, sir?"
Mama, that isn't no kind of job.
That isn't nothing at all.
Sometimes it's like I see the future
stretched out in front of me...
just plain as day,
the future, Mama...
hanging over there
at the edge of my day...
just waiting for me, a big, looming,
blank space full of nothing.
He wants to be a better man.
He wants to be a person
who can provide for his family.
And these men get it,
because they want to be a man...
that their children
can look up to...
a man who can eventually provide
for their families.
These guys that make it
through this program...
have had to really work hard
to accomplish what they're going for.
They're working on old manual
typewriters with no memory.
They have no research capacity.
They're living in the largest
cell block in the country.
So even late at night,
the toilets are going.
The radios are going.
It's never, ever quiet.
So when you're studying
and trying to read or do a paper...
and you're wadding up toilet paper
to put in your ears...
just so you can get some quiet,
it's not conducive for learning.
It's different
than my usual teaching.
Teaching out in the regular world...
people are going there
to get a degree.
They're hoping that
it's going to get them a good job...
and that's about it.
They don't have too much stake,
generally, in any particular course.
They're just trying
to get good grades.
With the men at Sing Sing, it's
a whole different thing for them.
Many of them,
the stakes are very high.
They know that, for them...
it could be an opportunity
at a life outside of prison.
Getting back to the allegory
of the cave...
the mind corresponds to what
Plato called The World of Ideas.
"There have been people who have said
they're getting this education."
"They're paying very little."
And in the old program...
when the state and the federal
government were paying...
it was even worse.
Because people would say...
"I can't afford to send my kids
to college that way."
"These prisoners are getting it
for free."
I think my response
has always been...
"These men and women
will come back to the community."
"How do you want them to come back?"
This isn't just a gift for them.
It's a gift for society.
It's a way that we make society
a better place.
My name is Joel Jimenez.
And I'm from Manhattan,
Lower East Side section of Manhattan.
It was 1992.
Several guys approached my brother.
One of them reached into his pocket.
And he looked back at the other guy
and told him, "Should I do it?"
So I panicked.
And as that unfolded,
I shot and killed him...
which what I thought was protecting
my brother at the time.
But the sad reality,
when the facts came out...
he didn't have nothing on him.
And it was a terrible moment...
that I get to live with
for the rest of my life.
We have two lives
that were destroyed...
his life as well as my life.
Everyone called him El Pollito.
They don't even know
what El Pollito means...
for those English-speaking people.
Pollito is baby chick.
Joel has a real flair for being able
to think outside the box.
You know, some of the questions
he asks in class...
are things that a lot of other people
don't think about.
Life in prison has been sort of
an emotional rollercoaster.
You have your good days
and your bad days.
When they're going for you,
things look great.
And then when things look down,
because you've been here so long...
it becomes very difficult
to be here...
each time seeing the life
you missed out on.
You know, his daughter
grew up without him.
And you know, and now
she's a teenager. And...
She was two years old
when I came to prison.
She was seven years old
when her mother passed away.
So my child had a rough childhood.
And it's something
I wish I could be there to help her.
And I missed out on that.
My relationship with my dad,
when I was younger...
it wasn't that good.
It's sad. I don't think a child
should have to go through that.
Now that I'm getting older,
it's like I'm realizing...
that you know, I have to develop
a better relationship with him...
not necessarily that I have to,
but that I should.
I guess it was just a matter of age
and, like, growing up and maturing.
Like, you know, you can't always
have a hatred towards somebody.
Because I guess I want as mad that
he wasn't there when I was younger.
But...
I missed out of so far,
18 years of her life.
And that means
her kindergarten graduation.
That means
her elementary school graduation...
her high school graduation.
Those are the things
that I missed out on.
He is doing something for himself...
preparing himself for the day
of his release, you know?
I mean, the whole family's just happy
that, you know...
there's something positive
coming out of this.
We're proud that...
We're proud...
We're proud
that he's made it this far.
I love you, Joel. And we are proud
of all you have accomplished.
I ended up in this fight.
And I decided to shoot this guy.
But at the time,
I felt I was protecting myself.
At the time, I was not
protecting myself physically...
but more of my dignity, my manhood.
I'm blending
some oil pastels together...
and trying to get dirty with it.
If I can't get dirty with it,
it's not any fun.
But it's therapeutic,
whenever I get drawing.
I lose track of time when I do so.
Obviously, we've got a lot of time
to use while in here.
I try to make the best out of it.
I kind of made fun of him
and call him Denis the Menace.
He used to love pranks.
So he would do the whole, you know,
putting Saran Wrap around the toilet.
He sits and listens for a while,
gets the lay of the land before...
He's not somebody
who jumps in with both feet.
But when he says something,
it's something really of value.
It triggers conversation.
It triggers argument.
He was kind of a womanizer.
And that got him in a lot of trouble.
He brought with him a portfolio
that night of his paintings...
to show me, his sketches
and so forth, and all very different.
All very talented.
I got inspired
after reading Rene Descartes.
It's named...
which is, "I think, therefore I am."
But I added "free" in Latin,
just to complete that message...
of what I was trying to say.
Here is Denis. And he's in chains.
There another message saying that...
even though his body might be
imprisoned, his mind is free.
I look forward to the time
he gets out.
I think he'll become
a well-known artist.
My parents are hardworking people.
They've always been behind me.
They've always been supportive.
What exactly do you want to hear
about me?
Like, "My name
is Natalie Jimenez."
"I'm the wife of Joel Jimenez."
And maybe what you...
Yeah, because I don't like
talking about myself.
My life is really such a secret
and such a personal.
I mean, I'm my own personal person
because of the circumstances...
that when people ask me about myself,
it's usually, like...
I guess fantasy that I'm telling
about myself, like, what...
- What do you...
- I tell people...
that he works in Westchester.
Because I figure, he lives there.
And I know he somewhat works there.
We've been together 15 years.
I met her in prison.
She was a volunteer
in the Elmira Correctional Facility.
My mother worked
in the same facility.
And she told me
that she had a project for me to do.
And she was going to have
one of the guys help me.
And I said,
"You mean like an inmate?"
And she said yes.
And I begged her.
I begged her, "Please, I don't want
to be in a filing room...
with an inmate. Please."
"Oh, no. He's a nice guy."
And I was like,
"No, I don't want to be..."
Because earlier that day,
I had heard about...
an inmate who swallowed a light bulb.
My thought was that
they were all crazy...
and they all swallow light bulbs
and do crazy things.
So but then I met him,
and he was fun and funny...
and nice and regular.
Dating in prison, it's not easy.
Because you only get to spend
intimate time...
maybe on the conjugal visits,
I don't know if you're aware of them.
Every 90 to 100 days
in this facility.
And it goes for three days.
A lot of people think
we're locked in...
like, a closet-sized room
for an hour.
And that's our conjugal visit.
And that's Hollywood for you,
I guess.
It's like a trailer, if you've
ever been in a trailer home.
They're also known as trailer visits,
which sounds kinda trashy.
But I have to bring everything.
I have to bring food, clothing.
It's kind of like we're going
on a trip, I guess, camping.
No glass containers, no pepper,
no loosely wrapped items.
Soap, toothpaste, deodorant
cannot have any alcohol.
I guess they think we might get drunk
on soap or... yeah, it was just...
We were just young and in love,
like no care in the world.
We do, like, a date night.
So like, I'll bring a dress,
and he'll bring a shirt and tie.
And this is us
on one of our date nights.
We look beautiful.
And we have a special dinner
and music and dancing and...
I had to get married in here.
You know, this is something that
I believed my wife deserved more.
This is the day we got married,
May 23, 2001.
This is Sean power lifting.
I have better...
I know I have better ones.
Look at this.
I think his heaviest weight
was 600 or 650 pounds.
And... but look how big he is there.
Look at his arms and his neck
and how thick he was.
Bodybuilding in a Speedo.
Oh, my God.
I think he told me he placed third
in the state for the competition.
Sean with his diploma
when he graduated.
That was his graduation
from Hudson Link.
Oh, my God.
He was a baby.
I'll never forget because
it was right before thanksgiving.
So we went out the Monday night
before thanksgiving.
And that was our first date.
We went, we walked, we had dinner.
We had a great conversation,
a really nice time.
At that point, I didn't know anything
about his past.
And he said,
"I have something to tell you."
And it's funny,
because my first thought was...
"Oh, my God, he's married."
Typical New York girl, right?
I don't know anything
about his background.
And somebody says that,
and I thought...
"Oh, I just went on a date
with a guy who's married."
And he said, "No, that's not it."
"But I was in jail.
And I want to tell you what it was."
"Because I really enjoyed today,
and I'd like to ask you out again."
"But you need to know the facts."
When I was 16 years old,
I got into trouble.
I shot and killed
my friend's father...
and ended up sentenced
to eight to 24 years in prison.
By the time I came home,
when I was 33 years old...
I had spent more time in prison
than out of prison.
In prison, there are a lot of things
you can be involved with...
but not a lot of things
you can accomplish.
So I would enroll and just go
to school as much as possible...
just always looking to better myself.
It's been the most unbelievable
experience.
The college program that we know
statistically changes lives...
has a great success rate,
is saving the state tons of money...
99 percent of them are coming home
at some point.
Do you want them the same way
they went in or worse?
Or do you want them changed...
and thinking about
what they've done and educated...
and looking to make a difference
in their lives?
I think that that's a nobrainer.
I've seen school
as a second chance...
at doing things right.
To see these professors coming in
and going in this hot room...
with 30-something strangers
to impart knowledge and information.
That would be life changing,
that's you know what?
This is where I'm supposed to be.
This is big for me. It's big.
Because I never thought
I would be doing good in school.
Like, I'm like an A student.
I've got maybe, I think,
one B, two B-pluses.
And the rest are
either As or A-minuses.
So it's an accomplishment.
It feels good to come here at night
and not just be in the yard.
Every time I go
into that cell, I realize...
a number of men have been
in this cell right here.
Some have failed.
Some have been broken.
But I always say,
"I won't count myself among those."
"I won't count myself
in their lot right there."
You can, like,
be part of the gang fights.
You can be part of the cuttings,
the stabbings, the drugs...
and whatever else goes on.
You can be part of that.
This is at your disposal.
Or you can turn it into a university.
People that lack education
have to act out.
You know, if I can't talk to you,
it's like if I'm talking to a girl.
If I can't talk to her,
I might touch her, you know?
So you know, it gives you the ability
to solve problems.
It gives you the ability to reason.
You become more analytical.
You think about things.
You think further down.
The game changes
from checkers to chess.
People talk about education.
What does education do for you?
And how has it transformed you?
I went down to what they call
the Masjid down in the chapel...
in the Muslim section.
There was a guy down there
who murdered my brother in 1977.
Stanley...
So I said to myself, "God, not now.
Not now. No. Why?"
I said,
"If I ever run into this dude...
I'm going to take his head off."
I said, "I'm going to take
his head off, man."
And I said to myself, "No."
Because I said, "I've changed."
I said, "I'm not the same person."
I said, "Man, hey, man. I went
and got all these certificates."
"I did this. I did that.
I'm not the same person."
That's when I went inside myself
for three days...
and I thought things out.
We came down, and he was over there.
There he is.
I looked him right in the eye.
I said, "Man,
why did you murder my brother?"
He said, "Man, I was 15 years old.
It was something that just happened."
I looked at him.
I'm trying to find a way to do so.
Nothing.
I said, "You know what, man?"
I reached out, shook his hand.
And I said, "Man, I forgive you."
And I hugged him.
And I said, "You don't get to worry
about nothing, man."
"There's nobody going to jump you.
Nobody going to stab you."
"Nobody going to do nothing to you.
You got my word on that."
And I walked away.
If I'd have fell into that trap...
if I'd have fall
into that influence...
if I wouldn't have said that I,
"I really want to change."
If it wasn't for the education...
if it wasn't for being around
brothers like these, you know...
I'd have never got out.
And the worst thing about it,
this case would've been overturned...
I still wouldn't have got out,
because I'd have took his head off.
So let's start tonight
with sharing your own poetry.
I asked you to bring in
your favorite poem.
All right, this is a poem I wrote
maybe 10, 12 years ago.
It's called "I am black history."
It goes like this.
"I planted seeds that gave birth
to civilizations."
"I'm the beginning and end."
"I've sat on thrones, recorded
my history through hieroglyphics...
scratched on stones."
"I fathered medicines, science,
philosophy, and astrology...
built pyramids with hand tools...
established the first universities
and schools."
"For millennia, I've ruled,
even taught my conquerors...
architected more than my share
of the world's wonders."
"I've been brutally slain,
even shackled and chained."
"I've dove into my liquid grave,
off the decks of ships for slaves."
"Millions of my bones lie
on the ocean's floor in rebellion."
"My blood has fertilized
the soils of the Americas."
"I've been lashed, castrated,
and burned to ash...
hung from tight ropes,
died for the right to vote."
"I've cried freedom at rallies."
"I've had a dream,
screamed black power...
bullet or the ballot."
"I've been desegregated
and more separated from my enemy."
"I've fought wars
to protect the system...
that's systematically killing me."
"I've lost my mind, killed and died
at the hands of my own kind."
"I've shot dope
and been a crack fiend...
abused and disrespected
my black queen."
"I've been down and up
the mountaintop...
been falsely accused, been guilty
incarcerated and locked down a lot."
"I've worked my way from the fields
to the boardrooms."
"I've loved and nurtured the growth
of my black woman and child."
"Envision me, the black man."
"And of my history, I am proud.
I am black history."
"I am an eagle in a cage...
unable to spread my wings and fly...
unable to do the things
that make me I."
"I am an eagle in a cage...
able to see the skies...
able to watch the sunset
and sunrise."
"Physically, I am well.
But inside, I cry."
"Inside, I die...
tortured, forced to watch
sparrows and butterflies."
"And I die and die."
"No, but this is not my demise."
"In fact, this is when I will rise."
"This is when I will let my spirit
soar high...
past mountains
and see through clouds in the sky."
"I remain I, regardless of how long
I am tired, how much I am tried."
"I will not fold. I will not hide.
I will not bide."
"And I damn sure will not die.
I will survive."
"I will be the eagle in the sky."
"No, this is not my demise."
It's really redemption.
I mean, I've never seen redemption.
I went to Sunday school
and church and all that.
But I've never really saw, felt,
heard, smelled redemption.
This is it.
While in prison,
I began to hate myself.
I began to hate myself
because of the pain...
that I caused the victim's mother.
I hated myself because of the grief
and long suffering...
that my family endured because
of my ignorance and stupidity.
This hate turned to anger.
I was angry at myself
for not listening to my parents...
when I knew I should.
I was angry because
I brought shame to them...
to my community, and to myself.
I was angry because
I could not go back...
and change the circumstances
of my life.
Thus, these feelings of self-hatred
soon developed...
into a sense of helplessness.
I began to sink into a vast ocean
of despair.
And while I drowned
in this ocean of despair...
this ocean of self-hatred,
this ocean of anger, I saw an anchor.
Connected to this anchor was a chain
in the form of links.
It was Hudson Link.
That anchor, Hudson Link,
lifted me up to majestic heights.
That anchor, Hudson Link, lifted me
up into a lifeboat of education...
and revived me and gave me
a second chance at life.
Hudson Link had mercy on me.
Hudson Link gave me mercy,
Mercy College.
And all of you all supporters
of Hudson Link, Mercy College...
I'm forever grateful.
And I promise to make the best
of this new life.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Thanks. Well, there's not much that
can top the spirit of those words.
But I think the one thing
that can top it...
is the conferring of degrees.
So we will look
to that spirit right now.
So let's begin.
Darrell Bolden.
Todd Mantz.
Denis Martinez.
Christopher Payton.
Joel Jimenez.
By the power of the authority
vested in me...
by the State of New York...
and the Mercy College Board
of Trustees...
I confer upon you
your respective degrees...
with all the rights and privileges
that pertaining.
Now you graduated.
You can take your tassel over.
And congratulations.
We're very proud of you.
I don't think anybody could sit here
and not be overcome.
Because this is very spiritual.
It's sort of like giving birth,
I decided.
If I was trying to tell somebody
about it...
lots of pain,
lots of work, lots of waiting...
lots of striving
and pushing one way or the other.
But you have a new life at the end.
That's the way I see it.
Now it's 9:00, and the graduation
is officially over.
We would like to ask all guests...
to please make their way
towards the exits. Thank you.
May I have your attention?
I need all inmates to report
to their room.
All visitors,
please come up to the front desk...
where the exit is at.
Excuse me.
May I have everyone's attention?
I need all inmates to report
to their room.
Bye. Be good, all right?
I love you. Bye.
I see it as truly redemption.
They're no longer the men
who ended up in prison.
They're new people transformed
by education.