Restoration of this fim was made
through The Lumiere Project Funds
as part of THE E.U. Media Program
Restored with the cooperation of
ZERO FOR CONDUCT!
Oh the village's prime...
...you're odorous of thyme...
...and whenever you ramble...
...you make my poor heart tremble...
Oh the village's pride...
...whose will you be bride...
...whoever will be wedded...
...to a girl so dearly yearned...
Come to your window, my darling...
...can't you hear me moaning...
When your face comes up shining...
...moon goes out of its glowing...
Let me see you shortly, will you...
...don't deny me this...
...so I can quiet down and leave you...
...sleep again in peace...
Oh those eyes of sweetness...
...are the reason for my grievance...
...my poor heart's all heavy...
I can swear to you my lady...
Someone's coming!
Go, Fotis!
- Good night Bilio!
- Good night.
Love me oh love me dearie...
...my precious expectation...
...just like I fell in love with you...
...during our premier session...
Your eyes were looking down and low...
...focusing on your school desk...
...as for your pretty little hands...
...were paging through...
...a text-
-book!
ONE-CLASS SEMI-GYMNASIUM
FOR FEMALES
- Hello, Sir Teacher.
- Hello, Manolis.
Eeh, what's with your eye?
Is it obvious?
Last night I was attacked by five men.
They mistook me for someone else.
It goes without saying
that I fought back.
- I overpowered all five of them.
- And your eye?
It got overpowered too.
She's coming! She's coming!
Good morning, girls!
Good morning!
If you would allow me, Ms. Headmistress,
jasmins for you!
- Thank you, child. How kind!
- You're welcome!
So then, today it's a History class.
As I already told you yesterday
Alexander the Great, even from puberty,
gave indications of his bravery
and intelligence.
In his father Phillipos' stables
there was a steed named Voukephalas
This steed
was ever so defiant...
and wild...
that absolutely no one
was capable of riding him...
Riding him I say,
no one was capable of!
One day Alexander
saw Voukephalas
and admired him.
He then decided
to tame him...
Aaah! Help me!
A weevil !
There it is!
Someone catch it!
Oooh, mummy!
I caught it! I caught it!
Aaah, I can't...
I can't have a class today...
I am much too excited!
The History lesson
will be instructed by you, Bilio.
Yes, Ms. Headmistress!
- Get well soon, Ms. Headmistress!
- Thank you.
Farewell, 'bye!
Keep quiet, girls! Quiet!
We don't want a class!
Who said there is one?
We'll do some singing!
I'll sing the latest hit in Athens
for you! I heard it on the radio!
Oh, when will all these classes
ever finish...
so I can step outside in
real-life contest...
How do I long to flirt and love
and how I wish...
...I'd make a real woman's conquest...
I'm all so tired of constantly
beholding...
the classroom desks, the teacher
and the sessions...
and now I'm craving for
a husband's fondling...
with genuine desire and obsession...
I want somebody to favor...
be his faithful darling wife...
He is to be a handsome fellow...
keen on pleasing me for life...
He should make me a heap of presents...
ever sweetly talk to me...
night and day when in my presence...
he's to kiss me wooingly...
For my hair he must be zealous...
and stroke it longingly...
Also want him to be jealous...
like Othello ragingly ...
He must constantly be training...
in this sporting love of his...
yet not in the least refraining...
when I whisper in his ears...
For my hair he must be zealous...
and stroke it longingly...
Also want him to be jealous...
like Othello ragingly...
He must constantly be training...
in this sporting love of his...
yet not in the least refraining...
when I whisper in his ears...
Zero for conduct !!!
You look at your watch much too often,
Mr. Fotis. Time for your medicine?
The medicine of love!
He longs for noontime,
when the school finishes!
Why are you having me on, boys?
I'm a young man!
It's no shame to love a girl.
She'll be my wife.
Oh, yes!
You may say so, but her father objects!
If the bride and the groom want it...
father-in-law has no saying...
Come boys, finish up and enjoy lunch!
So long!
By the prayers of our holy fathers,
Lord Jesus Christ our God,
have mercy upon us and save us.
Amen.
Please, be quiet!
- Bilio Foundouka!
- Present!
You're detained.
You'll leave an hour later!
- But...
- No buts! Keep silent!
No buts!
I have spoken!
The rest may leave.
In absolute quiet!
Enjoy your lunch, Sir!
- What happened with Bilio?
- Who knows?
She did well in the oral test anyway.
- He detains her every day.
- Well, 3 times a week for sure.
You see, he's in love and wants
to keep her close to him.
Oh, I wish I was, too...
All around in circle and Manolis
in the middle...
who's living a great life
with plenty of wine...
Eeeh! The Headmistress!
Girls!
Enjoy lunch, Ms. Headmistress!
Where's Bilio?
Well, as usual...
- She's detained?
- Until 1 o'clock.
- What did she do?
- Nothing.
- Was it it the teacher or the
Headmistress? - Him, of course.
You'll copy 2 pages from
Modern Greek Texts.
- You heard me, Bilio?
- I heard you.
TUTORIAL ROOM
Have you not departed yet,
Mrs. Melpomeni?
- I've been expecting you, Mr. Plato!
- Oh, have you?
Are you forgetting that I've invited
you to dine with me today?
- Dine with you?
- Have you forgotten?
I have prepared cuttlefish in red
sauce, your favorite!
Oh, you have! Too bad I'd forgotten it!
Oh, you brute!
But it is of no importance.
I'm reminding you of it!
Unfortunately I cannot come.
I've a detained student
writing in there.
But until you've warmed up the
cuttlefish, I'll be there.
- Your word on it?
- Of course, Mrs.Headmistress!
Oh, don't call me that!
Besides, I'm a Miss.
You may simply call me Melpomeni.
Believe me, I adore you!
When you've become certain of my eros
for you, you'll love me too!
I'm headed towards the preparation
of the cuttlefish! - Do that.
In anticipation!
I'll be there.
Unless I become cuttlefish myself
and eject some ink...
ROMEO AND JULIET
Manolis!
Yes, what?
Ah, it's you, Mr. Fotis?
Manolis, is the Teacher still in?
Yeah...
- And...?
- Yeah...
- Bilio?
- What's "yeah" for?
- Yeah...
- Why is Bilio still in?
- Don't know...
- You must know! Say it!
- Naah...
- Are you kidding me?
- Naah... No!
She's detained.
What for?
I'll go see why!
No, Mr. Fotis, you can't go in.
It's prohibited.
Alright.
I'll wait till she comes out
and settle this.
- Hello, lady!
- Take those in!
But it's noon, the cuttlefish is ready!
It's an emergency! Horrible things
are happening in the village!
You're alarming me!
The world has gone astray, Helen!
If only I told you that...
You don't say!
Jesus help us! We've become
Sodora and Gommoda (sic)!
Mind you, don't speak a word
to anyone!
Can such things be spoken out?
Is the meal ready, Tasso?
It's ready, Master but Bilio has
not come back from school yet.
She hasn't? But what's the time?
There! The half hour is striking.
The teacher must have
detained her again.
- If she doesn't study?
- What does that mean?
Even if she doesn't, the President's
daughter cannot be detained!
I'll write to the MP and have
the teacher transferred.
- Bring lunch, I'll eat alone!
- As you wish, Master.
It must be her.
What? It's you Ms. Headmistress?
Anything wrong with Bilio?
Be calm, Mr. President. Nothing's wrong
but I must talk to you.
You see now, best woman?
The world has gone astray!
Yes, it did!
- But don't you speak a word!
- Can such things be spoken out?
Listen to this!...
Shameful things!
How can that be!
How can it!
What's up, Thodoris?
What are you mumbling about?
Stelios, does your girl go to school?
Sure she does! Shouldn't she
be educated?
Then, this is the teacher of our
school, Plato.
And these... are the students!
Students?
Our girls, whom we trust him with
for their education!
Hold it, Thodoris! If you're not crazy
you'd better explain what you mean!
What I said! This very moment, the
teacher has kept a girl alone in class!
If this is true, he's done for!
My girl perhaps?
I don't know which one it is but
I know this: He must leave the village!
- Let's find out!
- Let's!
Well, quit writing now, Bilio!
No, I'll write it all!
I see you've taken your
detention seriously...
Don't you know the way I feel
about you?
Feel my heartbeats with your hand!
Go back home, Bilio!
Not this way!
The way I got in, so that
nobody sees you.
As for you...
What's the time?
- Ten to one.
- Ta!
What's up people?
Where are you off to?
- Come with us!
- But where to?
- Come for the village's honor!
- The honor, yes! Let's go!
For the village's honor!
The teacher must leave!
Don't sit there drinking!
Come with us!
For the village honor!
The teacher is groping our girls!
You too! Come on everyone!
Come together everyone, let's go!
The teacher must leave!
For our honor!
Wait, Mr. President!
There must not be a scandal.
But no! I must go there at once!
The teacher must leave!
That scoundrel!
The beast!
We'll crush him!
Send him away!
Manolis, help me carry him
into the office!
Yeah... But what's the matter?
You know or heard nothing,
you hear?
No, no...
Now you be careful!
Don't mention the girl or
you're done for!
Hold it! He's surrendering!
He's- sur-rendering!
Here comes the President!
Quiet down! I'm fully informed!
We'll sort everything out!
You all stay here.
I'll settle the whole thing.
Stay here, stay!
You scoundrel!
Shut up, I know everything!
I really should kill you
but you're lucky I don't want a scandal
about my daughter! Shut up!
You shut it too!
Padlock your mouth!
Shut it!
Teacher, you're leaving the village
first thing tomorrow!
Here he comes!
Dear fellow inhabitans!
Looks like the accusation was only
an unsubstantial suspicion.
Satan has enveloped him!
Send the teacher away!
But because our village cannot
stand even suspicions...
not even a shadow of a doubt...
the teacher is leaving!
Throw him out!
EPAM. BRIBECOME
M.P.
Dear Mr. Bribecome
We are fine and healthy and wish
the same for you too.
We kicked out the teacher you appointed
for us because he was not OK
and we're asking you as our MP to
appoint a female teacher for our village
This is the whole village's demand.
Panayotis Foundoukas
President of Kondoskali Village
Is my personal assistant still in?
- He's in alright, damn him...
- What's happened?
He tried to kiss me.
You should make him understand
you're not the kind of girl to be kissed
by just anyone...
Excuse me, I didn't know there was
a conference going on.
You see now Maria? Then they both
got embarrassed and blushed too!
I was telling Maria...
that I caught a fellow MP yesterday
with his typist and...
you know...
- I see, I see...
- Anything else for today?
- Just a letter.
What's the second bag for, then?
Because when I get into the Ministry
with 2 bags they believe
that you are quite a busy man
so your prestige goes up!
Well done, Mihalis!
I'm raising your salary!
You're kind, Sir!
What's this letter about?
The Kondoskali issue again.
It's from the President's rival
pharmacist Mr.Bandage.
- What does he want?
- He says malignancy reigns there.
They sent away this holy man,
the teacher
and prefer a female teacher instead.
The majority of the villagers, dear MP,
wants the male teacher back.
- Now, here comes trouble...
What's to be done, then?
Our lists will tell us, dear boy!
Whoever gets the majority of votes.
I'm afraid I'm mixed-up
whoever should I choose,
Kiki or Coco...
Kondoskali... Kondoskali...
Here it is!
Pharmacist Bandage,
former group leader...
yesteryear powerful,
has recently lost status...
estimated votes: 132. Mmm?
Foundoukas... Foundoukas...
But shouldn't we find out
who's right and why they
rejected the teacher?
Aaah, and look for a haystack needle?
Are we judges or politicians here?
Well, of course we're in politics...
Then you must know that in politics,
"right" is what most voters want.
Foundoukas...
Votes: 298...
Not bad at all...
But does Kondoskali actually
have so many voters?
If you include the dead ones!
When the President is a shark
even the dead like Lazarus vote too!
So, there's no doubt about it!
We're sending a female teacher there
so inform the Ministry of Education
quickly! - Yes, Mr. Bribecome!
And send them both a telegram.
But... hold it!
You don't look well, today.
Is anything wrong?
Something tragic, Mr. Bribecome.
I failed the Law School entrance exams!
And you're sad about that?
What did I get out of studying myself
blind and graduating with an A?
When I started my practice as a lawyer
I lost all my cases
and those who won them had got their
diplomas via their contacts.
I tried to play fair
and lost all the games...
I went back to the village
penniless
and I started promising and lying...
As a result?
I was voted for MP!
- Then you believe anyone can...
- Become an MP?
Easiest thing in the world!
You receive some grants...
Soon you get a nice pension...
And one fine morning
you become a Minister!
Now go out there
and don't worry!
Eeeh, welcome dear Plato!
How are you?
- Wait till I tell you...
- I know already.
- Know what?
- You blew it!
- Letters have arrived.
- Letters?
Let's talk inside. Or would
you rather sit in the park?
- As you like, Mihalis.
- Let's go, then!
Plato, you split Kondoskali
into two parties.
One of them rejects you
and the other one wants you!
So it's the love bug, isn't it?
I adore her! If I don't see her
again I'll kill myself!
Come now, that's too tragic!
I'm late for the Ministry.
So it's final? Nothing can be done?
Nothing, my friend. Bribecome was
explicit about a female teacher.
You see you're a male teacher.
If only you were a female...
it might be possible.
Bye, Plato!
Bye, Mihalis!
If you were a female...
A female...
Mihalis!
Finally we got rid of the nightmare!
Well, you know a thing
like that couldn't have happened.
I don't know that. I love you so much
that I'm jealous of my shadow too.
If I couldn't send him away
I'd strangle him!
Oh, silly boy!
I'm mostly concerned about my father
who doesn't want you for a son-in-law.
If you want me, he will, too.
What are you staring at?
Ah, that rock...
I admire it 'cause it has
the sea at its feet!
Even when staring at the shore
you're thinking of the sea.
In my life I've always
cast my nets wide...
once in the seas and
recently at shore...
Just a reveller who'd put
all love aside...
but my time has finally come,
I'm sure...
In your nets of purest love
I have been captured...
in the manner I once would
cast them too...
By your fondling I have been
enraptured...
and that bait of your eyes
I gazed into...
You shall never find a love
that's quite the same...
like the beautiful blue
waters of the sea...
I shall build you a little house
of coral frame...
wherein dwellers shall be us...
...and ecstasy.
No way, Polydoros!
I'm not giving my daughter
to the fisherman.
You're wrong, Panagiotis. Fotis will
be a good family man.
I have different plans for my daughter.
Yeah, make sure you give her to some
Athenian dandy who'll give you...
Six one!
Oh, welcome!
A telegram, Mr. President.
Hand it in, my child!
Here it is!
It must be from our MP,
Mr. Bribecome.
And what does he say, best man?
Taking action for a female teacher's
definite appointment
Yours wholly,
MP Epameinondas Bribecome.
Praised be God!
Leave it there, dear!
Leave it there!
A telegram, Mr. Bandage!
Leave it there, dear! Leave it there!
From our MP!
Let's see! Shall we
outfox the President?
What did you think?
Would we let him do as he liked?
We'll get our way in this!
Trying to satisfy your need STOP
Facing Ministry's reaction STOP
Continuing efforts for male teacher's
return STOP
Keep present notice secret
Yours wholly,
Epam. Bribecome, MP
Hail to Bribecome!
He'll manage perfectly!
So I told the assistant since I can't
go, send my sister who's also a teacher.
Is this the truth or a joke?
Joke? But I've also got your
appointment documents.
Really? How nice, me being appointed
after all these years!
Here.
Teacher Evangelia Papadaki, widow
Sourotitis, appointed to the gymansium
for female students at the county
of Kondoskali.
Oh my brother, let me kiss you!
- You'll have a good time there!
- I'll leave at once!
Not yet. I have a plan to snatch
Bilio, the President's daughter.
From her dowry you'll get a share.
- But...
- No buts. I'll tell you when!
I have my own ploy!
Now, when will this female teacher
come along and let us see her?
Well, if she's pretty...
we might even get something
out of it, Polydoros!
But is the MP sending us one?
How dare he not send her? He won't
be reelected, then!
Mind you, he knows better than that!
Postman's here!
Welcome, Babis!
A telegram, Mr. President!
Hand it in then, Babis!
Eeeh, poor Babis!
You've grown too old for it.
- Here it is!
- It's from our MP!
Speaking of the devil...
Evangelia Sourotiris, teacher,
appointed STOP
On my way to Makrohori
passing by Kondoskali
tomorrow Thursday afternoon
Yours wholly, Epameidondas
Bribecome
- That's today!
- Yes.
We must welcome him!
Yes, in the afternoon! We have to
organize our reception.
Of course, by all means!
Gerasimos, you go raise the flag
at the Municipality Office
and notify the Philarmonic.
- At once, President!
You bring my shoes.
- We have to rush now!
- Sure we have!
Give me a hand, Polydoros!
How did this happen, help me Kolias!
He chose the right time for a bath!
Oh, Ms. Headmistress, we've got news!
A new teacher's been appointed.
I'm aware of it, I just received
this telegram.
Headmistress of one-class
semi-Gymmasium of Kondoskali
I was appointed as teacher
to your school
arriving on Thursday
Evangelia Sourotiris.
Good! Along with the MP.
Then the schoolgirls must all be there.
Very well, Mr. President.
- Let the school janitor come, too!
- Of course!
Yeah...yeah...
- You put on your nicest clothes!
- Yeah...yeah...
Shall we call the Opposition party too?
- The pharmacist?
- Yes, what do you say?
Let's call them and spit in their eye!
Right! Then you go notify the pharmacist
and all his dog company.
And you, idiot, go pick some flowers
for the new teacher!
Why? Is this the Epitaph?
They do so in Athens!
- Shall I make some koliva, too?
- Koliva, why?
For the old teacher's funeral.
VEHICLE STATION
Oh, our dear MP!
Hello, Thymios!
How are you, Thymios?
I'm not Thymios, boss!
You forgot me already?
I'm Dimitros Bardousis.
Right you are!
Just when I was thinking you looked
like Dimitros Bardousis!
Of course I look like him,
I am him!
Off to Kondoskali, our village?
I'm going to Makrohori, but I'll also
greet people in Kondoskali.
I'm so glad to have seen you, MP!
- You've also made me a promise!
- Have I?
Oh, yes! Please remind me...
About my child.
My son.
Of course, how is he?
Still waiting for a position, you had
promised to get him one, boss.
But of course I will. You have any
particular ones in mind?
Why not make him the Prime Minister's
attaché who travels abroad often?
But does he speak any
foreign languages?
Sure he does! Speaks
perfect Arvanitic!
That's of no use at all!
Appoint him first...
then you can get an interpreter
to help the boy out.
Well, I'll look into it.
We'll see about it.
Passengers for Kondoskali, Makrohori
are now called!
May I?
Going to Kondoskali?
No!
I'm going to Kondoskali!
Aaah and I thought you were
off to Kondoskali.
- Perhaps you're in a draft, Miss?
- No!
It that so, then?
Mr. President ordered that the
Municipality Building be painted white?
Well, that's not a big issue, anyway!
Not big?!
Leave it there, child!
Leave it there!
It's more than big!
We, the opposition, should also
have been asked about it.
We want it painted blue!
You've gone too far already.
The President says white,
you say black.
You say day, the President says night.
Good morning...
Mr. President is proudly inviting you
to the reception ceremony
for our passing-by MP
as well as the new female teacher of
our community of Kondoskali
who is arriving shortly.
I'll have a party council
on whether we should participate in
this disgusting affair or not!
Our Member of the Parliament...
Mind you, he's in for some fun
that scoundrel...
Of course he is.
We'll take care of him!
COUNTY OF KONDOSKALI OFFICES
HAIL TO OUR MP
IT'S YOU WE WANT
TURPS
LONG LIVE OUR MP
MAKE WAY FOR OUR PRECIOUS ONE
Turn to your left!
Good morning all!
Morning, girls!
Ms. Headmistress, how do you do?
Hail to our MP!
STAND BACK CITIZENS
MAKE WAY FOR OUR PRECIOUS ONE
And hail once more!
Good morning to you, Sir, welcome!
Let's hail him once more!
Men of Kondoskali!
This cordial reception you
prepared for me
filled me with bliss and joy!
I never will forget this forunate day
(JUST ARRIVED...)
during which the noble inhabitants
of glorious village Kondostali
(...THE NEW LAXATIVE...)
have received their proxy
with such enthusiasm!
(...FLUXATOL)
Believe me when I say that
Kondoskali will very soon
stop being a village!
Cut it out!
Because soon projects of electricity
expansion are about to begin
as well as water supply and road
construction ones
offering work positions
to the population
and soon turning Kondoskali
into a Paris miniature!
Sell these elsewhere!
I will build hospitals
hotels for tourists
and two theatre houses!
And these will be done in the following
days or months or, at the most, years...
Just wait for a short while
because if you don't wait for
a short while
then...
you'll have to wait for too long!
Each request of yours is
immediately met!
You requested that I appointed
a female teacher for you
I directly took action and her
appointment has been signed!
Shortly she will be arriving
at her post.
But I'm already here.
I'm the teacher!
What did I tell you?
She's here!
This is your village's new teacher!
Call out hurrah!
All together now!
Welcome! Your name, please?
Evangelia Papadakis,
widow Sourotiris.
Absolutely charmed!
We welcome you to
our village Kondoskali
from which so many male and
female teachers have passed.
We trust our student daughters with you
certain that you'll instruct them
with patriotism.
This is Ms. Headmistress.
This is my daughter.
What's wrong?
I don't know, excuse me...
I'm dizzy.
Perhaps due to the heat...
or the bus...
Perhaps you're ...
Nooo, that's quite impossible!
I've been a widow for three years now.
You must rest. I will accomodate you
at my house. Come!
All right now?
Are you feeling well?
Absolutely well?
Good! Good!
I hope that you and my daughter
will have a nice time together.
- But that's what I came for!
- What you came for...?
Well, I mean...
I want to be a friend for my students
not just a teacher.
Then, I'll love you very much!
I'll love you even more!
Bilio, you may show the lady
to her room now.
Yes, father.
And why are you standing there
like a log? Carry the suitcase in!
Yeah... yes!
- This is your room.
- Thanks, Bilio.
I'll leave you to freshen up a little
and then we'll dine together.
Thanks!
- Leave the suitcase, don't tire
yourself out! - Yeah...
- What's your name?
- Yeah...
- That's your name?
- No, it's Manolis.
- This village is really hot, Manolis!
- Yeaaah...
Please help me undress...
Undress??
Oh yes!
I'm about to burst with this heat.
Unzip me back there please...
- Yeah, back there?
- Yes, unzip me.
Yeah, too hot, yeah...
Indeed it is!
Come on, help me out!
Heat, too much heat!
What's all that, fathead?
Yeaah.
Don't "yeaah" me, stupid!
It's me!
It's me, Plato!
Mister Plato!
Are you a ghost?
It's me, your friend the Teacher!
You became a woman?
Did anyone notice?
No one, Sir Teacher!
Listen, Manolis... I'll...
What's the teacher doing with Manolis
I wonder.
Probably tidying up her things.
So, you two will elope, right?
I cannot live without her.
So hear me out.
You and Panagos the chauffer
will both be at the wooden bench
in the woods when I tell you to.
I'll ask Bilio to walk with me
to that spot.
I'll put her in the car
and that'll be all.
- And what am I supposed to say?
- That you know nothing about it.
And when I get her dowry, one of the
President's vineyards will be yours.
Agreed?
So then, Mdm. Schoolmistress
welcome to our village!
- Thank you!
- What did you think of it?
Very nice!
That where the sea is
and there's the woods.
Really? Shall we walk there?
Of course, Bilio...
Tomorrow afternoon when it's cooler
take Mdm. Teacher for a walk to
the wooden bench.
You have a wooden bench?
Yes, up on the hill.
The view is marvellous there.
- Shall we go there tomorrow then?
- Of course, if you want us to.
Tell us, Bilio. Does she
seem to be good?
Dunno, girls. I only saw her last night.
The Headmistress took her this morning.
Girls, we must break her immediately!
Yes, mockery, yes!
I've brought you your new
schoolmistress!
I hope you'll present her with your
obedience, as well as
neatness and diligence.
Youthfulness is but a flower
and the fruit thereof is eros
Hapless he who lastly reaps it
It's the greatest of errors
Con-
-duct...
Zero!
Madam!
There's some paper stuck on you
at your back.
Paper?
Allow me, Ms. Headmistress...
Now, hold it...
I'd surely like to know
which one of you left this paper
on the table!
I'm sure that distrait Manolis forgot
the paper on the teacher's table.
Oh my hands are all sticky now!
My handkerchief...
Where's my handkerchief?
We're saved!
Getting on with this class is
impossible! I'm much too upset!
Me too! Me too!
So are we, Ms. Headmistress!
So are we!
Today being a Saturday
you might as well be dismissed.
Tomorrow, after church, we'll all
proceed to the beach for sea bathing!
Hooray!
Most certainly you'll come too,
Mrs. Evangelia.
Me? Sea bathing?
Well... you know...
Oh, I see...
It's all right then,
you'll only be there for sun bathing.
How come? Dismissed already, Bilio?
Yes, we finished earlier today.
The new teacher?
The Headmistress left with her.
Did you tell the Headmistress we're
having her for dinner tonight?
Oh yes, she'll be here. She's very
happy we've invited her.
And the teacher? Does she look content?
She told you anything?
We haven't spoken since last night.
We'll walk in the woods this afternoon.
Up to the wooden bench.
- You will?
- What time? Perhaps I could join you?
- We're leaving at 6.
Pity! I have a municipality meeting.
Some other time then.
Aah, what a nice lobster!
That's your order to Mr. Fotis,
President.
- How much does it weigh?
- 2.100. You'll settle this with him.
- Here's a tip for you.
- Thank you!
Today at 4 I'll be waiting
by the pine tree. Fotis.
I managed to get away. Said I
was off to a school friend of mine.
Darling girl!
But I have to go back soon. I'll walk
to the bench with the new teacher.
We got rid of the male teacher and now
we got ourselves a new trouble...
Won't you ever stop complaining?
Instead of cherishing the few moments
we spend together...
Quite right, Bilio. But you see
I want you by me at all times.
Fortune teller!
I'm a fortune teller, master.
Let me tell you all about your fate
in the future.
I know already. You'll tell me again
the things you said the other day.
There'll be new things to tell, today.
Vai-vai, I see some bad shade
in your eyes...
A bad one? Go on, then!
Hand me some silver, first.
Give us a smoke, too and I'll tell you
about the dark-eyed girl.
Okay, there you go.
Now tell us the rest of it.
Alas, there's a storm in store
for you, my boy!
Keep your eyes peeled on
the beauty that you love.
- What is she talking about?
- Sea is all around you, the sea!
Quite right. I own a boat, so it's in
the sea of course, couldn't be uphill...
It's no laughing matter. I see
a person in the sea...
Watch out, young man!
There. Take this too and farewell.
Thank you. Wishing you the best
for your life.
May the soil you touch
turn into gold.
The fortune teller!
God, I'm so late! The teacher will
be waiting for me!
Listen, Bilio.
I'll be here in the woods, waiting.
- When you and the teacher get here,
I'll join you. - But should you?
It'll look like a chance meeting.
So I'll spend more time by you!
Fine. Do as you like.
Bye now.
Anyway, Manolis, won't you tell me
what we came here for?
- Yeaah!
- Say it, then!
Why do you care? You'll see.
Don't you want a fare?
- Of course. Where to?
- To Athens.
You don't say! A good fare!
So this is the wooden bench?
- Yes. Do you like it?
- Very nice!
Won't you tell me then?
Who's the lucky man that you love?
I can't do that. We're not
really acquainted yet.
Fine, my girl. I won't insist.
You know, Bilio, my brother really
liked you very much!
Mr. Plato? I know he loved me but I
didn't really like that beard of his!
Why didn't you tell him
to shave it, then?
I'm certain that now back in Athens
when I saw him
he said he was about to shave it.
In fact, I could bet on it, now as
I'm talking to you he's quite shaven.
Oh, that poor man! What else
did he tell you?
He said he was about to come
and snatch you!
- Snatch me?
- Yes. He said
I'll snatch her, take her to Athens
and marry her.
He really said that?
He said it and he's saying it again.
What would you do if he did?
Good evening to you!
- Who is this?
- Fotis.
Taking a stroll?
You like our woods, Mdm. Teacher?
At moments I do, other moments I don't!
Bilio, perhaps Mr.President may get
angry with young men following us?
How will he know? I can't believe
you'd ever tell him.
And what do you do, Mr. Fotis?
I have trawlers. I catch fish.
I often do so myself. I like...
...black seabreams...
Do you really?
I caught many of them today.
Then could you please run and get me
half an oka? Go on! Now!
Sold'em out since morning.
Mmm, all of them?
Quickly, Panagos, start the car!
- Mission postponed.
- You brought me here for nothing?
- Yeah. - Yeah?
- No. -Then pay me off.
- At the end of the month.
- Get lost, wretch!
Why punch me, Panagos?
Panagos, hold it!
Hold it, Panagos!
Panagos, hold it...
Hold it... Panagos...
Here's to Mdm. Teacher's health!
Again?
We've had too much
wine, Mr. President!
It's the last one.
Well, now if you'll excuse me,
it is rather late.
- Goodnight to all.
- Goodnight, please come again soon!
One more glass of wine, Mdm. Teacher?
Bilio, my child, you may go to bed.
I will have a chat with Madam.
Yes, Dad.
- Good night!
- Good night.
Good night, Bilio!
So, you're a widow too, eh?
Me also a widower, for 12 years.
Loneliness is a bad thing.
And what do you think of our village?
Very nice! I wish I could stay
here forever.
That's not impossible.
But I'll be transferred some time soon.
Who says you will? We have our MP who
does whatever we wish him to!
But it may happen that even he
won't manage to do so.
If the Minister comes from
another party...
So what? If you happen to be
transferred you'll just stay here.
Bravely!
Also you will resign yourself
from teaching.
Mr. President, what will I
live on, then?
I'm here for you...
I'm here, I said.
You are? And what do you
mean by that?
I am a widower. Soon my daughter will
get married, so I'll marry you.
Me?
Can you think of a better luck for you?
I'm the first man of the village.
I'll make a queen out of you!
Then, will you accept?
I'm really touched, Mr. President
as well as tired, that journey,
you see...
Let me think about it!
Think, of course!
We have plenty of time!
- Good night, Mr. President.
- Good night, my dearest!
Come in!
What's your name?
Tasso.
That's a sweet name!
Don't be afraid! I'm coming
to fasten the bolt.
The bolt!
Widow, you better...
...change your surname...
...So they won't call you...
...widow...
You've scorched me
oh neighbourhood woman...
...you wretched...
...murderess...
Who... Who is it?
It's me, Mr. Plato, Mrs. Evangelia,
it's Manolis.
You startled me, silly...
Well, Mr. Plato...
you look exactly like Beauty herself!
Shut up! Why are you here?
The Headmistress sent me. They awaited
you for the beach trip but they left.
Already? We must hurry up.
Sit here and listen!
Yesterday we blew it.
When I saw Fotis
I had such a fright!
What's done is done. That's over.
We must do better today.
- All over again?
- Be silent and listen!
You'll take my suitcase and...
Bring them over
as quickly as possible!
Drown happily!
Bilio!
Come on, Manolis, you're
far too clumsy!
Yeah...
Try playing sailor and
you'll plundge down like lead...
Look at Bilio! She's swimming
too far again!
And she'll stay one mile away,
as she always does.
Biliooo!
Don't swim that far!
A diligent boy this Fotis, best man!
He even works on a Sunday!
Good for the girl who'll marry him.
The one he considers marrying
won't be his, anyway.
Biliooo, come back here!
Yeees, I will...
Bilio!
Bilio.
You, Mrs. Evangelia?
You came that far?
Aren't you tired?
- I am, a little.
- Come aboard, then.
Sit, Bilio.
I saw you swimming so far in and took
the boat 'cause I was worried about you.
- You really love me that much?
- Yes, Bilio! I do! I love you!
- I'm not who you think I am!
- You're not? What do you mean?
I mean that... Remember
my brother, Plato?
Our teacher? How could I not?
He loved you very much, Bilio!
He wanted to snatch you.
Snatch me?
Ah, you told me yesterday, too.
Yes, make you his wife.
And since...
he couldn't come back to the village
he was forced to... - To what?
It is me, Bilio!
What?
Yes, it's me Bilio!
There's a motorboat waiting for us.
- Nothing can keep us apart now!
- Don't you touch me, you're disgusting!
Help!
Help! They're drowning!
Bilio's drowning!
Run for the oars!
Oh my God, it's our Bilio!
Our Bilio!
Manolis, you fish this one out!
If it hadn't been for Fotis, father...
Didn't I tell you so, my best man?
A diligent boy, Fotis!
Real good for the girl he'll marry!
Well, he's found her already!
Come here, Fotis!
You saved her, Fotis, she's yours.
You can have her!
Let me drown!
Come here, you!
You have to account for youself.
You'll go to prison!
Mr. President, forgive him!
Perhaps he will show his repentance.
For your sake, I forgive him.
But then...
he will marry the girl!
My little darling!
English subs by never4ever
for KG (Nov. 2014)