Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Zoe and the Astronaut - Subtitles
I don't know how to say this.
There is no easy way.
Zoe, you're cancer has spread.
As you know, chemotherapy hasn't worked.
In situations like yours, as your doctor,
my best advice is to prepare yourself.
If there is anything you would like to do,
I would urge you to do it.
Live your days. Have fun.
How long has she got?
A few months. Three or four at the most.
Four at the most?
I'm sorry.
ZOE: Hi, Dad.
Hi, Darling. How are you feeling?
I'm okay.
Did you get what you were looking for?
I found a couple of things.
What are you doing?
Bills, bills and more bills.
ELIZABETH: Hi, Darling.
Yasmin came around. I told her you were at
the shops. She's going to come back later.
Great. Thanks.
I'm going to go upstairs and rest a little.
Okay, honey.
Okay. See you.
Is everything okay?
Not really.
We've lost the Hamilton contract.
We can't afford the treatment in California
I'll get another job.
No. It won't be enough.
We're running out of time.
(Coughing)
(Vomitting)
Are you okay, Zoe?
Just feeling a bit sick, but I'm okay.
I'll get you something.
No, Mum!
I said "I'm okay".
Sorry.
I'm going to brush my teeth and go to bed.
Okay.
Well, sleep tight and let me know
if you need anything.
Okay.
Goodnight.
Are you feeling better after last night?
I just felt a bit queasy. That's all.
They said it would happen.
Do you want me to call them?
No. That's fine.
Are you going to eat something?
I'm not really hungry.
You'll waste away.
I'm already wasting away, Mum.
Why don't you come with me to the office?
I've got to pick up a few files.
We'll get a burger on the way back.
I'm a vegetarian, Dad.
Well, we''ll get a veggie burger.
(Laughs). Okay.
Right.
Are you looking forward to that burger?
Yeah.
Listen, Zoe. Your mother...
Just go easy on her.
She's only worried because she loves you.
I just don't think she's come to terms
with what's going to happen.
We'll deal with it.
I know you'll handle it.
How's that boyfriend of yours?
Rob?
JOHN: Rob, hmm.
We broke up.
What happened?
He said he had his whole life ahead of him
and he couldn't deal with the stress
of a dying girlfriend. So...
He said that?
ZOE: Yeah.
What a dick!
JOHN: Okay. That's everything. Come on.
Are you alright with that?
- Yeah. Fine.
Alright. Put that straight in there.
That's good. Take that.
On there.
ZOE: Is that everything?
- Yeah. Yeah. Right!
Let's go get that burger!
Veggie burger!
Good?
Really good.
Dad?
JOHN: Hmm?
Tell me the story about how
you and Mum met.
(Laughs)
Why do you want to know that again?
In the end, you start thinking
about the beginning.
We were at College together and...
One day, I needed the toilet.
I went into the wrong toilet,
I went into the Ladies'...
And there was your Mother.
She was the most beautiful girl
I'd ever seen.
What will you do after I'm gone?
Do you think you'll stay together?
Of course we'll stay together, Zoe.
I love your Mother.
I love You. Very much.
We'll just take each day as it comes.
(Gasping)
(Coughing)
What's the matter?
I feel sick.
Listen. We are two minutes away from home.
Dad? Pull over.
JOHN: Alright. Okay.
Pull over! Quick.
Okay. Just keep breathing. Here we go.
(Coughing)
JOHN: Alright. Come on. You're alright.
Keep breathing. Keep breathing.
You'll be fine.
I think it was the Veggie Burger.
JOHN: Ahh! The Veggie Burger.
(Rumbling sound in the sky)
ZOE: Shit. Dad?
What is that?
(Crash)
Listen. Stay there. Just stay there.
ZOE: Dad!
Dad! Wait!
Dad! Over here!
Jesus! Are you alright?
Christ! You could've died there.
That was some crash.
It's my Pod.
JOHN: What?
It's my Space Pod.
I'm an Astronaut.
JOHN: Can you walk?
I just need to get used to it.
Should we contact someone?
Our house is near here.
We'll get you there.
We'll sort things from there.
Thanks.
Come on.
Through here.
Here you go.
Ohh. Jesus!
JOHN: Water. Get some Water.
JOHN: Okay. You're alright.
Christ! I can't believe you're alive.
Give him the water.
ZOE: Do you want some water?
Err...
ZOE: Are you sure you're okay?
ZOE: I think you should sit down.
ZOE: Dad!!
Dad!!
Hi.
Where am I?
You're in our house.
You passed out. You've been asleep
for two days.
Where are my clothes?
Err..Over there.
...
Are you hungry? You must be hungry.
My Mum has made breakfast downstairs.
So come and join us...
When you're dressed.
Morning.
Ahh. Good morning.
Did you sleep alright?
Yes. Thankyou.
Well, you've been out for two days.
You must be hungry?
Please. Take a seat.
Okay...um...
I'm John and this is my wife, Elizabeth.
This is our beautiful daughter, Zoe.
She's the one that found you.
Nice to meet you all.
And you are?...
Jacques
My name is Jacques.
ELIZABETH: Jacques?
Jacques?
Very nice.
Sit down.
ELIZABETH: Come on. We don't bite.
ELIZABETH: So...
I know you're not supposed to talk
about this, but John says
You're an Astronaut.
ELIZABETH: That you crash landed
in the field over the way?
That's right.
No offense, but you seem very young to be
an Astronaut.
Where are you based?
I wasn't based anywhere.
I was born in space.
What?
Born in space?
My Mother and Father were part of a
Space Cosmonaut mission.
The mission was aborted when they
veered off course.
They drifted into the cosmos
and lost contact.
How did you get back?
We'd been drifting for years.
Thankfully, our ship had everything
we needed.
We caught a glimpse of earth
a few months ago...
It was our only chance of getting back.
My parents...
They put me in a Pod
and fired me toward Earth.
JOHN: So...
Where are your parents now?
They're probably dead now.
All our crops had failed.
We wouldn't be able to live much longer.
That's terrible.
How old are you?
20 years old.
That's a long time in space.
Alright. Let's get moving.
Eat up.
A young man like you needs to keep his
strength up.
This is amazing!
That's bacon and those are eggs.
I've never tasted anything like it.
Well, you can't have many pigs and chickens
in space.
No.
(Whispers)
JOHN: No,no,no.
- ELIZABETH: Let him stay, come on.
JOHN: No, because it's ridiculous.
- ELIZABETH: Why not?
ELIZABETH: Why is it ridiculous?
His whole family has died.
JOHN: Look, stop.
JOHN: We don't know anything about him.
ELIZABETH: He seems great.
And look. Look how happy she is.
ELIZABETH: Look!
JOHN: This is not about you.
It doesn't have to be forever.
I'm not saying it's about me.
JOHN: It's about Zoe.
- ELIZABETH: Really?
Jacques...
ELIZABETH: With you being from out of space...
and not having a family, we thought you
could stay with us.
ELIZABETH: We've got plenty of room.
Just until you get yourself
sorted out.
That's very kind. Thankyou.
Great.
Right. Well that's that then.
JOHN: Zoe, why don't you go for a
walk with Jacques and show him around.
We might need to get him some new clothes.
Right. Yes. I'll sort some out.
Some of mine.
ZOE: So, what's it like up there?
In space.
There's no light.
No noise.
No air.
I've been looking at the stars a lot, recently.
Wondering what Earth looks like
from up there.
It looks like hope.
I'm dying.
Dying?
I've got cancer.
Oh. It's a terminal illness.
- JACQUES: I know what it is.
Crazy, right?
Is it curable?
Not mine.
The doctor says I only have
a few months to live. So...
I'm sorry.
I just thought you should know.
If you're going to be staying
with us for awhile.
JACQUES: What's 'Ice Cream'?
Are you serious?
Come on.
ZOE: Mum, Dad?
We're in here watching a film, love.
ZOE: Hi.
Come and join us, if you like.
Come in Jacques.
Sit down.
JOHN: Morning, Jacques.
Morning, John.
JOHN: Is everything alright?
Fine. Yes.
JOHN: Good.
You're sky is quite something.
JOHN: Yes.
Yes, I suppose it is.
Do the birds always make
this sound in the morning?
- Oh. Yes.
Look, Jacques. There's...
There's something I need to tell you.
Zoe's not well. She's sick.
She has something called 'leukaemia'.
It's rather delicate because the doctors
say she doesn't have long to live.
Yes.
She told me.
She told you?
Yesterday.
Oh, right.
Listen, I need to get to work now so...
- JACQUES: Bye, John.
Yeah. Bye.
Oh. Hello.
JACQUES: Hello.
I'm looking for Zoe.
Is she in?
ZOE: Hey, Yasmin.
Come on in.
Who's that, Zoe? You little devil.
Ahh... Yas, this is Jacques.
ZOE: A friend of the family.
ZOE: He's staying with us.
YASMIN: Jacques?
YASMIN: That's a nice name.
What is that? French?
...
Yeah.
So what's up?
I need a favour.
It's Steve.
What about him?
I need to see him.
Yas, stay away from him.
He's a loser.
- I know. He's got my Mum's engagement ring
and he won't give it back.
Can you come with me to get it?
When?
- Now. Before he pawns it.
ZOE: Yas...
- Please, Zoe.
Okay.
But this is the last time.
I'll come with you.
ZOE: Jacques, wait here.
We won't be long.
STEVE: No, you can't have it.
ZOE: Come on, Steve. Be reasonable.
DAVEY: Be reasonable?
You've got a lot of nerve for someone
dying of cancer.
- STEVE: Hey, stop it.
How have I not been reasonable?
Consider that ring compensation
for what your friend has put me through.
YASMIN: It's my Mum's engagement ring.
She's heartbroken.
She'll die if she knew that you stole it.
What's it worth?
I haven't got any money, Steve.
Sure we can find another way
for you to pay.
You're sick!
Come on, Yas. Let's go.
We'll call the police.
- Oh no you won't. If you do,
I'll tell them that we stole it together
and your mum will never forgive you.
Let's go, Yas.
DAVEY: Think about that offer, girls.
Yas!
I'll be waiting.
YAS: Oh my god. I hate him so much.
JACQUES: Did you get it?
No.
JACQUES: Wait here.
ZOE: No, Jacques. It's not worth it.
Wait here. I'll speak with him.
I smacked him, he's gone down.
Everyone starts screaming...
...his girlfriend has run out
into the street...
STEVE: You smacked him and he went down?
- I know but...
Who's this twat?
Are you alright, blondie?
Are you lost?
What the fuck do you want?
I've come for the ring.
Are you taking the piss?
You can't have it.
I'll give you three seconds.
(laughs)
You mug.
And then what?
STEVE: Dave, get him out.
DAVEY: Alright, "Milkybar Kid", I think
it's past your bedtime.
(Bones cracking)
(Bones breaking)
(Choking)
(Coughing)
Argghh!!!
Thankyou so much!
You're brilliant.
He got it.
ZOE: Mum?
Hi, kids.
ELIZABETH: Hi, Yas.
Hi.
Is it okay if Yas stays for dinner?
Of course.
Your dad will be home soon.
Jacques, do you want to help me
make a salad?
Sure.
ELIZABETH: Come on then.
I'm sure that you two have plenty of gossip
to catch up on.
ELIZABETH: It's really easy.
Just get the knife and chop.
Zoe, I can't tell you how happy
I am I've got the ring back.
I know.
It's all thanks to Jacques.
God knows what he said to Steve.
Are you and him an item?
Me and Jacques?
No.
You know he's really fit, right?
He's alright.
"Alright"?
You must be blind.
(Laughter)
People from college have been asking
about you.
Nobody has called.
They can't care that much.
(Front door opens)
Hi, Dad!
JOHN: Hi.
Yas?!
- YAS: Hi, Mr Armstrong.
How are you, darling? Alright?
- ZOE: Yeah, I'm okay.
How are your parents?
- YASMIN: They're good, thanks.
Dad, Yas is staying for dinner.
Wonderful.
The more the merrier.
Is your mother home?
Yeah. I think she's upstairs.
Alright.
Jacques.
I see she got you.
She always tries to get me to cut
the salad.
It's the onions. I don't mind eating them.
I can't bear to cut them.
ELIZABETH: Is that you, John?
Yes, dear.
Would you like some wine?
ELIZABETH: Ohh, yes please!
Would you like a glass, Jacques?
JACQUES: No, thankyou.
How...
How are you getting on?
Very well, thankyou.
Your family have been very kind.
You're welcome.
Have you managed to contact anyone yet?
No. Not yet.
Zoe has been showing you around, I hear?
Yes.
Earth is a very beautiful place.
Yeah.
I suppose it is. I think most of us are too
preoccupied to realise it most of the time.
(Slice)
JOHN: Whoa!
You okay?
I'm fine. Yes.
Right.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm too tired to sleep. That's all.
Are we doing the right thing with this boy?
Jacques?
Letting him stay?
He's got nowhere else to go.
That's not our problem.
We don't know anything about him.
Surely, he should have contacted
someone by now.
It's all a bit strange. Don't you think?
You're being paranoid.
It's not going to be forever.
I mean...
Zoe likes him.
I can see that.
Maybe that's what she needs right now.
Maybe.
I just feel so...
I just want to protect her.
You do, John.
You do.
I not ready to lose her, Liz.
I'm not ready, yet.
I've never looked at the sky
like this before.
It's beautiful.
There's a million stars up there
that connect us all.
Look at that.
It's a shooting star.
That could have been you.
Close your eyes.
Make a wish.
What did you wish for?
I wished that this moment would
never end.
ZOE: Hi, Mum.
ELIZABETH: Ah, brilliant.
Jacques?
Would you mind getting the shopping
bags from the car?
ELIZABETH: Thankyou.
You two seem to be getting on very well.
Yeah.
It's been fun showing him around.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
It's really opened my eyes to how beautiful
the world is.
Hmm...
And he's not too bad looking either, is he?
Mum.
Look. I know you're happy...
but I don't want you getting too attached.
He's not from this world.
He's still figuring it all out.
I don't want you to get heartbroken.
Heartbroken?
Mum. This is the happiest I've been.
ELIZABETH: Come here.
No.
No way.
(Front Door Closes)
Is that you, John?
Yes. It's me.
How was your day?
Where is he?
Who?
Jacques?
He's in the garden.
ELIZABETH: John?
John, what's the matter?
Is something wrong?
(Whispering)
What are you doing?
They are getting too close.
They're in love.
Can't you see?
Well, it can't go on.
It can't last.
She's dying, for Christ's sake.
It's the happiest she's been.
Now, you promise me that
you won't ruin it for her.
- Ruin it?
I am her father.
I'm supposed to protect her.
Let her have her moment, John.
Let her have her moment!
ZOE: When I'm up there...
I mean, when I die...
I want to be able to look down on Earth...
and smile.
How wonderful it is.
It's beautiful.
I'm not ready to die.
ZOE: There's still so much I want to do.
Only the body can die.
The soul lives on.
I'll live among the stars.
That's right.
I worry about my Mum and Dad.
How awful it must be to bury a child.
Dad? He can take it.
Mum?
I'm not so sure.
Everything will be okay.
Have you been crying?
- No.
He...
He's in her room.
They're just talking. I'm sure.
Talking?
Yeah...right.
Zoe's a good girl.
She's never been that way.
There's a first time for everything.
That's the father in you.
Every boy is a suspect.
Yes, because every boy is.
She'll be fine.
She thinks we won't cope.
When she's gone.
We're a family.
We'll stick together.
And we'll fight and fight.
And we'll keep on fighting.
Don't worry.
(Sneeze)
Shit.
Mum!
- What do you need?
ZOE: A tissue.
ELIZABETH: Oh, Jesus Christ!
Hang on.
ELIZABETH: Put your head back.
Move your hand. It's alright.
It's okay, darling.
Hold it here.
I'm going to call your father, okay.
Hold it there.
Speak to her a minute.
(Crying)
JOHN: Hi.
Oh.
She must be exhausted.
I'm sorry.
We've been up and about sightseeing.
It's not your fault.
You've been really good for her.
As long as she's comfortable,
she'll be fine here.
Getting a rest for a change.
Are you going into work today?
- No.
I'll work from home.
Good.
Jacques?
Come for a drive.
Zoe is very fond of you.
She's my child.
I understand her.
She's dying.
She's grabbing onto life with both hands
and you make her feel like she's...
winning.
It's more than I ever did.
It's the happiest I've seen her.
I'm grateful.
But I have a question.
Who are you, Jacques?
Where are you from?
And what the hell are you doing here?
An Astronaut?
(Scoffs)
I don't quite buy that.
That night when you helped with
the salad for dinner...
I watched you cut clean through your hand.
Clean through.
Not a drop of blood.
Yesterday, I came here to look
for the remains of your ship.
Nothing.
You explain that to me!
I mean, how can something like that
just disappear?
Huh?
Who the hell are you?!!
And what the hell do you want
with my daughter?!!
Let go of me, John.
Calm down.
JACQUES: I know you're hurting, John.
I know you're angry.
I'm sorry.
You deserve to know the truth.
JOHN: Then you tell me the truth.
I'm not really an astronaut, John.
I wasn't born in space.
The truth is...
I'm not from this planet at all.
JOHN: No.
The place I call home is far
away from here.
Way beyond this galaxy.
Way beyond your stars.
I'm what you call...
"Alien".
JOHN: Your hand?
Yes.
We don't bleed.
We don't feel pain.
JOHN: This is crazy.
Where do you think humans
came from, John?
We brought you here, to this planet.
A million years ago.
We gave you basic technology and knowledge
and you thrived.
You became self sufficient.
Independent.
Now we need you.
I don't understand.
JACQUES: I've been sent here because
our people are dying out.
You want to invade our planet?
- No.
This isn't one of your
science-fiction films.
Well, what then?
I was sent here to find a Queen.
A Queen for our people.
My Queen.
Zoe?
JACQUES: Yes.
You want Zoe?
JACQUES: Together we will begin to
repopulate our world.
She's Dying!
You sick bastard!
JOHN: I'm going to kill you!
Let go of me, John.
You piece of shit!
JACQUES: Calm down, John.
Calm down.
(Straining)
JACQUES: I can cure her, John.
I knew I shouldn't have invited you
into my home. You bastard.
JACQUES: John, I'm serious...
I can cure her.
JACQUES: She'll be as good as new.
You just have to let her go.
With you?
Back to you world?
JACQUES: Yes.
And if I refuse?
JACQUES: You've seen her, John.
She's going to die, soon.
JACQUES: This way she doesn't have to.
This way she can have a life.
And your world?
What's it like?
Compared to ours, why is it so much better?
You are dying out!
JACQUES: Our plight, is simply
one of genetics.
John, she'll be a Queen.
JACQUES: Our saviour.
JACQUES: She'll have everything she wants
and everything she needs.
And if she wants to come home?
JACQUES: I'm afraid that wouldn't
be possible.
How do I know that you're telling
the truth?
JACQUES: Take her to any of your medics.
They will verify her condition.
JACQUES: She'll be as good as new.
You only have to agree.
And you can cure her?
JACQUES: Yes.
Yes.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
You cure her.
(Cries)
JACQUES: Yes.
Yes.
ELIZABETH: Are you still awake?
I'm taking Zoe to the Doctor
in the morning.
ELIZABETH: Okay.
DOCTOR: Mr and Mrs Armstrong.
This is quite remarkable.
There's really no way to explain it.
Zoe.
Your leukaemia has cleared up.
It's gone.
I don't mean into remission.
I mean it's disappeared completely.
It's quite miraculous.
Your white cell count is normal.
And so is your general cell structure.
Blood oxygen levels are regulated and there
are no abnormalities in the bone marrow.
This is very good news.
We'll want to keep an eye on you for
the next few months.
But from what I can see,
you've made a full recovery.
Spectacular.
Someone up there really loves you.
(Front door opens)
We've got her back.
We've got our baby back!
You kept your word.
She's cured.
The cancer has gone.
So, that's it?
When will you take her?
I'm not a monster, John.
It's Zoe's birthday in two days.
I'll wait until after.
Nineteen.
What if she refuses?
We made a deal, John.
Isn't it amazing?
It is.
I'm going to live.
I'm actually going to live.
Can you believe it?
What is it?
There's something I need to tell you.
Okay.
I'm going to leave soon.
I have to go.
How soon?
The day after tomorrow.
It's my birthday tomorrow, Jacques.
Is it my mum and dad?
Are they making you leave?
- No.
It's not them.
Then why do you want to go?
I have to.
I must.
I can go with you?
We can go together.
- Zoe.
Listen to me.
There's something I need to tell you.
Something about who I am
and where I'm from.
What I'm doing here.
Okay.
You might find this hard to understand.
Jacques?
Just tell me.
(Inaudible dialogue)
(Slap)
How could you do?
How could you sign her life away without
consulting me?
That's our baby.
She's our baby!
Now you see why I have to go.
I have no choice.
ELIZABETH: What do we do now, John?
Who do we call?
For now, we do nothing.
We sit tight and we wait.
ELIZABETH: Wait for what?
It's Zoe's birthday tomorrow.
He said that he'd wait until after that.
ELIZABETH: How soon after?
I don't know.
ELIZABETH: We have to tell her, John.
We've got to tell her who he really is.
We have no choice.
We can't do that. We have to keep
it between ourselves.
We have to find a way to get him
him away from her.
ELIZABETH: How could I be so stupid?
We let him into our home.
We let that alien into our home.
ELIZABETH: What are we going to do, John?
We have to fight him, Liz.
We have to fight him to keep
our little girl.
Come here.
Mum?
What are you doing up?
It's 6:00am.
I'm baking you a cake.
Happy birthday!
ZOE: Thanks, mum.
Coffee?
ZOE: Yeah.
You're so grown up.
I can't believe this day has come around
so quickly.
- I know.
When I gave birth to you, you were
this big.
I'm so proud of you, Zoe.
Everything you've been through.
The leukaemia and everything.
- Mum.
I know.
I get so emotional.
You're my one and only child.
It's natural.
Your father has invited the neighbours
for your birthday lunch.
Hope you don't mind.
- No. Not at all.
Doing anything fun later?
Yas will be here.
So, we'll probably go and get a drink
with some of my school friends.
Sounds nice.
I'm so glad to spend another birthday
with you, Zoe.
I love you.
ZOE: I love you too, mum.
(Spanish accent) KATE: It's okay, you know.
He's does not know how to dance.
No rhythm. But it's fine. My family
eventually teach him.
You know. A little bit of salsa!
And now he moves a bit more.
We call him 'Scarecrow'.
Or 'Giraffe on rollerblades'.
How did you two meet?
You're a cute couple.
Oh, Jacques isn't my boyfriend.
Ah, he's your...
No. No. No.
He's Zoe's. Sort of.
Oh. I'm sorry, Yasmin. I thought he...
TIM: Don't worry, Yasmin. She's always
putting her foot in it. Aren't you darling?
- Yes. It's true.
Ah, baby. One moment.
There we are.
Cheese puffs!
Hey!
Your weight.
(Whispering)
Stop it!
YASMIN: I love your dress, Kate.
It's gorgeous.
Thank you. Tim got it for me actually.
- I did? When?
I picked it up with his credit card.
(Laugh)
Listen, that's the beginning of the end.
You want to watch that.
There you go.
- No, Thank you.
TIM: Kate's pregnant.
What?
She's pregnant.
KATE: Yes.
That is wonderful news!
Come here.
When are you due?
We're only in the first trimester.
Seven months to go.
Congratulations.
-Thank you.
JOHN: Welcome aboard.
Thanks.
Have you thought of any names?
Alejandro.
TIM: We're not sure about that one, yet.
Enrique.
Enrique!!!
- Enrique.
Listen, how about 'Josh'?
- Josh?
- I like Josh.
TIM: It's nice. Exactly.
It's a good quality name.
- Josh?
What's wrong with 'Josh'?
- Baby, we talked about this.
Guillermo!
Alejandro, maybe.
TIM: Gelmo?
KATE: 'Gelmo'?
KATE: G-U-I-L-L-E-R-M-O!
ZOE: An orange juice for you, kate.
- Thank you, Zoe. Happy Birthday!
ZOE: Thankyou.
Thank you.
JOHN: You alright?
ZOE: Yeah, fine.
- Everything good?
ZOE: Yeah. I feel fine.
KATE: It's so good to see you up
and about again.
TIM: Happy birthday, Zoe.
ZOE: Thank you, Tim.
KATE: We just met your gorgeous
boyfriend, Jacques.
KATE: Mmm...Yes...
ZOE: Yeah.
KATE: Eh, John?
JOHN: Yes.
Ah, listen.
(Whispering)
The cake.
KATE: Go, go, go.
- Okay.
(Applause)
Happy birthday!!!
(Cheering)
Just a few words.
To Zoe.
Our wonderful daughter.
Zoe has been a beacon of light
in our lives.
She's fought through hell and high water.
And always with a smile on her face.
She's an inspiration.
A rock. You are a rock.
Remission after remission.
And we are...
so glad that we can spend another
birthday with you.
Zoe!
Jesus Christ.
Elizabeth, please.
Please.
No, John.
To hell with him.
I won't stand by and watch while he tries
to take our daughter away.
What's going on?
Him.
That thing.
That's what's going on.
- Elizabeth.
We invite you into our home
we feed you, we clothe you
and you betray us by trying to steal
our daughter away from us.
Damn you, Jacques.
Who the hell do you think you are?
Elizabeth, this is not the time.
This is the time!
This is the fucking time!
This looks like a family thing.
I think we should go.
JOHN: Tim, I'm sorry.
TIM: It's okay.
Would you mind letting yourselves out?
- No problem.
TIM: Go. go. Come on.
JOHN: Kate. Tim. Thanks.
JOHN: Give us a call.
Now, Elizabeth.
Calm down.
I will not calm down!
ZOE: Mum?
YASMIN: Should I go?
No, Yas. Stay right where you are.
Your dad found out some very interesting
things about Jacques.
I told you not to say anything, John.
She's my wife.
He's an alien.
He's not an astronaut.
He's from another planet!
He's here to kidnap you.
He cured your leukaemia and made you better
so he can take you back to his planet.
Or wherever the hell he is from.
Your father made a deal with him in secret.
But I'm sorry.
We can't have that.
It's time for you to leave, Jacques.
YASMIN: Crazy.
We had to tell you, Zoe.
You made a deal?
I had no choice.
You were dying!
I know who he is.
I know all about him.
About where he's from.
What are you saying?
- I'm saying...
Jacques has told me everything.
And I've decided that I'm going with him.
What!?
I'm going with him.
No. This is ludicrous.
No. I won't allow it.
Over my dead body!
Elizabeth?
Stay back, John!
Don't defend him, Zoe.
JACQUES: Put the knife down, Elizabeth.
- Like hell I will.
Stop it.
Just stop it.
ZOE: I'm not a child anymore.
Mum.
Dad.
I love you.
But, you know as well as I do
I should be dead right now.
I've spent years of my life fighting it.
Remission after remission after remission.
And...
I'm tired.
I'm so tired, Mum.
Jacques.
Whoever he is.
Wherever he's from...
He fell out of the sky and he changed
my life.
He made me want to live again.
He cured me. What more can I ask for?
I love him.
That's right.
So...
If my only options are
Cancer and 'Chemo'...
Or life with Jacques...
Can you blame me?
I choose life.
I choose him.
Because I'm so scared...
of the alternative.
I don't want to die.
So, I've made my choice.
So, this is how it's going to end?
I need you to accept it.
JACQUES: It's time.
Is this the place?
JACQUES: Yes
It is.
What are we looking for?
Can you hear it?
Oh my god. John. Look.
Is that what I think it is?
It's my people.
They're here.
We love you, Zoe.
We love you so much.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
Please don't be sad.
Mum?
We'll think about you every day.
And you'll still be our
little baby.
You'll see me.
When you look up at the stars.
I love you.
Don't go, Zoe.
What am I going to do without you?
Thankyou.
For being the best friend a person
could ever ask for.
You held me up.
Supported me.
Take care of yourself. Okay?
I love you, Zoe.
I love you, too.
It's time.
JACQUES: You might want to step back a bit.
I'm ready.
Hold me tight.
Don't let go.
Don't let go!
I won't!
(Deep rumbling sound)
Subtitles by SAHARA ROAD