This view's gonna be amazing.
- I have a surprise for you.
- What's that?
Close your eyes.
Open them.
Will you marry...
Yes.
Where did you go?
This isn't funny, Todd.
Where are you?
Help! Anyone! Can you help?
Please, help me!
Please. Todd.
All right. That's the last one.
Please tell me the mooring's intact.
Looks fine. The earthquake
didn't cause any visible cracks.
All right. Great.
I get to stay above water today.
Another chance for me
to teach your uncle how it's done.
Whatever.
Hey, Ray, if you're not getting
any bites, let's pull it in.
Never want to
stay in the same spot too long.
Hey, man.
What if this is the spot, Hunter?
Come on. Slow and steady.
That's the McCray way.
Maybe too slow and too steady
is the reason...
why you still haven't caught
the big one, Uncle Ray.
Yeah, Ray, what about that big one?
Hey, keep on.
I'm gonna show both of y'all.
Just keep on.
We're gonna miss you.
Are you sure you won't reconsider?
Look around, Hunter.
This?
This is heaven, baby.
You ain't gonna find
anything better than this.
I'm not gonna pretend
I haven't become fond of this place.
And us?
That's not the issue.
What do they think they're doing?
Besides working my last nerve?
I think they breaking
every maritime law there is.
That's why some people
should stay on the shore.
Yeah, they got fools
over there too, Hunter.
That, my friend,
is why I live on a boat.
I smell a teachable moment coming.
Me too.
(Foreign Language)
Come on. Move the clown car
over here. Move it.
Who the hell are you?
Adult supervision.
Thanks, pops. You know,
I think we got it from here, though.
From here, I don't see one person...
that could pass
a field sobriety test.
Harbor master, boy.
Hand over them fireworks.
Do you have any idea
how much I spent on these?
Not as much as you're gonna have to
pay the tourist police...
if I turn you in.
Whatever.
Have fun.
I took this off him.
Get your boat fixed.
See? He's cool.
Cheers to Mr. Tik.
(Foreign Language)
You see the look on the kid's face
when you took his fireworks?
Priceless.
You better grab that pole, Ray,
before it's gone.
Oh shit. Come on.
I got it. It's the big one!
- I got it. I got it this time.
- Come on.
- Almost.
- Easy.
- Come on.
- Here's a big one. I got it!
What's that?
Fires? Dead bodies?
I'm gonna have to start
taking my blood pressure medicine...
- before I leave the dock.
- He's been in the water a long time.
You guys need to look at this.
Maybe that's where
the body came from.
That's not good.
I'm gonna call the authorities.
Let's head in.
I'm gonna pull the drone.
I'ma cover his ugly ass up.
Could this be an algae bloom?
Yeah, maybe
if we were in the Caribbean.
Not in these waters, though.
Uncle Ray?
Get off my niece!
Hell is wrong with you, man?
Look, stay right there where you at.
Look, you don't want
none of this, man.
I don't know who you are
or what you are...
but you better
stay the hell away from me.
I don't know about you.
You want some of this?
- You want some of this?
- I'm scared.
Get back. Come on. Hunter!
- Stay right here.
- Please.
Oh stop, man. Look, I said stop!
You know what "halt" means?
Bitch, you better move.
I'm not playing with you.
Ray, take care of Jada. I got this.
Look, buddy. I don't know
what you've been through...
but unless you back off,
this is gonna go through you next.
Jada! No. Baby, please.
- I'm scared.
- It's okay.
Stay right here.
Stay with me, baby. Stay.
- Is she all right?
- Is it dead?
- Is it gone?
- Did you kill it?
- I think so.
- Good.
Hunter!
You've got to be kidding me.
It's just a meth head, right?
Some old punk washed up
on the side of the pier.
I don't know, Ray,
why don't you show him your badge?
Maybe that'll stop him.
Formalities ended
when he bit my niece!
Got to be
a rational explanation, right?
Well, if you got one, I'm all ears.
Buh-bye.
You want some more of this?
You better not come back over here.
Ray?
Oh shit.
Jada.
It's okay.
Are we dreaming?
No. I wish we were.
I got this, man. Go radio for help...
- please.
- I'm on it.
Stay with me.
So this makes, what,
five double shifts in a row now?
Six, if you're counting.
Mom, when's the last time
you had a date?
Look, she's hot, right, Taani?
Smokin'.
You're sweet. What I do
is more important than how I look.
But you just need
to find some balance.
Dad's been gone a long time.
He'd want you to be happy.
I am happy.
Now that's more like it.
Hello?
I've got
an accident on my hands here.
Let me guess.
Another charter client...
cast his line
into his buddy's tackle box?
No, but I owe you dinner for that.
And a bottle of wine.
The trauma still lingers.
It's a different kind of accident.
It's Ray's niece.
She's hurt pretty bad.
Oh yeah. I'm on my way.
Duty calls.
More like booty calls.
What'd he say?
- Enough.
- Look, all I'm saying is...
what's the point
of living in paradise...
without someone to share it with?
When I get home, you better be there,
walls still standing.
Promise. I love you.
I'll take care of her, Mrs. Wright.
Yeah. That's what I'm afraid of.
Bye.
Come on. Give me your arm.
I got you. Wasn't nothing normal
about that back there, Hunter.
I mean, nothing we did
was even able to stop him.
How do we know
there's no more out there...
looking for
another midday snack, huh?
Hey, Ray, reel it in.
- You're gonna be okay.
- Okay. Hey, guys.
Hey, Doc.
Hey, Jada?
- What happened?
- Curved laceration.
Tissue loss.
This is a bite wound. What happened?
Look, we pulled this dead guy in
off the water, right?
We laid him down and then...
His teeth...
he started biting everybody...
and then Hunter grabbed a machete...
- and he went...
- Hey.
This guy regains consciousness...
he starts biting
and attacking everybody...
and then we throw him overboard.
It's okay, Jada.
- You're okay, honey.
- Okay. Coming through.
So are you gonna be leaving?
Yeah, tomorrow's my last day
in Emrys Bay.
No good-byes? You owe me dinner.
- You'll be okay.
- Are you coming or not?
I'm gonna talk to Sheriff Akoni...
see if we can figure out
what's going on out there.
Truck's in the lot.
Meet us at the hospital later?
Got it.
Hey.
- Thanks for getting here so quick.
- No problem.
She's really gonna be okay, right?
She's gonna be fine.
This is Akoni. I'm at the pier.
The water looks calm.
It's all fine here.
- Head out to Comet's Beach next.
- Copy that.
Thought you'd be long gone, Shaw.
Yeah, sometimes the heart and head
aren't always in sync.
Is there a reason why you're
walking around with a machete?
If you saw what I saw,
you'd want one in both hands.
Yeah, Ray called in.
Some kind of sea monster?
A lunatic attacked his niece.
Beach squatter?
Boating accident? What?
I've been working on the water
for 30 years.
I have never, ever, seen
anything like this.
I don't have the time to
go on a wild goose chase with you.
What's going on out there
is a bigger problem.
You see that, right?
- Okay.
- Come on. Take a ride with me.
You hear the sounds
that come in waves
The singer's name is Dag.
Or maybe you're into the drummer.
His name is Ivan. He's Russian!
Interested?
Ask me again
when I can hear myself think.
Yeah, party!
- Chemical spill?
- Maybe.
That's the only thing
I could think of...
that may explain
that guy we saw on the boat today.
Where's the body?
I don't know. This is
where we threw it overboard, though.
We need to see where the source is
coming from.
I got eyes for you.
Rand, you're so cool.
- That was incredible.
- I know.
So you like our set?
Yeah. You guys were...
Not your kind of thing, huh?
No, we had fun.
Just doesn't really seem like you.
Thank you.
Rand's taste is
more "mallet to the head."
Me?
All I want is fans who like our music
because it comes from the heart...
not because it's loud.
I'm Dag.
Sam.
I think the earthquake
may have something to do with this.
We didn't go this deep last time.
Is that a documented wreck?
Not that I'm aware of.
Ship's name and designation
have been removed.
No telling where it's from then.
No, this is an Anton 350
made by Anders Marine in Denmark.
Very few were ever made
with this extended 80-foot hull.
Whatever took it down
took down a very rare ship.
How do you know that?
Grew up in San Pedro,
right off the docks.
Some people know cars.
I know boats.
There's the light source.
Did you see that?
Yeah...
I put a machete into
the chest of one of these guys today.
It didn't stop him,
didn't slow him down one bit.
Come on, Shaw.
- Tell you what I think they are.
- What's that?
It's alive, but dead.
Let's stick to reality.
These are zombies.
You got me, Shaw. You got me.
Don't even say it.
Get us out of here.
Pok, there's been
some kind of outbreak offshore.
Evac is mandatory.
Get everyone off the beach now,
and find my daughter.
Attention: by order
of the Emrys Bay Police...
the beach is closed.
This is a mandatory evacuation
until further notice.
This is not a drill.
- Hey.
- Hey, Doc.
Akoni and I think
there's been some kind of outbreak...
so isolate Jada,
keep your eyes open...
for anyone else
who comes in with similar injuries.
Okay. What are we talking about here?
- Danny, check this out.
- Clear the beach.
Seek shelter.
- Could you...
- Okay.
It should be over there.
That's not a sound I like to hear.
Look, Sam's at my house
with Akoni's daughter.
If anything happens,
can you get to them?
Got it, but the tsunami's
only part of the problem.
There's been some kind of outbreak.
I've got to start prepping patients
for evac. You be safe.
Wait!
What are we gonna do
about those things?
What are you gonna do about that?
Oh my gosh, a tsunami.
That's totally insane.
Your mom's gonna have a busy shift.
Your dad too.
So I guess we're not getting tacos.
Where do you think you're going?
We need to get behind the wave.
I've seen those things.
I know what they're capable of.
When the wave hits the beach...
flooding's gonna be
the least of our problems.
People are gonna need our help.
How are we gonna do that
without getting ourselves killed?
We're gonna
ride the barrel of the wave.
When we get to the beach,
we'll storm it.
We'll help everybody that we can.
- You know you're crazy, right?
- Hang on.
It's a zombie tsunami.
Come on. They're moving past us.
Run!
Save your bullets.
Blaine?
Blaine, honey, are you okay?
Shaun didn't make it.
But we did, baby.
That's all that matters.
Hey!
What'd I say?
Baby!
Hey, look, if there was ever a time
to celebrate, this is it.
Okay, so we'll only
keep you two isolated...
until we know everything's okay.
Great. It keeps
getting better and better.
It's just a precaution
until we can determine...
what this outbreak is.
What I saw out there...
it's gonna take more than this
to kill them.
Dr. Wright, we need you outside.
Okay. Hang in there.
I'll check in soon,
but I got to get back.
This evacuation's reduced us
to a skeleton staff.
I'm trying. No!
- Over here!
- Come on...
they're not breathing! What's wrong?
- You took one of them on?
- Yeah, Ray and I.
It was a lot easier
when we could throw them overboard.
Hey, get away from them!
Get off the beach!
They're hurt. They need help.
Come on!
You see what I'm talking about here?
Zombies it is.
I still can't get a hold of my mom
or anybody.
- What about your dad?
- No, nothing yet.
What's wrong with their faces?
Tsunami must have messed them up.
What if those things get up here?
We've got to
get away from this place.
- Come on.
- Yeah.
Come on, this way. Let's go.
I'll take care of that one.
- Watch out.
- Get out of here.
Out of my way.
- Get out.
- Run, come on!
Run!
Let's get out of here. Thank you!
Uncle Ray.
Hey, baby.
I'm so cold.
It's gonna be okay.
Let me get you some cover.
So hungry, I just...
That's... Let me get the nurse
to bring you something to eat, okay?
Jada?
Jada!
Hey, stay with me.
Jada, stay with me.
No. Jada. Jada, what are you doing?
Hey, stop! Hey! Jada, stop!
Hey! Jada, don't! Jada, stop!
What you doing?
Jada, get off him! Stop doing that!
No! Hey, help! Help!
Beach is overrun.
We've got to set up a triage
for the victims.
Maybe not.
Let's get back to the station,
regroup, and call for backup.
Ray's truck.
They're everywhere!
- Stop! Don't shoot.
- Man, we're not one of them.
You again.
Yeah, of course.
I see you got a new sidekick.
I'm sorry. He's an idiot.
Can you please help us?
Where'd you two come from?
We were at the beach.
It was awful, and we lost Shaun.
Could you just, like, get us
to our hotel or something?
Five-star hotel's not gonna
protect you from that.
What's that even supposed to mean?
That it's not a problem
you can buy your way out of.
So buckle up, sweetheart.
They're coming.
4, 5, 0, 8.
Hello?
Someone, help!
Somebody!
No!
Oh my God.
Have you seen what's out there?
Yeah.
If the contagion's aerosol,
you could contract it from breathing.
Unless you plan
on tying their mouths shut...
- this is not gonna get it.
- They're infected.
- Clearly, it's a contagion.
- Look, it's more than that!
They rode in here
on that big-ass wave...
bringing a double dose of disaster
to this town like nobody's seen...
so I suggest you lace up
your running shoes, Doc...
because if what's out there
bites you, it's game over.
How is this happening?
How? Why?
I stopped caring about that...
when I saw my niece
bite the head off of that orderly.
Do you know what that sounds like?
Do you know what that looks like?
Move right to acceptance, Doc...
'cause denial is a death sentence.
I can't reach any other units
on comms.
Has anyone reported in?
- No one.
- What are we dealing with here, sir?
Welcome to Crazy Town, Officer Pok.
Come on!
Blaine, come on.
Hurry up! Come on!
- Sorry.
- Blaine!
Give me the chair!
Get me the other one.
Come on, Doc.
We can't stop them all
with just these.
I know.
Okay. We cut through the terrace.
The admin offices
are right next door.
Terrace it is.
How could you do that?
Man, it's everybody for themselves!
She saved your ass.
What would you expect me to do, man?
Let them bite me?
No way.
I'm gonna do everything it takes
to survive.
Including this.
Lower your weapon.
Lower your weapon!
Put it down.
You got some balls, kid.
- I got bullets too.
- Take it easy.
I want those big guns in there.
That's not gonna happen.
Give me the keys now!
Open the door!
Give me the keys! Open the door.
Give me the keys now. Now!
Stay with me, Pok. Stay with me.
This kid's worse
than the things outside.
Rand!
How's that for "pay to play"?
Let's go!
Come on. This way.
Come on! Oh no!
No!
Hey, wait.
Check out here. Go.
Come on.
I think I sprained my ankle.
Okay, duck.
- Oh my God!
- Taani!
Help!
Taani!
Come on, Ta...
Taani, look out!
Get away from them!
Go! We'll find you!
Okay.
This is Emrys Bay station
issuing an open-channel mayday.
In addition to tsunami damage...
we've had an outbreak
of unknown origin. Over.
To all naval assets
in the vicinity...
this is Emrys Bay station
issuing an open-channel mayday.
Tell me again
why I didn't shoot that kid dead.
That thing hanging around your neck.
Fair enough.
So I logged into
the maritime registry...
using Ray's account...
There's only one Anton 350
in the regional archives...
and it's registered
to Revok Industries...
from 1981 to 1985...
but then it was decommissioned.
Status now is salvaged, junked.
Then what's it doing
at the bottom of the ocean?
Exactly. Something doesn't add up.
I think
we've got more pressing issues.
The key to all this is this ship.
If we can find one person
that knows something about it...
maybe we can get some answers.
It's not safe here. We've got to go.
We're gonna need some more firepower.
Okay, we cross over
to the main building.
We cut through Radiology.
Okay.
Oh, hell no!
Bite me.
Jada, don't you have
something else to do?
Oh my God.
Whatever that is, it's not Jada.
Yeah, I know.
Still not gonna be an easy call
to my sister Gina, though.
We pulled enough hardware
off drug boats and narco planes...
over the years
to outfit a small army.
Wow.
Did you get this off a drug dealer?
Some kid bought it online
with his mom's credit card.
Went all shogun
on his brother's bedroom.
What happened to his brother?
Still looking for his pinky toe.
When we're done with them,
we're gonna find my daughter.
Hey!
Dude, are you serious right now?
Seriously, you guys can't
just leave me like this.
Let's go kill some dead guys.
Hey, this is murder! Hey!
I can't hold them off any longer.
Do it now!
Nice shot.
They're still squirming.
I'll take squirming over biting
any day.
Reinforcements.
'Cause one would have been too easy.
Come on.
You shoot a zombie in the head,
they're supposed to die, right?
Maybe there's something more.
That's what I'm afraid of.
Look. Dead ahead.
They're getting on my nerves.
Hold on.
Roadkill.
Come on.
Don't look back. Come on.
Come on, be quick. Come on.
Wake up! Come on,
open the door! Wake up!
- Come on! They're trying to kill us!
- What's going on, man?
- What's wrong with them?
- What are you doing?
Get back in here, Ivan.
Rock and roll, baby!
Come on! We gotta go!
We got to go now!
Car's dead.
What are we gonna do?
We'll figure this out.
They're everywhere.
Come on!
Hello?
This is private property.
The gate's there for a reason,
so just go away.
No. I need your help, please.
They're after me.
Turn around. I need to check you out.
Look, perv, just open the door!
Have you been bitten?
What?
Look. Look at me.
Do I look like I have been bitten?
Show me the back of your head.
Oh my God! Fine.
If you don't open the door now,
I am gonna be bit.
Are we all good?
Hello?
Yeah, okay.
You live here by yourself?
- Yeah.
- That explains the Unabomber chic.
Can you please put that away?
You first.
Okay.
I've been watching from up here.
Looks really bad.
I have monitors all around town.
When these things arrived...
just about everyone was infected
in less than an hour.
There are so many of them.
I need to call my dad.
Can I use that?
Please?
Thank you.
Dad, do you copy?
Taani, where are you? You're okay?
You don't know
how glad I am to hear your voice.
Yeah.
I'm safe.
I'm...
I'm at the compound
on top of the hillside.
At Driscoll's?
I told you never
to go near that place. He's crazy.
Yeah.
Great. Dad,
I didn't really have a choice, 'kay?
His place is pretty fortified.
Do you really want me to leave?
No. I don't want you to leave.
I need you to go get Sam.
We got separated at the market.
Just stay put. We'll come to you.
Be careful.
Stay safe.
At least we know she's okay.
Yeah.
We should probably go in now.
So long, sucker.
Hey, baby.
Hey. Baby...
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean anything
by that, baby.
- You have to find a way out.
- No, you're coming with me.
I can't. I'll slow you down.
- No. I'm not leaving you.
- You're gonna have to.
You'll move faster without me.
Yeah, well, what are you gonna do?
I'm gonna get their attention.
Wait, here. Take this.
Right here! Over here!
You hear the sounds
that come in waves
By people dancing on a grave
Here! Help! Over here! Help!
And things are just
about to get depraved
We'll party. Party
Party to raise the dead
- Party
- Come on.
Party to raise the dead
'Cause once you're underground.
You won't hear a sound
We got to go get him.
He hurt his foot.
We'll get him.
Come on.
Hey, Sam.
It's gonna be all right.
He's dead because of me.
I don't know where my mom is,
and we got separated from Taani.
Taani's gonna be fine. She's the one
who told us where to find you.
- They didn't get her?
- No.
We're gonna get your mom
at the hospital...
and then we're gonna get Taani.
Don't you worry.
Thank you, Hunter.
- Let's be quick, Shaw.
- I'm on it.
See if you can text your mom.
- Still no signal.
- She could be anywhere.
I need to let her know that I'm here.
Anything we do
is gonna draw their attention.
Exactly.
I need to get to the nurse's station.
You're not going alone.
I know every inch of this place.
You two will just slow me down.
Take this. You're gonna need
to protect yourself.
- I know how to use a gun.
- You're not getting a gun.
Fine.
Awesome. Coast is clear.
Wait!
The patients are getting restless.
Time for their medicine.
- Attention, please.
- What's she doing?
- I don't know.
- This is an important message...
for Dr. Kenzie Wright.
Please come to the second floor
of the nurse's station...
to claim your daughter.
She's extremely worried...
and would like
to leave this freak show behind.
Can't hold them off for much longer.
I don't know what's worse,
their teeth...
Or their breath.
Got any ideas?
Let's see if we can
shock some sense into them.
Let go! Please! Let go!
Hey. Sam's safe.
Is she on this floor?
Down the hall.
Ray, take this.
You two guys been having a cookout?
Just go.
Sam?
Sam, come on.
Mom!
Come on. Grab her hands.
I'll get her feet.
Get your knife.
You're okay.
Come on. Let's go.
All right.
Wait. Hang on.
These ones are different.
Yeah, this is one of the ones
that started all this.
He came in on the waves.
It looks like
these guys were experimented on.
We got to get out.
Sam, Kenzie, stay by me. Come on.
All right, get in the car.
Go easy on Driscoll.
He doesn't like guests.
Dad!
You said you weren't going out.
Now this time,
you put your friend in danger.
I know. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Oh my gosh. Are you all right?
- Have you been bitten?
- No, I haven't been.
No! No biters in the house.
I said I wasn't bitten.
Shaw.
Hey, before we bail, do you mind if
we use that radio to call for help?
Just don't mess up anything
on my desk.
This is Officer Kameo Akoni
of Emrys Bay.
We need assistance.
Anyone out there?
It's quiet out there.
Cell towers are down.
There hasn't been any chatter
on the radio for hours.
Not that I'd want to talk to anybody.
We've had two tsunamis...
and no one has come
to check on us in town.
That should tell you
something right there.
Help has to be on the way.
Coast Guard's coming.
There's no one out there.
Akoni?
What's going on down there?
- Akoni!
- Dad?
Akoni!
Run! It's coming!
- Dad!
- What the hell...
is going on down there?
Say something! Akoni!
- Stay back, Sam.
- Akoni!
Mom!
Thanks, Driscoll.
No problem.
Way to go, Mom.
Everybody okay?
Dad?
- Dad?
- I'm sorry.
- No.
- I'm sorry, baby.
I'm so sorry.
- No!
- I'm sorry.
No.
We can't stay here.
Place held up just fine
till you whackadoodles showed up.
Your little science project
that almost killed my daughter and I?
We can agree
that one's on you, right?
And exactly what were you doing
with your bunkmate down there?
Trying to figure out
what makes them tick.
- What'd you learn?
- The liquid inside it...
tested consistent with phosphorus.
That explains
the blue glow in the water.
The Taser is the only thing
I've seen that could stop it.
We stopped
a whole bunch in the hospital...
with electricity as well.
That's why I connected the Taser
to the sword.
Zombie nuts roasting on an open fire.
How are gonna kill them all
with one Taser?
Downed power lines.
I saw several of them at the beach,
but the grid is still running.
We use the tidal pools
to conduct the electricity.
All we need to do is
lure the zombies into the water...
and then we run the power to it.
- Fish in a barrel.
- But the ship is not in your barrel.
We're gonna have to
blow up that ship too.
If we can take care of
most of them...
then the Coast Guard can take care
of the stragglers when they get here.
If they get here.
Okay. How do we blow up the ship?
Here.
You can take this C4 with you.
You can take grenades.
You can even take this cereal
with you when you leave.
You're gonna leave, right?
I'll take the ones on land.
I guess
I'm the captain of the boat, huh?
What the hell do I know about C4?
Driscoll, we're gonna
need your help with that.
A lot of people are gonna die
unless we stop them.
All right. I'm in.
I'll clear a path,
and we'll all make a run for it.
Come on.
What's wrong?
His Taser isn't working.
He needs my help.
Come on.
Fire up the wood chipper.
It's feeding time.
Nice moves.
Thanks.
Come on, Driscoll! Come on, let's go!
You're gonna have
some good roses this year.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
- Let's go.
- No, you come on. Let's go.
Hurry up. It's over here.
Hey, wait a minute, man! Wait!
All right. Watch your step.
Hey.
Look, if anything happens to me,
just take care of Sam, okay?
Nothing's gonna happen
to either of you.
I promise.
Should have just
followed my instincts...
motored to another port
where it's safe.
So that's why you live in a boat?
So you can take off
when things get rough?
I always knew you weren't
the settling-down type of guy...
Hunter.
Knowing that made it easier
to be friends without getting hurt.
Seeing you and Sam at the hospital...
risking everything
to get back to each other...
Taani and her dad
doing the same thing.
I thought I had it all.
Made me realize...
I don't have anything.
Aw, hell no.
Look, y'all been
beating around the bush for months.
This ain't no time for canoodling.
Sam!
Come on.
Thank you.
Yeah.
We both know
how this is going to end.
It's not over till it's over.
Doesn't anyone else think it's weird
that he ain't turned yet?
They didn't bite through his head
and penetrate his skull...
didn't get to the brain.
I've been watching on my monitors.
It takes longer through the skin.
Town's in your hands now, Hunter.
Take care of it.
And take care of them.
Do it better than I did.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'll tell you what I know.
Revok Pharmaceuticals
came here 30 years ago.
They claimed
to be making major strides...
with a new anti-aging drug.
They needed to test it on humans...
away from FDA scrutiny
in the United States.
They brought in staff,
patients, security...
and the local council leaders and I
just needed to make sure...
that everything stayed off the radar.
They paid us.
They financed trips...
and they made sure that my wife...
got the best medical treatment...
before she passed on.
If you wouldn't mind
fast-forwarding to the part...
where the zombies come to town...
I think we'd all appreciate it.
They lied.
The drug wasn't ready.
They shouldn't have been
trying it on humans.
There are hideous side effects...
and they knew
we couldn't say anything, because...
we were all complicit.
How could you allow this, Kameo?
By the time
we realized what they were doing...
they'd shipped out
all the patients and staff.
But in the back of my mind...
I knew they sunk the ship.
When Hunter tied the boat at
the bottom of the ocean to Revok...
there was no denying
what I had been a party to...
what I had done.
You're not seeing
the bigger play here.
The trials actually worked.
Those patients' hideous reactions
were not side effects.
They were the desired effects.
So they developed a drug...
that would weaponize
an entire population...
one that would destroy itself
from within?
A biological weapon is worth
more on the black market...
than any anti-aging drug.
Come on. Let's move.
Go!
I got this, guys.
Run!
Go! Keep going!
Come on.
Daddy, come...
- Wasp knife?
- Yeah.
Got another?
Have this one.
Don't you have enough toys already?
No.
I love you.
Grab the bag. Let's go.
Okay.
All right. Let's get to it.
Come on, Taani.
I'll catch up.
All right,
call me if you get into any trouble.
Driscoll, what about the ones
still up at your house?
You didn't think
I took all the C4 with me, did you?
Ray...
see you on the other side.
You too, brother.
Hey, man, is that stuff stable?
Stable as I am.
Move out my way.
There it is.
All right, the fuses blew
when the lines went down.
I can make the downed power lines
active again.
I'm gonna use those tidal pools
to complete the circuit.
Then we'll reset the breaker.
Once we do that,
the power's gonna flow.
We're gonna have to hurry.
I'll get the lines in the water.
Stay here.
Don't hit that switch
until I tell you. Got it?
Yeah.
Time to kick some ass.
All right, hit it!
Guys...
we've got to hurry.
They're getting close.
I still don't understand
why I have to be the one...
to secure the bombs
to the sunken ship.
Because I have to
drive this thing away...
before the detonator goes off.
That's your stuff,
and I'm not putting her in the water.
Okay, fine.
I'll make sure
the C4 locks on to the boat.
Up to you to do the rest.
I got it.
I don't know
why I keep saying "yes" to everybody.
I don't even like people.
Maybe 'cause
you're kind of a good guy.
Nope.
Okay. It worked.
- And now we got to get the zombies.
- We need bait.
Okay.
I'm gonna Pied Piper them
to follow me into the tidal pools.
- Once I do...
- We'll pull the switch.
Exactly.
Hey!
Come and get it!
Come over here!
Come on! Come and get it!
Over here!
Hey, over here!
Oh yeah.
Come and get it. Come on!
Throw me the C4 once I go in.
Time to fight crazy with crazy.
Driscoll, get out the water! Move!
Move!
Move, Driscoll! Move!
No!
Go up front.
- Hunter needs help.
- You stay here!
Be careful!
Come on.
Now! Throw the switch!
Okay.
Hurry. They're close.
Put this vest on. Get in the water.
It's not happening.
- Taani!
- No.
Look, when that anchor
hits the bottom...
- this boat is not going anywhere.
- Your point?
If your dad was here...
he'd kick my butt
if I didn't kick you off my boat...
- so I'm kicking you off my boat!
- Okay.
When you get in the water,
hold the vest...
lay back, and ride the wave.
What about the zombies?
Don't worry about them.
They don't have a prayer.
It's not working!
Come on.
Mom!
It worked.
Hey, Hunter. It's Ray. Come in.
Hunter, do you copy?
Ray, we got them.
What's going on out there?
It's a little rough out here...
but I'm about to catch the big one.
Oh no.
Come on, Hunter!
Come on.
Oh my...
Hey.
I didn't think you made it.
Looks like we got most of them.
Mom. Come on.
Taani?
I've got you.
Help.
Are you okay?
It's okay.
Sit down.
What about Ray?
You're gonna be okay.
A little bruised up,
but you just need rest.
Are you still leaving?
Not on your life, Kenzie.
Good, 'cause you still owe me dinner.
And wine.
And a movie.
Anything else?
It's about time.
Finally.
Come on.
What are we gonna do now?
Whatever we do,
we're doing it together.