ZORRO AT THE COURT OF ENGLAND
Manuel Garcia is accused of
having aroused, by his talks
and his writings, the people
of Hamilton
and of having incited them
to revolt.
By virtue of his powers,
the Governor of the Island,
Sir Basil Ruthford,
sentences the accused
to death by hanging.
One day, they will have
to pay for this.
This is the third in a month.
Sooner or later, it will be our turn.
Manuel ! Manuel !
It's time for us to revolt !
Everyone !
We must rebel !
No-one can do anything
against these tyrants.
Damn you all ! Assassins !
Damn you all !
Execute him !
Replace the rope.
Your Excellency !
May I point out to you
that, according to tradition, if a
condemned man escapes death,
for any reason like this one,
he is granted his freedom.
You dare question my orders ?
Sergeant, shoot
the condemned man
where he stands.
Quickly !  Stop him !
Shut the gate, quickly !
Manuel !
Courage, Maria.
I will be back !
Captain, what are you doing
standing there ? Get moving !
Rest assured,
he will not escape me.
Follow me !
Idiots ! Cretins !
You have let him get away.
The next time,
I will get him for sure !
What are you doing standing there ?
Get moving !
Curses upon him !
Down there, a ship awaits you.
It will take you to England.
Explain what is happening here.
Tell the Queen she is poorly
represented on this island.
I will spread the news,
you can rely on me.
I will do all I can to talk
with the Queen.
But I would like to know your name
and see your face
So I may properly express
my gratitude to you.
Time presses, you must go.
When justice and liberty
once again triumph on this island,
I will reveal my name to you.
For the moment, I can only
tell you that I am called
Zorro !
The entire population remain
loyal to Your Majesty,
and support your efforts
in advancing the prosperity
and well-being of this country.
But the harassment and abuse
instigated by Your Majesty's
current representative
serve only to exasperate
the people.
The Judges are biased firmly
behind the Governor
and only listen to the witnesses
for the prosecution.
The convicted serve their
sentences in the Clinton mines.
The few prisoners who
survive the harsh work,
are held in a cave, chained
like beasts.
It is because of this
that a brave and worthy man,
known only by the name of
Zorro,
and to whom I owe my life,
has rallied the people
in the hope of finally seeing
the triumph of justice.
But it is difficult
to check a revolt once
it has been triggered.
And this rogue Governor
risks compromising the loyal
respect that your subjects
feel towards England.
I urge you to intervene
without delay.
We will do so, if your report
to us is confirmed.
Your Majesty,
may I suffer the severest of
your punishments
should you find that I have lied.
We cannot condemn one
of our Governors
simply on the basis of rumour
and one isolated denunciation.
But if the situation proves
to be as you say,
Governor Basil Ruthford
will be recalled and dealt
with severely,
and he will be replaced by one
who better represents
the law and order we demand.
As for your ghostly hero ...
What did you call him ?
Zorro.
While we may well admire
his audacity and courage,
we are forced to consider
his exploits,
however well-intentioned,
as completely illegal.
No-one has the right to take
the law into his own hands.
Zorro considers himself
an outsider
and not answerable to
England's statutes.
We shall see about that.
Your Majesty,
if you will excuse us.
The Privy Council requests
your permission
to enter.
You may go, Senor Garcia.
Have no fear.
Justice will be done.
It was with that certainty
in my mind
that I came to address
Your Majesty.
General Kingston, allow the
Privy Council to enter.
Gentlemen...
Be seated.
The Privy Council has been
convened to discuss
a trade agreement
with Denmark, and ...
My Lord Privy Seal, you will
excuse me for interrupting
but, before we talk about the
trade agreement with Denmark,
I would like to submit to the
judgment of the Privy Council
a report that has troubled
me profoundly.
One of our subjects, a native
of one of our colonies,
the Island of Hamilton,
in the Bermudas,
has told me of
a desperate situation
developing in this colony
as the result of the harassment
and abuse
that the Governor is undertaking
both in our name,
and in the name of England.
I might humbly observe that
cases where
subjects are dissatisfied
with their government are legion.
And that, very often,
their motives are
strictly personal.
This man miraculously escaped
his own execution that was
decreed by the Governor.
Rather than flee,
he decided to come to England,
to ask for justice for himself
and for his country,
declaring he was ready to be
punished if he has lied.
Might I ask
who is this Governor ?
Sir Basil Ruthford.
Before settling this matter,
we want to know the truth
about conditions on this island.
The Privy Council must send
one of its senior members,
who will prepare for me
a detailed status report.
And so, who among you,
is willing
to face the difficulties
and possible dangers
of a voyage such as this ?
I am, Your Majesty.
You, Lord Moore ?
I came to this role
by right of succession
and I have not yet been able
to prove to Your Majesty
my dedication and loyalty.
I am pleased
to take this opportunity.
I thought the role of guardian
to your nephew and niece
was the closest to your heart ?
Young William Scott is now
attending Royal Military College.
I can therefore hardly
do more for his education.
As for Patricia Scott,
she is a girl who is full of life
and she would be delighted
to accompany me
upon this trip.
That being the case ...
- Admiral Britt.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Place one of your vessels
at the disposal of Lord Moore.
As quickly as possible.
Now let us turn to the trade
agreement with Denmark ....
Milady, according to your Uncle,
one boat is not enough
to carry all your baggage.
It will require the entire
Fleet of Her Majesty.
- So, I must restrain myself ?
- Just so, MiIady.
I have always wanted
to go on a long trip,
to see new places.
Well, I can understand you
wanting to see Paris or Rome,
but Hamilton ....
Rome and Paris are so close.
I will have lots of opportunities
in my life to visit them.
Why such a sad face ?
This will be our first time apart.
Do you think I will love you
less, little brother ?
No, but what will I do on a Sunday,
if you aren't there to greet me ?
You must write to me,
and I will do the same.
On my return, we will each read
all that has been written.
The only good thing in all this
is that Uncle is also leaving.
I won't have to see him anymore
and I won't have to answer
his insufferable questions.
''Well then, my boy, how are things ?
''Are you behaving as appropriate
for the heir to a great name ?
''Do you recall - the boy is the
father of the man?''
- Can't you bear it ?
- No.
I am afraid that
reports of your sea voyage
have not been taken well.
What is your judgment ?
The situation is critical.
Your creditors are likely
to create a scandal.
You must do something
to prevent it.
I cannot perform miracles.
You forget, it seems, that
our last business together
netted you a handsome profit.
I have not forgotten, and
I am grateful to you. But ...
But the situation today is
more serious than ever.
My niece Patricia is young
and quite charming.
There are already suitors
at my door.
What if I am faced with
a proposal of marriage
that I cannot refuse ?
What can I possibly say to this
future husband ?
That Patricia Scott, instead of
being a rich heiress,
doesn't have a farthing
to her name,
because I have squandered
her fortune ?
The laws in England are
very severe in such cases.
For me, it would be the end.
By taking her away with me,
I am removing that danger.
Also, this trip to Hamilton
provides me a useful ally.
Sir Basil Ruthford, the Governor,
is a good friend of mine.
I understand.
But how can we deal with
the current crisis ?
Sell the properties in Sheffield.
Sheffield ? The last remaining
properties of the children !
I will make sure they are
no longer required.
Milady...
Cadet William Scott,
your free period is over.
We must go.
Goodbye, Patricia.
Return soon.
Zorro... Zorro... Zorro !
I hear that name,
from everyone I meet.
And now, from you as well.
Yes, from me. Of course.
Zorro isn't just a name,
he is a myth.
A myth ?
A bandit, a common outlaw.
When he falls into my hands,
he won't look so alluring,
swinging from the gallows !
What if you should fail,
and word of his exploits
reaches England ?
England is far away.
And the English have better
things to do
than concern themselves
about this island
In your place, I wouldn't be
so cocksure.
When I first knew you,
you were poor.
but I loved you as much
as I do now.
Let's leave for a remote
part of the world
where we can live modestly
together.
Rosanna, you are a woman.
You cannot understand.
Do you think I could go
back to the sort of life
we first led here, having
grown used to this ?
I love the money, yes,
but I love the power above all.
You are ignoring
the elation that I feel
as I order around these
beggars who hate me
but fall at my feet
because they fear me.
- Who is it ?
- Captain Wells.
With urgent and important news.
One moment, Captain.
Go, I beg you.
Do you believe no-one knows
of our relationship ?
It's better if we maintain
appearances.
They can be maintained later.
Come in, Captain Wells.
Well, Captain ?
Excellency, a dispatch has
arrived from Port Combley.
An English vessel has arrived
unexpectedly.
Lord Moore has disembarked,
accompanied by a young woman,
his niece, I understand.
They have hired a carriage
and are coming here.
Percy Moore ?
What are you waiting for ?
Take a detachment
and go and meet them.
Convey to them my welcome.
I never thought there
could be so much sun.
Now we can forget
the fogs of London, Patricia.
Who are those men ?
Why are they treated that way ?
They are traitors.
They disobeyed the orders
of the Governor.
What is it now ?
Quickly !
Throw out your gun
and get down.
Welcome to Hamilton, Lord Moore.
You have just passed
a column of prisoners.
Those sorry people
were once happy citizens.
But...
they could no longer afford
to pay the arbitrary taxes
imposed by the Governor.
Sir Basil Ruthford, invoking a
law that he himself imposed,
confiscated their property
and reduced them to slavery.
They now toil for
a mouthful of bread
and a filthy mattress of straw.
The people know that the
Queen has heard of this abuse
and has sent you, Lord Moore,
to inspect the colony.
We are hopeful that
you will bring a halt to what is
happening here. Otherwise...
Otherwise ?
Otherwise, by the word of Zorro,
I will enforce justice.
And you will return to England,
bearing my trademark :
the Z that is my initial.
Will you also submit me
to the same treatment ?
No.
On a face as beautiful as yours,
I could not use the sword.
I will draw the Z,
but with a flower.
Goodbye !
Quickly ! That way !
Down there !
Quickly, let's pursue him !
Amazing, unbelievable !
Such banditry in one of
Her Majesty's colonies !
To think that my friend Ruthford
is unable to prevent
such things happening.
It is hardly surprising, Milord,
given the sight we had
of those poor prisoners.
What are you saying,
you are impertinent !
I advise you to hold your tongue.
Good day, Milady.  Milord.
Has something happened ?
I am Pedro Suarez,
and the surrounding land is mine.
Did you see the soldiers
- pursuing a masked man ?
No. May I ask to whom I have
the honour of speaking ?
Lord Percy Moore,
envoy of
Her Majesty, Queen Victoria.
This is my niece, Patricia Scott.
We were heading to the
Governor's home, when Zorro,
threatened us.
Zorro ?
I thought this Zorro was a
figment of popular legend.
I can assure you, Senor Suarez,
we saw him with our own eyes.
In that case, I accept your assurance.
Nothing, he disappeared.
Captain Wells, at the service
of the Governor.
In short, Captain, you have
allowed him to escape.
Excuse me, Captain, but why have
you arrested my servant Pedrito ?
Ah, he is your servant ?
You surely don't think that
Zorro and Pedrito are one ?
Free him !
Lord Moore, when you wish.
I have been ordered to escort
you to the Palace.
The precaution is now useless.
But you can follow us if you like.
Good day to you !
If you will allow,
I will come with you.
If you wish.
I will direct you.  I wish
to prove to Lady Patricia
that this land is not all
chained prisoners
and masked bandits.
Pedrito, my horse !
Follow me !
And here we are, Lady Patricia.
Rosanna will show you
to your rooms
which, I hope, will please you.
Through the windows you
can see the entire park.
- As for yourself ...
- Of little importance.
If the ladies permit,
we should talk, my dear Basil.
It will be a great pleasure.
A reunion with an old friend.
I can't wait to get together,
and reminisce about old times.
If you will follow me, Lady Scott.
Until later, Excellency.
Although I am no longer
a young man,
I am still single.
Rosanna Gonzalez manages
the home,
a task little suited to a man.
A charming woman.
Yes, this is quite true.
Would you care for a whisky
in my office ?
Gladly.
This is wonderful, Milady !
The countryside is marvellous.
- Are you not happy ?
- I'm not sure.
When we left the ship,
I was happy
but since then - those men
in chains and that masked man
have left me a little troubled.
Pedro Suarez also - he
troubled you.
He seemed to me to be
devouring you with his eyes !
I can't say the same
of his servant Pedrito.
Ah, he is a nice boy.
Try this whisky. It is 15 years old.
Tip-top.
It's best that I let you know
straightaway
the reasons for my presence here.
The Queen has heard some
unflattering things
about the way you govern here.
I know.
It's said I have an iron fist,
that I am a tyrant,
that I oppress the population.
Please understand me.
The Queen is still very young,
and rather overenthusiastic
in handling her grave duties.
But, given time,
she will come to appreciate
that Empire can be maintained
only with force.
Then, you do not disapprove
of my approach ?
No, not at all.
As long as it is not used to
enhance your personal fortune.
I don't understand you.
This whisky is truly exceptional.
We were very close in our
younger days, Basil,
and we know each other's
strengths and weaknesses.
When the Queen called
for this inspection,
I immediately put myself forward.
''Can my friend Basil really
have committed such a
sin ?", I asked myself.
I thought it would be better
if I were to come here,
rather than any other.
For example,
General Kingston.
Kingston, you say ?
The adviser most listened to
by Her Majesty.
The men in chains, and the
presence of Zorro, would have
given him a clear enough idea
of the true situation here.
Perhaps you would already be
on your way back to England,
under the cloud of a serious charge.
Then it only remains for me to
thank you, Sir Percy
and fervently to wish that
our old friendship
be renewed by fresh
commonalities of interest.
That is my wish also.
Excuse me, Milady.
For Milady Patricia Scott.
A gift from my master,
Don Pedro Suarez.
With this.
These are for you, from me.
Without a note, because I do
not know how to write.
Read it to me.
''Now the flowers of Hamilton
''know that there is another
more lovely than they
''and they bow to your beauty.
''Pedro Suarez.''
Ah, such a beautiful sentiment !
Louisa,
one should never trust the
amorous words of men.
It is not true.  It is a lie.
I wanted to defend the
honour of my daughter.
But I didn't shoot.
I didn't shoot !
What you are saying is false.
Mind what you say, Cortez,
and respect this Tribunal, which
has the honour of welcoming
the Special Envoy from
Her Majesty, The Queen.
Conduct yourself calmly,
and we will give you justice.
It is true.
I kept some writings in my home
of Manuel Garcia, knowing
that it was prohibited.
When the soldiers came to search,
I immediately agreed to co-operate.
But one soldier,
in spite of my pleading,
abused my daughter
with words and gestures
that would incense every father.
I intervened.
But he resisted me.
His colleague, wishing to
defend him, fired at me.
But the bullet hit my opponent.
I am speaking the absolute truth.
Ask my daughter if what I say
is not what happened
The Tribunal does not accept
the testimony of relatives.
Then, believe me !
I swear before God that
I have spoken the truth !
- Believe me.
- Have Captain Wells enter.
Captain Wells !
Do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth, and
nothing but the truth.
Say, "I swear".
I swear.
Captain Wells, without reading
what is written here,
do you confirm your testimony
made in this statement ?
Excuse me, Excellency.
Without wishing to interfere,
it is my duty
to know exactly what
Captain Wells has said.
Speak, Wells.
The accused is wrong
to claim I had any involvement.
In fact, he could not even
have seen me there.
I was coming through the door,
just preparing to intervene,
but I was too slow.
Before I could act,
the accused had grabbed
a gun from one of my men
and killed his opponent.
No, that isn't true !
It isn't true !
It's a lie ! A lie ! A lie !
Silence !
Or I will clear the Court.
It is a falsehood, sir.
The Captain was in the tavern.
He played cards at my table.
- You are sure ?
- Certain.
Why did you say nothing ?
I have a wife and children.
They wouldn't let me.
What about you ?
Me ? My only concern is
for a peaceful life.
What if you appealed to Zorro ?
He is more capable than I
in handling this sort of thing.
Silence !
You can step down, Captain.
Excellency.
The Prosecution has the floor.
This crime is punishable
by death,
but, given the particular
provocation in this case,
I call for the sentence to be
commuted to forced labour
for perpetuity.
The Defence has the floor.
The Defence has the floor !
I call for clemency of the Court.
Silence !
In the name of Her Britannic
Majesty, Queen Victoria,
given the findings of this trial
which prove the culpability
of the accused
I sentence Francisco Cortez
to forced labour for perpetuity.
He will serve his sentence
in the mines of Clinton,
where he will be transferred
without any delay.
Silence !
The mines of Clinton ?
I'd rather be killed than that !
Assassins !
Guards, clear the Court !
I am sorry, Lord Moore,
But you must see the necessity
to deal severely
with these people.
I understand.
To make amends,
I intend to organise
tomorrow at the Palace
a ball in your honour, and
that of your niece.
Thank you.
Do you accept the challenge ?
Certainly.
Good fortune, Captain !
You have brought me luck !
Nobody move !
It was your false testimony
that condemned an innocent man
to forced labour.
I could kill you.
But I am giving you the chance
to defend yourself.
Just the two of us !
I let you keep your life,
but this indelible sign will be
the mark of your infamy.
Each time that I see you again,
I will add others to it !
Stay where you are !
Grab him ! There he goes !
It's Zorro ! We've taken him !
Let me go ! Release me,
you cretins ! Cretins !
Louisa !
- Well, will you come ?
- I don't know.
Milady may have need of me.
No, I don't think so.
I will wait for you in a half-hour.
Very well.
I imagine that, in London,
the waltz is very popular.
Here,
we are just being introduced to it.
My word, Lady Patricia, it is
the truth, you dance divinely.
May I also have the honour
of dancing with you ?
Please.
Everyone has noted the attention
you have shown to that young lady.
A diplomatic obligation, my dear.
I must keep on good terms
with her guardian.
Ah yes, really ?
You don't seem to find it
too distasteful.
Rosanna, believe me,
do not concern yourself with
matters that do not affect you.
Be careful in what you're
doing, Basil.
You cannot set me aside so easily.
May I take her from you ?
With pleasure, Milord.
Lady Patricia, may we take a
few moments in the garden ?
Yes, willingly.
I dance rather badly,
and I think a bit of fresh air
will do us both good.
It is stifling inside.
What a beautiful starry sky !
There are two things that
never change here :
the stars and the sun.
You seem sad about that.
Yes. Because here they cannot
be enjoyed for their true value.
And yet, when we first met,
you seemed well content
with your lot.
Oh, I am;  but I would like my
fellow man to feel the same.
Yesterday morning, that poor
Cortez was sentenced
and was condemned
to a terrible punishment.
Last night, Zorro was boasting
about what he would do to
Captain Wells.
Boasting ? A man who dares
confront his enemies alone ?
What ardour !
So, you also share
the admiration that everyone
feels for Zorro ?
I don't know much about
the situation in this colony.
It's a matter that concerns
my Uncle, Lord Moore.
But my intuition is that
Zorro is fighting a just cause.
I see.
Now I will refrain from
speaking about him.
Lady Patricia,
since you arrived,
I have thought of nothing but you.
I am stricken with a feeling
that I can only describe
as love, and ...
I beg you, Don Suarez,
do not go on.
You Latins,
you burn with passion,
but, very often, your fire
goes out as easily as it was lit.
I will prove to you that
you are wrong.
At least, leave me with a hope.
Shouldn't I be getting back ?
- Lady Patricia ?
- Not with me.
I believe someone is looking
for you.
Dear Patricia,
you promised me the next dance.
Sr. Suarez was showing me the
wonders of this fabulous country.
Sr. Suarez is an excellent guide
and an example to us all.
If only all were like him, here !
You permit me ?
Are you coming ?
No, thank you. As I told you,
it is too hot inside.
Your visit has delighted us.
You fill this sad palace
with the breath of youth.
If my coming has provoked
so much emotion,
perhaps it would have been
better if I'd stayed in England.
Why ?
Has someone been speaking
to you in the same manner ?
Nobody move !
Lord Moore has been witness
to a terrible injustice.
An innocent man
has been condemned.
You can still prove
that your coming here
was not useless ....
by arranging for the immediate
release of Francisco Cortez.
Otherwise, it will be myself
who, tomorrow night,
will free the prisoner !
Don't shoot !
Guards, catch him !
Quickly, after him !
Ow ! Ouch !
What are you doing there ?
Did you see Zorro ?
- Yes.
- Where is he ?
He stunned me, he went that way.
Guards ! Block the exits !
Man all the gates !
Louisa !
What are you doing here ?
I heard shooting.
It's nothing. Just Zorro, as usual.
What does that mean to us ?
My mistress needs me..
Some other time.
- Stay here a while with me.
- No.
Louisa...
- How are you, Milady ?
- Better, thank you.
It's over now, thank Heaven.
Is it true, what that man said ?
An innocent man was condemned
and you let it happen ?
Let's dance.
May the party continue.
I don't have any luck.
Once more, I missed seeing
the famous Zorro.
I was taking the air,
and got back too late.
Perhaps you could have
captured him ?
That is not my responsibility.
That's up to Captain Wells
and his soldiers.
So, Wells ?
Nothing. He disappeared.
As fleet of foot as always.
Wells, he has scarred you again.
If this keeps up,
your face will resemble
a map in an atlas.
Patricia, will you dance ?
Excuse us.
Madame Rosanna ?
I came to wish you a good night
and to check that all the
excitements of the evening
didn't disturb you too much.
I thank you for your
thoughtfulness.
This is the second time
that I've seen Zorro
and I must confess that
I find him rather fascinating.
You, Lady Patricia,
fascinated by a bandit ?
A bandit, perhaps.
But, you must admit,
he has courage.
To defy the Governor in his
own Palace,
on his own, in spite of the guards !
I understand.
At your age, I also was
easily enchanted
by tales of adventure.
And I wrapped myself
inside my dreams.
But then, over time,
all my dreams have been dashed,
and I have finished up,
trapped on this island,
far from the rest of the world.
Aren't you happy here ?
Happy ? Yes ...
As much as a woman can be
who keeps her eyes open
and can see the face of reality.
You have had a lot of success
this evening, Patricia.
I saw that Don Pedro was
paying court to you.
and also ... the Governor.
They were all very pleasant
towards me.
But, take care, Lady Patricia.
Beware of those who flatter you.
Here, any novelty generates
a lot of enthusiasm,
but it doesn't last long.
So, don't have too many illusions !
Yes, but what do you mean ?
I mean that it is rather dangerous
to play games with the Governor.
The Governor ?
Don't play the innocent.
Be aware that I am ready to
defend, with all my power,
the position I have gained for
myself with pain and humiliation.
But ...
But I've done nothing.
Of course not, Patricia.
Excuse me.
I do not want to make you cry.
I want only ....
to put you on your guard.
You know, maybe I had a
little too much to drink tonight.
And I needed to unburden myself.
It is good for women to confide
with each other. Isn't it ?
Though you are younger than I,
I sense that we understand
each other.
Good night, Lady Patricia.
And enjoy your dreams
of adventure.
No, don't be afraid.
I want to talk with you.
I refuse to listen to a bandit.
I am not a bandit.
You know I fight for a just cause.
To free this colony from a tyrant
and to release the innocents
from our prisons.
Do not believe what the friends
of the Governor say of me.
I would be very sad
if you thought badly of me.
Why does it matter
what I think of you ?
To know you believe in me
would urge me to victory.
- Lady Patricia !
- You must go !
Stay in your room tonight.
I am coming to the Palace
to rescue Cortez.
No. They will capture you.
There are guards everywhere.
Goodbye.
Patricia !
Why have you not
kept up with us ?
We have been looking
everywhere for you.
My horse carried me
in the wrong direction.
We were enjoying the freedom
of the gallop.
That was unwise, my dear.
Zorro is somewhere in this
vicinity, according to reports.
Imagine that,
if you had met with him ?
That man is capable of anything.
Excellency,
he is heading for the clearing.
He is cornered, trapped !
Then go, quickly !
Go, return home !
Go home !
What are you doing ?
Working !
- Did you see Zorro ?
- No, only his horse.
Idiots !
You have let him get away.
You, search for him,
and be quick !
You, Sergeant. You will never
get a promotion !
All of you, down there !
Search around the perimeter
- from top to bottom !
And you, get back to work !
Search as far as you can !
And keep your eyes about you !
He must not escape us !
Hurry up !
Follow me !
You, what are you doing there ?
Get your cart out of here !
There's nothing like an old port
to finish a meal properly.
Excellency,
Captain Wells wishes to see you.
Let him enter.
Excellent, this port,
truly excellent.
I am happy that you like it.
I had it brought from Lisbon.
What is it, Captain ?
Excellency,
the main entrance is guarded.
No-one can enter without
a pass signed by me.
3 patrols surround the grounds,
as many are watching the park.
Those who do not know
the password will be arrested.
It is absolutely impossible
for Zorro,
unless he has
the gift of invisibility,
to get into the Palace.
And, even if he did get in,
he would not get out alive.
I cannot agree to that, Captain.
Zorro, I want him alive.
That would be the best execution
we have ever seen in Hamilton.
My compliments, Captain.
This time, I am certain,
you will repay Zorro for the
humiliations he inflicted on you.
I predict that his capture
and execution
will bring an end to this myth
that has excited the more
romantic amongst us.
Excuse me, I feel tired.
Please allow me to withdraw.
I will accompany you, Milady.
Return to your post.
I will wait all night
to hear the good news.
Excellency,
I assure you that, this time,
he will not get away.
Will you keep me company,
Lord Moore ?
I will take this opportunity
to speak with you of a topic
close to my heart.
- Gladly.
- After you.
Get moving !
Guards, halt !
Left turn !
Change the guard !
Nice hand-over !
Left turn !
Forward, march !
That's good, let's go.
Five !
Wait.
Four !
Are you not going to bed, Milady ?
No, not yet.
But you can go, if you wish.
Thank you, Milady.
It's said ...
that the heart does not age.
And I have experienced
just that, in recent days.
The continued presence
of your niece
has instilled in me a feeling,
both sincere
and profound, in this regard.
I asked you to stay the night,
so we might speak about this.
Then, speak. Express yourself.
Milord, I have the honour to
request the hand of your niece.
Lady Patricia Scott.
Your request is a great honour.
But I ask you to consider
the young age of Patricia.
And then ...
And then ?
And then, there are matters
to be discussed,
to be agreed, in detail.
I do not expect less.
We have the entire night
ahead of us to do this.
One, two ! One, two ! One, two !
- Is all well ?
- Yes.
Louisa !
My love !
You stifled me. The gate !
The patrol will see it.
You are right.
- Come on, let's go.
- Where to ?
- Down there.
- I'm frightened, it's too dark.
Precisely, let's go.
We'd better put our cards on
the table, my dear Basil.
The few days I have spent here
have confirmed what I suspected.
Meaning ?
You have governed this colony
with terror,
abusing your power to amass
a huge personal fortune.
I have sufficient evidence
to write my report for the Queen...
So...
why don't you do it, then ?
I have told you.
I am your friend.
We had decided to lay down
our cards.
Let's leave aside the
declarations of friendship
and get to the facts.
Let me tell you what I know
about you.
You haven't a penny to your name.
Gambling and women
are your only passions.
Passions that cost you dear.
The Moore fortune has long
been depleted,
and, I understand, the fortune
of the Scott children,
which you were to control
until their majority,
is severely compromised.
Continue. What you say is
very interesting.
That is almost everything,
my dear friend.
Send a report to the Queen
favourable towards me
and give your consent
to my marriage with Patricia.
Even without a dowry ?
That's the point which will
interest you the most.
Because I will agree to marry
Patricia without a dowry.
At last, there you are !
It's the fault of the women.
Attention !
- Has he gone ?
- Yes.
Let's go.
This way.
There is one last question,
my dear Basil.
Yes ?
What is it ?
This Rosanna Gonzalez,
I sense that she is intimately
linked with you.
Will she not cause trouble ?
Have no fear.
At the right time,
I will get rid of her.
Let's go.
How are things ?
Let me see the prisoner.
Hm, he seems a little sad.
It can't be too cheerful
being shut up in there.
I must go.
I have to make an inspection.
Very well, off you go.
'Bye. Take care, yes ?
He is through there.
Quickly !
Zorro went through there !
This way.
Watch the prisoner.
Zorro is in the prison.
Zorro !
Remove his uniform.
- Have you seen him ?
- No.
Come with me.
Secure all exits !
- Have you seen Zorro ?
- Idiot ! Why ask me ?
To our agreement, Moore.
Secure the exits !
Zorro is in the Palace.
Zorro !
Idiots.
Search for him,
he can't get away !
Back here again ?
You, through there !
Take a look.
- This way.
- You, follow me !
Pedrito !
Let's go.
Come on !
There he is.
Get yourselves to safety.
I will deal with them.
Have you seen Zorro ?
- He has escaped to the park.
- Follow me !
- What is going on ?
- I don't know.
Excellency !
- Wells, what is happening ?
- Zorro is in the Palace.
By truth,
this time he won't escape !
Arrest him, and you will receive
a promotion in rank !
- Lieutenant !
- At your command.
- The Left Wing. I'll take this side.
- Let's go.
Halt !
Throw down your sword !
Hey, you two !
Where are you going ?
We're looking for Zorro.
Go no further.
Mount a guard here.
- Yes, sir.
- Forward !
Stand your ground !
This time, I have you.
You shall not escape me.
Throw down your sword !
Stop him !
You cannot escape from here !
Stop !
Out of the way ! Let me shoot him !
Get out of the way !
- Push him off !
- Give that to me !
Untangle yourself !
Capture him ! Capture him !
Quickly !
You, that way !
Come with me !
Wells, secure all the exits !
Quickly !
Zorro !
This way ! Look on the roof !
You, that way !
Search the rooms.
Well, Captain Wells ?
Have no fear, we'll get him.
Then, go. And do it quickly !
Patricia !
Hide in here.
Lady Patricia, open up !
Yes, I am coming.
What is it ?
Excuse me,
but Zorro is inside the Palace.
We were worried about you.
You are still dressed, Patricia ?
I was going to bed, when
I heard the gunshots.
I must confess that
I was a little frightened.
Would you like Rosanna
to join you ?
No, that isn't necessary.
If I need anything, I will call
Louisa. Good night.
Good night.
- Thank you.
- You must go, now.
- Why did you help me ?
- Because ....
Because they would
have you killed.
It was simple humanity
that I acted that way.
Is that the only reason ?
Yes. Why do you press me ?
For your love.
My love ?
Yes. You love me as I love you.
No.
Why do your lips deny
what is revealed by your eyes ?
No, let me go.
Goodbye, Patricia.
The one I freed is waiting for me.
I must get him to safety.
Wait !
I am frightened for you.
Fear not, all will be well.
See if anyone is coming.
- Sergeant, are you wounded ?
- No !
Once again he has fled.
He escaped from me.
You're a bunch of idiots !
He was there, trapped,
and you let him get away.
You won't get away so easily !
I will hang all those responsible.
You, here ?
I have to speak with you, Basil.
Get out. Not now.
No ! You will listen to me.
I know everything.
You thought getting rid of me
would enable your new plans,
but you were sadly mistaken.
Never will you marry Patricia Scott.
I will prevent it !
Where did this idea come from ?
That's enough, Basil !
You have told me so many lies.
I heard your discussion with
Moore, so be on your guard,
I am ready to do anything.
Even notifying the Queen
about your misdeeds.
You will regret this, Basil !
Be sure that you will.
I will have my revenge.
Gentlemen,
you know the case that now
must be discussed
fills us with bitterness.
One of our advisors, Lord Moore,
abusing the function of guardian
that we entrusted to him,
has squandered the legacy
left to his niece and nephew
Patricia and William Scott.
His administrator, Charles Burn,
has confessed everything.
His crimes, already terrible,
are further compounded
by the prestigious position
he occupies as a noble Lord,
a role that should serve as an
example to all our citizens.
In addition, the infrequent
news coming from the Island
is not reassuring.
The power of Zorro seems
to grow by the day,
and the repression is becoming
ever more ruthless.
Obviously, Lord Moore has not
only betrayed his niece and nephew.
He has betrayed the trust
that we placed on him.
And so, it is from the members
of this Privy Council, that
we have decided that you,
General Kingston,
will travel to Hamilton
and restore order.
As you command, Your Majesty.
I will sail for Hamilton
without delay.
Let us hope that you arrive
before it is too late.
Very nice indeed.
My dear Governor,
may I congratulate you.
The idea of putting a price
on the head of Zorro
is excellent.
Oh, this Zorro !
Just a fool who thinks he can
change things with his ranting.
- I hope you will play again.
- Of course.
She played admirably.
It was a joy to listen to.
My compliments.
Do I take it that you would
like things to change ?
Oh, no.
For me,
things are good as they are.
I am content. I pay my taxes,
even if I find them a little high.
I am on very good terms
with the Governor.
Why would I want things
to change ?
There will always be malcontents
and the dissatisfied.
Captain Wells,
we were speaking of your Zorro.
My Zorro ?
Shortly you will see him
hanging from the end of a rope.
Betrayed by those who are
his friends and supporters.
I think that you are wrong,
Captain Wells.
Zorro is revered.
I am sure that, in Hamilton,
there is no-one
who would betray him for money.
You are deluding yourself.
Patricia !
Don't pay any attention
to what my niece said.
At her age, the young often
look upon rough bandits
as heroes,
if only because they pretend
to act in the name of
an imaginary justice.
In fact, you are describing
the judgment of a child ....
I find you pensive and let down.
I understand.
You were hoping to find here
a land of peace and joy.
Instead, you've found only hatred,
strife and the abuse of power.
Even you admit it.
Lady Patricia, I admit that
I prefer the quiet life.
But I have eyes that see,
a mind that makes judgments
and a heart ...
I know.
Yet, I haven't heard you take
the side of those struggling
and who want to change things.
What would you have me do ?
Put on a sword, don a black mask
and start a fight ?
Conspire against the Governor,
like Manuel Garcia and Cortez,
and finish up a prisoner
or, at best, exiled ?
No, that's not for me.
So you will spend your
whole life as you now are,
complacent,
with no fight in you ?
I fight for things that mean
something to me.
Like love, for example.
The love I felt for you
on the day I first saw you
and which gives me
the courage to ask you :
Will you marry me, Patricia ?
You are very kind, Pedro,
and I thank you for
your proposal,
but, for the moment, I have
to say that
what you ask me is impossible.
Then, there is no more doubt.
From your reaction, you have
just confirmed to me
that you are in love with Zorro.
And if that were so ?
Take care. It is dangerous to
fall in love with a shadow.
And Zorro, for you,
is only a shadow.
The quicker this marriage takes
place, the better for us all.
I think you are right, Moore.
Silence !
I've been quiet for a period
to trick the Governor into
thinking his troubles are over.
But now is the time
when we must all be prepared.
We are happy that the time
to act has arrived.
And before risking our lives,
I propose that,
during the uprising,
we proclaim our
independence from England.
I do not agree. We must not
act against the Queen
for whom
we must remain faithful.
The envoy from the Queen,
on whom we placed our hopes,
has shown himself incapable.
He even increased the powers
of the Governor.
That corrupt diplomat,
who, from personal interest,
supports the Governor,
should not make us forget
that our colony has known
happy times
and prosperous ones,
through our link with England.
We will, therefore, only rebel
against the corrupt power
of the man who represents
the Queen.
These are the conditions
under which
I am willing to lead you.
You are right, Zorro.
We will follow you.
And do what you want.
- You all agree ?
- Yes !
For now,
all of you return to your homes.
Wait patiently for my orders.
''You are in great danger.
''Leave the Palace immediately.
A carriage awaits you.
''Zorro.''
- Who is it ?
- It is I, Milady. Mendez.
Well ?
I wanted to tell you that
the Governor
hasn't retired to his bed.
He's had 2 horses saddled: one
for himself, one for Capt. Wells.
- You wait 'til now to tell me ?
- I couldn't do so before.
Check the stable and try to
find out where they are going.
You !
I was not mistaken.
The charm of a bandit was
enough to make you forget
that you are of noble birth.
- Where are we going ?
- You will know soon enough.
The other night, at the Palace,
when I knocked on your door,
a suspicion struck me.
I decided to check and, shortly
after, from my window,
I saw Zorro leave you, after
holding you tenderly.
Why didn't you
have him arrested ?
It would have embarrassed you,
and compromised our plan.
What plan ?
Your marriage
to Sir Basil Ruthford.
My marriage ?
Basil is madly enamoured of you.
He has asked me for your hand.
And you have consented ?
We are even now heading for
the Convent of San Diego.
You will be married there
tomorrow.
This remote spot has been
chosen to avoid any folly
on your part, or that of Zorro.
You would do well to sit back,
and listen to me.
This is pointless.
I refuse to marry him.
If I am dragged to the altar,
I will say no to the priest.
I doubt that.
I have some things to tell you ....
Yes !
Just a minute, I'm coming,
Here I am !
Where is your master ?
- I'm sorry. He is sleeping.
- Wake him, I must speak with him !
I have orders not to disturb
him under any circumstances.
This is a matter of life-or-death.
- I understand, but ....
- What is it, Pedrito ?
Milady Rosanna, pardon me.
This is no time for niceties.
This is an urgent matter.
You may leave us.
What is it ?
Don Pedro, the lady you love
is in danger.
You must intervene.
The lady I love ?
Do not pretend.
Patricia, everyone knows it.
What has happened to Patricia ?
She is being taken to
the Convent of San Diego,
where, in the morning, she
will be married to the Governor.
I must send her a wedding gift,
with my best wishes.
But ... I thought ...
You must not concern yourself.
Yes, I have a great affection
for Lady Patricia.
I may even love her a little,
but not to the point of
confronting the Governor.
This young woman is
the victim of a conspiracy
between her guardian
and Basil Ruthford !
How do you know that ?
I heard them plotting.
If you were to intervene ....
The Governor dislikes me,
as does the Queen's Envoy.
No, thank you, I won't get involved
It's too dangerous a game.
In this world, there are plenty
of other women.
Certainly, it's not women we lack.
But, as for men in Hamilton,
there is only one worthy
of the name : Zorro !
I have an idea.
Try and find Zorro.
Get to Cortez.
Tell him it's the time to act.
It is of little matter to me
if I am poor.
I can forgive your crimes,
but I beseech you :
do not force me
to marry a man I despise.
And what of your brother ?
What will happen to him ?
He will have to leave College.
And renounce a future
worthy of his name.
and of his rank.
Have you thought of that ?
Sir Basil wants you so much
that he has waived your dowry.
He will pay for William's education.
In exchange, you will send
a favourable report to the Queen.
We are being bartered
to resolve your problems.
Well ?
Get ready.
They are coming. Get ready.
Silence !
Hold your tongues !
I said - Silence !
You - quiet !
Quickly, free us !
Liberty, liberty !
Come on, all of you !
Quickly, to horse !
Follow me !
Louisa ! Hurry yourself !
- Where are you taking me ?
- Climb up, have no fear.
Don't ask so many questions.
What is this ?
Is anyone else about ?
No... Excellency.
Who are you ?
What are you doing here ?
I - I am ...
I will tell you ...
Basil Ruthford,
do you wish to take as
your wife, this woman
Patricia Scott ?
I do.
Patricia Scott,
do you wish to take as your
husband, this man, Basil Ruthford ?
No !
Sir Basil Ruthford,
you will be dealt with differently.
You must pay for all your crimes.
But not here.
You are not worthy
of the House of the Lord.
I could kill you now.
But the English Court
must judge you.
No ! I demand justice.
Patricia, come here.
Patricia !
Take him !
Let me go !
I see you have already solved
my problems.
General Kingston,  Envoy of
Her Majesty, Queen of England.
I have come here to restore
order and justice.
Lord Moore,
you have betrayed your duty
and caused the revolt
of these people.
In the name of Her Majesty,
I arrest you.
You, take him !
And you, put down your arms.
Excellency, I confess to acting
for the good of my country
and the triumph of justice.
I am ready to be judged by
the Court of England.
Here is my sword.
Keep it.
I know that you acted in
the best interests of England.
And I am ready publicly
to acknowledge it.
But, to do that, you must
first remove your mask
and show your true face.
Pedro !
Silence !
Don Pedro Suarez,
by virtue of the powers
vested in me
and in the name of Her Majesty,
Victoria Alexandra of Kent,
Queen of England,
I hereby appoint you
Governor of the Island of Hamilton.
English subtitles: David Blake (2014)