"To cross the road,
"push the button and wait
for cars to stop at a red light."
NOEL-NOEL
in the movie
ON FOOT, ON HORSEBACK AND BY CAR
A movie by MORIS DELBEZ
and SERGE DE BOUSSAC.
Director
MORIS DELBEZ
Screenplay by SERGE DE BOUSSAC.
and JACK ANTOINE
DENISE GRAY.
GIL VIDAL
JACK FABBREE
EME CLARION
(member of the Comédie Française troupe)
JEAN GALLAN
JEAN TISSIER
ARDISSON
VIVIAN GOSSE
and NOEL ROCKEVER
SOPHIE DOMIEU
DERRY COWLE.
J.P. Belmondo and others
Producer
LOUIE DE MAZUR
Composer
PAUL MIZRAKI
FACULTY OF PHARMACOLOGY
Mireille!
Do you need a ride?
No, thanks, some other time.
Don't you realize
you're wasting your time?
Can't you see that this poor child
is in love with a homegrown Don Juan?
- I ran away from everyone.
- Good for you.
Okay, now let's go
to my parents' house.
Doesn't it bother you?
- Of course not. It's just, uh.
Since I've been hesitant
to introduce you to my own,
it's like playing tennis
with one racket.
- We're engaged.
- We are engaged.
But telling your parents about it
that's a whole other thing.
It's an empty formality.
I'm for tradition.
So did my mother.
The problem is,
you don't have the same ones.
All right. All in good time.
Let's go!
Paul!
You guys are so touching!
Maybe for a change,
leave us alone?
We look at you and envy you!
May you have
our best wishes!
- Did you find it?
- There's a strange sound.
Are you okay?
It's okay.
Yeah, man,
you really nailed it!
- А...
- Ooh-la-la-la!
They can't be left alone
not even for five minutes.
This is not a good time!
Don't get so worked up, old man!
Ouch, he's hurt!
- No, he's not!
- Yes, yes! You're hurt!
- We need to call an ambulance!
Stay out of this!
Relax, man,
we'll take care of everything.
I'll call the fire department,
it can't get any worse!
Come on!
Meet you guys here!
Get out of the car!
Pass me
some kind of instrument.
Thank you.
The distance between
between the witnesses is two meters.
And the names of the daredevil's children.
Maurice, Etienne, Micheline.
А!
Mr. Policeman,
you'll save valuable time
if you use this notebook.
Is that it? Thank you.
- Mariel, can you do us a favor?
- That's all I know how to do!
Here, here's my papers,
make a deal with the cops.
- We have a very important meeting!
- You can count on me.
Here's the proof.
I don't like the way
this case is taking.
- Have we disturbed too many people?
- We gotta get outta here!
Guys, save yourselves!
А! The final touch!
Any witnesses?
Я!
- So there was no one in the car?
- Well, I didn't see anything, foreman.
- Make me a report.
- A report?
- Well, you've seen the daisies, haven't you?
- Well, uh.
Where are we meeting
with Mireille and her challenger?
In "Bin'se."
- At Bin's?
- It's in Saint-Germain-des-Prés.
О!
Oh, no, no, no. I decidedly
do not like your new hat!
It's a fashion.
BANANA DAY
Here you go.
- How's it going, Mr. Duchemin?
- Slowly.
The baby's been
a big help, huh?
Mr. Martin!
You have good taste.
What do you think of my
new car?
No good, Mr. Viviani.
It's no good!
Your cars! Your cars!
Do you know what you're doing
with your cars?
You're making our little square
little square,
that was once
pleasant and peaceful.
Come on, Marguerite.
We need laws
that prohibit it!
Yes, yes, laws! Laws!
And progress?
Where will he put progress?!
Wait, let's ask here.
Excuse me, sir. А!
- It's Bean's!
- Thank you.
Looks like a basement.
I introduced you to my
at the Peace Café.
I often wonder, Marguerite,
if we haven't given our daughter
too much freedom?
Let's go downstairs after all.
We'll see.
- Is there a fire?
- No, monsieur, it's all right.
Come on, let's go.
My parents.
Where?
Hi!
It's Dad.
Mom.
And this is Paul.
He usually looks better, but today.
we had transportation problems.
Please.
Sit down, Leon.
Scotch tape?
Make it scotch.
Daddy, Mommy!
I'm so glad you came!
Do you like them?
- Mireille, listen.
- Very much!
- That's very nice.
- Very nice!
Paul and I love each other.
You're not the one who should be talking,
Mireille!
We love each other, madam.
I presume, monsieur, that
your parents know?
To be completely honest...
We're going to Paul's parents
as soon as we've made arrangements with you.
We're not supposed to organize
to organize?!
My parents
are almost impossible to see.
They're so original. They only accept
only some of the old bosses
at his estate in Solonie.
That's the kind of invitations they have.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't look for your glasses, Dad, I'll read it.
"Monsieur and Madame de Granlew
request to do the honors."
"to come shoot paws
in their La Renee forest."
"October 30th of this year."
It's in a month!
Okay, we'll be there.
Let me do that.
But this invitation is addressed
to the Count and Countess de Mericourt!
No, it's ours. Especially
since the invention of the proofreader.
Mireille! You'll have to excuse her.
Mireille had
an amazing idea!
All three of you will come to the castle!
- Is that a castle?
- Oh, it's small.
It's a done deal.
Do you have a car?
А... Uh, no. We don't have a car.
Is it shameful to come by train
- is shameful?
No, but you have to make
three transfers.
We're used to
to take the subway.
You have to come!
Would you tell me, young man,
what this means:
"shoot your paws"?
Daddy, I'll explain everything to you.
Everything's gonna work out just fine.
The key is to participate in the hunt.
Yeah, and then I'll tell you all about it.
Here, Dad, here's your invitation.
But it's the only way
to meet his parents.
You're welcome!
No, no, I won't allow it.
I won't let you...
Yeah, yeah, I'm coming.
It's cool here, huh?
Yeah, cool.
The young man is charming.
I'm sure he loves Mireille.
But I have a feeling
something's bothering him.
He drives a luxury car,
Mireille takes the subway.
They weren't supposed to meet,
is what I'm saying. Let's go!
So we're not going
"paw hunting"?
What paws?
А! Paws.
Be reasonable, we don't even
don't even know what they are, paws.
Too bad, I would have loved it.
First of all, we don't have a car.
Secondly, an invitation
in the name of Count de Mericourt.
Oh, by the way, I'll have
send him his invitation.
To the Count.
Another new car?
There's a lot of dust
in new cars!
You'd better clean the stairs!
What's it to you?
You live on the first floor!
Do I have the right to take care
my car or not?!
Your car?
Look at the sign,
if you don't believe me.
Alice Lambeg, concierge.
Mrs. Lambeg, I may be old-fashioned,
but something eludes me.
What do you need it for,
this automobile?
I'll make escapades,
from time to time.
We can barely see you.
We ordered it four and a half years ago.
We asked you to come
to meet our needs,
but when you're the concierge,
you obviously don't have priority.
Well, well, well.
It's a nice gray color.
- Obviously, it's not a luxury.
But when you get behind the wheel,
you're speechless.
What are you waiting for,
Mr. Martin?
Except for you Marines
in the house.
We're thinking about it.
- You see, Mr. Martin,
there are times in life
when you have to come out of your hole.
I like it in my hole,
Mrs. Lambeg.
That's what they all say. And then when they come out,
they're very happy.
Have you seen my
anti-theft device?!
Goes from the steering wheel straight
to the janitor's closet.
It's for the night!
Infantryman!
I don't care about the Marine.
Well, Leon, are you coming?
What are you doing in there?
Do we have a proofreader at home?
An invitation:
for Mr. and Mrs. Martin.
Grunlew, Grunlew...
But it's the same one
who commanded the Hussars at Tulier!
Maybe. We don't know.
We are invited and...
of course, they're not
they're not very close to us.
Yes, colossi!
Pillars of their generation!
Maybe it is.
So, Guillard?
What have you decided?
We live about 50 meters
from each other. I agree.
We're old friends.
I agree.
But I won't lend you a dime
to buy a car!
No, no, and no!
How could it be, Leon!
We swore we'd be the two
the last two pedestrians of Paris!
Eh, my dear,
I understand why
you don't understand me.
You don't have a daughter.
If you'd been to Bin's....
- At Bin's?
- Yes, at Bin's, at Bin's.
in a smoke-filled closet,
where young men and women
drinking scotch,
by putting mercury and chromium
mercury and chromium,
maybe something would change
something different.
You'd think, perhaps,
that you're an old monkey
clinging to a dried-up branch.
- Definitely not!
- A kind gesture, commander!
There's no way we're going
to this hunt in a cab?!
Instead of borrowing money,
I'd rather borrow a car.
Everybody's got one now.
- Why don't we just steal it?
There's still an opportunity.
- Bravo! Don't count on me!
We're already funding
a sailing nursery.
Hélène!
Enough of your silly fantasies!
And do me a favor,
take off that hat!
You look like a jellyfish!
Now it's time for me to go to bed.
Good night!
- Good night.
Dad, don't think about the car anymore!
Don't start!
But we have to find a way
to find 300,000 francs,
without having to get off
from the honest road!
Damn it!
I'm reminded of that
of your epic cancan from 1922.
Ellen, I've had enough
with your cancan!
And I'm fed up with cars!
Get in!
And don't touch me!
CAULIFLOWER DAY
- Straight?
- I'll tell you right now.
Yeah, it's fine. It's fine.
So, what, every day.
a new idea?
Ah, it's done! Only thing is.
the supplier is late with the goods.
Dear Friend. If you had
your own truck,
if you were calm.
Nowadays, anyone who doesn't have his own car
looks like a poor relative.
Especially at ceremonies.
- You don't have one either.
- Yes, I do! I'll buy one the other day.
Just yesterday you were against it.
Mr. Viviani!
I'm against people who have a car
who don't need one!
You don't have a daughter!
- But I have four sons!
There's no connection!
Boys should be brought up
in a strict, Spartan way!
By bus!
- And what do you buy?
- Well, I buy, uh... uh...
I'm not sure yet.
I want a car that
would have an effect,
but not too conspicuous.
It's for hunting.
Hunt!
Wow!
Is he bragging or something?
Enterprises Robiche & Co.
FUNERAL HOME
Try your luck!
There's a raffle tonight!
A ticket, monsieur?
That's the one!
- You make me laugh!
- Then laugh!
On Via Piccardi.
we start together, from the bottom.
You with your Marilyn,
me with my "Rita."
We're not even on the freeway yet,
and you're already three blocks behind.
Full tank or empty?
- It doesn't depend.
- We'll see about that.
- We already did.
Hello, gentlemen.
Have you seen the deputy director?
It's gotta be hanging out there somewhere.
Imagine this,
I'm gonna ask him for an advance.
- Is that so?
- It's pretty big.
Yes! Yesterday, I crawled out
out of my hole.
Success is like money.
you get it right away.
If you hesitate,
it won't work.
And I'll tell the chief this:
Monsieur!
There he is.
You're the lucky one.
He doesn't seem to be in
not in a bad mood today.
Well, I'll be off.
I'll bet you an aperitif
that he won't make up his mind?
bookkeeper martan city
Get out!
"All the details about the varieties
of the models on display at the Salon!"
Ask for "Salon Magazine!"
Thank you, monsieur.
I'm sure they'll tell the whole neighborhood
that we're going to the Salon. That's ridiculous.
So what? It's forbidden?
And why would we even choose a car
if we don't have the money?
We're going to see,
just to see!
I don't want to decide blindly.
I'm not going to Grunle's
in the first car I see!
You know me.
- All right, let's go. It's gonna be crowded.
No, it's empty at noon.
People are eating lunch.
The French are maniacs.
At noon, they eat lunch.
Isn't that right?
At noon, the French have lunch.
Nobody's hungry, it seems!
- I'm sick of you.
It's probably all foreigners.
You hired guns!
Get a move on!
43rd CAR SALON.
- Unbelievable!
- Are you interested?
Yeah, I mean, I'd like
to take a look at the car.
She's behind you.
Oh, yeah, I can see her antenna
her antenna!
No, ma'am, no.
Personally, I see a rider on the roof
and the windshield, a horsewoman.
Let's not discuss it.
I like it, I'll take it.
Put it aside for me.
I'm waiting for the money to come in.
Are you crazy?!
Okay, I'm signing you up.
Delivery's in six months.
Is this a joke? We're invited to shoot
at the bumps. uh, paws at the end of the month.
Monsieur, my daughter's happiness
my daughter's happiness depends on this day.
If she doesn't get married,
you're not the one who's going to comfort her!
I don't know about that,
I'd have to look at it.
I need this car
October 30th.
Well, you'll have an order ticket in your pocket
an order ticket!
Don't make fun of me.
How do you want me to drive
around Solonie with an order ticket?
Monsieur, for all production cars.
there is a delivery time.
Here. Here you go.
But monsieur!
Leon!
We could look at that one over there.
There's no one around it.
Luxury cars scare people.
She must be very expensive.
Shall we go take a look?
What are we risking?
- What's that?
- Some kind of defense.
It's kind of like a restroom in there.
- Wow, that's fun to look at.
- Don't touch it!
- I'm not touching anything!
It's like a telephone.
- And up there, look up there!
She's a beauty, isn't she?
We're here.
We'd like to inquire...
to know the price.
Oh, but there's a little bar inside!
And a smoking area.
We already have an apartment.
We're looking for a car...
But there it is!
Go, go, go!
Wait a minute, you can't inspect a car like this
you can't take a quick look at a car like this!
People visit it. Like a museum!
- We don't want to disturb you.
- No, no, come in. Come in, ma'am!
Come in, monsieur.
- That's it.
- Move over.
Yeah, yeah, I'm moving. Here, there's a spot.
Come on, move, move!
- It's very comfortable!
- What a boring gentleman!
It's a runaway model.
The Archbishop of Canterbury
bought one just like it.
With a Prayer Book to go along with it.
Tell the Archbishop that, uh.
I'm sorry, but at the end of the day.
Look, you're a businessman,
I'm guessing,
you can work
right in the car!
Basically, you'll be able to
save money!
And if you're a father of a family--
you can entertain your children.
See?
This fantasy is not in the car
of the archbishop, obviously.
And finally!
Finally, safety!
Look!
It's a useless precaution, because
there are no accidents with this car!
It's funny.
It's very easy to open,
you're about to see.
It's childishly simple:
you click here.
at...
And then you...
What's the matter? Oh, you fuck!
Oh, come on. I mean, come on.
Hold on, I'll go get help!
In the meantime.
read this.
Very curious.
See you soon!
Thank you, ma'am.
So, how was the salon?
Overrated.
Or cars,
that can be paid for outright,
but we have to wait three years,
or cars,
that can be picked up right away,
but which cannot be
to pay for.
Good evening.
So, how was the salon?
Amazing! Wonderful!
Have a nice day.
Well? How's the salon?
Well, that's too much!
The concierge is in possession
in 2 horsepower.
"And finally, the number 17201
won 40 million in Group 4."
"These were the results
of the National Lottery draw."
And now on the program.
light music.
No one ever wins!
Was it worth it
to count on!
I had a little bit of an idea.
In fact, I almost got it.
Would 2 more digits...
2 more digits in another series.....
and I would have won.
Look, I've been thinking about
what you said this morning.
Yeah, I need a truck!
Here, for example, listen to this!
Used car dealership
is selling a flatbed truck.
The sides are very convenient
for vegetables.
A rare find!
Impeccably "savvy".
185,000 kilometers.
185,000?
Yeah, 185,000.
Well, it's used.
Of course it is!
But they wrote
"rare opportunity."
I have no reason
to doubt it.
Well, some garages
they're twisting the meter.
Might as well add to it.
Do you have the amount of money
do you have the money you need?
Let's find it.
- I'm a little short.
- I have a loan.
There's a loan.
Two wheels to pay,
two wheels not to pay.
It's gonna feel like
like you're driving sideways and sideways.
Good night, Mr. Duchemin,
I'm going to bed.
Good night, Mr. Martin.
- Yes?
- Can I come in?
Uh, sure.
Working?
Uh, yeah.
Good for you.
Serious.
"Pharmaco-dynamics."
It's the study of the effects
of drugs on the body.
How much you know!
Listen, Mireille,
I was thinking about the car.
We need to find a way to make money,
you know, more money than usual.
Oh, Dad.
I don't want you
I don't want you to feel that way.
I don't want you to change your life
to change your life for me.
Don't be selfish, daughter!
If this hunt
you won't be proud of us,
the most unfortunate ones
will be your mother and me.
And then...
to rise in respect
for yourself,
I need this car
this car.
Then tomorrow I'll ask the faculty
from the guys on the faculty.
Go to bed, Daddy.
It's not heavy,
but it's very cumbersome.
Keep the change.
But it's missing
20 francs!
Didn't anyone ever tell you
that students need to be helped?!
- Poor France!
- I think I'll go.
- Shame on you!
- There they are.
Papa Martan won't know
how to thank us!
Yeah, it's not every semester
we get ideas like this!
Mr. Martin, today is
is your lucky day!
- Our respects, Mrs. Martin!
- Thank you.
They're great!
- Hello, monsieur!
- No, we're just being nice.
Mr. Martin, we've brought you
a gold mine for you!
It's Surditos!
What's that?
Deaf apparatus.
The invention of the Gazansky Father.
We brought 50. You'll sell them
for 10,000 francs apiece,
you each get 5 grand.
Mr. Martin!
Your profit for everything -
250 grand!
Who am I supposed to sell
these machines?
Make yourself a list
and get to work.
Mireille, we're gonna need to release
the package.
But wait a minute,
I haven't said yes yet!
I'm not cut out for trading!
I'll even be cheated
to buy blue Galloises.
The trade, Mr. Martin.
is that
to let you fool yourself
on the purchase and then get revenge.
Léon, don't forget that your father was
the first gossip of Dijon.
Maybe it's hereditary.
will manifest itself?
Well, I'd be surprised.
The goods have been delivered!
Don't forget, Mr. Martin,
we are your guardian angels!
Thank you.
Goodbye, gentlemen.
And all of this
to buy a car!
How stupid to be poor,
Oh, my God!
Yeah, well, uh.
Here we go.
It looks pretty complicated.
In my youth.
the same result was achieved
with a simple horn.
- There should be a manual.
- Here it is.
It's Polish.
I have a college degree,
but I don't read Polish.
Give me a hand here.
Give me your ear.
- Don't hurt me!
- Oh, don't worry.
Shut the other one up.
Hey!
Do you hear anything?
I can't hear anything!
That's not good.
How about this?
I hear a slight crackle!
For a deaf person, it's a joy,
a slight crackle!
Who to sell to first?
If you ask
a lot of questions, you'll get confused!
The day of my first communion.
you were behind the counter with the nuns,
and you sold everything.
It's true, isn't it?
A whole counter full of lace circles,
completely useless!
Or maybe I have a gift.
I'm gonna go drop off one of those Surditos
to Duchemin.
But he's not deaf!
Margarita, don't make it harder for me
with all those statements.
Okay, right? I'll see you soon.
- Mr. Duchemin!
- I'm coming, I'm coming! I'm not deaf!
Weigh this for me.
- Hello!
- Hello, Mr. Martin!
Do you have a couple minutes?
- Actually, I'm just, uh.
- It's important.
Okay, I'll be at your service in a minute.
Wait for me at the store.
Oh, that's great.
Everything all right?
Look!
Thank you, ma'am.
What the hell is that?
Impressive, huh?
But...
what's that for?
It's for people who are
a little tight on the ears.
Yeah, but the baby.
For now, he does hear well.
But in a month, in a year.
can you say
that this child will not suddenly
deaf as a post?
- No, but, uh.
You see, you have to think
about the future, Mr. Duchemin.
Yes?
Hide this machine
in the closet,
and if ever
your baby goes deaf.
he'll be so happy
to find him!
Just one kind gesture.
For a baby,
not very spoiled!
- How's that?
- No, he's not spoiled.
With your worries, with your trade...
He's not spoiled, here.
Not spoiled, admittedly!
Not spoiled.
He's having fun with Surditos.
- Do you think that, uh.
You can devote 12,000 francs
francs to the happiness of this child, can't you?
Think about the future,
one more time.
You've been told the future is nobody's.
Well, it's not! The future.
When he sold lace to the nuns,
it was his kindness that helped him. But here.
I'm afraid it's going to be a little more complicated than that.
But he looks
quite happy.
Are you happy?
He's happy. He's fine.
Thank you.
There was no rush.
Do we put him in a box
or should we leave him like that?
I don't care.
We can leave it to him for now.
Okay, all right. Goodbye!
Yes, the instructions are in the box.
I'll note that it's in Polish.
But since that's for later...
We'll have time
to learn Polish.
FERNANDEL
Seneschal the Magnificent
You're not interested in souvenirs?
Not today.
Oh, shit! Fine.
I see you're not interested
you're not interested in souvenirs either.
Please stop nagging.
I haven't told my parents
to my parents yet,
but I already hinted at it.
I'm making them.
You're ashamed of me!
Mireille!
- But that's what it looks like.
Dad's been going out of his way
about this hunt.
We'll show up at your place, but no one
will know who we are.
Please!
Let's go.
See also.
Ah, these are friends of my parents.
If they see me, it's for an hour.
Could you let me through,
please?
Monsieur, you are on the sidewalk.
And the sidewalks belong
to the pedestrians.
Well, not this one.
Now what, there are
different categories of sidewalks?!
Where are we going?
- Monsieur,
when my husband, in 1918.
marched in a parade,
he was on the highway!
- Ellen,
you know that in November, 1918.
I was in bed with the mumps.
Oh, come on, come on.
Oh, come on,
make a kind gesture!
The highway is for cars,
the sidewalk is for pedestrians!
- I'm warning you, I'm going.
- Here!
They're friends of my parents.
All right, for your pleasure.
I'm only gonna try to hit one.
You're so beautiful. The most
the prettiest girl on the Champs Elysees.
What about other places?
- And we're not going that way.
- Oh, don't touch me!
Take me to the station!
Come on, come on in quietly.
I want to go to the station!
Is that my right?!
I don't have a lot of rights
I have left.
I expect
to elevate the precinct
the tortured voice
of the last pedestrian in Paris!
Your humble servant,
gentlemen. Let's go!
You'll see, it's gonna
will change your life!
Well, we didn't complain much,
Mr. Martin.
Thank you.
In America now.
everyone's wearing Sourdittos!
Mr. Martin!
Mr. Surditos.
oh, Mr. Deputy Director!
Trading
during business hours?
- Yeah.
- In my office now!
So,
is that her?
- Yes, it is.
And this time, I have to say,
I was very lucky!
It's the highest grade!
You're about to hear
that sound!
With a motor like this.
you'll never be bored!
That's because
I didn't warm it up.
Yeah, I let it cool down,
because when it was heated up.
it was smoking.
The smoke, of course,
it's not that significant,
didn't interfere with the steering at all.
Tell me, Mr. Duchemin,
I have to take
my driver's test.
Here I was thinking that, uh.
Here, Mr. Deputy Director, this is what you wanted
you wanted to give your mother.
Thank you.
We're having the wrong October.
I had nothing to do with it!
What do these two receipts mean?
Auguste put
a second carburetor on the Rita,
and Robert is the second compressor
on the Marilyn?
Up until now, our cars
have had ordinary performance!
I'll take care of it, Mr. Deputy Director.
See you soon, goodbye.
- It's not hard at all!
- Yes, it is.
We'll have to do more
to improve.
It's Robert's fault.
You keep saying
that my "Rita" is hot.
I've got a boosted engine!
Otherwise it's just an ordinary car.
And it's supposed to give fire!
That's what this is for!
All right. Uh-huh.
I'll see what I can do.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Martin,
thank you, thank you!
You can count on us
if you need a favor in return.
Yeah, here's the thing, by the way.
I have to take my driver's license
for my driver's license.
Here I was thinking that, uh.
- You have to go straight.
- I'm going straight, aren't I?
- Brake, brake!
- I can't find the brake...
- Brake in the middle! In the middle!
- I can't find it!
Oh, I found it!
Let me do it myself!
Stupid!
That's my wife.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- I feel like I'm making progress already!
Hey! Watch out! Watch out!
Watch out!
О! You're gonna pay me
for the oranges! You!
Don't worry, darling.
I'll take half a kilo from you.
Half a kilo?! What nerve!
Come on, pay up, don't argue!
Pay up, pay up.
You're so funny! Pay up!
50, 60... 80...
100... and so on...
I stop...
Letting off the gas.
And I'm releasing the clutch.
And I'm slowing down.
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm slowing down.
All right!
I have a feeling it's going to be great!
There was one world, and then ho.....
Did you see me, Mireille?
I'm huddled on the sidewalk.
Off.
handbrake.
Ignition.
Margarita,
is it definitely set for 2:00?
You don't have to ask me
every five minutes!
You're just nervous.
- No, I'm not nervous!
I'm very calm.
I'm not embarrassed
I'm not embarrassed at all.
But we could, Dad,
could we go over the rules again?
I've read them 2 times.
It's not like I'm gonna sign up
for night classes,
to memorize a brochure
12 pages! Ridiculous!
Let's get strong.
Who's there?
Just don't worry.
I knew it, he's having lunch!
It's noon, my dear!
At noon, the French.
Of course! It's a forgivable habit
in normal times.
But all exams are based
on the same principle:
full head, empty stomach!
Difficult digestion
is the candidate's enemy.
You'll fall asleep at the wheel.
О!
Mr. Martan,
weak tea improves
mental acuity.
Look at the English!
- I hate tea!
The English, too!
Oh, but they're not easy guys,
these young men!
- I did what you asked!
- Well done!
And may I ask,
what you did?
My father called the examiner -
yours and Mrs. Martin's.
Blat?!
Monsieur, I have failed
I have failed at many things in my life,
but I failed them
on my own!
Besides, I don't believe in blatancy.
But it's not about blag,
Mr. Martin!
We just gave your names
to the examiner,
only stating that morally.
you deserve a driver's license.
That's all.
- Oh, okay. That's better!
Another thing.
Be brave!
Everything is on your side!
In that case,
thank you, gentlemen. Thank you.
- We'll come over to celebrate your success!
- See you soon, then!
Maybe we could have a cup of tea,
Marguerite?
I don't have any tea.
Would you like an orange, Daddy?
Oh, no!
I'm sick of oranges!
Well, you shouldn't have turned over
the whole cart!
How! It's you!
Don't be nervous!
- They're coming!
- They're coming.
А! They're coming.
The stopping is flawless!
My style!
Leon, look!
Yay!
- Are you all right, Carteret?
- Everything's fine, Mr. Inspector.
All right. [Chuckles]
Go have some coffee.
I'll take an exam from one or two,
reminisce about my youth.
Oh, that's great.
- Well, it's my turn.
- Go on, you don't want to keep him waiting.
I'll see you soon.
Is he kind?
- The sweetest!
You couldn't have done better!
Come on, don't be afraid.
It's not the President of the Republic.
Hello, monsieur!
Martan! Leon Martin.
It's me.
I know.
Yes,
I know you know.
Believe it or not,
I abhor
any form of favoritism.
Of course, in serious
cases like mine.
Shall we go? Let's go.
Would you allow me to ask you
a few questions about the rules?
Please.
Please, please.
Let's get these
little formalities.
You're very confident.
I'm sure of you, too.
When you cross a busy street
traffic, what do you do?
Actually, mind you, normally.
Margarita would be the driver.
She just passed.
- And suppose Marguerite didn't?
Well...
Well, then, if there's nowhere
there are no cars anywhere.
well, if there isn't one,
right or left.
I'm passing through.
But if the traffic
is very dense?
Dense traffic?
Well, if it's heavy traffic,
Well, then I guess there'll be a guard there.
I'll do what he says!
All right. Uh-huh.
A little judgment and
a little discretion and caution, and it'll all work out!
It's not complicated!
What's the sign that warns you
about turning?
A sign that warns
It's a pink sign
with green edges around it,
and a big zigzag
in the middle.
Sometimes they add children
playing with baskets.
Mm-hmm.
Let's go.
I'll close it, it's windy!
Oh, your hat!
Oh, I'm sorry.
- It's a different examiner!
- Oh, they're all worthy.
- Oh, no!
- Here, I got it, Mr. Inspector.
I'm sorry, that was
involuntary movement.
I hope it's not too badly spoiled.
- Come on, let's go!
Would you like to drive?
No? Yes... okay.
If he's good at shifting
in first, he'll be saved.
Disaster!
It's obvious he learned
on a hearse!
Get out of here!
I'd get out! But how?
They're everywhere!
It's been 20 minutes
since they left!
- Why don't we go for tea in Rambouillet?
- Very funny!
I didn't pass?
You're making fun of me
at me?!
Oh, that's how it is! All right...
We'll see about that.
Next!
- How am I doing?
- You'll be fine with a shotgun.
Of course, there will still be
the cuffs.
And the car?
We have to decide today!
We'll go soon. We'll go to the place
where Duchemin bought his truck.
Hopefully, for 300,000 francs.
we'll find something decent.
Yeah, I've got three more Sourditos
three more Surditos.
Anyway,
you'll have to behave
smart, Marguerite.
You know, uh,
things are heating up at home.
My parents launched an attack
to get me to marry their protégé.
- Hélène Cordier?
- Yes, of course.
Her father will soon be
richer than mine!
This is just unacceptable!
- And she'll be on your hunt?
- Yes, she will.
It's in two days, Mireille.
They won't make me!
If I have to, I'll run away
and come after you.
We'll walk hand in hand through the streets,
and sleep under bridges!
We're gonna be happy,
because we'll be together!
And taking advantage of the fact
of the music hitting your ears,
I will tell you
that I love you,
while the rest of us
can't hear us.
KING
USED CARS
"DRIVING LOW."
"AS NEW."
"ONE OWNER"
"DRIVING LOW."
"AS NEW."
Is this a job? А? A job?!
You've been here eight days,
and you've done nothing but do stupid things!
Well, I'm telling you:
you're fired!
Oh, no, monsieur.
Mr. Chartrice!
Mr. Chartreuse!
Give me one last chance!
- No!
I have a large family,
who can't take any hardship.
So be it! But I say
in the presence of your comrades:
I'll keep you if you sell the 777 C75
if you sell the 777 C75.
"777 С75" ?!
She's crossed the Sahara 14 times!
At least 14 times!
Nobody wants her!
- Get out of it!
But it's unsellable!
There's a lot of complicated work
complicated work, and then, uh.
All right,
I'm gonna go pack my things.
There's a scooter store
is offering me a job.
Right where I belong.
I was kicked out eight days ago.
And here, perhaps,
your clients.
Nervous, shy....
It's their first car.
If they come in,
you might have a chance.
Hello, monsieur.
Hello, monsieur,
hello, madame!
Heaven sent you.
I hope so.
We need a car,
of course.
That's great,
we got 87 of them!
I should add that we've had them for a long time.
So we know them like the back of our hand.
Follow me.
The problem is relatively simple...
We need
a big car!
- Ah! Big car?
- Yeah, big car.
I mean, do you want
a big car?
- Yeah, I'm good for it.
- Uh, okay. Uh, excuse me for a second.
Be persistent.
It's like you're begging!
Leave it to me!
They want a big car.
I said: "777 С75" !
He was impressed with us.
He consults with his superiors.
- All right, I'll go organize.
- Uh, yeah.
Are you done?
No.
Take them for a walk.
Well, I'm gonna go for a walk with them.
А! Here we go!
Do you want a well-known brand?
We need one that's gonna
to make an impression.
It's for an engagement at Solonie.
First for the engagement party, but to make sure
the car would serve us well afterward.
Wait, wait, wait... You need
a car to go to the engagement party,
and then, uh. So you're saying you need her
need her at least twice?
Well, yeah, at least two times.
- We have this.
- But we need a new car!
Oh, you're right about that.
The pre-war models have faded.
Look, don't give up hope.
Nothing is impossible!
- So...
- Attention, young man!
I work in an office
with 25 upholstery machines.
So, the car is comfortable, quiet....
And the motor?
Well, with a motor, of course.
Well, naturally. You don't buy a car
to push a car!
We'll take the motor that comes
that comes with the car.
So, comfortable, quiet.
and with its own motor.
This one is perfect!
It's gorgeous!
I can already see the faces
of our friends in the yard.
И...
is it expensive?
It's not very expensive.
It has a small drawback.
She's a little "floaty."
- Amphibious?
- No, I don't know. Anyway.
She hesitates on the bends.
Not long, but hesitant.
So you have to...
Anyway, don't get too turned around.
Not too much... Well, we all have
flaws-- you, me--
That's understandable.
But don't you have a model
not so dangerous?
We'll find it, we'll find it!
Nothing is impossible!
Uh, excuse me. Uh, so.
Would you mind telling me
my boy,
why are your coworkers
staring at us like that?
They're rookies.
Watching me work,
so that later on.
to adopt my style.
I'll be honest with you,
I'm kind of the owner's favorite around here.
But let's not...
That's so funny!
It's, uh. well, it's, uh. no.
Do you know if you have this model
do you have this model? I'd love to.
Alas, it's a Bulgarian model.
You won't find it at all.
- All right, then.
- Please!
Uh, no, it's that way...
You're a strange salesman.
You don't advise us.
We're an honest store.
I can't let you
drive off in the middle of nowhere!
I can't feel my legs anymore!
Never mind! It's not like we're getting out of here
We're not walking out of here!
What about this one?
Uh, uh. Uh, well.
No, no, no! You can't!
It'll break!
It's gonna break! Please!
There's this...
Young man,
why don't you talk about this one?
Well, this one's not for sale!
Is that so? And why?
The management is keeping her
for themselves.
What do you mean he keeps it for himself?
As far as I know, this place
everything's for sale. No?
Otherwise it wouldn't be here!
- Leon, Leon.
That pink hat that looked so good on you,
you sent to your client?
No, I kept it.
So don't get involved.
I'll handle it.
Э... how much?
- 290.
But I doubt
you'll be able to get it.
Young man,
bring in your superintendent.
Listen to me! What you need
a big car,
it's small!
Well, you know, it's just, uh.
Maybe I should give you a warning.
I said "big car,"
I didn't say "barge."
4 hp. - it's a big car,
if you're getting in it
not very big people.
Mr. Chartreuse!
Yes? What's the matter?
These monsieurs and madams
want your car.
A pearl!
I'm taking her home
tonight.
- I liked her.
- I'm sorry.
I promised it to my wife.
She's good at this.
Listen, monsieur,
going around your store,
you're sure to find
amongst these beautiful cars
a nice car
for Mrs. Charlessris!
All right, all right! I give up!
Take it!
- Thank you.
- I'm so excited.
- Me too!
Me too!
Take a look!
1,250 kilometers? She's only got...
What?!
Yeah, she's only got 1,250 kilometers.
That's it.
You can trust the meter.
Because in the rain.
the customers wouldn't leave,
and in nice weather.
- even more so.
You can see, by the way, that she's been taken care of.
Well, nothing's impossible.
And, you see, at speed.
it will work!
All right, then,
I'm gonna start her up!
I'm gonna turn the key in the ignition
on the count of three!
One... two... three!
It's a cinch!
- I had no doubt!
I'll take it!
- Wait, let me go!
Monsieur, we are buying this car,
to make our daughter proud of us.
She's really good, isn't she?
Cars like this--
just a little bit, believe me!
You'll see.
They're all the same.
They save the good times for themselves.
But this time.
you got the wrong guy!
All right. (chuckles)
If there are any malfunctions,
you have until tomorrow
until tomorrow, 12:00.
Well, 12, 12. 12 and a quarter!
Don't worry!
I'm sorry.
If you're wondering where the motor is,
it's right here in the back.
- Goodbye, monsieur, and thank you!
- Goodbye!
Here you go.
We tortured you, huh?
There's a little bit.
But that's okay.
No offense. You're welcome.
- Oh, it's this way.
No, not that way. This way.
Please.
Let me go.
- But you don't have a license!
- But I'm a better driver!
What an ego! What if you
hurt someone?
Then we're gonna make a quick switch
places. Move.
Hold on, I'm moving.
Let me drive
my car!
I can tell,
you just got your license!
Do you own
this machine?
- Turn the motor off!
- I can't!
- Take the key out of the ignition!
- I did! Here it is, the key!
What's going on?
- Admit you don't know.
Oh, just a minute, huh?
All that's left
to stop the windshield wipers.
The engine must have gotten a little
overheated. You'll see.
You've been sold a model
with a very independent character.
But we, my dear,
we're still doing it!
We parked in front of your house
because there were no spaces across the street.
- Want to go for a ride?
- Never!
I have an aversion
to automobiles!
He's so post-Marna!
He was in a cab
between Fauche and Galliani,
my son-in-law was driving...
- Enough, Hélène! Enough!
I didn't touch anything!
It sometimes starts on its own.
Maybe there's something about the plugs
not shutting off properly?
Hush, Marguerite! Hush!
Quiet!
You see!
She reacts to noise.
I should have known.
- Ah, the case, Marguerite!
- A case?
- Give it!
- Careful.
Don't turn left!
You're turning left!
Wait, that's it.
- Spin it!
- Don't pull, don't pull!
- Just spin it!
And in general,
stretch it first!
Stick to the system!
Let me pull first.
Is that right?
- That's right.
It's going to work.
- I can't do it!
Did you do that on purpose?
- It's not me, it's the wind!
- Yeah, the wind, the wind.
- We need to coordinate our efforts.
- Now, hold on.
Guillard, don't laugh,
but command it.
Attention!
On my command:
once...
two...
three!
Oh, shit!
To tell you the truth,
it was a little small.
- Where am I supposed to hook it up?
- Like me, to the bumper.
There's no bumper.
- How is there no bumper?
- No bumper.
- No bumper...
- I'm telling you, no bumper.
- Ha, no bumper!
- Go look for yourself!
Here, look.
No bumper?
Probably lost it on the road.
She's good!
She's very good!
Yeah, it's good, but we'll
we'll show it to you tomorrow,
because today.
she made a huge effort.
But you don't have a bumper!
No, my dear,
there's no bumper. I know there is.
Have a nice day!
You see that car,
Marguerite?
And there's nothing special about her
nothing special about her, huh?
But I definitely
like her!
I love it!
AUTO PARTS STORE
Pay attention, daddy,
when you turn around!
- Mr. Martan!
- Mr. Deputy Director!
- Did you buy the bumper?
- Yeah. But I got the rest of it, too.
Such a small
modest car.
Uh, would you please come
to my office.
I'm sorry...
Mr. Martin,
since you have a car,
I would ask you to go with me to inspect
of Robert and Auguste's upcoming motorcades.
I suspect there's an inappropriate spirit
there's an inappropriate spirit in our office!
Observe
and then report back!
All right, Mr. Deputy Director.
Would you allow me
ask you for a favor?
- Spell it out.
- Here.
With any luck, my daughter
might be getting engaged tomorrow.
- It depends on what?
- On the hunt, Mr. Deputy Director.
For my daughter's happiness.
I will enter a very closed society.
I'll shoot my paws....
- I don't understand anything!
Go take your day off!
- Thank you, sorry.
They've come to inspect,
Mr. Martin?
Yes, dear Bosro.
Do you mind? Is everything all right in there?
- See for yourself.
- Okay, I will.
But what are they doing?
We'll never make it this far!
Hello, gentlemen...
Hello, gentlemen!
I hope you're happy. э,
satisfied with the beautiful ceremony.
No, it's kind of endless!
Where's the driver?
You're going now.
You are.
- That thing burst again.
- Robert!
Oh, you bastard!
Hey, Robert, what are you doing?! I'm not going.
I have my own car!
Robert, stop!
Are you crazy?
He started it!
Trying to get away from me,
because I'm more loaded!
- Shut up, please!
- Yeah, very elegant!
Oh, sorry! We're going fast.
If you have a moment,
take a look at the speedometer!
Slow down, Robert!
Auguste, stop this bullfight!
I'm firing you! Both of you!
Here we go.
You shouldn't have
to stand up for us, Mr. Martin.
- All three of us got fired.
- How stupid! For some sin.
The race would still be on,
but what ruined us was that you lost
the coffin on the Quai de Javel.
- What will you do, Mr. Martin?
- Oh, I don't know.
I'm not gonna say anything at home yet,
because tomorrow. we have, uh.
great day!
They're coming!
- Good morning!
- Oh, you're gorgeous!
Splendid! Splendid!
Oh, that looks good on you!
It's not as great
as your husband's, but it suits!
I'll try not to mess it up.
- Ah, a gun!
- Always useful!
Marcel used it to shoot down
an airplane in 1940!
The machine was falling,
and Marcel was calmly aiming.
This may be cruel,
but it's either the plane or him!
Ellen, I'm ordering you
to return to the house.
Now!
- Not too brutal?
- You're not going to play, you're going to kill!
- It's my first time.
- I'm sorry.
A booty bag.
Credibility is in the details.
We'll fill it!
The guiding principle:
Don't skimp on accessories.
My father's binoculars!
The real Leon!
Good luck!
Watch the gun!
My respects, everyone!
Good luck! Bye!
Ellen, would you please hand me
my logbook.
Yes, Father.
Here you go.
Let's do it!
2 liters of "super."
3 liters of plain.
4 liters of plain.
2 liters of "super."
5 liters of plain.
This is a dosage of my invention,
that gives you a lightning-fast leap from your seat.
2 liters of "super."
How long is it gonna be like this?
Maurice, I want you to pass the word
"get out" to this fanfare.
Answer your master,
that it's better to look like a fanfaron,
than an old mummy with a nervous tic!
Jokes!
- Enough!
I don't mess with vacationers
going rabbit hunting!
I'll get gas
somewhere else!
Vacationers.
You're the vacationer!
Did you see this one?
- I did.
- I answered him!
- Well done!
10 liters.
How far is it to Orleans?
- 12 kilometers.
Fanfaron.
I don't care about the fanfaron.
Monsieur! Bring the car over here!
With their parking system.
no one will see we're in a car!
Do what everyone else does.
And who's that?
Dad, these are my guests.
The nicest people.
Monsieur has a big business.
If I were him, I'd have a smaller business
a smaller business with a bigger car.
Come on, I saw it.
Well, look.
They would have walked from the train station,
the effect would have been the same.
All right, let's go.
We're out!
First impressions
is of the utmost importance.
Oh, we've done everything
necessary.
Leon Martin.
My wife. My daughter.
She studies pharmaco-...?
- Dynamics.
pharmaco-dynamics with your
big boy. Hello!
- My wife, Mrs. De Granlew.
- Madame, it's a pleasure.
- How do you do?
- Mr. and Mrs. De Grandcourt.
All nobility, I see!
But not me. Cordier!
An old mummy
with a nervous tic.
That was a poor choice of words.
You don't have a tic any more than anyone else.
The nicest people!
It's that girl
that's been bugging you so much?
All right, let's go!
Yeah, let's go!
Everybody to their cars!
We'll set up posts along the edge
of my La Renee forest.
Give me your gun, monsieur.
All right, then. Thank you.
Well, what am I gonna use
to shoot my paws with?
And that's when my father bought everything:
a village, a hill,
the local railroad.
It will serve
for traveling servants.
I envy you: you're so rich,
and yet you've managed to stay so simple!
We could get started,
but your parents aren't here, young lady.
- Don't forget, they only have four horsepower.
- You're right, young lady.
Don't be angry,
I'm an old grouch.
If you'll excuse us, we'll go,
and the guard will wait for your parents.
Léon!
- Monsieur?
Stay here, you'll catch up with us
with Monsieur and Mrs. Martin.
Do you have his gun?
- I'll take care of it, sir.
All right. Uh-huh.
He likes you.
I'm sure he likes you.
It worked!
Hello!
Where are our friends?
- We'll go to them with Mirka.
My name is Leon.
- Oh, me too!
We have the same name!
And we have the same jackets.
- But you have different hats!
Oh, you've got my gun!
Let's go.
My gun.
let's call it what it is.
Shall we go? Let's go.
Leon!
- Hello, monsieur.
- I saw her, but she didn't wait.
He's so surprised
that you blew it.
That dog's not exactly
condescending.
What is that?
Is she swearing at me?!
- She's got the trail!
- Again?
I'm sorry.
Missed!
She's leaving.
Come on, go away, you animal!
I can't hunt
when people are pissing on me.
Try to kill something for her
kill something for her.
I do what I can!
I'm the only one you can hear!
Damn it!
Ah, there they are!
- Give me a hand.
- Quietly, quietly.
- I'm going quietly.
Careful, that's it.
I had the strangest bad luck
I didn't kill anything.
It's beautiful!
Oh, Marguerite!
We'll still have
something to eat.
All right, let's move
200 meters to St. Auban.
- Are we going back?
- No, honey, not now.
No, no, Leon!
Allow me, but this time.
deaf real.
Stop, don't!
It's a beautiful day,
isn't it?
I say,
it's a beautiful day!
Great weather!
Sunshine!
- May I serve, madam?
- No, they're not all here yet.
I don't understand why you're stubbornly picking
possibly poisonous mushrooms?
I don't want to come back
empty-handed!
- I'll try to track down your parents.
- Thank you, Paul.
Oh, there's plenty more!
I don't want to interfere
your pleasure,
but this is the third
dinner bell.
Oh, my God! Come on, let's go!
Ooh-la-la-la! I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Here are your parents,
young lady.
Here you go. Just, uh.
I want my hat back.
Excuse us, we were walking
at a measured pace.
The forest is so beautiful, so peaceful.
Compared to Paris.
That's not what I thought.
That you're from the village!
- Why?
Little things.
As soon as Paul gets back,
we'll sit at the table.
You never eat on time
eat on time.
In 1952.
at my friend Lesueur's,
CEO
of Robiche Enterprises.
I'm sorry.
How well do you know
the CEO of Robiche?
Very close.
There's a nice guy living in my house,
a simple accountant,
who just happens to work
at one of the branches.
What's his name?
Martan. Martan is like me.
It's a pretty
common last name.
This man,
not very young,
was unfairly,
very unfairly fired yesterday.
Leon! You got fired?!
Yes, Marguerite.
Some accountant!
Now, I guess
it's all clear now.
Oh, that's enough!
Exactly, Mr. Cordier,
it's very clear!
We were wrong about each other,
that's all.
It happens.
I think the one who's most disappointed
- is me.
If you knew what it took
for some accountant to get on that hunt!
Buy a car,
the ugliest car ever!
He sold 50 hearing aids
for the deaf after hours!
And even though
accountants get tired
after a day's work.
It's very hard
pretending to be rich!
to keep up the mark in the hunt,
when you've never held a gun
ever held a gun in your life!
Everything my wife and I are wearing.
we borrowed.
Neighbors! Thing by thing.
Yeah, imagine that--
she loves your son.
He really loves you.
But it doesn't matter.
We'll marry her off
to some clerk.
To each his own kingdom.
- Mr. Martin!
- Thank you, sir.
I know the way.
Oh, come on,
are we crying?
But it's Cordier, isn't it?
My father must have kicked them out.
He can't stand fools!
I still don't understand
how Father Marthan
managed to reinstate the three of us
back to work, and with a raise!
By proxy!
What kind of car do you want
to go to church in, honey?
Good taste in girls!
Guillard, come sit with us.
We'll squeeze in!
No, thanks.
I'll walk!
You'll be late!
Let's move!
Hey, Martan!
I'll ask the priest to wait!
Traffic all the way
Concord Square.
Hey, let's take the subway!
Come on, daughter.
Did you see that?
The doors close themselves!
What a mess!
Hey, did you see that?
END
Transcript and subtitles:
Lisok (Lisochek)